<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/511</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>511</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/511/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"150\nS 0 U T H - W E S T E R N  .1 O U II N A L.\n:M\nmm\n\u00bbV.lV\"\nI :\n:,..!\n.\u25a0 \u25a0 .\nnboatsdircct from Now Orleans, nnd carried! pied mostly by low, small, wooden hovels, and numerous\ncross  fences of plank, immediately  off the  Streets;   win.],,\nI     UlC   Cll\\ ,   W [HUH    1I1K1II \\      ICUCllll   IHIU.\"   \u00ab..\u2014      UUJWHAV1     IU....WU,      w ~      -3-\"  \u201e.......-,,,,,],\u25a0 [j\npestilence: especially was it believul, that are protected from moderate breezes by an adjacent hili,\nbeen freely used, was an important prophy-|From the brinks the ground rises gradually, in one or two\nlanded from steamb\nto the hospital.\nSo long had been tho intermission of epidemic malignant every facility is afforded by them for stagnant air, which can-\nfever in tho city, that tho inhabitants began to entertain the not be swept out by moderate winds. It extended itself in\nhope, if not the belief, that the strict attention of the police tojnlmost every instance towards the immediate vicinity of the\nthe cleanliness of the city, would finally redeem it from other,bayoux or ravines, or in the low grounds contiguous, which\n... ,      , -.      ' \u2022    -,\" '\u2022   C     I! 1      .1\u20141   .--      --    \u25a0     -.-J     C-       1      1 \u201e....    1      \u201e.!!_ .     ....\nvisitations of the ;\nlime, which had be\nlactic.\nVI.    The Epidemic of 1337, began by a lew sporadic\ncases about the 8th and Oth of September, and became epidemic about the 15th.    Yet the cases were not numerous or\nvery malignant until about the middle of October.    In the\nfirst ten or fifteen days of iis prevalence, many cases were\nmild or so modified as  to create doubts in minds of many\nwhether the disease- were really malignant yellow fever. D\nring this time, if efficient means hud been taken to cause the\npopulation to disperse, and desert the city, we doubt not the\npestilence might have been stayed: but it was not until near\nthe 25th of September, that the Board of Health or the city\nauthorities, could determine, from the opinions of the medical\nfaculty, as to the actual danger which the citizens would en\ncounter by remaining in the city.    For want of timely no\ntice of the danger, tho dispersion was gradual and slow, even\nuntil the middle of October.    The disease continued to prevail, with occasional abatements, until tho 25th of November;\nalthough the prevalence of the disease was much checked by\nIho cold winds and frosts which occurred early in November,\nDuring the prevalence of the (lis -ase, from the 8th of September to the 25lh of November, when the last death occurred, the whole number of deaths, of all  diseases, was about\ntwo hundred and eighty, within the city and at the hospital.\nSeveral of those at the hospital, were patients landed from\nsteamboats direct from New Orleans.    Besides those, there\nwere ten or fifteen who died at different places in the country, whither they had retired, after having imbibed the seeds\nof the disease in  Natchez.    So that the entire number of\ndeaths from this epidemic, might be near three hundred.    In tl\ntho early period of the epidemic, especially, the number of\nrecoveries were much more numerous than the deaths:  probably two to one; which shows a moro manageable typo of\ndisease than was experienced in 1823 or 1825.    During the\nmonth of October, the type of the disease was more malignant and fatal.    Several cases which occurred in Washing\nton and the country, from having visited the city, assumed tlit\ncharacter of a high grade of bilious fever; and, we are informed, many of tho more manageable enscs in tho city, were\nof the same character.\nThe first cases and deaths occurred in that part of the city,\nsouth, south-east, and south-west of the intersection of Commerce and Main streets, near the heads of several largo ravines and the flat surfaces above them. About the middle of\nOctober, it had extended over the greater part of the city; but\nprevailed mostly in the declivities leading towards ihe several\nlarge ravines which put up on the south, south-west and southeast pails of tho city. Tho north-eastern half of the city\ncould hardly be saiel to havo been visited by tho epidemic.\nThe squares in which it first and most prevailed, were occu-\nhundred yards, to tho height of from twenty to forty j-\u201e(.t\nThe bottoms, and often the sides of these ravines, when not\nperpendicular, are carpeted with n short, fine grass, called\nthe \" Bermuda grass,\" which admits of no spontaneous accumulation of filth, The disease prevailed much in the same\nvicinity in 1819, as I have been assured by an eye witness,\nThe weather, for several weeks previous to the middle of\nAugust, had been attended by frequent showers and heavy\nrains. The spring had been very late and cold. From the;\nmiddle of August to the first of October, the weather was\ndry and very hot, with occasional showers. The thermometer, in the coolest situation of the open air, averaged, for the\nlast fifteen days of August, at 0 o'clock, A.M., 70\u00b0; nnd at\n3 P. M., 91\u00b0: for the first fifteen days of September, at G\nA. M\u201e 72\u00b0; and at 3 JVM- 91\u00b0: during the first fifteen days\nof October, at 6 A. M , 08\u00b0; and at 3 P. M. 78\u00b0. The first\nfifteen or twenty days of November, likewise, were nearly\nup lo summer heat, being often above SO*. Tho cool weather which occurred for a few days about the last of October\nand the first of November, appeared to have put a checli to\nthe disease; but it broke out again dining ihe warm weather\nof the first twenty days of November, Several of those who\nreturned to the city as late as the 15th of November, fell vie\nthus to the infected air contained in closed houses, after there\nlud been several frosts. Ofthis class were the deaths which\ntook place on the 17th, 18th, 19th, and 20th of November;\non each of which days the burials were from four to seven.\nA severe rain, followed by cold winds, and freezing on the\nnight of the 20th and 21st of November, finally destroyed\ninfection. The last death of those previously attacked,\nor infected, took place on the 25th of November.\nThe health of tho city, previous to the first of September,\nwas very good: no uncommon degree of sickness prevailed in\nthe vicinity, showing the disease in the city from causes operating locally. Tho yellow fever had been prevailing with\ngreat mortality in New Orleans for nearly six weeks before it\nbroke out in Natchez, during which time many patients with\nyellow fever, were received into the hospital, direct from New\nOrleans, no quarantine restrictions being imposed.\nThe only cause assigned for this epidemic, so fur as 1 have\nbeen able to ascertain, is the old one of 1817 and 1819, viz:\ndigging down and filling Up the low parts of the city; and,\nilso, city filth in certain back yards, sewers, &amp;c. On both of\nthese, as a cause of yellow fever, we have already remarked\nfreely.\nWithout entering into a close argument to prove the point,\nwc believe tho circumstances connected with the epidemic ol\n1837, ns well as of previous years, show, that when the malarious contamination of the atmosphere has attained its maximum, as a predisposing cause of disease, a few cases o(\n,","fullrs":{},"find":"512.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"511","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1790873","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.71 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
