<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/442</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>442</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/442/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"T\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\nwhich it sometimes becomes attached, do not remain long\nenough for it to attain its perfect growth. When it falls upon\nthe ground it begins to decline and finally dies, if not destroyed by cattle and other stock.\nI have seen it, though very seldom, attached by roots to the\nhark of the tree upon which it was found ; but it was only in\nthose hist! nces in which a fibre became confined by the growing of the coarse bark of the tree and was thus compelled to\ntake root in the interstices of the bark. From this attacl:\nment it has seemed to derive nutriment only to that portion\nnear the rooty attachment, where it was luxurient and branch\nincr- the remainder being as usual. For, deriving sustenance\nfrom the air, it is provided with numerous glandular scales or\nlamella; projecting out from the whole extent of the leaves\nand stem. These may be seen with the naked eye ; but with\na microscope they appear projecting from the stein, like the\nleaves from the stalk of mullicn, but proportionably shorter.\nBetween them also are seen many fine brown spots or pores,\nwhich appear, when seen through a microscope, like large\napertures with a raised margin and centre, and around the\ncentre in the groove between it and the margin are perceived\na or 0 small apertures or pores, penetrating the substance of\nthe stem. These are doubtless glands or pores by which\nthey derive their nutriment from the damp air.\nThis moss is evidently an evergreen and grows most\nin the damp warm weather of winter :* although it grows\nalso in summer. Cold winters injure it, and very severe cold destroys its luxurience. It blossoms late in\ndie spring and in summer; and bears a small bell-shaped\n(lower, about the size of the small ground daisies. These\nflowers grow solitary and sesile in the axillas between the\nleaves and branches of the main stem. The flower is succeeded by a one-celled, trivalvcd capsule, about half a line in\nthickness and one inch in length, and sometimes less; this\ncapsule contains from five to twenty small oat-shaped seeds\nfrom one, to one and a half lines in length, and about one fifth\nor one sixth of a line in thickness.\nThe seeds arc closely imbeded in the upper extremity \u00b0f\ntin: capsule; and each is attached to the extremity of -c filament or stipe; this filament or stipe is inserted into -'he receptacle by a small pedicel provided with an ogre.' of 20 or 30\nremarkably fine silky fibres, from five to seivn lines in length;\nalso each seed, at the opposite end of the filament or stripe, is\nprovided with a similar fine pappus of silky fibres nearly ns\nlong as those of tho egret. These silky capillaries are remarkably apt to attach themselves and hold to any thing\nrough, Hence when wafted by currents of air they readily\nattach themselves to the bark of trees, where they germinate\nand grow. The egret and pappus upon the seed doubly\nensure its attachment to the bark and branches of almost every\nkind of trees.\nThe seed matures late in the fall, when the capsules burst\nami the seeds, by means of their egrets and pappus become\ndisseminated by the winds.    During a  warm damp winter,\n' Ii win i,e remembered Hint our winters Instead of being seasons of extreme\ncold, nn- often rather seasons ofwet weather\u2014Hie thermometer sometimes rang.\n'ni! from lo\u00b0 to 75\u00b0 of Fahrenheit in December mid January ; and but very sel\ndom below ao\u00ab Fahrenheit.\nthese seeds will produce a short bud of the moss from one\nfourth of an inch to one inch in length, of the same color and\nappearance as the leaf of the moss.\nThis vegetable, although in appearance composed of large\nbunches or tangled tresses, when each single plant seperated\nto itself, consists of a long fiextious stem, from six inches to\nfive feet in length, of a greyish green or grey appearance,\nwith dichotomous and trichotomous leavesor frond lets putting\nout from the main stem every three or four inches, each leaf\nbeing from half an inch to one and a half inches in length and\nsubulate. About every eight or ten inches, and sometimes\nless it sends off a lateral branch, which like the main stem\ngrows annually, and sends forth other branches and leaves.\nThe main stem as it bangs suspended across the slender\nbranches of trees, grows Irom both extremities, while the\nlateral branches can grow at one end only. The long fresses\nwhich cover the forest trees are made up of several separate\nplants intertangled and intertwined together; all hanging\ndown together with their leaves and lateral branches of different lengths, cause them to appear like amorphous masses of\nfibres and ends.\nThe extent to which these branches grow in any given\ntime is not known to the writer; but it js probable that the\nbranches do not grow more than two or three inches in one\nyear, if so much. I have seen the young shoots from the\nseed not more than an inch long, which were probably the\ngrowth of one year; others which were from two to six\nncbes, were probably the growth of two or three years;\nthose of four or five feet in length are probably the growth of\nhalf an age.\n1 have seen germs of moss in January, not more than one\ntenth of an inch long, growing out of the seed; and this I\nsuppose was the growth from the fall seed which bad matured\none or two months-before; as other seeds which had not escaped from the capsules had not sprouted at all, or very slightly.\nEach stem or principal branch after one year's growth contains- hi the centre, a small black fibre, knotted or jointed at\n.\u2022he points where the branches and leaves put forth. When\nthe epidermis or bark is detached or rotted off, it leaves a\nblack knotted fibre not unlike coarse curled or knotted horse\nhair, and when in masses it resembles masses of Ihe same,\nknotted and intimately tangled together. In the South, these\nfibrous matters are used for the purposes for which hair, straw,\nand wool, are used at the North, in the manufacture of cushions, mattresses, pads, and harness padding, and for these purposes it is even more valuable than hair or straw. Nearly\nall the mattresses and summer beds in the South are made of\nthis valuable article. M.\nWashington, Miss., Jan. 31st, 1838.\nTHE SOUNDING MOUNTAIN.\nThe following is an extract of a letter from Lieut. Welsted,\nated Mount Sinai, September 26, 183G, and published in the\nJournal of the Asiatic Society, Bengal:\u2014\" You once expressed a wish to know something of the Djibbel Narcono or\nsounding mountain, concerning which there has been so much\ndoubt and discussion in Europe. I visited it on my way\nhere\u2014it is situated on the sea shore about eight miles from\nm\niiii\n*.\n\u25a0\n'\u25a0;\nI\nil","fullrs":{},"find":"443.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"442","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1763892","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
