<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 24</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2183</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2183</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2183/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 24","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"24\nIt is a subject of great and growing importance to secure an element of power am\nprosperity now operating to our sectional disadvantage, and it would be unwise ta\npermit those armies of immigration to go annually into the Northwestern territor*.\nbuildup a column of States along some great iron highway to the Pacific, and estabtaj!\na governing power which will ultimately control the policy of the Union. Let us p^.\nmit no mere prejudices of race or section to deprive us of a fair participation; there\u00bb\nno natural antagonism between the varieties of our species\u2014it is the mere antagonism\nof sectional interest that divides them. Our own ancestors were Northern men; ate\nwe the less true to the interests or honor of one section ? Take even the polyglot\npopulation from Europe, and in a few generations it adopts our language, our sectional\npeculiarities, and supports the flag of the Union with as much devotion as those whoae\nextraction traces through the most remote ancestry. Like the turbid waters of the\nMississippi, it requires but filtration to render it pure and salubrious.\nAnother great source of political influence of the North is derived from her shipping\ninterest, and this has been built up, in a great degree, by the facilities of receiving from\nand remitting into the interior the subjects of commerce. But the Southern Statu\nhave failed to cultivate that important interest, and have bestowed upon the North\nthose freights which have trained the mariners of America for a national contest. It is\nthe resource of exclusive coastwise trade with the Southern States, and the assurance\nof almost a monopoly of Southern exports, which repealed the tonnage duty, reversed\nthe trident of the mistress of the seas, and achieved a triumph greater than those of\nActeum or Trafalgar It was the staples of the South which nerved the pinions that\nwaved to supremacy. Cannot the South encourage her sons to marine adventure.\nThe coast of Virginia and the Carolinas abound with hardy and resolute seamen.\nPierce but the interior with the railroad; strike the rock now barren; and the streams\nof commerce will gush forth to her ports, and call her sons to honorable and advantageous employment.\nI will assign no specific representation to an interest so connected with the industrial\nconcerns of a State. But enough has been said to prove that internal improvement,\nwith its inevitable result of manufactures, commerce and immigration, have generated\nan electoral and representative power sufficient to establish the supremacy o'\nthe North.\nTo prove, however, that the system of self-development recommended to the Southwest is based upon considerations of patriotism and of sectional prosperity, and up*1\nno idle fears of the safety of the South, or of the integrity of her institutions'? Itma*\nnot be improper to state a few facts in regard to the relative physical condition ot the\ntwo sections, and first in regard to this comparative area.\nThe area of the Southern and Southwestern slaveholding States\nis, in acres, ...... 537,064.160\nThe area of the Atlantic non-slaveholding States and including\nthe Territory of Minnesota, - - - 344,642,16\u00b0\nExcess of area in favor of the slaveholding States,      -       - 193,322,000\nThis comparison would allay the apprehension that slavery can be surrounded\nextinguished by the geographical portion ofthe Northern section ; but farther reflects\nwill show that slavery is in no danger from the want of operative area.\nThe number of slaves in the United States is 3,l78.05o.    Now, if the whole arc8^\nthe slaveholding States be alloted to the employment of this class, it would glV\neach slave an area of 170 acres.    If, however, we suppose that the agricultural ^P","fullrs":{},"find":"2184.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2183","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"549686","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.52 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
