<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/428</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>428</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/428/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"\\m j\n63\nS 0 I' TH-wESTE R N  JOURNAL.\n\" i ;'\neloquent, and always judicious. As 1 comes a Christian divine, and philosopher, be adopts as his principle, \"that the\nconscience of every individual is lo him the supreme and ultimate rule of duly;\u2014but to insure safe decisions, Ihe mind\nmust be kept free from prejudice and passions, and above all,\nit must be guided, regulated, and enlightened.\" In this, he\nfollows Bishop Butler, who. among uninspired men, is in the\nfirst class of moral teachers. \"Conscience was, says that\nwriter, placed within to be our proper governor, to direct and\nregulate all undue principles and motives of action. It carries\nits own authority with it, that it is our natural guide, the guide\nassigned us by the Author of our nature.\"\nSome modern writers have adopted the utility of actions\nand their expediency, as the criterion of their rectitude and\nthe supreme standard of obligation. With whatever ingenuity and force they have maintained their hypothesis, it cannot\nbe denied, that it is liable to mislead, and therefore not a safe\nguide of huminconduct. Th sue-:! nil.-, undoubtedly, is to\nfollow an enlightened conscience, and in all cases to act as we]\nshould wish others to do to ns in a similar situation, The\nstudy of morals serves to enlighten the conscience, and to\nquicken ils sensibility. And where the actions of men are\nperformed under a sense of accountability to God, and with\nan assured belief of a future state, we shall rarely err, either\nin belief or action.\nHiving adopted an enlightened conscience ns the rule of\nduty. Dr. Adams proceeds to consider.\nI. Our relation to God, and the moral duties thence arising.\nII Our relation to our country, and the moral duties thence\narising; that is, the duties of patriotism.\nIII Tie' ::,:.: le-;.;::-.:-; cf mankind to one another, and'\nthe duties th ..:. is - i thai is. (he duties which men reciprocally \u2022-\u2022-.'   \u2022   :h   '..-..\".\nIV. Pers .. : :      s,   rl\nV   A   revi w of the ch\nof life, so far as regardj -\nvolve, their moral pri:\n&amp;c.\nVI. A special consideration of certain duties and virtues,\nof a character peculiarly Christian : and a similar consideration of certain vices and evils.\nThe .-.:.. -::i of ihe treatise embraces a review of\nthe ch:-.:' me ;::s on which we are to rely, for improving\nthe moral condition of mankind, and advancing human\nhappiness.\nI will only add to these remarks, that the writer has illuminated every page with choice illustrations from the most distinguished writers of ancient and modern times, and from\nthese who adorn our own country, as well as Europe. He\nhes e:.lis:ed, in the cause of morals, the authority of genius:\nand he has shewn great judgment, as well as industry, in selecting his authorities. It is a work of great labor. In\nmorals, as in law, the mind seeks an exact rule; although it\nmay be otherwise in poetry and works of imagination. If\ntruth is desired in the latter ils the basis, still the writer does\nnol seek, .Mirth,- reader r-Tiir\", exacl illustration\nvs of men to themselvi\njyments\n:..-   :.. iral Ji:ivs  which ::,- y in-\ns. practices, influences, tendencies.\n\u2022-..r tin- South.Western Joonm,\nWOM 1&gt;\"'S CONaUEST,\nA POEM.\nHigh Mope my bosom swelled, and I was proid;\nBut o'er me hath passed life's bitter wave,\nAnd in the utter wreck of human hopes,\nThe pride of heart hath been subdued.\n# # * * \u2022\nHast ever felt the hand of poverty\nTo press thee down in dust, or bowed thyself\nBeneath affliction or misfortune's power,\nAnd not discerned, ere long, above the clouds,\nHope's bow of promise?    Or, a mariner,\nHast ever been upon the midnight deep,\nDriven and tost upon ihe sounding seas,\nAnd not been made to utter, audibly,\nAccents of praise, for that dear, lonely star,\nThat, breaking through the night, and tempest gloom,\nAnnounced to thee,the storm and peril past?\nYes, weary, heavy-laden souls have hope;\nThe tempest tost find rest.    But who may tell\nOf rest or hope, for him, whose beau is pierced,\nAnd rankles with the wounds of friendship false I\nOr who can face the wo: LI with even temper,\nWin n slander's poisoned tint hath reached his name,\nAimed by a hand, he would have thought the last\nTo aim a weapon there!\nTo be deceived,\nTo find our ardent confidence betrayed,\nAnd made th\" sport of he-artless treachery,\nAh! 'lis too much for frail humanity !\nBut I have fell the archer's fatal shaft,\nAnd, like the stricken deer, in vain have sought,\nAmid t':.\" herds of men. in wild tumult,\nTo s    'he or to forget ihe raging pain\u2014\nBut 'twns an arrow dipped in gall, and vain\nWar the relief.    Yes, pleasure's syren songs\nNow vainly fell upon my careless ear;\nIn  vain, her fairy forms, their giddy dance\nLed on, in halls of sensual delight,\nAnd beckoned me lo them to come away;\nIn vain, ambition pointed glory's path,\nThe world, its gay allurements spread, in vain.\n* * * \u00bb *        *\n1 et. in my heart, there sprang one ray of hope,\n(St  ....'\u2022- hope !  E'en by despnir itself inspired,)\nWhich lighted, with a momentary smilo\nOf melancholy joy, my clouded brow.\nA hope, and a fell purpose of revenge,\nIt was. that cans.el that melancholy smile.\nYes, my account was sailed with the world,\nAnd I exulted in the fiendish hope,\nIn sanguinary strife, to meet the foe\nWho had imbittered life's well-spring to me,\nAnd. in ihe red tide welling at his heart,\nTo glut the burning spirit of revenue!\nOr willingly, by that same hand to die.\nAnd thus, in s'.veet oblivion, end, at or.ee.","fullrs":{},"find":"429.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"428","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1708612","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.63 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
