<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 25</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/614</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>614</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/614/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 25","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"in-\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n251\nblack board, and, at tho suggestion of the President, one of\nthe young ladies, with inimitable grace and dignity, requested the gentleman to come forward and explain tho problem,\ninasmuch as they had worked it out for him, but he did not\nchoose to make himself known.\n\"Music.\u2014The class in this delightful science was under\nthe instruction of Professor Pfister. He had undoubtedly\nbeen untiring in his duties, or his class, ( many of which were\nvery young) could never have undergone the severe and scrutinizing examination to which they were subjected. The\nyoung ladies wero particularly catechised on the principles\nol the science, to which the talented Prolessor had particu\nhilly directed their attention. Before the practical illustrations were given, Mr. P. delivered a short and appropriate\naddress to the parents and pupils, a copy of which we shall\nendeavor to procure for publication. The applause which\nsucceeded ils delivery, was-a sure guaranty that it was well\nreceived.\n. \"Professor Pfister exercised the young ladies on the\npiano, accompanied by the voice, which produced a happy\neffect at tho close of the examination.\n\" It was surprising to observe with what readiness tho\nyoung ladies answered all questions put to them. Many of\nthem wero examined in all the classes, and their minds were\nconsequently diverted from one study to another with great\nrapidity\u2014there was no looking at tho book; they know it\nall. It was indeed a gratifying scene for the President nnd\nhis capable assistants, to behold so noble a reward for all their\ntoil in ' teaching the young idea,' but how much more gratifying must it have been to parents, many of whom came from\na distance, to witness the expansion of their daughters' intellects and their increase in useful knowledge. Tho room was\ncrowded every day, and it is worthy of remark, that the\nyoung gentlemen, by their polite and constant attention, con-\nvinced us that they had the welfare of some of the rising\ngeneration deeply at heart!!\n\"On Fiiday, Miss Martha Fort, a young lady of the\nInstitution, delivered tho following address to her young associates, in the Methodist Church, in the presence of a crowded auditory.\n\"ADDRE3S.\n\" One year has elapsed since the Mississippi Female Col\nego came into existence; one year, with its trials, its anxie\nties, and its toils, has passed on, bearing its unchangeable ac\ncount, since we first associated ourselves together in the pur\niuit of knowledge. One year of our youth has been consumed, and wherein have wo been profited? Wo trust our\nprecious time has not been fruitlessly wasted, or our labor\nwithout advantage. Our friends have recently witnessed the\nproofs of our acquaintance with the several branches of science to which we have devoted our time, and directed our\nattention; they have seen the method pursued, in order to\ndiscipline the mind and fit it for the duties and the trials of\nlife. We trust their expectations with regard to our advancement havo been fully realized; and that their kind wishes\nand more substantial proofs of solicitude for our success, have\nnot been lavished upon ungrateful hearts.\n\"For ourselves, on taking a retrospeclive view of this our\nfirst Collegiate year, do not our hearts glow with feelings of\ndelight and satisfaction, as we retrace the steps we have taken\nin tho paths of knowledge?    And will not the hours spent\nin the acquisition of intellectual wealth, be treasured by memory, as some of the most delightful hours of our existence?\nTo my companions in this pursuit, I would chiefly address\nmyself.    I shall not speak of the importance of education,\nbelieving you are already aware of its deep and abiding influence; but leave the subject for an abler pen, and more eloquent tongue to render full justice to its merits and importance.    I shall simply speak of the influence exerted in the\nworld by woman, and of her duties in relation to that influence.    Nature seems, by her gifts, to have distinctly defined\nthe stand which each sex should occupy.    On man, she has\nbestowed strength, energy, and ambition, which prompt him\nto seek for empire over his fellow-men: while on woman,\nshe has lavished those gentler qualities which are more effectual in enchaining the heart.    But woman has ever exercised\nmore or less influence on the affairs of the moral and political world, and, as that influence has been exerted in the cause\nof virtue (and morality\u2014or opposed lo it, in the same ratio,\nhas the happiness of the human family been increased or diminished.    We need only turn over the pages of history,\nfrom the creation to the present time, to be convinced of the\ntruth of this statement.    Indeed, the first transaction which\nwe have on record, is but a sad exemplification of this assurance, which resulted in the conversion of our beautiful paradise into a scene of toil and sorrow; from thence we find\nthe annals of antiquity interspersed with the names of women who have directly or indirectly exercised a most powerful influence on their affairs.    Whole nations have owed\nmuch of their national character to tho influence of their females\u2014some, impelled by the most ardent devotion to the\nvirtues of patriotism, courage, and love of liberty, have won\nfor themselves high and deathless names on the records of\nFame.    But those nations sunk in effeminacy, where woman\nwas considered but the slave of man\u2014have soon lost their\nrank among tho nations of the earth.\n\" Woman exercised much influence in the affairs of ancient\nGreece and Rome; much of tho weal and woo of these\nmighty empires maybe traced to this source. In three revolutions in the government of Rome, the influence exerted by\nwoman was the immediate cause; and her power saved Rome\nwhen her victorious though banished Coriolanus appeared before her walls as the enemy of his country. We have also,\nrecords to disprove the truth of the assertion, that woman has\nnot ability to govern. In tho earliest history of Assyria, wc\nhave an account of Scmiramis ruling with despotic sway\nover a powerful kingdom, which, under her wise legislation,\nincreased in wealth, prosperity, and power; and who, by an\nextraordinary course of splendid actions, has recorded her\nname high upon the list of heroes and conquerors. Carthage,\nthe rival of imperial Rome, owed its existence to the energy\nof woman. And, in scripture, wc read instances of women\nelevated to the most honorable stations of power in the land\nof Canaan. In more modern times, notwithstanding the\ndeep-rooted   prejudice   against   female  domination, many\n&amp;","fullrs":{},"find":"615.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"614","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1706730","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.63 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
