<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/381</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>381</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/381/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n19\njtidice, by attachments or antipathies; whether self-love and\ninterest have been Ihe prevailing motives, or reason and judgment. We should examine our own conduct, the principles\nand motives by which our lives have been governed, whether\nwe have based our actions on the great principles of moral\nrectitude, or have only acted as we havo been influenced by\nthe impulse of the moment. In short, we should loam to\ncurb our imagination, direct our thoughts, and govern our\nwills. Then, and not -till then, shall we hive accomplished\nthe great end of our creation.\nAgain, self-government is important, as it gives us a knowledge and teaches us the government of others. Human tin\nlure has been essentially the same in every age of the world,\nMen have ever been actuated and governed by flic same\ncauses; and be, who knows himself tho best, knows man ihe\nbest; or, in other words, is the best judge of human nature,\nAs in physics, like causes produce like effects, so in morals,\nsimilar motives have bepii followed by similar actions : and\nour world has, from time to time, been visited by war, pestilence and famine, and our land drenched with human gore\nand rent by intestine feuds and commotions. To govern others, I say, we must know and govern ourselves. Alan is the\ntext hook, which we should constantly read; it is a\nbook which we always carry with us, (though, forsooth,\nsome have only a pocket edition), We must know our own\ncharacters, dispositions nnd habits. And, although we would\nsometimes gladly shrink from such an investigation) yet there\ntells the real character. Our whole lives should frequently\nbe brought up before us in review. We should consider how\nmany opportunities for improvement we have lost; how many\nthings of importance have come within our own observation,\nwhich have made no impression, but have given piece to\nthings of no value. And though wc may have lived long,\ntraversed sea and land, hoarded up the treasures of the earth,\nand stored our minds with classic lore; though we may have\nvisited the tombs of our fathers, and held converse with the\nsilent dead ; though wc may have traversed the dark and subterranean caverns of the earth,\u2014yet wo may have left unexplored a still darker recess in our own characters. Wc may\nnever have entered the human penetralia and held converse\nwith ourselves. Wc may never have studied the mechanism\nof those movements by which external things make a lasting\nimpression upon the organs of sense. To understand this\nprocess\u2014lo know ourselves, we must,'I repeal, be active and\nindustrious.\nMm often the real character of others is veiled and con\nceiled by the mantle of hypocrisy ; by pride, affectation and\ndissimulation ; and we can only know them,\"as we know\nand judge ourselves under similar circumstances. How important is this self-government and self-knowledge to him who\nis iiilrnslcd with ihe government and education of others! How\nresponsible the situation of htm who is to give tone and character to those who are to wield the future destinies of our\nnation, especially of those who are placed over our schools,\u2014\ncolleges and other seminaries of learning. In an institution\nlike this, where are congregated young men of difl'erent dispositions, inclinations and habits ; to apply the right corrective\nfor gooil moral government, and to ensure a proper amount of\nstudy, require a good knowledge of man.     And he will succeed the best who bus ihe best knowledge and command of\nhimself\u2014who, instead  of getting angry  at  the  little freaks\nwhich sometimes occur in College among young men of\nbuoyant and clastic spirits,\u2014instead of watching and spying\nevery movement, and placing a sentinel  at every student's\ndoor to awe and intimidate,\u2014will  endeavour to persuade\nthen; to a right course of conduct, by appealing to theirsense\nof honor, to their respect for themselves and for their friends.\nHe  will endeavour to  direct  and  cheer them   on their- wav\nthrotlgll the academic groves, and  greet them as  they enter\nthe portals of the temple of science.    He will tell them, that\nevery time they subdue the rising tumult within their bosoms,\nthey have obtained a victory over themselves which will tell\nupon their future destiny ;  that every such victory will raise\nthem a step higher ill the scale of moral excellence.    AIora|\nlaw always subdues without degrading, because it raises us in\nour own estimation, instead of prostrating and degrading us .'\nand the submission is agreeable because it is voluntary.    In\ngoverning ourselves, we  exercise a high  prerogative, that of\nsovereign king and lord.    Wc are not automatons\u2014mere machines moved by external force, by the baser feelings of fear\nand cowardice;   but by the nobler feelings of our nature, reason and judgment\u2014tho noblest attributes  of Deity !    This\nself-control is alike essential to the statesman, the divine, the\norator, and to all who would fill any of the great departments\nof life.    The statesman in  the limes of political prosperity,\nwhen no cloud darkens the horizon, when he is cheered by\nthe unanimous voice of his countrymen, when there are no\nparty strifes or contentions, may, though  he be not distinguished for his wisdom, legislate for the good of his country,\nand for Ihe honor of the nation.\n\" When smooth old Ocean ami each storm's asleep,\nThon ignorance may plough the watery deep;\nlltu whan tlio (lemons of tho tempest rave,\nSkill must conduct tho vessel through the- wave.\"\nYes, in the times of great excitement) when party spirit runs\nhigh, when the political elements are all in motion, when the\nclouds of public calamity have thickened to a tempest, when\nquestions of great national importance are to be discussed and\nsettled,\u2014then the skilful pilot must be at the helm ; then his\nmoral strength is brought to the test; then his philanthropy\nand patriotism are tried ; anil how many have ever borne tho\ntest! how many have always acted according to their better\njudgment !\nThe Divine, loo, in his work of mercy, should be what the\nBible is calculated lo make every ono who reads and understands it, \" perfect in every good work.\" The Iiiblc represents man as he was, is, and ever will be. This is the standard by which man may try his real character; and the Divine\nshould so understand ihe character of man that be can mete\nt a portion to each one in due season. Thus prepared anil\narmed with the sword of the spirit, he should visit the humble\ncottage as well as the royal palace. Like his Divine master,\nhe should visit the sick and the afflicted, and administer the\nealing balm of consolation. To preach with success, he\nshould know how lo govern his own feelings and the feelings","fullrs":{},"find":"382.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"381","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1751646","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
