<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/484</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>484</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/484/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 15","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN J 0 U R N AL\n111\niect was not the result of much investigation, yet the fact that\nthese colors are palest in the dryest weather, and deepest while\nthe barometer is sinking and the nir growing more humid,\nseems to corroborate the position. And this view would account at once for \" the dim transparent haze diffused through\nthe air,\" mentioned by Mr. Gaylord, as it would also for the\nderp colors of sunset during the burning of the prairies. As\nin the cause ofthe beautiful pencillingsof the \"amber west,\"\nwhich I have been calling zodiacal hnlos, (perhaps very erroneously,) I have not formed even a conjecture. It probably docs riot exist in the earth, nor even in its atmosphere, as\ndie brushes arc not visible except when the atmosphere is\ncomparatively pure. I have never witnessed them in a very\nhumid or smoky atmosphere.\nA lie-lit of another character remains to be noticed. On\nthe night of the 19th, immediately after twilight, I perceived\nllie dim outline of a pyramid of nebulous light, with the mid\ndie of its vertex in the constellation Taurus. Its base was\nabout 12\" wide, and its axis, as nearly as I can determine it\nfrom repeated observation, 1\" north of and parallel to, the\necliptic. From these facts, it will be perceived, it lies wholly\nwithin the zodiac, and hence I conclude it to be the zodiacal\nlight. Its nebulosity resembles that ofthe milky way, but is\nsometimes a little brighter. It has appeared every fair even\ning since the 19th until the presence of the moon has pre\nvented ils examination; it revolves with the heavens and disappears between 8 and 9, P. M. I should not hesitate to\npronounce it zodiacal light, but for the fact that its axis lies\nnorth of the ecliptic, instead of exactly in il at its base, or\nwith such a direction as to pass through the sun's centre; and\nbecause this axis lies parallel to, instead of making a small\nangle with the ecliptic.\nThe appearance of this phenomenon suggested to me to\nobserve the needle, us I, at first, suspected the light to be au-\nroral; and 1 was surprised to find the fluctuations so great\nHut having satisfied myself that the light was not auroral,\nthese magnetic movements were left entirely unexplained\nSince that time I have kept a register of the movements of\nthe needle. Having revolved the face of a fine compass to\nthe variation for the particular instrument, (8\" 12' east,) I\nplaced it entirely out of the influence of any local attraction,\nevelled it, and set it carefully with the needle at zero, at 4\nM,    In the morning at 9, of the following day, it was\nI\nstationary at 10' east, at 2 P. M. it hud reached zero again,\nwhere it remained till after 5 P. M., but at 11 P. M. it was\nfully 15' west I making 25' of variation in twelve hours.\nSince that time it has rarely been west of zero, but has been,\nusually, 10' east at 9 in the morning. Observations of sufficient number, and length of time, have not yet been made to\npronounce the diurnal variation so. great, though I strongly\nsuspect the fact. 1 promise to keep a register of this interesting matter, and commur.ic.ate it from time to time to the\nLyceum. How many conflicting lines and land claims would\nthe determination of such a diurnal variation, explain and\nsettle I\nAgain: the past month has furnished us with several evenings, in which the \"warm currents\" abounded. And lest\nby the insertion in the Lyceum Journal of the views of a\nwriter for the Knickerbocker, it should seem thnt those views\nmet (lie sanction of the Lyceum, I would record my dissent to\nIhem nearly in toto.    Since the questions in regard to warm\ncurrents were propounded to our body, by an honorary member, some time last summer, I have had the subject under frequent consideration, carefully noting the circumstances under\nwhich they occur, but have discovered nothing which would\noccasion mo now to trouble you, but for the above reasons.\nThese currents are not \" very rapid in their passage, nor transient in their stay,\" for I have frequently returned, after passing them, to examine them at leisure.    Nor are they more\nfrequent early, than late in the evening: for my own observations have shown them more frequent between 9 nnd 12 P.\nM.    What the writer means by \" the aggregating nature of\ncaloric,\" I cannot understand, having been early taught to believe that caloric tended to equilibrium.   If these currents be\nnothing more than the streaks of air, (warmed by the sun when\ntoo low to heat all equally,) set in motion, how shall we account for their appearance in a brisk breeze, and at so late an\nhour as 12 o'clock ?    No known properties of caloric can account for its failure to diffuse itself immediately, if the atmosphere which receives it be pure, and similar to that which\nsurrounds it.    Hence I conclude ihat its character is gaseous,\nand that it is generated very near where it is found by the\npasser-by.    That it is entirely different from common pure\natmosphere, I have satisfied myself, by finding a current, and\nremaining in it for several breaths.    It is sensible to the olfac-\ntorie-s, and very oppressive to breathe.   From ihe smothering\nsensation it produces, (resembling that one feels on breathing\na short time under bed clothes,) I have little doubt that il is a\nnitrous gas, how produced I cannot conceive.    In ploughing,\nin the summer and autumn, I have frequently opened seams\nof air confined in the heated ground, and breathed the very\nsame species of air.    And not imfreqiienlly a slight degree of\nthe same scent is perceptible in tho south wind.    (By the\nway, why is no wind, but a south one, sensible to the olfactories?)    Nor does an examination of my register sustain tho\nposition that they indicate approaching rain, or thunder and\nlightning.    For in only one instance have I rain recorded\nwithin three days of such note; at other times, six and even\neight days have elapsed without rain, or lightning in any direction, and these facts, with me, entirely discredit their electric character.    If it did not seem like \"sporting with the\nlightnings,\" I should be disposed to ridicule the idea of \"hot\nand cold currents corresponding to positive and negative\nelectricity. \"\nBut much as February has presented of interest, you are\ndoubtless reatly to wish its manes n long quiet, unless the future may furnish it a more amusing biographer. But be not\n]iasty\u2014its anecdotes are not all told. We have had rain,\nsleet, and snow, hail, thunder and mud \u2014lunar bows and solar\nbows\u2014and numerous other beaux, scarcely noticeable under\nthe head of meteorology : and I shall at least have the vote of\nthe ladies, that that month is most interesting which brings\nwith it tho greatest number of beaux. F.\nml\n\u25a0[k\\\n\u25a0\u00bbm\\\n.W;9\n\u25a0 \u25a0,'*\u25a0:\nm\ni,\nThe philosopher, who studies the works of God, is nearly\nallied to him who studies the words of his Creator.","fullrs":{},"find":"485.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"484","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1776523","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
