<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 26</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/582</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>582</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/582/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 26","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"mm\np\n# i,\nIff \u2022:\nm \u25a0\u25a0\n1\n1:\n.W-'|\n\u25a0\u00bb'\u2022:\u2022\n218\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nIll\nj ? \\\nII\ni \u25a0 \u25a0,\n..\u25a0\u2022\u25a0\n'I,'.-\n'\nh\n1.3;\ni .1.1)\nHi\n\u25a0\".Ik*  ;\n,,,\nfigures in an attitude of fondness, the arm of the one encircling\nthe neck of the other, while the disengaged hand of the one\nwho embraces is extended horizontally, as if accompanying\nby its action some expressive pledge, injunction, or discourse,\nrelating to the \"crux ansata,\" as the figure is called, which\nis presenting by one party and about to be received by the\nother, and is generally understood to represent the key ofthe\nNileOn some of tho groups, both the figures wear the human face; in others, the male wears the head of the goat,\nand in others, of the hawkOn the outer walls ofthe temple, the same subjects are frequently repeated, particularly on\nthe south, where the parties are guarded by the hovering\nvulture, accompanied by long inscriptions in small hiero-\nglyphical charactersThe design of the northern part of\nibis temple is more distinct, from being less encumbered with\nrubbish, and the sculpture is less injured and defaced.\nThe subject of these pictorial representations appears to\nrelate to the progressive rewards of a successful hero, from\nhis first receiving the benedictions of the priesthood, to his\nbeing admitted to the honor of presenting an offering in person to the divinity, arranged in successive picturesThe\nfirst toward the east, or ne'ar the portico, contains a group of\nfour persons, tho principal of which, may be either a priest\nor a deity; he wears a feathered head-dress, and from his\nwrist hangs a chain, ingeniously formed of hieroglyphieal\nemblems, while he supports himself on a staff of tho same\nadmission into their order, and the last, his incorporation\namong them by the investiture of the sacerdolal headdress\nand by his offering of bulls lo Priapus, whoso mysterious\npresidency over nil religious rites, whose triumphant elevations in all processions, whose eternal representations in eveiv\ntemple, from the threshold to the sanctuary, and even upon\nthe altars themselves, I have endeavored in vain to understandThe dress of the hero through every step, except the\nchange of head ornaments in the last, is rather that of a war-\nior than that of a priest; the features are evidently those of\nan individual portrait throughout, anel bear, in many instances, the closest resemblance in all the representations of the\nfaceInscriptive tablets are always hung near him, and the\nprotecting vulture is his constant guard; a combination of\ncircumstances which incur a supposition of its designating\ntho honors done to some successful warrior, who might have\nfounded this small temple ns a monument of gratitude to the\ndivinity who presided over his arms, and to whom it might\nhavo boon subsequently dedicated as a lasting record of bis\nvictories.\nThe inner walls of tho sanctuary represent a grand sacrifice, beautifully sculptured, the stone preserving the fineness\nand color of marbleNear the terminating door, the hero\nis represented between the priest and priestess, who both embrace him; and towards the entrance of tho sanctuary he is\nseen, attended by the female only, officiating before a rich al\nnatureTo this personage, the hero is in the act of being tar, and presenting an offering of incense in one hand, while\npresented, by a human figure, wilh a goat's head, wearing he pours out a libation with the other, Around the altar are\nthe sacerdotal habit, and followed by a female with tho lotus-1beasts and birds of sacrifice, fishes, fruits, and flowers, the lo-\nstaff and key, or crux ansataThe slender figure is closely tjis and palm in all their varieties, vases of liquors, and em-\nwrapped in a rich embroidered robe, painted in splendid CO- blemntic representations of iho divinity, lsis   Upon the altar\nlors, and a serpent is seen issuing from the front of the head\ndressThe priest reclines one hand on tho shoulder of him\nwhom he presents, and lays the other on his head, as if in\nbenediction ; while the god extends his arm, and placing his\nhand on the brow ofthe hero, bestows his approbation or his\nblessing.\nitself is represented a large boat, containing a votive temple\nsurrounded by the winged globe, tho emblem of eternity; the\nextremities of this boat arc terminated by ram's heads, executed in a bold style, and richly ornamented; and before the\nvotive temple worshippers are kneelingOver every pari\nof this picture are long inscriptions, in perpendicular co\nin the next compartment, the same individuals present tojlmnns, of small hieroglyphics, while tho hero himself is still\nhim, in whoso presence he last stood, the offering of lotus accompanied by his inscriptive tablets, and still guarded by\nflowers; and the third picture represents him with a different\nhead-dress, sacrificing to the priest and attendant female who\npresided over his first introduction, the victims for the feast,\nbound animals, birds, fruits, flowers, &amp;cThe last of these\ndivisions portray him with the horns and sacred bonnet, worn\nby the priest in the sacrifice, and presenting to the divine\nPriapus an offoring of four young bulls, which ho leads before him in a group, by strings fastened to their fore legs,\nholding them coiled in his hand, while a key hangs at the\nend of each, grasping, at the same lime, a wavy staff anel\nholding in his right hand a rod, by which the offered animals are driven.\nOn tho first inspection of this progressive history, I was\ninclined to interpri t it as the progress of a candidate for initiation into tho sacred body, with whom every attribute of\npower appears to have been lodged; and to consider tho first\nas alluding to his presentation for approval; the second, his\noffering to him who had bestowed the benediction and accep-\ntho protecting bird   Could this have been the offering of a\nspoil taken in battle? tho consecration of the vessel which\nhad borne him successfully through a voyage of danger? or\nof ono in which he was about to embark for war?\nOn following the line ofthe portico, toward the Nile, fragments are met with which prove tho attachment of other\nbuildings, now destroyed\u2014and at a short distance are the remains of a Greek or Roman circular porch, to the north ol\nwhich is a red granite statue, in a sitting- posture, of coarse\nexecution, and much disfigured, in ihe proportion of about\nnine feet high, and with the arms crossed on the breast, holding in one hand a crook, in the other, a flail, like the figures\nat the Memnoniuin at Thebes, but without hieroglyphieal ornaments, ns if it had never been finished,\nNothing remains of this temple, further to the north, except one side of the pilastered gallery, and a small part ol\nthe sanctuary wallThis edifice appears to have been built\non the same plan and dimensions as the southern one, since\nlance; the third, his sacrifice to the priesthood as the price of'the square pillars are precisely of the same size and number,","fullrs":{},"find":"583.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"582","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1746442","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
