<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 1</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2198</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2198</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2198/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 6, Page 1","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[1]\nSOUTHERN AND WESTERN\nRAIL-KOAD CONVENTION.\nPROCEEDINGS   OF   THE   FIRST   DAY.\nJanuary 5, 1852.\nThe Convention assembled at the Second Municipality Hall of New-Orleans ;\nfrom six to eight hundred delegates being present, representing eleven states,\nwere received by Col. Maunsel White, President ofthe Opelousas Convention,\nwith the following brief address :\n\" Gentlemen,\u2014Delegates from our sister states, we tender you a cordial and\nhearty welcome. We recognize you as friends and brothers, come amongst us\nby special invitation to deliberate on a matter worthy of American enterprise,\nin which the whole of the south-western states are deeply interested. Our design offers abundant inducement for the ready co-operation of all who may\nhonor us with their attention. Viewed as public undertakings, the whole Union\nmust acknowledge their importance, and even in the smaller consideration of\nindividual interests, perhaps there never were roads contemplated of higher pro-\nraise. Now, gentlemen, it will be for you to choose and elect the officers whom\nyou desire to preside over this Convention, as wc feel ourselves bound in courtesy\nto yield you that privilege, confident that in the exercise of this duty, you will be\nactuated by the sole desire of doing ample tend even-handed justice to all the\nvarious interests that may be involved. This friendly meeting of representatives of popular interest for the common consideration of so profound a question,\nis entirely in accordance with the character of our age and day ; and we sincerely\ntrust, gentlemen, that the result of our deliberations will be equally compatible\nwith the all-accomplishing genius of our country. Again, gentlemen, we bid\nyou welcome. The meeting is now prepared for organization. May He who\nalone presides in an unquestionable wisdom, bless and direct your proceedings.\"\nOn motion of J. E. Caldwell, Hon. C. S. Tarpley, of Mississippi, was chosen\nPresident, pro tern., and J. M. Burke, of Lafayette, Secretary, pro tern,.\nMr. Tarpley, on taking the chair, said he was profoundly sensible of the high\ncompliment that had been paid him, in being chosen to preside temporarily over\n'^deliberations of so great a Convention. Should a suitable occasion present\n'\u2022self, he would give his views on some of the great matters that would engage\ntne attention of the body. But this, he trusted, would be a working Conven-\non; and the first proceeding in order, was for the chairmen of delegations to\nfinalist of the delegates\nJoshua Baldwin, of New-Orleans, moved that a committee of three persons\nm each State represented in the Convention, be appointed to nominate percent officers.\nres l +\u2022 Bow, of New-Orleans, proposed a substitute for Mr. Baldwin's\ntion U l\u00b0?' t*lat a .recess \u00b0f an hour be taken ; that the chairman of each delega-\nto nn   '   m        '*sts \u00b0^ ^ir respective colleagues, and that then a committee\nnominate permanent officers, to be chosen, three from   the Convention at\nf*iXtVf-o\u00a3tom each state*\nklesat    f tm' of Little Rock' offered an amendment to the substitute, that the\nAs thS r^m- eaclx state elect one of tlieir nuraber t0 form the committee.\nmotion W*irir ^v aboUt t0 take the sense of thc Convention on Mr- Martin's\nlhe tab!        j?-      Garland, of New-Orleans, moved to lay both substitutes on\nwas t] e' arjd llls \"notion prevailed.    The original resolution of Mr. Baldwin\n8t*te for th      Pte&lt;*&gt; w&gt;th an amendment, substituting two delegates from each\nttodate 1   ]\u25a0      -\u00b0f New-\u00b0rleans, moved that preparations be made to accom-\nPresencp ln  tbe  hall, who may compliment the   Convention with their","fullrs":{},"find":"2199.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2198","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"563476","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
