<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/571</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>571</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/571/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 15","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\nm\n207\nlosophyi but, thanks to 'tho march of mind,' there is now\n,]lfl dawn of a more propitious era. Before another century shall have passed, the intellect and the soul of wo-\nin-iii, elevated, expanded and refined, by nobler studies, shall\nentertain and breathe forth such sentiments of moral Illness\nand beauty as shall not dishonor a being \"madea little lower\nthe angels.\"\nfrm\nPROPHETIC. Fulton, tho inventor of the steamboat,\nseemed to be endued with the spirit of prophecy, in respect\nto the navigation by steam of the Mississippi, the Missouri,\nnnd oilier great rivers of the west; yet we know not that it\never entered his imagination that, by his invention, Europe\nand America would bo brought within ten days of each\nother,\nThe following is Fulton's letter to tho Hon. Joel Barlow,\ndated more than thirty years ago, a few days after his first\nsteamboat trip on tho Hudson :\n\"My in:\\;t Fiiiund\u2014My steamboat voyage to Albany\nind back, has turned out rather more favorable than I hud\ncalculated. The distance from New York to Albany is\nooo handled and fifty miles; I ran it up in thirty-two hours,\nnod down in thirty hours. 'The latter is just five miles an\nhour. I had a light breeze against mo tho whole waygoing\nad coming, so that no use was made of my sails; and the\nroy.ige has been performed wholly by the power of the\nSeam engine. I overlook many sloops and schooners beating to windward, and passed them as if they had been at anchor.\n\u25a0'The power of propelling boats by steam is now fully\nproved, 'The morning 1 left New York, there were not\np rhaps thirty persons in the City, who believed that the\nton! would ever move one mile an hour, or be of the least\niiiilily. And while we were; putting off from the wharf,\nwhich was crowded with spectators, I heard a number ol\nUrcastic remarks; this is the way. you know, in which i\nnorant men compliment what they call philosophers and\nprojectors.\n\"Having employed much time, and money, and zeal, in\nsccotnplishing this work, it gives mc, as it will you, great\npleasure lo see it so fully answer my expectations. It will\ngive a quick and cheap conveyance to merchandise on the\nMississippi, Missouri, and other grcat rivers, which are now\nliving open their treasures to the enterprise of our country-\n\"ten. And although the prospect of personal emolument\n\"M been some inducement to me, yet 1 feel infinitely more\npleasure in reflecting with you on tho immense advantage\nwat ray country will derive from the invention.\"\nSANDWICH ISLANDS.\nRfinorlaMc Phenomena in lhc  Tides at the Sandurich, Islands.\nOn the evening and night of the 7th November, 1837, a\niwst remarkable commotion of the sea was witnessed at Honolulu, in many respects similar to that witnessed at these\nislands in May, 1819. One inch and a half of rain had fallen during the previous twenty-four hours; the wind was\n''Mb from the north-cast, squally at intervals. The atmosphere was clear and cool\u2014thermometer 74.5.    Tho barom\neter had gradually fallen during the four previous days, but\nthis evening hud again risen to 30.06, at G o'clock, when tho\nalarm was given that the sea was retiring. The first recession was the greatest\u2014something more than eight feet; but\nbeing unprepared to make observations at the moment, the\nexact fall was not measured. 'The reefs surrounding the\nharbor were left dry, and the fish aground were mostly dead.\n'The sea quickly returned, anel in twenty-eight minutes reached the height of an ordinary high-tide: scarcely remaining\nstationary, it again receded and fell six feet. This was re\u00b0-\npeated at intervals of twenty-eight minutes.\nSinco tho above was written, distressing accounts have\nbeen received from IVIaui and Hawaii of the damage done to\nproperty and loss of life. On the leeward side ol Maui the\nsame rise and lull took place as at Honolulu, but on lhc win-\nward part of the island the sea retired about twenty fathoms\nand quickly returned in one gigantic wave, sweeping.every\nthing before it, houses, trees, cimoes, and every moveable object exposed to ils fury. At a small village, called Kahulni,\nin the district of Wailukii, on the sea retiring, the amazed\ninhabitants followed il as it receded, eagerly catching the\nstranded fish, shouting nnd hallooing with pleasure, when\nsuddenly lhc sea rose perpendicularly before them like a precipice, and rushing to the beach, buried the assembled multitudes in the flood, and overflowing the shore, swept uwny\nevery house; in the village hot ono; the canoes and property\nofthe natives wero all destroyed. Happily, owing to iho\namphibious education of tho people, but two lives were list\nhere, but us the same occurrence happened all along the seaside, we shall probably hear of more deaths.\nAt Byron's Bay, on Hawaii, ihe same phenomenon took\nplace. An unusual number of persons were collected lo-\ngether attending a protracted meeting, consequenlly every\nhouse was crowded. At half past six lhc sea retired at (lie\nrale of four or five knots nn hour, reducing tho soundings\nfrom five to three and a half fathoms at tho anchorage, and\nleaving a great extent of the harbor dry. Hundreds of curious souls rushed down to witness tho novelty, when a gi-\ngantic wave came roaring to the shore at the rate of six or\neight knots an hour, rising twenty feet above high water\nmark, and fell on the beach) with a noise resembling a heavy\npeal of thunder, burying the people in the flood; destroying\nhouses, canoes, nnd fish-ponds, washing away the food and\nclothing of tho inhabitants, large quantities of animals, firo\nwood, and timber collected on the strand for sale. 'The cries\nof distress were horrible; those in the water unable to swim\namong tho wreck of houses, and pieces of timber, struggling\nfor their lives, and those onshore wailing for their friends\nand relatives. The British whale ship Admiral Cocbburn\nwas at anchor in the Bay, and to ihe timely aid and humane\nexertions of her master (Lawrence) and crew, many arc indebted for their lives; but for the assistance rendered by their\nboats, many who wero stunned and insensible, would havo\nbeen carried out to sea, and perished, as the natives had not\na single canoo left that would float. Every thing was destroyed; thoso who escaped with their lives had neither food\nnor raiment left. In Kanokapa and Knahelu alone, sixty-\nx houses wero destroyed, and eleven persons lost their lives,\n:*;;:'","fullrs":{},"find":"572.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"571","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1785011","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
