<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/600</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>600</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/600/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n235\nin which bo has been raised, laws human or divine have for\nhim no authority. Looking not to the Mgis of virtue, and\nihe supremacy of law for proteclion, but armed with the instruments of violence, and the concealed weapons of assassination, he enters upon his ignoble career. Tho gambling\ntable and the grog-shop nre his daily haunts. He revels, bullies, and gets drunk. In swaggering, sottish insolence, he insults his fellow-man, perhaps his bosom friend, and either\ngets killed himself, or plunges the dagger into a brother's\nheart, and terminates on the scaffold his inglorious race. To\nall within the reach of his influence, he lives a curse, and\ndies detested.\nWho shall be charged with this fearful ruin of an undy-\nin\" spirit? Doating mother, indulgent, but misguided father\n\u2014you have done the fearful deed. By allowing your son to\ngrow up in the indulgence of a lawless and self-willed spirit,\nyou did what you could to educate him for disgrace and mise\nry throughout the whole duration of his future existence\nWere this ruin, which has been caused by your foolish indul\ngence, confined to the present life, however appalling in real\nity it may be, it would sink into comparative insignificance\nBut how shall we estimate the untold fierceness of that tempest of wrath and wretchedness, by which the lawless spirit\nwill be driven and tossed through all eternity? And this incalculable ruin has all been effected by your foolish indulgence. When fire shall havo ceased to burn, and water to\ndrown, then\u2014but not till then\u2014may you rationally hope for\ndifferent results from the system of education, alas I too prevalent, and too popular in this deluded age.\nBefore high heaven I conjure you this day, fellow-citizens,\none and all,\u2014parents, guardians, trustees, students\u2014unite\nwith us in one vigorous and persevering effort to stem this\nfearful tide of self-will, anarchy, and lawless violence, which\nthreatens to deluge the land, and overwhelm our dearest earthly interests, our institutions anel our laws, in an abyss of wide-\nspreading desolation.\nTo you, young gentlemen, who have this day received the\nwell-earned meed of academic honors, this subject addresses\nitself with peculiar force. Your education and circumstances\nin life, will put il in your power to be the means of much\ngood or much evil to your fellow men. Do you nobly aspire\nto be pre-eminent, not in mischief, but in doing good? Are\nyoui generous souls fired with a laudable ambition to pursue\nsuch a course, as will reflect honor on your Alma Mater, promote your own happiness, and secure to society at large a\nrich harvest of untold blessings? If so, I know not any\nmethod by which you can more certainly accomplish these\nobjects, than by cultivating in yourselves, and in all who may\ncome within the sphere of your influence, a profound reve-\nrencc for tho supremacy of law.\nIn this respect, society must be reformed, radically re\nformed, or we are undone. Unless this desolating torrent of\nself-will, lawlessness, and anarchy, can be arrested in its fear-\nful course, I hazard nothing in the prediction, that less than\nhalf a century will see our schools, colleges, and free mstilu-\ntions buried in one mass of promiscuous rum. We call upon you, therefore, young gentlemen, by your love of country,\nand your affection for your Alma Mater, to lend us a help-\ning hand in this good work of reformation. At every risk,\nand by all the means in your power, discountenance this demoniac spirit of lawlessness, wherever it may be found.\nBy pursuing this course, you may not gain as much popularity in some circles, as you would, were you to drink with\nthe drunken, and riot with the rowdy. But, my young\nfriends, though a lawless brood, the offspring of that old serpent, the devil, may hiss at you, true honor, unfading-laurels,\nriches that ne'er decay, will be your noble reward. You will\nsecure tho favor of the wise and the good, the testimony of\nan approving conscience, nnd the smiles of your Heavenly\nFather.\nI should feel, that I had neglected the most important part\nof my duty, were I, on this interesting occasion, to oveilook\nan application of the foregoing principles, which is by far\ntho most important of which the human mind can form any\nconception. Their value, when applied to man as a physical, organic, and intellectual being, however immense in itself, becomes as nothing, when compared with their pre-eminent importance, taken in connexion with man as a religious\nbeing, viewed in relation to God, and a flit re state of existence.\nThat man is elevated to an immeasurable distance above\ntho most perfect of the brute creation, by the possession of religious faculties, which have a direct reference to God, and to\na future state of existence, cannot fairly be questioned.\nIf, then, man does indeed possess religious faculties\u2014and,\nespecially, if those faculties are the noblest and most authoritative in his nature\u2014it must be evident to every reflecting j\nmind, that the principles already laid down, when taken ivM\nthis connexion, have a tremendous importance. The happiness or misery to which man is heir, as a religious being, infinitely surpasses the loftiest ken of imagination.\nThe laws, by which this happiness or misery is regulated,\narc not an anomaly in the government of the Universe.\nThey, too, arc uniform in their operation.\nScience falsely so called, puffed up by a fleshly-mind\u2014a\nvain and deceitful philosophy, arrogantly intruding into\nthoso things of which it is profoundly ignorant\u2014may imagine, that it has discovered the operatic.-i of those laws to be\nwholly fortuitous and accidental. As well might the ignorant peasant argue from the ascent of smoke against the universality of the law of gravitation.\nMan, then, as a religious being, nnd thus connected with\nGod and eternity, is subject to laws, through the uniform operation of which, he is constantly treasuring up for himself an\ncruish that is intolerable, or happiness that no language can\neXpVcss-\" an exceeding great and eternal weight of glory.\"\nHere it is that our subject assumes an importance so vast, thai\nit can bo'comprehended only by the Omniscient. He has\nthoroughly scanned the whole grounds, and given his verdict Do you ask what it is? Go to Calvary, and read it\nthere Read, that you have not been \" redeemed by corruptible things, as silver and gold-but by the precious blood of\nChrist as of a lamb without blemish and without spot.'\nThe painful life, and agonizing death, to which the Son of\nGod voluntarily subjected himself for our redemption, exhibit\nthe immense value of the soul more plainly, than could oth-\nil')\n&lt;:","fullrs":{},"find":"601.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"600","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1697290","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.62 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
