<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/376</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>376</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/376/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 15","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOU TII -WES T E R N J 0 U R N A L.\n15\n| The following is a fair specimen of German ideality\u2014\nthough we have seen a more glowing and faithful transla\ntion of thesamedream.\u2014 Ed. S, W. Jour.]\nTranslated fur theX. V. Mirror.\nA DREAM.\n\"The intent of this fiction,\" says a German author, \"will\nexcuse its boldness. If my heart was ever so unfortunate,\nso withered, as that all the sentiments which affirm the existence of God were there destroyed, I would rend again these\npages; I would be staggered by them, and I would regain\nmvsalva.ion and my faith. Some men deny tho existence of\nGod with as much indifference as others admit it; and there\nare some who have believed it twenty years, nnd who ha\nnot encountered, till their twenty-first, the solemn moment,\nwhen they have discovered, with ravishment, the rich appanage ofthis belief the vivifying warmth ofthis fountain of joy.\nPayle has said in his dictionary, that atheism does not aflbrd\na refuge from the fear of eternal sufferings, The following\ndream maybe considered ns this thought put in action.\n\"When, in infancy, they tell us that toward midnight, at\nthe hour when sleep presses most heavily on the soul, dreams,\nbecome more sinister, the dead arise, and, in solitary churches,\nimitate the pious services of ihe living, death frightens us on\naccount of the dead. When obscurity approaches, wo turn\naway our thoughts from the church and its dark windows:\ntho terrors of infancy, far more than its pleasures, resume\ntheir wings to flutter around us, during the night of the drowsy soul. Ah! extinguish not those sparks; leave us our\ndreams, even tho most sombre! They nre far more sweet\nthan our actual existence; they lead us back to that age when\nthe river of life reflected heaven.\n\" One summer evening, I was lying on the side of a hill:\nI fell asleep and dreamed that I awoke, in the middle of the\nnight, in a cemetery.    The clock struck eleven.    The tombs\nwere all opened, and the iron gales of the church, agitated\nby an invisible bund, opened and closed with a loud noise.   1\nsaw on the walls flitting shadows, and these were not projected by bodies : other livid shapes rose in the air, and only\nthe  inliuils reposed in their graves.    There was in the heavens a grayish cloud, thick, heavy, and which a gigantic\nphantom compressed into long folds.   Above ine, 1 heard the\ndistant fall of avalanches, and under my feet ihe first commotion of a vast earthquake   All the church trembled, and the\nair was shaken by harsh, discordant sounds.   Pale lightnings\ngleamed through the darkness.    I was impelled, by very tor\nror, to seek refuge in the temple : two glaring basilisk's wen\nplaced before iis awful doors.    I advanced to the throng of\nunknown shapes, on whom the seal of ancient ages was impressed.   All these pressed around the simple altar; their\nbreathing was agitated and  their breasts heaved with violence.    One only of the dead, who had lately been interred\nin the church, reposed in his shroud ; there was no throbbing\nin his bosom, and the smile of a happy dream played on his\ncountenance; but at tho approach of a living one he awoke;\nhe ceased to smile; he opened his dull eyelids with a painful\neffort; the place of tho eye was void, and in that of the heart\nthere was only a profound wound; bo raised his bands; he\njoined them  to pray; but the arms grew long; they separated from the body, and the joined hands fell to the earth.\n\"At ihe top of the vault of the church was (he dial of eternity; no numbers, no pointers were to be seen; but a dark\nband revolved around it slowly, and the dead tried to reckon\nthe time. Then descended from on high, upon the altar, a\nradiant figure, noble, exulted, and who bore the impress of an\nimperishable grief; the dead cried out, 'Oh ! Christ! is there\nno God?' He replied, 'There is none?' The shade's all\ntrembled, and Christ continued\u2014'I have gone through the\nworlds; I have risen above the stars, and there\u2014there is no\nGod! I have descended even to the last limits of the universe; I have looked into the abyss and cried\u2014Father,\nwhere art thou?\u2014But I heard only the rain which fell,drop\nby drop, into the abyss, and the eternal tempest, that no order\ngoverns, alone replied. Then, again raising my eyes lo the\nvault of heaven, I found only a dark and bottomless vacancy\nEtemity reposes on chaos and wastes it, and consumes itself\nslowly: redouble your bitter and harrowing lamentations;\nwith thrilling cries let ihe shapes disperse, for now my task is\ndone.\"\n\"The despairing shapes vanished like the vapor which the\ncold has condensed; the church was soon descried; but sink\nlenly\u2014dreadful spectacle!\u2014the dead infants, who, in their\nturn, had risen in the cemetery, ran and prostrated themselves\nbefore the majestic figure which was upon the nltnr, and said.\nJesus, have not we a father?' And he replied, with a\ntorrent of tears\u2014'We are all orphans\u2014you nnd I\u2014we have\nno father ' At these words, the lemple and the children crumbled into dust, nnd ihe whole edifice ol the world, in ils immensity, dissolved before me.\"\nAUTUMN.\nThe first severe frost had come, anil the miraculous change\nhad passed upon the leaves, which is unknown only in America,    The blood-red sugar-maple,  with a leaf brighter and\nmore delicate than a Circassian lip, stood here and there in\ntile forest, like the Sultan's Standard in a host, the military and\nfar-seen aristocrat of the wilderness; the birch, with its spiritlike and amber leave's, ghosts of tho departed summer, turned\nyet nlongthe edge ofthe woods, liko lining of the palest gold;\nthe  broad sycamore and the fan-like catalpa flaunted their\nsaffron foliage in the sun, spotted with gold: like the wings of\na lady-bird ; ihe kingly oak,  with  its summit shaken bare,\nstill  hid its trunk in a drapery of a sumptuous dye, like a\nstricken monarch, gathering his robes of state about him to\ndie royally in bis purple; the tall poplar, with ils minaret  of\nsilver leaves, stood blanched like a coward, in the dying forest,\nburdening every breeze with  its complaining; tho 'hickory\npaled through its enduring green; the bright berries of the\nmountain-ash, flushed with a more sanguine glory in the unobstructed sun; the gaudy tulip-tree, Sybarite of vegetation,\nstripped of its golden cups, still drank the intoxicating light of\nnoon-day in leaves, than which the lip of an Indian shell was\nnevermore delicately tinted;  the still deeper dyed vines of\nthe wilderness, perishing with the noble things whose  summer they bud shared, outshone them in their decline, as woman, in her death, is heavcnlier than tho being on whom in","fullrs":{},"find":"377.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"376","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1818008","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
