<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/390</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>390</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/390/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:55">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"i y\nI\n: r\n\u25a0j\n\/\n,\nkMtB\nS O t; Til- W E S T E R N J 0 V II N A I,.\nJEFFERSON COLLEGE AND WASHINGTON LYCEUM, [hiiemeiiis of pleasure and ambition, ami devoting from pi\nThe monthly meeting of the Lyceum will he holden nt ciplo his whole life (often shortened by the nature of\nthree o'clock, I'M on Saturday, iho Oth January, 1838, in pursuits) to painful nnd laborious duties   Has lie talents!\ntho College Hall   The Exercises are to lea Lecture from In our Republican Government the highest offices in |\n.Mr(!V11Forbes, \" I In the Past mid Present,\" nnd an Slate are accessible to them when coupled with energy.\nl.'.-i\u00abav }nr   find.1    W  Mnnptln    mi    \" Tin,    Vfulnw    l-'i'ver  in   bis- lllirel   liir \\i-,,altb 1      Thnt  u-hli-h   in  r;tlii&gt;i- ,-niinl ,-i'.-^ ,....\nEssay by DoctJWMonette, on \" The Yellow Fever in\nNatchez.\" Judge Ji linings is excused from his appointment\nin an essay, in consequence, of his imperfect restoration to\nhealth.\n1.ai lies and Gentlemen are ri rpectfully invited lo att) in I.\nJAVan HoEsen, Secretary.\nhis thirst for wealth ? That which in other countries is or\naccumulated by long, intense, unremitting toil, ishereacquir\nwith comparative ease, in a few yearsBut ho turns fro\nthese', to him light nnd empty things, to do it mighty work.\nbe leaves the endearments of home, the enjoyments of t\nlished society, nnd goes forth into ihe frontiers nnd bordeis\ncivilization,    He is to be found in the pestilential swamps\nTHE\nTl\nupon\n-\u2014 eiwii\/.nunu    etc is to oe iniiiui in ine pesuienuui swamps\n:\u2022: Mississippi static COLONIZATION SOCIETYFlorida and Louisiana, and on tie- wild prairies of Micsou\nle Executive Commitlco ofthis Society havo mndo a call nnd Texasi ,lis I';ith is nmonS tho sav;lS\u00b0 *&lt;d men ol i|\nthe benevolent and philanthropic, in the State of Mis- WMt&gt; a'\"1 '\"' is l\" bo seen kneeling by the humble bedside .\npiIn- further aid in lie pros cution ofthe grand design tno ''&gt;''\"\" African,    lie is seen toiling ihrough the winti\n! 1 l'i 111    III'      I M   I J'    \\ 1 &gt; J '   ill   llllU       l,iltl.i'l..lllJ|tU,    III      1 J|(J     ULUIU   \"I      Klin-{\nsissippi, for further aid in the prosecution ofthe grand design tno dy,nS \u2022\"\u25a0\"'can   no is seen toning tnrougii the winti\n'   leura the name of \"Missis- storm';\"\"' \"\"der the summer heat   And what is his obje\n\u2022   herein?   He seeks not wealth, for poverty clings to him, ar\nhis garments arc mean, and often threadbare   Me seeks m\n, fame, for, from the mass, he receives but reproaches and coi\nlate philanthropist, James Green, of this State, tempt   \"What then is his object?    Ho is doing \"his Mai\nAnother vessel, with emigrants and supplies for tho colony, lers work\"\u2014he is spreading the kindly nnd gentle influence\nis I., bes-in oul from Nt w Orleans, by this society, in .March1\"' ''\"' holy religion he professesAnd bright and beautifti\nnextnre the marks nnd fruits of his labors   They nre found ii\nnl establishing ihe colony which h\nsippi in Ab ii a\"   Tin- s, tih ni' nt nl' the colony bus already\n\u2022 imenccd under flnllcring auspices; and a town has been\nlaiel out, as its capital, c   I'd \"Greenville,\" in honor ofthe\nlate philanthropist, James (Iret n, of this Stat\nllt'Xt\nIi is believed tint a judicious cxpondiluro of 820,000 pel\nyear, fir live years, will place the   ('ninny upon u   basis  ni\npermanent and progressive\nonly.\nFor lit,\nTill-: ITINERANT,\nlltll.Woslcm Jilia:.,.\nmany a reclaimed drunkard, and many a reformed profligat\nand gamester,    They nre found by ihe contented cheerfti\nlirt side, and by the couch of pain and sickness\u2014he has plante-i\npeace win re there was discoid, nnd  fixed hope where thcr,\nwas despair\u2014and thus he goes on, patient and untiring in hi\n.work, doing good to his fellow men, until death, (often has\nThore e\\i.-ts, in every human mind, n deep seated feeling oijtcncd by his labors,) closes the scene   And this is a travel\nmingled reverence and admiration of heroism and self-devotion; ling Methodist preacher! ernest.\nwhether displayed by tho proud warrior on iho battle-field, or\ni   s enthusiastic martyr expiring at tho stake   'What reader\nhas nni hung wilh intcresl on iho glowing fictions of Scott\nm his Tales of ihe Crusaders, and tho true and thrilling narratives, in fox's Book of Martyrs   The days of daring\nadventure are past   Yri with what delighl dues the imaginative mind recur 10 them   Wo sec, in fancy,tho mail-clad\nKnight go forth from his frowning fortress with his sturdy\nretainers, to battle wilh tho Paynim, on tho plains of Palestine,    Wo behold him on his fleet barb, careering over the\nsand,- of Syria in fight with the Saracen\u2014weseo tin- Knight-\nerrant in the fearful tournament, splintering  his lance for\nihe honour of his ladye-lovc\u2014his proudest hope in  be ihe\nihemenf u Troubadour's lay, his most earnest wish to die\nknightly In Ins steel harness on tho battlo plain\u2014ihe secret\n\u2022\u2022harm in ell ibis, is to be found in thai inherent feelingnllu-\n\u2022 led ,,in ihe commencement nl'ibis article   Who would\nbelieve thai  even  in  the  present day, in Ibis prosaic age\nol dollars and cents, there can  be found among us a class of\nmen, exhibiting in themsolvcsa heroism and self-devotion, far\nfar beyond any, ever shown by the Iron Knights of yore?\nSmile not incredulously, reader, when I say it exists in tho cha.\nracier of the unobtrusive, humble, nnd sometimes despised\nItinerant or travelling Preacher   I, is a character full ol\npoetic interest and beauty   Couccivo tho caso of a man in\nFor Iho South-Western Journal.\nUSE OF THE SEXTANT.\nProblem: To take the double meridian allituelc of a heavenly body, which is above the reach of the Sextant.\n(I.)  Take a good mirror which revolves in ils frame upon\na horizontal axis, and adjust il with reference to the heavenly\nbody, so that the angle of incidence shall be less than 00 tie\",\nand so thai the reflected ray may fall upon tho eye at the distance of 1(1 or 1-i feet.\n{\u25a0I.) Place between the mirror nnd the observer, some\nhorizontal reflecting surface, (mercury, molasses, pitch or wain-, '-.ben there is no wind,) a, such a point that the images\nfrom the two reflectors may fall upon the eye at the same moment.\n(\u25a0'\u2022\u25a0) While the heavenly object is culminating, measure,\nquickly, its altitude above the mirror reflection, nnd read il\noff; then, wilh like despatch, measure the angle from the horizontal reflection to that of the mirror.\nThe sum of these will be the apparent double meridian\naltitude of the body.\nScholium : About live minutes elapses at the passage ol\nany heavenly body over tho meridian, during which its allituelc exhibits very litile changeThe expert observer mo?\nmake the above measurements in two minutes, and the error\n.he very bloom and vigor of his youth, foregoing all t    Z , , T\u21226\" S \"J \"f\" \"\"'\"'\"*\u2122* \"- '\neroin0       in,a|.|may be neglected in his calculation,    The use of two","fullrs":{},"find":"391.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"390","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1906401","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.82 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
