<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/579</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>579</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/579/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 23","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOU T II -W ESTERN   JOUR N A L\n21,'\nlo the exact locality.    All doubt on the subject is now re\nmoved.    M. Isnai-di, tho famous Pieelmonteso archaeologist.\nIns discovered in the. archives of Genoa authentic: proof that\nColumbus was born at Colognetto, in the republic of Genoa.\n|i consists in a letter written by the government of that state,\ndoted the fifth of November, 1585, to their ambassador, Doria,\nnt Madrid, in which the following passage occurs:\u2014' Christopher Columbus, of Colognelto, an illustrious man, as you\nought to know, being in Spain, has ordered, by his will,\nthat a house shall be built ut Genoa, which shall bear his\nname, and has instituted a fund for the preservation of thi\nbuilding.\"1 \t\nMeteorological Register, The following note from\nMrs. Margaret Forshey will explain the change of Meteoric Tables in the present number of the Journal:\nRock Island, (III.,) June 10, 1838,\nMn. EniToit:\nI very much regret that my absence from lhc Slate foils few mouths, will leave a blank in my Meteorologie Regis\nter, To supply this deficiency, I must refer you to the copious notes of my venerable friend Dr. Tooley; whilst I\npromise you, or rather him, as the patron of my undertaking,\nthat my register shall he resumed, upon my return from the\nnorth I hope under more favorable auspices. Mr. Forshey has made arrangements to procure me a barometer from\nihe hands of Mr. Espy; the want of which instrument has\nheretofore rendered my observations almost useless.- For the\nbarometrical column furnished in some of my tables, I am\nindebted to the kindness of the lion. W. P. Me Hen, in loaning me his barometer.\nWith the hope that a few months will restore me to Mississippi, and to a more perfect prosecution of my enterprise,\n1 remain, &amp;c.\nMi  Fousiikv.\nTHE ABORIGINES OK AMERICA.\nVarious have been the theories and conjectures as regards\nthe primitive colonists of the New World, from want of historical documents, or some species of positive proof The\nhistorian and antiquarian have therefore to depend on the nature and amount of accumulated probabilities resulting from\nanalogy: it is consequently evident that the greater the probabilities, the. more nearly do they approximate to certainty\nand indued conviction. However true it may be that analogy, even when it presents no apparent imperfection, can seldom be received as conclusivo argument with a calculating\nstudent, and never with a deliberate skeptic ; and that though\nit may form a part\u2014even an important part\u2014of speculative\nreasoning,' it cannot be permitted lo do more by philosophers\nof exact minds however candid or disposed\u2014man possessing\nbut finite reasoning powers and having no determined certainly of any tiling which has not been palpably perceived\nby his own senses, is necessarily obliged to depend for most\nof Ins knowledge on the conclusions of analogy, which\nleaches him how lo infer things unknown from those known.\nAnd as all his knowledge, not derived from immediate sensation, results from this analogy or relation of things, he is ob-\n'iged to rely on it in a majority of the  circumstances and\nopinions of life; rather than discard all hopes of increased\nIntelligence, pleasure and power. Hence it is that the process and practice of inductive reasoning have been so much\ncherished by modern philosophers; and that acts have enlarged as science has improved.\nAccumulated diets when generalized seem to establish, a\nprinciple; and accumulated probabilities when analysed may\nestablish a theory. Of course, caution and scrutiny must be\nused in both instances, before truth in tho former and certainty in the latter can be attained. Facts may indeed establish truths; but it is difficult to derive certainty from probabilities alone; yet when some ascertained facts are united\nwith many probabilities of correct analogy, a candid mind\nmay rest satisfied with the conclusion deduced. Such is the\nmodus operandi proposed in attempting to ascertain who\nwere the aboriginal settlers of this continent.\nNations are distinguished by organic structure or peculiar\ndevelopments, by language, by customs, and by religious\nrites, etc, etc., and though there maybe many differences between people of one land and those of another, from climate,\ntune and other causes, whenever and wherever we perceive\npeculiar similarity of a radical nature, we may conclude\nthere was an original sameness or identity. Differences\ncannot destroy the distinction nor the likeness.\nModern philosophers usually divide man into six races\u2014\nthe Caucasian, Hyperborean, Mongolian, American, Malayan, and Negro or Ethiopian ; and describe them by certain\ndistinctive features or appearances. The negro may be (lis-\ntinguished in every part of the world; and so mny tho red\nman of America. But though we can with certainty trace\nthe negro to Africa, wc cannot with a like certainty trace the\nred man to nny part of the old world.\nThe theory which would trace the American to theJew-\nish race, cannot bo admitted by an exact mind: for tho Jews\nare still extant, with the same peculiar fealur.es as of old,\nnd are of the Caucasian race of man. Positive facts are\ntherefore in the outset against such a theory: for no intelligent mind can admit that the red and beardless American\nwas ever identified with the Jews, whose peculiar cast of\nfeatures can never be mistaken, anel has existed from time\nimmemorial. Nor can he be identified with any nation or\npeople extant.\nSlill records may furnish a clue to the required identification: for an identification is necessary, unless one should\ngratuitously supposo that a peculiar race of men hud been\ncreated for the purpose of peopling America: and this could\nbo the conjecture of infidels and general credulists or skeptics alone.\nBut first it may be necessary to state that any identification, \"or any arguments bused on probabilities, must be deduced from the records anel condition \u2022 of the Mexicans, when\ntheir country had been invaded by Spain: for their history,\ntradition, monuments, language and religion have been more\naccurately ascertained, than those of any other people or\ntribe in America, when discovered by Europeans. It is then\nwell to state that Mexico at that period was under the control\nof, and chiefly peopled by, a different nation from lhal which\nhad there previously existed and flourished\u2014that an invad-\n.&gt;5i,'.'\n1\n. \"i '\u25a0'\nTi.\nif\n\u00a3'-1-\n\u25a0i !\n' r'l\nM\n\u25a0si\nI-\n1\n4\nit","fullrs":{},"find":"580.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"579","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1773028","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
