<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/452</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>452</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/452/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"82\nSOUTH- W E S T E R N J 0 II li N A L.\nVi;ft.\nt\nI i'.'l\non yellow fever, to prepare the way for establishing his theory of marsh-miasni, has adduced an array of facts and evidence incontrovertible, proving that animal putrefaction may\nexist to any extent, and tinder all circumstances, without producing yellow fever; and consequently, that it is not a iicces-\nsarysource of the miasm; and that, of course, yellow fever\nmiasm is, or may be, produced from some other cause. He\nhas shown, that this kind of putrefaction, is not even a frequent concurring circumstance; nnd that animal putrefaction\nhas existed in cities, and other localities, under the most favor\nable circumstances for its production, according to that doc\ntrine, without having produced yellow fever, either epidemic\nally or sporadically, lie has shown conclusively, that pit\ntried pork, putrid bacon, putrid fish, &amp;c., fresh or salted, will\nnot generate this miasm ; nor will dead bodies of any kind,\nwithout salt, in a putrescent state, produce it; not even the putrefaction of human bodies, by hundreds, upon the burning\nsands and marshes of Egypt; nor is il produced by the intolerable stench produced and kept up by animal matters in\ncities, or about factories of glue and catgut; about butcheries,\ntanneries, chandleries, &amp;c. These facts, which are incontrovertible, all confirm the opinion sanctioned by experience,\nthat the miasm or infection of yellow fever, be it what it may,\nis not, in any sense, dependent upon, or connected with tho\nfcetor of animal putrefaction, either in its incipient state, or in\na state of complete decomposition. It has been placed beyond\ndoubt, that the miasm, or infection of yellow fever, has been\ngenerated abundantly in the holds of ships at sea, where no\nputrid animal or vegetable matters have existed; a good example of this kind is found in Ihe United Slates brig \"Enterprise,\" hereafter referred to. There arc cities or towns in the\ntropics, where abundance of putrid animal and vegetable\nmatters are combined with effluvia from mud and marshy bottoms of shallow harbors, and yet they enjoy uninterrupted\nhealth: an example of this kind is found in the town of ('am-\npeachey hereafter cited.\n2d. Of vegetable putrefaction. That this is not the essential cause of yellow fever miasm, is proved bv the same:\narray of facts and arguments which are brought against that\nof animal putrefaction. Vegetable putrefaction of the most\noffensive kind, and in the most extensive degrees, have occurred, without producing a single case of yellow fever in\nthose frequenting them; and the most devastating epidemics\nhave prevailed, where no mass of vegetable putrefaction\ncould be detected. In our own neighborhoods, how often do\nwe find colton seed in a rotten stale, to the amount of several\nhundred bushels together, with a stench almost intolerable,\nwhere no fever of any kind, much less yellow fever, is produced on the plantations? During the hot weather of summer, this is a common occurrence; yet, in no instance has it\nproduced yellow fever among the swarms of negroes, and\noften white men, who are daily about them. In the last epidemic of Natchez, no masses of vegetable putrefaction were\neven suspected. When vegetable putrefaction or decompose\ntion is carried on most rapidly, or in seasons with regular\nvicissitudes of rain and sunshine, there is no yellow fever:\nbut it makes its appearance often when all moisture is dissipated from the face of the ground: and when the process of\nvegetable decomposition, must have entirely ceased, for wani\nol moisture. The whole weight of testimony is against the\nprobability of vegetable putrefaction being an active cause.\n3. Of marsh miasm. Dr. Bancroft has labored much\nto prove that this is the true cause of yellow fever; bin hi,\nlabors on that point have all been in vain. We find this disease prevailing equally in the vicinity of marshes, anil on\nthe dry and barren rock, where no marsh is near. We find\nit equally prevalent on high and on low situations; upon, the\nhigh bluff at Natchez, and on the still more elevated Hi I Is (,f\nWashington, as well as in the low marshes of Charleston and\nthe quagmires of New Orleans; upon the sandy beaches of\nPensacola and Mobile, and upon the rocks of Lisbon, Cadiz,\nand Gibraltar: we find it equally in the alluvial delta of th,.\nMississippi and Orinoco, and upon the sterile shores of Curra-\ncoa, where marshes are unknown. On the other hand, in\nmany alluvial and marshy regions on the lower Mississippi\nand elsewhere, which ought to be most favorable to the production of mnrsh-miasm, yellow fever is unknown. In the\nWest Indies, where it is endemic all the year, it prevails alike\non the fertile, and on the barren shores; but it is unknown in\nthe interior.\n4th. Arid and humid atmospheres are alike non-essential\nto its production. For, under every variety of aridity oi\nhumidity of the atmosphere, has it appeared in our own country, as well as elsewhere. It has made its first appearance\nin New Orleans as an epidemic, in cloudy, damp, and wel\nweather; it has appeared there also in the driest weather; it has appeared also in other southern ports, in dry nnd\nin humid weather; after a wet and a dry spring; after a\nwarm and a cool spring; it has prevailed at Natchez, after a\nwet and a dry summer; and, again, when the same months\nhave not been either unusually wet or dry. It prevails in\ncommercial places, equally where the air is habitually humid,\nand where it is habitually arid: no less in Charleston auJ\nNew Orleans, than on the parched shores of Curracoa.\nDr. Peixotto informs us, that the yellow fever is endemial\nin the island of Curracoa at all times and seasons, but it occurs\nmore especially in the calm and sultry months of the year.\nNew comers from northern latitudes are its appropriate subjects : the natives and seasoned inhabitants being exempt from\nits attacks.\" * On this island, it becomes epidemic only when\nlarge numbers of northern strangers arrive during thesitltrit\nmonths of the year. Yet the air of this island is proverbial\nfor its dry, elastic qualities. Dr. P. informs us, \" The air m\npure anil dry, and seldom or never darkened with mists anil\nfogs, so frequent nt the North. * * * During the droughts,\nwhich arc common, the leafless desolation of winter reigns\nnnd. r a tropical sun: ordinary wells are exhausted; animate\nand inanimate nature suffers under the burden, and seems\nnearly ready to waste away and perish.\" f On this island,\nthere is no marsh, or scarcely a stream of fresh water.\n5th. Sensible changes of temperature, alone, have no material influence over the generation, or accumulation ofthis\nmiasm. The general views, entertained by those who aureate the theory that a certain unremitted mean tempcraturth\n'NowYork,Mod. and Pliys. Jour.vol, 1, p,411,4J2.\n' Ibidem, p. 303,100,","fullrs":{},"find":"453.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"452","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1855541","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
