<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/389</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>389</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/389/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:55">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S O U T II - W E S T HUM J o U R N A f.\ncreation nnd servant of the public will; each newspaper, in lone of his friendsFrom this, il will be seen, thnt if the reorder to live at all, must advocate the sentiments of largo mass-pott of his mental alienation was true, it happily is so no\nes ofthe community ; and each individual editor selects for ad- longer,\nvocacy those particular doctrines, tenets or sentiments, most     ., |t.,-|,llsni God on the 29th of March, to visit mo with ihe\ncongenial to his own, sovercsl calamity thnt can bt fall ono of his creatures, in ihe\nThe press is a general benefactor; it is the philanthropist death of my wife, with whom I had lived in love for twenty-\nof Time; the mirror of tho world   It presents sixyoars; and since that event, until about a fortnight ago, I\njlived with my family, two sons and three daughters, dutiful\n.and affectionate, in a secluded house near RoslinI am now\nin Edinburgh; and early in November, hope to resume mv\nid lily duties in the University.\"\n\" I have many blessings for which I am humbly thankful\ni to tho Almighty,    And though I have not borne my a III n tion\njso well as I might have done, ycl  I have borne it with sub-\nIt is the philosopher's stone; it is ihe medium of all knowl- mission and resignation, and fei I that, (hough this world is\nedge' it is the encourngcr of science: it is praclical rhctoricjdarkened to me, I may be able yel to exert the faculties, hum-\nnnd logic; it illustrates geometry; it acquaints us with thel0'8 us they arewhich God has given me, if not to the benefit,\nprinciples of geology; it is the besl philologist in the world;; not to (be detrimen! of my fellow mortals\"        *\n '\u2022 The grand debate,\nThe populai harangue, the ,ar'reply,\nThe logic, end 'lie wisdom, and the wit\ndi' patriots, bursting with her tic rave;\nNews from all nations, revolutions, wars;\nCaptions and suicides; mirth, madness, woe\nI louses in ashes, end the fall of stocks:\nBirths, marriages, and deaths.\"\nI nm sir, yours, sincerely,\nJohn   Wilson.\nG, Oloticestor-placo, Edinburgh, Oct1837.\"\nSOUTH-W ESTER N ..'&lt; )URNA!,.\nNATCHEZ,  DECEMBER  30,  1837,\nit explodes astrology, and superstition flics before it ns from\nthe glance of Deity: in natural philosophy, itisthomosl natural\nof all philosophy; ii is tho crucible of chemistry; it is the\nlens of astronomy; tho prism of mankind, which refracts all\ntho light acquired by the few philomaths of the find, in their\nevery varied hue, upon the whole world of enquirors, All\ntho blandishments of polite literature; all the truths of philosophy and all the experience of ngi s, are, by iho press, brought OUH JOURNAL,\ndown to the companionship of youthWo havo tho expectation ol being able, in tho next mini-\nThere is much propriety also in the editorial uso of the bcr ofthe South-Western Journal, to present u history ol\nplurulpersonal pronoun in tho United Si itesThe fifteen Jefferbon (.'01,1,1:01:from its first cstnblishmenl to the pre-\nhundred newspapers of tho country speak ihe sentiments of sent time, by a writer Cully competent to tho task.Such a\nfourteen millions of inhabitants; and in power nnd in voluinclhistory cannot fail of being appreciated by nil ihose who are\nof sound, it is ns 1 In\u2022 voice of nations, From hill to hill and interested in ilia advancement of Southern literary tu e] s-i.\nfrom city to city \" lea; is the live thunder1 of moral power when entitle institutions.\nthe press speaks with anger, and with jusl cause hurls the Somo editorial articles, promised in nor lasl number, are\n\"deep damnation of its curse \" upon wrong   The blood of unavoidably deli -.ml until tho next.\ntin-   tyrant   curdles   under  ils   robuko;   corruption   hides     \\-.-, ,,.,, \u2022,,,,!,   , r.,i    1,11 f      i\n\u2022 ' ' lie v.nui.i make ten grateful acknowledgements fnr the\nin  its darkest   retreats;   treachery   flics  as  tho midnight c,\u201e.,._i.i\u201e \u201e.;,,;,,,\u201e 1 ; .1, 1,.,, 1    \u201e   ,-    1        11     ,- n\n' \u25a0 , favorable o[,inion winch bus been so freely nnd checrlully\nmurderer from ihe glowing torch-light of the press, and          11       .,.,-\u25a0    1 ,1 ,    -., .1\nb        \u00b0 1    -\u2022    \u2022    expressed by our Iriends, gentlemen connected with tho press\nguilt dreads ii worse than tho sunless cells ol the InquisitionL\u201e(, \u201e,,..,, \u201e,: ,,\u201e|)|l|,|ii\u201e, |;\u201e.,,\u201e,,s |]|m||;|(i nn Q     \u201e\u201e\u201e\u201e    }\nThe press is power! 1, is tho prop, Uing agency ,1 freedom I bccoming BcfJuajn\u201e ,1 \u201e.,',), ;,respecting our , ntcrprise nnd\nWithout it, liberty would censo to exist among men; litem- \u201e,\u201e Bpccimen numbei, \u201e,hich wo bave issuedi Subscribers\nturo would languish, and civilization decline to barbari inhavo scnt in ,,,,-,|lames ,,s wpidly ,., ,,\u201e, |||(l?( ,.\u201e\u201e\u201e\u201e\u2022,\u201e.\nIt is both the offspring and foster parent ol scicnco and learn-couM bilVl, anticipatedThese nre good auguries Ibr tho\n\"\"\u25a0'\u25a0    u i3lho \",m\"1' \"' ll\"' \u2022\"'\u2022\u25a0\u25a0 K u\"-: each Pnss,'\"S prosperity of the South-Western Journal, and thai ,\u201e,\neven,, and presenting tho picturo of the times lo tho &lt; leni\nof History, as sin- paints Ibr the latest generationsIt reared\nup the columns of national glory, nnd is tho main pillar of\nthotomploof Liberty; it is \"tho lever which moves tho men-\ntal world.''\nProfessor Wilson.\u2014In our last, we noticed a report,\nrespecting a most melancholy alienation of ibis distinguished\ngentleman's intellect,\u201411 piece of intelligence which has curried gloom with it throughout our countryWe rejoice now\nto bo able to say, that ibis report was not in all respects correct.\nThe \"London Courier\" ofthe 17th nilpublishes the following extract from a loiter, from this great and amiable man, to\npoilaiit interest, which it aspires to advocate and represent, in\nthis wealthy and influential section of our countryHaving\nreceived, from the bund of our bountiful Crcuti r, a clime that\nunites enchanting beauty with almost unbounded profusion, it\nbecomes us to cultivate the intellectual as well as natural resources and advantages 0!' our position, Commerce nnd\nwealth have ever been tho handmaids of refinement and mental improvement; nnd it is well for us, having every outward\ncircumstance propitious, that we have commenced, in enrncsl,\ntho improvement of tho mind, by the pursuit of letters and\nscience, nnd the accumulation of that moral and intellectual\nWealth, which so adorn society, give dignity and polish lo\nopulence, and realize- tho utmost of human happiness,\nvol.1.\u201411.","fullrs":{},"find":"390.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"389","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1838380","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
