<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2212</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2212</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2212/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 15","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[15]\nAPPENDIX TO CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS.\nNo. I.\nffiCT   OF  A RAIL-ROAD FROM   VICKSBURG,   YIA   MONROE   AND   SHREVEPORT,\nPB0     0UGn   mE    INTERIOR   OF   TEXAS,    SUBMITTED    BY   THE   DELEGATION   OT\nHOBTIHMW LOUISIANA.\nEEPOET.\nThis road has been projected for the purpose of developing the northern part of the\nof Louisiana, and the northern, eastern, and middle portions of Texas, securing this\nAeto the city of New-Orleans, and to add another section to a *rreat national road.    It\n11 pass through a tier of parishes in this state, containing over four millions of acres of\n\u25a0 i fertile land, fully equal to tho best lands in the world for the growth of cotton. The\nwhole of this land is arable, with the exception of a comparatively inconsiderable portion\n.abject to annual inundation. These parishes now produce about 130,000 bags of cotton. Without the aid of a rail-road this amount is not likely to be increased. Indeed,\nnothing hut the unsurpassed fertility of the soil could sustain their present population, in\ntbe absence of any other means for getting their produce to market, and obtaining their\nsupplies, than is afforded by small streams of water, unnavigable for many months in the\nyear, and which, at best, meet the demands of a very limited portion of the country in\nquestion. Take, as an illustration of this statement, the parish of Caddo, which is more\nfavorably situated tor navigation than any other of the northern parishes. For several\nmonths during the year just closed the good people of this parish have been six weeks\nfrom New-Orleans \" in due course of mail.\" Flour has been selling at $12 per bbl.;\nBacon, 16 cts.; Sugar and Coffee, 12 and 14 cts.; Lard, 25 cts.; and other family supplies in proportion. Merchants have hauled their goods from the Mississippi, in wagons,\nand commenced selling them about the time their bills, for the purchase of them, began to\nfalldue. Other goods, purchased for the Shreveport market, have been met at New-\nOrleans, shipped up the Mississippi, and opened at various points on that river, in markets unsuited to their quality, and forced sale-; made to sustain, if possible, the credit of\nthe purchaser. The whole cotton crop ofthe parish is at this time under shelter at the\ngin houses, or locked up in the warehouses at Shreveport, waiting a rise in Red River.\nThese extravagant prices\u2014these ruinous delays\u2014this unnatural course of trade, and general derangement of business calculations, return upon ns with the regularity of the business seasons, and must continue to recur so long as our only dependence is upon the uncertain navigation of Red River. Even with all these disadvantages, the fertility of\nthe soil in this parish has induced its rapid settlement. The Indians were removed so\nlate as 1839, and the same year the lauds were offered for sale by the government. The\nparish now contains six thousand slaves. \"Fifty thousand acres of land nave been brought\ninto cultivation; and she will send to market this year, as the produce of her own soil,\ntwelve thousand bags of cotton. Shreveport, which is marked out by its geographical po-\nihon as the centre of trade, not only for this parish, but for a vast extent of country to\ntne west of it in Texas, has a population of twenty-five hundred inhabitants, and is the\ncon&lt;l place in the state in point of commercial importance. The trade between Shreveport and New-Orleans already amounts to several millions. But the planters of Caddo\n\u2022ansn, and the ctm-rprising merchants of Shreveport, are struggling against adverse cir-\nmstances, under the weight of which they must finally yield, unless some scheme is\n*nsea for their relief. There are 191,000 acres of uncultivated land in this parish, held\nDrn'inV;-tt' t^^zens' aEd a large amount still unsold by the government. When a fair\nbuH\u00b0rtIf \"i \"' t'1'Ii 3'la'^ have been brought into cultivation, Caddo parish will send one\ntaile 1 ti7nisr,,1d bags of cotton to market. The limits of this report do not permit a de-\nand w'S i lsltl''a' statement of each of the parishes through which the road is projected;\n\"ad Dr-0 1* 3eh:eted Caddo, because it is about an average parish in size, present wealth,\nfte fact ':tlwi\u2014;ind because more favorably situated than moat ofthe other parishes;\n*ith th \\'r n77nL*t0 it&gt; demonstrate the absolute necessity of a rail-road communication\nmd r;G \"tj^siasippi to its continued prosperity. Other parishes, as Bossier, Claibourne,\n\u25a0hnost wb ll e1Uil% fertile in lands, are still more isolated in position, and must remain\nration Tl ^ unc*evc'0Ped and worthless to the state, unless aided by rail-road c-omnrani-\n* Terv m 1 r0:\"' wo\"''' -Tidily develop this whole region of country ; and if built, it is\nNN, nite aD(i solxrr calculation to say, that within six years these parishes would\nnponit i     ms 400-000  bagscotton.    But the fertility of the soil and the trade based\nto thc ro T\u00b0 ^'' axe QOt the only elements of wealth this road will develop. Contiguous\nte aro large and extensive forests of valuable pine timber.    Upon the water-","fullrs":{},"find":"2213.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2212","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"589349","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
