<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/433</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>433</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/433/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\niiit\u00a3:\nill':\n',:v-'i'\n\u25a0' :i &gt;\u25a0 \u2022\niias\nI'tW\n* l!'\"'.1\ns# ') ' I \u00bb\n,'   ,1\nI*\ni \u25a0 : : -\n66\nSOU T II - WE S T E R N JOURNAL.\nor the arts of the mechanic and tradesman, ofthe shop andjral professions, we utterly deny it. Who are the clever prac-\ncounting-house, the arts of brick-making and house-build ing:, | lical men, as they are termed 1 Who are the men of business\nof casting up accounts and guaging\nthat take an active part, and perform that part with credit in our\nown country, and at this very time? The most distinguish-\ned members of both houses of Congress, and in all the learn-\nbarrels ?   What sciences ?\nAstronomy and chemistry, hydrostatics and optics, or the sciences of navigation, and surveying, of military and  civil engineering?    Is the intention of a liberal education, to make|ed professions, the most active and useful public officers, the\nsurveyors and engineers, shop-keepers, and sailors, or physi- most eminent divines, lawyers, and physicians, are in general\nthose who have been educated at classical schools. The\nchurches, the courts of justice-, the halls of legislation, the\nhospitals, and even the exchange, exhibit men industrious and\nntelligent, energetic and skilful, tlio ornament of their profes-\ncians and lawyers, orators and divines, legislators and states-\nmi\u00bbi? To what are the senate, the pulpit, the bar, indebted\nfor their greatest honors? Is it not to eloquence? Whence\nis this eloquence derived? From the study of arithmetic\nand algebra, geometry and trigonometry, or from the Belles\nLettres, from polite literature, from the classics? We would\nnot detract a tittle from the honors due to science, nor yet\nIrom those useful accomplishments, the arts of spelling, reading, writing, and ciphering. But we maintain, that something\nmore is necessary to enter with advantage on the study of the\nlearned professions. But many have risen to distinction in\nsociety, and in their profession, who were destitute of classical\nlearning. This, if it proves any thing, proves too much. By\nthe samo mode of reasoning, we might demonstrate all education to be useless. For some have been elevated to eminent stations who were altogether uneducated. Again, in\nthis enterprising and money-making country, many, from a\nvery low origin and an exceedingly humble beginning, have\nattained to enormous opulence. But how little is overgrown\nwealth, associated with ignorance and vulgarity, calculated\nto advance the happiness of its possessor, or to render him\ntruly respectable and influential in society !    For want of a\nsions, the pride of their countrymen, the glory of their country ; n majority of whom have enjoyed, to some extent, the\nbenefits of classical instruction. Who nre the theoretical and\nvisionary, the enthusiastic, and superstitious, the fanatics and\nimposlors, but men who, without a foundation of classical\nlearning, and destitute of any solid attainments, endeavor to\ncarry into execution their preposterous plans, their destructive and often impracticable projects ? We grant that monpv\nmay often be accumulated in abundance, by illiterate persons,\nwhose energies, both of mind and body, are continually directed to the acquisition of gain, and that wealth may imparl\nto them a degree of importance and consequence in the opinion of the unthinking multitude: but honor, esteem, consideration in society, the approbation of the thoughtful and discerning, are reserved for that sort of practical man, who has\nadded to the possession of sound sense, the acquirements of\nthe scholar, and the polish of the gentleman. Then let not\nthis stale objection about the want of practical utility in clas-\ncapacity to appreciate llic refined delights of literature, in sieal studies, which indeed lies in a much greater degree\nconsequence of a defective or erroneous education, how many against ihchigher branches ofpurcmalhematics, an objection\nare led to the gaming table and grog-shop, to the haunts of which has been n thousand times repeated, and as often refuted, be any longer reiterated. If we form our ideas according to the vulgar notion of utility, the plough is obviously a\nmore useful instrument than the telescope, and the ploughman a more important personage than the astronomer. The\ngrand object ol liberal education, we take it, is not to teach\nmanual labor and servile employments, but to expand the intellect, to refine the taste, to liberalize the views, to elevate the\nmoral feelings, to assimilate, in fine, the immortal heaven-descended soul of man, to the great Author of his existence, lo\nqualify for respectability anil extensive usefulness here, and\nendless happiness hereafter.\nBonaparte has been referred to as an exemplification of th\"\nbeneficial effects resulting from mathematical studies. If th\"\nart of slaughtering human beings in the most expeditious and\nscientific manner, and the calculating with numerical exactness bow many valuable lives must he sacrificed to besiege a |\ntown, or storm a fort, be the art of all most worthy to be nil-\ntivated, then we must acknowledge that the French Emperoi\nStands, in modern times at least, pre-eminent and unrivalled. '\nThis great destroyer of his species, this mighty Juggernaut,\nbeneath whoso advancing triumphal car were crushed mil'\ninfamy and ruin, lo pass away the time, and get rid of the en\nnui which oppresses them? What miserable havoc is made\nof the king's English, and what ridiculous blunders are often\ncommitted by men who attempt lo write, or to speak in public\nin consequence of their not knowing the exact meaning of\nwords! This knowledge is only to be acquired by a faithful\nstudy of the Latin and Greek, or of English writers written\non the model of the ancient classics. Some, I know, like our\nown beloved Washington, have, without classical instruction,\nattained an admirable style. But such exceptions rather tend\nlo confirm than invalidate the general principle. Men of\nthe dwarfish stature of ordinary mortals, will surely not measure themselves by the standard of such colossal intellects.\nGreat men must ever be chiefly self-taught. In them nature\nsupplies tho deficiencies of education. Another objection demands a passing notice. It is said the education we propose,\nis not sufficiently practical, that classical scholars are seldom\npractical men, men of business habits. What is intended by\nthe term practical! If it he meant that studying Latin and\nGreek does not make a man practically acquainted with husbandry, and carpentry, with the use of the plough and spade,\nof the axe and plane, with the veterinary art, and various oth- lions ol  idolizing and adoring subjects, and in whose worship :\ner most useful  arts and employments, we readily grant il.\nBut if it be asserted that a knowledge of the ancient languages docs not prepare one for studying with advantage, and\npractising with success, the Law, Medicine, and all other libe-\nWere mingled the lamentations of the widow and the orphan.\nwith ihe songs of triumph and ihe shouts of victory, manifested\nno predilection for polite literature. What little learning he possessed, was of the calculating sort, merely mathematical or Sta-","fullrs":{},"find":"434.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"433","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1915050","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.83 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
