<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Appenxix, Page v</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2146</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2146</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2146/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Appenxix, Page v","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"APPENDIX.\n,    \u201eine.\u00aba    The upper parishes produce also 33,000 bales of cotton; and St.\nj ,M rW bmffl' of \u00bb       \u2022'\u25a0     ' .      J   j Vermilion, sell, aceoriliiig to their  statistics, as pub-\ntS^S^O^,?, 4o\"oSi head of beef cattle, calve,, and sheep fo, mutton, to\n\u25a0      I trie l\u00ab'1 \"L\"ler '\nlj.bN,\u00ab.Orle\u00abn&lt; \u25a0\"\"*\u25a0\u2022; reasonably bo expected of plantations fronting on tho\n11 \u00bb\u00ab\u25a0' \u00bb\u00b0i J\" *SSS Donaldsonville, on the Lalonrche, nor the thirteen plantations on\n,,,.l, of Rapides, Included in tho above estimate, tnai gage will send their\nBed River. '\u00bb.\"\"\u201e j VI , it must be dually bor.te in mrmi tbal the preset price ol transport for\n...d\u201ecel.Vth'-'~d:.?\".'..  IV, m ,i,ree. to Ii,.- dollar, per head, ...ear iron, two and a hall\n\u25a0\u201ei.lacel.y Hi- \u00ab\u00bbji \u25a0' from \u201e\u201e.\u201e to fi\u201e  \u2022,\u201e],.\u201e per head, sugar Iron, twoaud aliall\nUf cattle, 'hrougl   lie, ear, _ ^ L;ifon,d|0 whe\u201e \u201e \u201e ,om0 |\u201ewer    The pltn.\n\u201e f.er d.l f\"ES\u201ei BIvor generally sell their crops at home. But ,n order that the full\n\u201e,\u201en.oo the M &gt;;''\"&lt;' ,\u201e ,,\u201e mhmh\u201e.j, may be appreciated, I shall at tins point introduce\nforce ofthe \u00ab\u00bb \u2122 \u00ab''\"'' J\u00b0      ,.\u201e\u201e,\u201e\u201e, comprised of the parishes of St. Mary aud St. Martin, a,\nll\u00bbsl\u00abti'*'\"'pf.\u201elc\",Banner, in the tow ' Franklin, under date of Uie21.t rebrunry last,\npublished in rti ' \u25a0 , verified 1)y \u201e,e books 0f the steamboats that have done their business the\n\u201e predicated up c[liess | was informed by the most respectable merchants and plan-\npojt\/uar &gt;'e\u00b0rf;. [ f,.r,\u201eu this document itappears that the cost of transport of their products\nten, was uiioi - .freights  and pas.aee iimney to and fro, have averaged the patt\n\"\"\u2022\"^SSoforthe^e, 1 wo parishes* Now, Lafayette, Vermilion and St. Landry, con-,\nf\u201eur )''\u25a0'\u2022\"\u25a0'''; \"\u25a0':.,||,,,1 lhe .. Opel, ,usas country,\" and lying above the Attakapas, and having fut-\n\"\" ' nickel \u2022 and although not producing so much sugar, yet they more than make u?\n.\u00b0if i, l.v their cotton, beef cattle, &amp;c, and consequently their expenses would he equally\nlM,1r n\u00abt \/reater than those of Attakapas.    But taking it as only the same, say $295,000, we\nt       .1   .11m (if ft'\/W 111)\" as the present business ofthe Attakapas and Opelousas, and which i-:\n^IhtuJver half of the road.    The cost of making lhe whole road is estimated at $10,000 per\n[\\. or'-ihmii Jl,600,000 for the whole road.    Now, lei us see what would be the profit ou this\nClfnf this road    'i'h.'. cost of maintaining ihe road, and running the cars on the Georgia rail-\n^'r,Muai is m per cent, of their gross receipts,; those of New York 30i; those of Massa-\n.    and the average of the latter, for the past seven years, is 40H per cent.    Now lo taks\n40 per cent. off.*590,000 (the business of Attakapas ami Opelousas, and In.m [heir peculiar silua-\niii.ii ii would have to come by ilie road) would leave \u00a7351,000 as the profit on this half of the road,\nbcine equal to 22 per cent, on $1,000,000, the whole cost of the road !    Nor is this all.    By the\npresent mode of getting their produce to market, these planters  are subjected to expenses of\ncooperage., and great loss fiom drainage ofthe sugar, from its having lo be rolled so much in loac-\niirand unloading, and of insurance, which  is equal to   sixty cents to each  hogshead, all of\nMich would he saved by this road to them, even if the charges were the same they now pay.\nThe back freight is equal to about 6a per cent, of their down freight.    Let us now return to the\nlugar statistics, and suppose the transport on this road would be reduced to SI 00 per hogshead,\non the average, which is about half the present prices, and we will have \u25a0\n110,800 hogsheads sugar, at SI 50  $166,200\n800,000barrels molasses and cistern hottoms, at 50c     100.000\nReturn freight and passage money equal to 65 percent     172,900\nGross receipts  $439,000\nDeduct 40 per cent, for maintenance of road     105,040\nNet nnnual income $273,4C0\nEqual to 17 per cent, on the cost of the road, besides the saving of insurance, cooperage of hoga-\nbetdsand barrels, and loss of sugar by drainage, and other causes.    Nor do I refer to any in-\nNm of business, the natural result of such a convenience as this road will induce.    In t'lis esti-\nrisl have not included the large amount of beef cattle, calves, sheep for mutton, (of which they\n' , lll0&gt;&gt;s'lllds,) nor the cotton. These I have purposely left out to counterbalance shipments\n;*\u2122!Bmboa\\of Pinters residing on the Mississippi and Red rivers, and thai part ofthe La-\n\"\"rnv T i,llylda0!lvillc' Tllns\" items must reach $150,000, and are deemed amply sufficient\n\u2022re tain l ' , \"cft *e,,t ,'r,m lilis section by means other than the rail-road. These calculations\nLouin'ii .1 \u00b0\"lhl* actuaI statistics the past year. But when we remark that the section of\ni\u00bbme r&gt; \u00b0' i whlc''this road is contemplated to run, comprises 23,000 square miles, equal\n\"\u2022rntiori f\u2122,uchSlatesa** Massachusetts, and that not one-fifth of its finest lands are now in cul-\n'and that &lt;7, i?'\" i \u25a0\"\";,L ''\" 0UtIet as Ulis ro!td is dcsi,-'\"eli lo furnish ; and not one-tenth of the\n\u00b0fihisr&lt;w I u cultjvated, if the road is made, it is not unreasonable to suppose, that :he stock\n'\u2022\"ii.hv i! \u00a3!, u *' in the United States. Prom its healthfulness, it is destined, it no dis-\ntopw fcrtiii,;? r \u25a0,\"\u25a0\"\"' States what tho Sou\"' of Frai,ce is toEurope-a resort fir health.\n\"\u2022oMifcB\u00ab^rl'^furr'sh,.llS every inducement the richest soil can claim: its beautiful islands\nMhauitlc^ \u25a0 hi ''.'\"'\",,,,nM- 'be finest places for summer resort, sea air and sea bathin?; and its\nCb\"&gt;eysuii&gt;hur , *' ' !\"1,l2ii\"ie\"f\u00abvery kind, its mineral springs of St-Martin. its Belle\n\u2022\"hereon (hit P11, ,,r\",2i ?' f\"- Landry, all. all ccinsjiire to give this road a pre-eminence over all\ncil\u00a3\u2122dcount;^\nJ5 and whMdo wi * TT'l\\ n\"A-,0ok for a lnoment heyond Opelousas, its present proposed termi-\n5!*Und thirlv swr,' *?\".' di.tanee from thence to tlieea-tcrn border ofTe.tns. between thirty-\ni'^icri there v , I ! , -7'',,f''\"nl1 hnitude, (which is her centre,) is only 124 miles; in this\n\u25a0\"jMbusetts imv, a.eve'\u00b0i,ed another portion of Louisiana, equal in size lo the whole State of\nTIIa\u00abachu.eV- ,'V u t..l;oute from Algiers to Texas, fuur auc.h States ia territorial tzient\n?** \u00abiU'ons of' ' ' U',llhln our own Hl\"ils-    Rl|t \"hat is Texas?    She is out of debt, with\nJ*\"'-   Sheowns m\u00ab   *  !\"      r treasury. hy the recent settlement with the Uniled Srates Govern-\nywrt'mesa*larep\u00ab   .i   d\" n\"0 l\"\"ldl'l'cl and fifty millions of acres of vacant land; she is forty-\nbo as we faiale of Massachusetts, and New-Jersey thrown in besides ; the tide of","fullrs":{},"find":"2147.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2146","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"533671","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
