<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2214</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2214</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2214/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 17","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[ 17]\nthe attention ofthe undersigned, is deemed entirely practicable. Steps have\nengage t ' cm.easurvey ofthe route; but as this has not been done, we are happy\nj^entaken^ ^ bcfore the Convention the opinion of Professor Forshey, given in the\n^spondence below.\n\" New-Orleans, January oth, 1852.\ny     are informed that the  friends  of internal improvement in the northern part\nrt  uisiana   have projected a  rail-road from Vicksburg across  the state,  by way of\ni      e and Shreveport.    The information which has been collected, leads the friends ol*\n110 i to believe that no great difficulties present themselves on the route, and that taking\n&amp;e r(|^le ji,ie wether, it will be au easy one.    You are also aware that, by orders of the\nrriment, a route has been surveyed, quire recently, from Lake Providence to Fulton,\n^ffit is understood a low estimate lias been made of the cost of this road.    I believe\nonce surveyed the route to Alexandria, a little lower down than Monroe.   You also\ntave intimate knowledge of this whole region of country.\n\"Will you be srood enough to inform me what is your opinion ofthe practicability of\nthe proposed route? And, if it will not trouble you too much, furnish a rough estimate\nof the probable cost of the road ?\n\"Have the friends of this enterprise selected the best route to cross the state, and\ndevelop the resources ofthe northern parishes ? Or is there any better or more practicable route ?\n\"Your early attention to this is solicited, and will much oblige the undersigned, and\nmany, the friends of internal improvement in our state.\n\"Very respectfully, &amp;c., \u2022\n\"C. G.Yoosg.\"\n\" Car rot. lt on, La., January 6th, 1852.\n\" Dr. C. G. Young,\n\"Dear Sir\u2014Your note oi' yesterday is at hand, asking my opinion in regard to the\npracticability of constructing a rail-road from Shreveport, on the Red Iiiver, to V icksburg,\non the .Mississippi, via Monroe on the Ouachita.\n\"The questions you ask I shall answer, as I suppose, of course, they were intended\npurely as a professional matter, without entering into questions regarding its utility, which\nare, doubtless, better understood by yourselves than 1 could present them.\n\"I answer as to practicability, that there is ou the whole route nothing approaching\nvery near to the impracticable,\n\"This line would be 180 miles long, and would keep within ten miles ofthe same parallel, namely, latitude thirty-lwo degrees thirty minutes, all the way,\n\"Commencing on the east bank of Red River, opposite to Shreveport, the best route\nwould cross the Bayou Bodcan, below the lake, two or three miles, and pursue a line,\nnearly direct, to Minden, on the Dauchete: thence dellecting a little northward, to avoid\nthe broken lands about the head waters of the Black Lake Bayou, it would pursue the\nsummit ridge Dearly due east, between the waters of the D'Arbonne on the north, and\nthe Dngdeniona and Castor on the south; and without crossing a single stream large\nenough to have a name, in 75 miles, would reach the Ouachita river, ooposite Monroe, in\nP^ely the same latitude with Shreveport.\n'_*rotn Monroe, the best line would continue eastward, not far from the township line\nW T. 7,8, north, crossing tbe Lafourche Bayou and Boeuff River, a little south ofthe ex-\n\"?{\"* soud' corner of the Bastrop Grant, the Bayou Macon, and Joe's Bayou, in   the\nMiddle \u00b0' T. 7, and thence run  along the bank of the latter to the nearest bend of the\ncisas river: along the bank of the Tensas, and across its bend, the line would cross that\nthe61\"8t ur near L',e \"orth line of -*1* 6' an&lt;* t!ie ft\u00b0undaway Bayou at Richmond, north o f\non rt^M- \u00b0-'\" ^a'nut Bayou ; and thence eastward, the line would reach tbe river bank,\nne Mississippi, at some place between Young's Point and the estate of General Dun-\nPj\u2014thence it would keep near the bank ofthe river to a point opposite Vicksburg.'\nunonf    ^rea,est difficulties on this route are not in the construction of a railway track\n\u25a0lone ,r\u00b0\\  ^ro.U!.lc'' without any considerable excavation  or embankment.    This may be\n\u00b0f tijnh1       m'nimum, or near the minimum cost of railway construction.    The abundance\nri\u201e,    er.on the way at nearly every portion ofthe line, and the slight grades required,\n\u2022Sample assurance of this.\nand sp6 lrUi\u00b0 .'^\"'cuhies consist, first, in the bridges or crossings of several large streams ;\n\"'ist^Tl ' '\" l!l-6 cl,aracter \u00b0f die overflowed region to be crossed.\n\u2022i e-uch'    i   fe ^' 'Je **ve **rst c'ass bridges to he constructed on the route; and if built\n'oabouf5\"    a'U'a' inaQI,er, as are common on similar streams, thoy must cost a sum equal\nmiles of S'X |n'fes.ot' roa&lt;l each ; and three bridges of the second class, equal each to two\n'heiaiti' r        which may be estimated in all as increasing the cost of the whole road above\n\"The   U'\"' ^ ^Ur\" noL le8S lhan S3r,0'00\u00b0-\nnext difficulty is a much less one as to increased cc5t.    It would require that the","fullrs":{},"find":"2215.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2214","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"599564","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.57 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
