<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/426</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>426</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/426/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"f\n'\u20221 \u25a0'.\n60\nS O U Til- W E S T E R X   J 0 tl R X A L.\nn-.jff'.,\nT  i\n\u25a0f;\nIf?\nm\n\\   . \u2022\nI\nN   '\nSeven o'clock, P. M. ahticle iv.\nM7 P M   the Convention met, pursuant to adjournment.      '\u25a0 T\"\u00ab stated meetings of this sociely shall be held an-\nThe Secretary being absent,  on   motion of Mr. Lester, &lt;\"\u00ab%  on the second Monday in January:  in  the city o\nVdolphus (1 Wi ir, of Lowndes, was appointed Sec'y pro tern. Jackson.\n(In motion of James Phillips, Esq., the Constitution was     2, Special meetings may be convened by order of the di.\nread, and the sections severally odopti d, as follows - [ rectors, having given previous nonce, ol Iwo months.\nCONSTITUTION, AtvrioLE v.\nWe. the undersigned, believing it of vital importance thai     This Constitntion can be alter. .1 at any regular meeting\nthose immediately interested in  the cause of education, bepy a majority of the members present,\nunanimous in their opinions anil views, do hereby pledge our-\u25a0 A\" ' \" '''' '''\nselves zealously to support the following Constitution;\u2014 );'ivc members shall constitute a quorum.\nARTICLE I. ''\"  \"lotion of Mr.   Dubuisson,  which  was   seconded  by\nThis Association shall be known by the name of the Mis- General Coffee, the Constitution was presented for the sign*\nsis.-ippi Association for the Promotion of Education.    Its ob-jlllres \"' those present.\nject shall bo to promote, by every laudable means, the diflu-      On his motion il was also resolved, that the Committee re-\nsion of knowledge in regard to education, especially by aim- P\u00b0rt on tl\"' second Monday, in place ofthe 8th of January.\ning to create some general system of education in this State\u20141    (,]1 motion of Mr. Tucker, of Lowndes, the convention\nthe elevation ofthe character of teachers who may adopt proceeded to the election of officers of the association, which\ninstruction as a regular profession, and dispel that apathy resulted as follows,\nwhich exists on this great subject. Professor o. i.. dubuisson, of Jefferson  College, Presi-\nARTICLE II.\nThis association shall h- composed of such teachers of a\ngood literary and moral character, ami others who may take\nan interest in the improvement of the society, as may sign tho\nDr. John W. Kino, of Brandon, Vice President.\nJames Phillips, Esq., of Jackson, Corresponding Sec'y.\nM  K. Dudley, Esq., Recording Rceretary.\nConstitution Dr. M. W. Phillips, Dr. J. L. Montgomery, Solomon Tift,\nof Jackson, Rev. D. Comfort of Clinton, and Pryor Lea, ol\n1. The officers \",' this society shall consist of a president,'Jackson, Directors.\nvice-president, recording and corresponding secretary, and:    Mr. Coffee offered the following resolution:\nlive directors. Resolved, By this convention, that editors of newspapers in\n2. The president shall preside at tin- meeting of the society.; this Stale, friendly to the cause of education, be requested lo\nIn his absence the vice-president nt president protemporeshall publish the proceedings of this convention, which was car-\noccupy the chair.\n3. Tie- recording secretary shall give notice of all meetings, keep a regular record of their proceedings, and have\ncharge of all papers belonging i\" ihe society\n4. Tl\n\u2022li\nsoc\nried unanimously\nJudge Phillips offered the following resolution:\nResolved, That any person wishing to become a member\nofthis association, and thereby promoting the cause of educa-\n\u25a0I. '1'be corresponding secretary, subject to the board of tion in this Stale, may do so at anytime, by applying to the\nrectory, shall be the organ ol communication with other recording secretary, and signing the Constitution, as adopted\nL'icticsund individuals. by said association,\u2014which was adopted unanimously,\n5. Tie. board of directors shall have the general mnnage-     Mr. Pntridgo offered the following resolution :\n    ..- ., ;    ;.t I.    ..:...   . .   1   . : I ....   .:., . . ....\nty, wilh authority to devise aid cany into I     Resolved, That the President cause drafts or copies of the\neif -t such measures as will In -, promote its interest Constitution of this Society, to be circulated in every county\nil. They shall appoint competent persons to deliver the of this State: and whenever ten members are attached to the\nannual address and lectures, recommend to the society stiita- same, such county society shall become auxiliary to the State\nble persons to serve on s'.-iiidiiig committees. 'association, which was carried unanimously.\n7.   li shall  be their duty to see ,1:\nproper notice be given     Mr. Lester offered the following resolution:\n\u2022      1,  Ml,in    \u2022\u2022'-   men   ucu}   lu ;t&lt;   mill ]ii njiei   nun, e  tie  given Mr,   l.Ostor tlllel'eel tile lOllOWlllg 1'CSOlUl loll -\nof the annual meetings, by the secretariat least three months Resolved, Thai tho proceedings of this convention be\nprevious to the time ol commencing; and exhibit their pro-signed by the chairman, and countersigned by the secretary,\n.-.-.-dings and reports thereon at the annual meetings; and fill which was unanimously carried\n_n ...   --...I  :.. .u.   i l    .... .1..;..  .,\" ,- ,-.,    :... .\nall vacancies that may occur in the board, or their officers ol\nthe soci' ty.\n.?. They shall have power io appoint from their number\na local executive committee, to carry into eflect, under their\ndirection, all the duties assigned them by this Constitution.\n9. It shall further be their duty, when the sociely shall\nthink proper, to procure the annual address and lectures, the\nreports of the committee, and other communications to the\nsociety for publication ; and they shall have power to till va-\n;oncies that may occur during the recess of the meeting\nAI. R   Dudley, Sec'y.\nm. itEin, Chairman,\nli E v l E W\n\u2022Elements or Moral Philobophy.\"   it&gt; tlip Hev. fanner Atlanta, D. I). Printed\nWell a Tliurmon, Printers to tho University, Cnmbrldje.\u20148vo. pp\nby r.\n193.\nThis volume tie;\n: deserves notice both for its subject and execution.    It is the fruit of Lectures delivered by the author, as tl\nhe\nthe\nHorry Professor of Moral and Political Philosophy in th\nCollege of Charleston, S. C. and President ofthe same.    H\nnative of Massachusetts,     He is already favorably know?","fullrs":{},"find":"427.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"426","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1819365","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
