<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/494</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>494</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/494/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"t-:Ni\nfete1\nii:,fl\nI '' * ''Y, \u25a0\nI    'ij.-*\"\n!i. Mi\nc*-\nI1H\ns o u i' ii- W e a 'i' e r N journal.\nlb-\n'\ntivato philosophy in the bosom of their families. In both\ncountries, a vast advantage is possessed over the English or.\nmy, in respect to the- pursuits of their leisure. Nothing can\nsurpass, if equal, the conviviality (not lo say dissipation,) of\nthe officers of the English army. Cards and bumpers are\ninfinitely moro popular than books and philosophy; and for\nthe plain reason, that their education is originally deficient,\nand their leisure and pay ample. In justice to the English,\nwe should say of their rivals the French, that a majority of\ntheir officers are not belter educated than the English, but\nthey are of a more enterprising and active character, have\nmuch moro duty to perform, and cannot support leisure with\nsuch contented and idle dignity. An officer in England\ngains access lo the best sociely, by his rank; in France by\nhis gallantry or scientific enterprise, und in the United States\nby his industry, accomplishments, and behavior.\nSilly. The next department of our subject, is to examine\nthe effects of military education upon individual mind, and\nnational character. It will not be difficult to conclude', that\nthe course of study and discipline, pursued in these schools,\nmust engender habits of great effort, profound and connected\nthought. But, further, il induces a habit of systematizing\nand classifying, and testing every thing by a standard of\nknown accuracy. All the benefits (and they are many) of\nmathematical study, are gained by the military student; among\nwhich we find the discipline of the reasoning powers, by that\nprofound and only intelligible species of logic, geometric\ndemonstration and Algebraic analysis. A thorough course\nof the exact, ns of the natural sciences, inspires with admiration at the magnificent machinery of the universe, the beauty and perfect adaptation of all things to their purposes ; and\nwith reverence for the divine source.' whence all originated.\nIt has been objected, and not without an appearance of\nplausibility, that a military education engenders a war spirit,\nhardens the heart, and blunts the affections: and these objections, if valid, are most serious ones; and we feel called upon\nto examine them. \u2022 It should first be remembered that officers\nof an army are not remunerated in proportion to the battles\nthey fight or the; blood they shed. Their profession is salaried, and their compensation is neilher enhanced by active\nservices, nor diminished by the leisure of peace. If it st\nbe urged that men always wish to distinguish themselves in\ntheir profession, anel that war only furnishes the man of arms\nthis opportunity,\u2014we can but acknowledge that uneducated\nand ambitious men\u2014those whose contracted philanthropy\ncould desire a reputation at the expense of innocent, or unnecessary blood, and whoso minds can find no occupation to\nrelieve the lassitude of idleness and dissipation,\u2014these ma\nand most generally do thirst for actual service. But just\nhere we discover a new argument for military education \u2022 to\nenlarge the views and give a taste for mental culture; to instil a patriotism too expanded to wish one's country stained\nt wilh blood, anel yet to be prepared in case of necessity to\nrender efficient service wilh the greatest saving of human\nlife. How despicable would appear a judge, who would\nseek his own renown by endeavoring to produce crime and\nlitigation ; or the physician, who, to exhibit his healing skill,\nshould poison the fountains of his  vicinity.    Examples of\nthis kind are rare, and yet objections might be urged against\nthe study of law for the civil magistracy, with (he same propriety, as against tho military officer. And in regard to\nblunting the finer feelings, it may be true of common soldiery who have seen much service, as it is of the hang-man or\nguillotine executioner: but 'tis no more true of the noble-\nminded officer than ofthe magistrate or physician. \"A\ntaste; for sanguinary sights, has ever been the characteristic\nof weak and cowardly dispositions. Merely being accustomed to the sight of blood, wounds and death, has no tendency to make men brave. Where there is no personal hazard, no intrepidity can be shown.\" The tendency, then, of\nmilitary education, so far from rendering men callous to human suffering, in making them intrepid, is, on the contrary,\nrather to render them keenly alive to others' woes, and to bc\nprompt in relieving them. The officer stands, as it were, a\nsentinel on the watch-towers of his country, not longing for\na struggle in which he must suffer, and perhaps die, but\nready to (ire his signal gun at the approach of danger, and\nawake his fellow guards to the rescue.\nIf these are the effects of military education upon individual\nmind, its influence upon national character follows, anel partakes of tho same nature. The promptness and efficiency ofn\nnation's defence elevates it in the estimation of neighboring\npowers, at the same time that it deters the ambitious and grasping, from insult and aggression. But the greatest influence is\nexerted at home in the security of its inhabitants. A people\nconstantly exposed to the sword of its neighbors, is harrassed\nby fear, and drawn from the duties of domestic industry; bul\nwhen national defence is ample, tranquility and happiness\nabound, and prosperity and plenty crown the; inhabitants.\nFinally and briefly. How far may military discipline he\nintroduced, with advantage, inlo civil institutions of learning.'\nSeveral military schools have been established and conduct-\neel with great success in the United States, yet, if I mistake\nnot, they have all been too exclusively military, for an advantageous preparation for either of the learned professions.\nThey have followed too nearly the subjects taught in the\nUnited States Academy; and for the general education every\nyoung man should have in setting out in life, this is too exclusive. Most of these military attainments arc absolutely\nlost. We believe, however, that an institution, whose course\nof studies is that ordinarily pursued in college, and whose\ndiscipline is military\u2014all duties enforced with military rigor,\nand tho necessary exercise of its students taken in drilling,\nwould ensure a degree of order and acquirement, at present\nunknown to civil institutions. And for several very cogent\nreasons. First, a uniform dress had a wonderful influence\nin levelling distinctions, as all, by this means, appear with\nequal neatness and gentility; and military pride, which soon\nsprings up in the young, when uniformed and drilled, has\nan equally surprising effect upon tho conduct. An appeal\nto the honor of a soldier will eflect more than the fear ofpun-\nishment from a score of laws, occasionally executed. Besides, in no civil institution does punishment tread invariably\nupon the \"heels\" of delinquency, as in military law; ami\nthe punishments of civil law, though often physically more\nsevere, carry wilh  them much less of poignant  odium and","fullrs":{},"find":"495.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"494","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1887837","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.80 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
