<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/493</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>493</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/493/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I 0 U Til- W E S T E R N J 0 U R N A L ,\n11 r\nran any rank or patronage .cancel a single delinquency, or\nhwate one degree, the relative standing of a cadet.    The\nirtion wo sometimes hear, that the institution is aristocratic\n,n I accessible only to the rich and influential, is either deli\nUrate slander, or betrays the ignorance of its origin.\nThe location of this institution is ono of its happiest fea-\ntures.   Adorned, as il  is,  by every beauty and grandeur\nwhich the lavish hand of nature can bestow, it has also the\nndvantngo of being most classic in revolutionary history.\nAnd when, on a bitter winter's night, the cadet is treading his\nsentinel post, ruminating upon the  hardships of a soldier's\nprofession, and feeling his limbs begin to grow numb with\ncold, be catches, perhaps, a starlight gleam of the crumbling\nbattlements of Fort Putnam, on tho highland brow above\nhim, and in a moment, the images of a daring Putnam, a beloved Kosciusko,  a revered La Fayette, and nn immortal\nWashington are before him,    He is Heading whore limy\ntoiled and agonized for liberty,\u2014he quickens his pace, forgets\nihat il is cold, and perhaps before another relief comes round,\naib'opnf perspiration might be scon on the brow of the cm-\nbryo bore).    From the character of a  Putnam, whose name\nthe fort bears, he learns that the sternest military rigor is not\ninconsistent with the; kind offices of mercy, charily, and philanthropy.    From Kosciusko, its engineer and builder, ho\nlenrnstho glory of sacrificing country, home, and friends, \"to\ncrusade for freedom, in freedom's holy land.\"   The beauteous\ngarden of nature, which bears his name, is kept fresh and\ngreen by youths who cherish his memory.    His favorite retreat was here in this sequestered nook, against that stupendous overhanging rock, fit emblem this of ihe holy cause he\nfought in, for thus did bleeding America lean for support upon the \" Rock of Ages.\"     In the midst of this garden, there\nstands a large vase; of tho purest while; marble, and from its\nbottom, a clear fountain springs perennial, and upon its mar\n!:in is carved, simply,  \"Kosciusko.\"    And upon the most\nconspicuous spot in the plain, there stands a monument, of the\nsun.' pure marble, so that stranger passes not, without witnessing the lasting gratitude of cadets, and reading the revered\nname \"Kosciusko.\"    From\"Washington's valley,\" another\nbeauteous and retired spot, where leaping cascades and dashing water-falls, \"make music ever,\" and laurels grow perennial, as if to crown the valo which bears the name of the\ndeparted hero\u2014from this the cadet is reminded ofthe character of the father of his country.    And from his example he\nmay learn\u2014what may he not learn?    At the mention of that\nname, the proudest soldier might bow tho knee of humility,\nand beseech his Maker for the most distant resemblance to\n'his model of excellencies.    Fort Putnam, and the Hudson,\nwhich sweeps beneath it, and \" Robison's house \" beyond, are\nall eloquent with the black and changeless infamy of a once\ndistinguished American officer, who bartered his bleeding\ncountry for the gold of the oppressor.    The lesson taught by\ncontrasting his memory with thnt of those whose duties wero\nin and nobly done, never fails to make a salutary impression\n\"pan him who is just entering upon the threshold of his mil-\n\"ary career.    So tho young mariner upon the ocean wave,\nwho sees here and there a gallant sail leap proudly over tho\nwaters, and on another S'.le a single wreck- dashing among\nihe breakers, turns from the dangers: of an untried channel,\nand speeds him to his moorings, where tho channel is known\nand the waters deep and placid. These are a (rw of the\nmost prominent appendages, which render West Point a happy location for a military academy. And my audience\nwill pardon me, if the remembrance of days of tho soldier's\njoy and pride, has betrayed me from my subject, as ihe reality-\nhas often lured mo from more, imperative duties.\nTho method ndopted by government of selecting cadets,\nwe deem highly objectionable, and liable to the grossest\nabuses. How easy is it, at all times and for any person, to\nprocure as many recommendations as may be desired, as\nthere is no lad whom somebody does not think smart. And\nby this very means, we find an entering class of cadets, nearly as promiscuous in regard to talents as any body of young\nmen taken at random. It is nol sufficient that a few months'\ncadetship sifts out the blockheads, and leaves the talented for\ngraduation. For how many pangs must it cost fond parents,\nto find their sons dismissed in that very public manner for\nimbecility or indolence; and how many young men are ruined by the oil in in attached to such a dismission, From a class\nof one hundred and twenty, the number of graduates will\nusually be forty: fully a third beingfound deficient or dismissed, or resign to avoid ono or the other: tho other third\nleaving from disgust or the request of their friends, and a few\nfrom ill health, How easily might all this expense to the\nrovemment and ruin of character bo avoided, were we to\nadopt the; French plan of selecting from public and thorough\nexamination, young men of talents, industry, nnd robust constitution I\nThat the; objects of military education are fully realized\nin the United Stales, our army will answer for itself.    Perhaps in no army, not even the French, are the officers uniformly men of so high attainment; and for the plain reason,\nthat the only avenue to the army is through the Military\nAcademy.    Besides the mere; officering the army, another\nobject is effected, which is peculiar to the United States, namely\u2014ihe diffusing among community such acquirements as\nare obtained only in military schools: so that, in the event of\nwar, tho militia may have active and efficient gunners, engineers and commanders.    This necessity arises from the United number of our standing forces, and the necessity of nn\nimmediate call upon the militia in ense of war.   Education, in\nthe military academy nt West Point, is equally thoiough in\nits departments, though embracing fewer subjects than in ihe\nPolytechnic school.    Yet, in the latter, each is appointed to\nbis department of Engineering, Gunnery, or Architecture,\nand omits both the others;  whilst, in the United States, each\ncadet masters the whole course.    The result is, that France\nhas officers of a more profound acquaintance with a single\nbranch, whilst we have them of higher general accomplishment.    We shall not decide between the merits of these systems, as each is probably best adapted to the nation in which\nit obtains.     In .both,  however, a sufficient knowledge and\ntaste for scientific research is gained, to enable the army officers to devote their leisure, which, in time of peace, is great,\nto the prosecution of their studies.     In France particularly,\nose who have ample fortunes, retire from the army, and cub\ni,:M\n\u25a0r:m\n'MM\n\u25a0m\nm\n&lt;-tt\ni   \u25a0:-\ni\n\u25a0\n31\n.\ni.\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"494.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"493","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1834575","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
