<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/423</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>423</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/423/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOU T II - W E S T E R N  J O U R N A L.\nevent was undoubtedly iho study of the classics.    From the\nGreek nnd Roman authors, the moderns learned in think.  In-\nAs io prose translations of ihe poets, who ever reads, unless\nii be an indolent school-boy to save himself the trouble of con-\n(c.|lect assumed now courage, shook its daring wing, nnd cs- stilling his grammar ami dictionary, Davidson's Virgil, or\nsayed a bolder flight. Patience of investigation was ncqtur\nnl. nnd freedom of inquiry fearlessly indulged. The love of\ntruth displayed itself in ihe love of liberty. The Reformation\nevent hand in hand with the revival of letters; and ihe torch\nof religion, as -.veil as of science, was lighted at '.lie (lame\nwhich, unextinguished, slill burned in tli.\" convents ofthe\nmonks. Th\" reformers wero men well versed in Grecian\nmil Roman lore, ami drew from this armory polished weapons\nof etherial temper, with which they were enabled successfully\nto combat and overthrow the long established errors ol\nPopery.\nl-iut the classics not only furnish models in composition ol\nal! thai is chaste and eloquent, beautiful and sublime : hut they\nSmart's Horace? In poetic translations, in Pope's Homer,\nas has been well said, wo have much of Pope, but little of\nHomer, wo see generally more of the translator than of the\nauthor;\u2014e. g. A bust of iho Venus foe Medicis, or tho\nFurneso Hercules, taken by a second or third-rate artist, would\nbe as faithful n representation, and would convey about ns\ngood an idea ol the originals.\nThe Roman language is the key to the French, Spanish\nand Portuguese, which are only cognate dialects ol the Latin,\nA competent knowledge of this hist, not only wondeifullv !a-\ncilitates the acquisition of the most fashionable and useful\nmodern language, bin is, as we before observed, of incalculable value to the English student, who would understand ihe\n3 abound  In  manly sentiments, and   illustrious examples, full  import and use of his own  vernacular  tongue,     It  is\nWe are presented, every where, with instances of greatness\nel' soul, rising above all selfish vi.-ws, of unshaken fidelity\nof ardent love of country, of invincible fortitude, uncon\npromising hatred of tyranny, disinterested patriotism, and in\ncorruptible integrity. Constant familiarity with authors who\npresent, on almost every page, such exhibitions of character,\nwith matchless eloquence, anil irresistible force, must be pro\ndue-live of ihe most noble and generous emotions in the sus\nceptible bosom of youth. The mind, like the waters travel's-\ning subterranean minerals, imbibes the mature of the thoughts\nand sentiments through which it passes in the course of its\nstudies, especially at an age. when all the senses are lively\nami vigorous, and readily yield to any impression.    The\nneedless to enlarge on the obvious utility ol the Latin in these\nrespects, which must be apparent In every one in the least\nconversant with the subject, In a subsequent part of this essay will be pointed out some of the peculiar advantages resulting from ihe study of (Ireek.\nAnother strong argument in favor of classical studies is\nderived from llic- influence which they have exerted on the\nliterature of modern nations, a reference lo whose history\nwill clearly show that literature has ever flourished or declined, precisely in proportion as ancient learning has been\ncultivated, or neglected. The Augustan period of French\nliterature was undoubtedly the age of Louis I-lib, when the\nStudy of the classics was prosecuted will, the greatest zeal\npublican ages of Greece and Rome afford the purest models and success. It was then those standard editions, in nsuui\nof virtue, abound in examples of heroism, magnanimity audi De\/phini, with which every school boy is familiar, wore pub\npublic spirit. Fabricius and Aristides, Cincinnntus andllished expressly for the use of the Dauphin, the king's eldest\nEpaminondas, are worthy to be placed by the side of Wash, son, by some ofthe most learned men of France, Then\nton, Lafayette and others, who have bequeathed to us the in- flourished Feiielon, Massillon, Bordaloue and  Bossuet, those\nlieritance of their lame, and the legacy of their bright exam,\npie, What an excellent school for the education of the youth\nof our happy republic is the instructive page of Grecian and\nRoman history! As they read the spirit-stirring incidents of\ntheir wonderful story, they will learn to glow with the enthusiasm of valor and patriotism, and to emulate, in their conduct, all that is noble, generous and magnanimous, They\ncatch by sympathy the virtues mid graces of which they read;\nthey read the beautiful description, anil are led to imitate the excellencies which they admire and revere. Early then let the\nyouthful student be taught to think as they thought, to feel\nas they felt, to speak as they spoke, and converse with the\nmaster-spirits of the two greatest nations of antiquity in their\nown expressive and unrivalled dialects. Still let him con-\ntemplato tlio self-sacrificing devotion of a Regulus and a\nLeonidas, the stern, indomitable resolution of (Jato, the lofty\nvirtues of Socrates and Seneca.\nBut it will be said why spend four or five years in studying the originals, when the same advantage may be derived\nfrom the perusal of translations! Translations may possibly\nconvey the meaning of a classic author, but the force, the\nbeauty, the. delicate turns of expression and thought, which\nare intraiisfiisibleand intranslatable, mustbenhnostentirely lost.\neminent orators and divines, who were all classical scholars,\nand formed their style on classical models. H is the highest\npraise of lUulk-re, Racine and Corneille, that they have successfully imitated and rivalled Aristophanes, Euripides and\nSophocles. Since Polytechnic schools, which, in a great\nmeasure dispense with the classics, have come into vogue,\nwhat writers has France produced at all comparable to the great\nwriters above mentioned? I las there nut been a great declension, even since the age of Voltaire? The same remarks which\nhave been made in regard to French, might be shown to be equally applicable to Spanish, Portugucseand Italian literature. They\nire all so many rivulets (lowing from those ancient and inexhaustible fountains of truth, majesty mid beauty, the Latin\nand Greek authors. Their influence on our own literature\nhowever, more particularly deserves our attention. Exam\nine the long and splendid catalogues of English statesmen, divines, orators, poets, philosophers nnd historians. Were they\nnot, almost without exception, classical scholars, men who had\ndrank deeply at the well-springs of ancient learning, and\nwho admired, studied and imitated the best writers of Greeot\nand Rome? This is true not only of the poets, but likewise\nof the historians. Hume, Robertson nnd Gibbon formee\nthemselves on the faultless models presented by Herodotus\n.Vi\nm\nm\ne\na;\nfei\nf ;\u25a0\u25a0-\nM\n\u25a0 '  -m\ntin","fullrs":{},"find":"424.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"423","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1897720","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.81 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
