<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Transcript Crump 205A</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Special Collections Online</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-sce:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <note type="preferred citation" displayLabel="Cite As">LSU Special Collections Online, Louisiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.</note>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/LSU_SCE/id/202</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2006-10-23</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-11-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>LSU_SCE</alias>
         <pointer>202</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/LSU_SCE/202/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-02 09:47:14">{"title":"Transcript Crump 205A","creato":{},"date":{},"dates":{},"publis":{},"contri":{},"subjec":{},"descri":{},"notes":{},"langua":{},"transc":"Narrator: Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Interviewer: Pamela Dean Session II Transcriber: Barrett Campbell 14 July 1992 [End Tape 204, Side B. Begin Tape 205, Side A.] DEAN: [005] Okay. CRUMP: I didn't have a clue as to how to study in college. It was different than what I needed to study in high school. It was different in how I needed to prepare for tests. Because in high school, we were usually asked a lot of multiple choice questions, it seemed, and we rarely had to write out an answer to a question. When we did, it was a fact we had to answer. It wasn't very much thinking involved, as I recall it. I got to the university, and we had to think. Well, I wasn't used to that. I didn't know how to do that, quite, so I didn't know how to prepare for tests. I did not do well in Spanish because I had never taken a foreign language. But my instructor was fascinated with my ability to pronounce the words, and she said, \"You pronounce the words so well, and you hear the sounds so well.\" She says, \"If you'll will come to my office twenty minutes before class, I will tutor you.\" I did, and I don't even think I came very long, and my grades turned around totally. I mean, I went from an \"F\" to an \"A\", so I got a \"B\" out of the course. DEAN: Who was the professor, do you remember? CRUMP: I don't remember her name . . . I sure don't. Lovely woman. DEAN: Do you recall was she a full professor or instructor or graduate student, or . . . CRUMP: She was not a graduate student. She was either instructor or full professor, and she was a very, very heavy woman. Soft skin that looked peachy, northern accent. DEAN: Did you sense that she was taking an interest in you because you were black, and she wanted to encourage you? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Or simply that you had the potential. CRUMP: Didn't sense it at all. Yes. If it was because I was black, I'm glad, but I didn't know that. I thought she just sensed the potential, and she was right. I had that same potential for every class I took, but I did not have another professor like her. Had I had a little bit more of the tutoring that she gave I would have, then I would have made very good grades and would have graduated in four years, but I didn't. I was lost a lot of times. Totally lost. How I got out of most of my classes, I don't know. I must have been just naturally smart in some things because I just didn't know the system. I didn't know in\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A flunking a course to drop it. I didn't know if I got really behind to drop. I didn't know any of that. It seemed like there was no one there who knew to tell me that. My counselors were useless as far as I was concerned. They offered me nothing, nothing useful. DEAN: These were faculty advisors who were supposed to give you some clue . . . CRUMP: Right, yes. They gave me no clues. I got no help from them. They just sat there and listened to me and gave me nothing back. I didn't have anywhere to go. My parents didn't know anything about college, and so I flunked out, not knowing how not to flunk out. I had no idea. DEAN: What year was this? CRUMP: It was the end of the summer of my first year I flunked out, and I sat out for a semester. Then I came back and I was in for a year and a half, and I flunked out again. Then I came back and stayed until my fourth year and got hired because in the seventies, this was in seventy, they were hiring blacks. In this town, if you were black with clerical skills, you had it because they were putting all the blacks out front they could and all the blacks in offices they could. It was very hard to find any with clerical skills. We had not been to the vo-tech schools because there weren't any black secretaries. No one had the foresight to do this. I just imagined it. I didn't know that it was going to become possible. Southern's secretarial training was horrible. Horrible! I was so much more advanced than those students at Southern. I had done so much more than they had done. There's no way they could have beat me out for the job. DEAN: Tell me about some of the classes that you did take, both the ones you flunked and the ones you passed. CRUMP: I flunked math . . . that's, that's the one. I flunked it twice, and that was really my holdup. I needed a tutor, and I didn't know that, and no one knew because I did not understand the approach he was using in math. I thought I was just dumb in math. I wasn't. I wasn't. DEAN: What math class was this, Algebra? CRUMP: General math. I flunked general math. I was afraid of math in the first place because I never thought of myself as good at it because I made \"C's\" in it in high school, but I never flunked anything. This flunking business I didn't understand. DEAN: English? CRUMP: [53] English? I did well in it, for me. I got \"C's\" because we had to think. We had to write about what we read. Well, I had never done that. But I remember, this one professor told me, he said, he would be discussing the works that we had read. He would look at me and he said, \"You look like you've got a thought on this.\" I would say, \"No, I don't.\" I don't know if I did or not, but he would say this to me lots. He'd say, \"You look\n\n2\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A like you have a thought on this.\" He asked me to come to his office a couple of times, and I did, but I felt he was inappropriate with me. He sat too close to me. He asked me questions about fishing in my hometown, and if he came out to my hometown would my dad show him fishing areas, no, would I show him the fishing areas, and I said, \"Well, my dad would show you.\" You know, and things like that, and so I felt he was inappropriate so I didn't like . . . DEAN: A little too personal? CRUMP: Yes, a little too personal. His knees touched mine a couple of times, too. DEAN: Oh. CRUMP: Yes, so. That was the only experience I had like that. I had heard of experiences like that, more than that. Actually if he had made more of an advance on me I would have had a hard time with it because I wouldn't have quite known what to do at that time, being my professor, you know. DEAN: This idea of sexual harassment was not something we knew about, right? CRUMP: No, no. It was that if he did it, it was your fault. You must have been sitting provocatively, had on too much makeup or something. He considered me as a thinker, but I wasn't. If I was, I wasn't aware of thinking. I was listening because I was fascinated at other people thinking and other people responding. I was lost, but I managed to get a \"C\". There were many classes that I was lost in that I got a \"B\" or a \"C\" in. How, I don't know. I had never felt that way before, lost. One of my favorite professors was Mark Carleton, a history professor. [71] DEAN: I know him well. CRUMP: Yes. He made history so interesting. I never knew history was so interesting. When Mark talked about it, and he was entertaining in the way he talked about it. You could tell he enjoyed it, and therefore I did. Even though it was a very large class, I wouldn't think of missing Mark's class. I think I got a \"C\" out of that, but for me, that was good! That was really good. I may have gotten a \"B\" out of that. I'm not sure. DEAN: Was this U.S. history or Louisiana history? CRUMP: U.S. DEAN: U.S. history. Did you take any other history classes? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Did you hear about T. Harry Williams?\n\n3\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: Did you hear anything? What did you hear about him? I collect T. Harry stories. CRUMP: Now I can't remember, but I know that . . . I think he . . . was he . . . he was there then, because I remember some of the girls going to his house trick-or-treating. You know, they were saying, you know, \"I trick-or-treated T. Harry Williams's.\" He was teaching there then? DEAN: Yes. CRUMP: Yes, because there were people who took his class. I didn't know to take his class. I didn't know about him, but they said it was wonderful. But since I . . . it just kind of went here for me, I didn't . . . this was about thinking, you see, and I didn't know about thinking. I didn't know about really, really getting into history. I didn't know about thinking about what Maxine wanted, you know, in a conscious process. I knew about it in spurts. I knew how to think in segments, but I didn't know how to flow into this will lead to this type thinking. I was just learning that. I was just watching people who could do that and I had no concept of what that was like. I really walked through in my sleep a lot there, not knowing I was, but I was absorbing nonetheless. I was absorbing. DEAN: Was Mark Carleton's class your best class? Or were there other classes that you did well and liked? CRUMP: Well, actually, Spanish was, I did the best in because I had been tutored. I understood how to study it and I understood how to listen in class for what I needed. That was fun. It may have helped me to understand some of my other classes better and what to listen for to be prepared for the test. Accounting is another one that destroyed me. That was when I flunked out the next time because I still had this fear of math. I had a very BORING instructor. He just didn't care. It was like he put the information out there. If you got it, you got it. If you didn't, you didn't. It fell out of his mouth and, I almost went to sleep in his class. He just didn't bother. He was extremely boring. I used to have nightmares about that class. I really did. Whenever I had a professor who took one moment to connect with me individually, I did well in that class. Swimming was one of those classes. [103] I got a \"B\" in swimming because I went in there frightened. I had taken first swimming class and had a very good instructor then, a woman, I don't remember her name, but she told me at the end of the class, she said, \"You just started to really learn at the end of this class.\" She said, \"I don't want you to stop now.\" She said, \"I want to sign you up for the next class.\" So I went the next semester, and there was already a card in there for me for the thing, I said, \"Oh, I guess I got to take this.\" So I went in there, they had boys and girls and it was like, \"Oh, God!\" So I went up to the coach, and I said, \"Coach, I've finished beginning, but I didn't do very well in beginning class. These kids are already swimming, and I'm not going to be able to do this well starting out.\" He said, \"I'm not going to judge you by the way they swim. I'll judge your progress.\" That was what he did, and I made a higher grade than\n\n4\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A some of them who came in swimming. He had the right attitude for me. When he saw that I had some struggles at the very beginning, he put one of the lifeguards with me to work on my skills to get them up. Once I understood what the stroke was supposed to do, then I got it. I think I had been taught such backward ways, in a ways, such backward ways of learning. Sorry, but that was the way it was for my teachers. That I had had some screwed up styles taught to me, until I had to unlearn them at LSU and . . . I used to have to figure things out for myself, it seemed like, from the other teachers. So once I got it, I had it. Anything that, once you helped me understand what it is I'm doing here, then I could do it. In every situation where I had somebody work with me, then I got it. Not one math teacher, not one accounting teacher, not one physics teacher was that way. So those were the classes that killed me. Those were the only ones I couldn't pass. Because there was something in the concept that I never got. There was economics, everything that had numbers. Economics was a nightmare for me, too. I never understood the first thing. I didn't know what he was talking about. All of those professors seemed to not care, but it could have also been that I never connected with them, that I never went to them and said I didn't know or didn't understand. My understanding of it was so far away I didn't even know what to ask them. Only thing I could have gone to them and said, \"I am totally lost. I haven't the faintest idea what you are talking about.\" But I decided that my education there may not have come at the academic level that I might have liked or my parents might have liked, but the education was no less invaluable. Invaluable to me. I admired those students, particularly those black students, who came in and just went right through with high grades and everything. [131] But they came out of good schools in Baton Rouge, for one thing, you know. I wasn't a dumb student, so I certainly can't say that it was because . . . you know that I'm excusing why they . . . but the schools in Baton Rouge were better. I mean, there were some really good schools because when we used to have to go to state competitions and things like that and compete with some of these Baton Rouge schools, we never beat them out. We had a couple of genius students at our school, and those are the only students that ever beat anybody out in competition at the other schools, but they were just geniuses. So I knew that there were some inadequacies in the schools that I went to. So many of these students, in fact, all of the black students who came the first year were, were the tops in their class, including me, but I was tops in the class of a school that was somewhat deprived. So I think I did well for what I came from, although I blamed myself at many points. I felt that maybe I wasn't working hard enough, didn't have good study habits, and that may have been true, too. I had some poor study habits at times. In a way, I thought that some of my poor study habits was because I didn't have a social life. I had so much time on my hands. I really had time to study. I just didn't feel like studying because something else was flat there. I started to miss a full social life. I was deprived of black students for the benefits I thought I got from associating with the white students to get the future that I thought I wanted. Because they it was limited where I went with them in terms of, I don't know, it just seemed to be some functions I was left\n\n5\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A out of. Like I was never invited to a fraternity party, and that's what they had on weekends. You didn't have to be in a fraternity to go, but certainly no one was going to take me there because the sororities and fraternities were not going to accept me there at all. I would have been thrown out on my face, in the mud, probably. I mean, it was that serious. So, there were a lot of things like that I didn't get to go. When I went places with my friends, we went to a play at LSU, to a movie, to the game room, to bowling allies in town, to each other's dorms, or somebody's apartment. I could go to foreign students' parties. I became friends with a lot of foreign students, and I went to their parties in their apartments and stuff. I got to do that, but . . . DEAN: [158] Did you date at all? CRUMP: I had one date my first semester and one date my second. One date my first year and one date my second year. It wasn't until the summer of my third year that I started to date. DEAN: Who did you date those first two dates? CRUMP: There was, the first two, the first two dates were with the same guy, a friend of mine, my cousin's wife introduced me to him because he lived next door to her and he went to school at Southern. Bill Heidel. DEAN: So it was not an LSU student? CRUMP: No. He had his own car, a '65 Mustang, which was cool. That was the car to have. He was his mother's only son, and his mother was very, very snobbish about her son. DEAN: Did she approve of you? CRUMP: No. \"I'm sorry, Bill's asleep.\" \"That's okay, Mama I'll take it.\" Gee! DEAN: What didn't she approve of in you? CRUMP: I don't know, anybody with her son, probably. DEAN: I see. But later on, you did begin to date? CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: LSU students? Were they or no? CRUMP: No, he was from Southern, too. DEAN: He was from Southern.\n\n6\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A CRUMP: I didn't date an LSU student . . . well, after that . . . after that guy, I dated an LSU student. Ralph Tyson, who is now a judge. We dated for the duration of the time I was there. DEAN: Were there campus-wide dances that you went to or anything like that? CRUMP: Yes, there were, sure did. People would ask me to dance, whites, foreign students. Jambalaya Jamboree. Especially in the late sixties, it was popular to dance with a black student then. It was just definitely popular because chances are she could dance. And I could. That got to be popular and so, yes, at big party functions and . . . just not fraternity and sorority, forget it. DEAN: They didn't start the black fraternities and sororities until after you had left, is that right? CRUMP: Right. It was in seventy-two, three, or four, somewhere in there. But I wouldn't have joined anyway. I had a friend, Sing Lee, Chinese, who was raised by southern whites, and he had a southern accent. I used to say, \"Sing, I just can't get over your accent!\" He could not understand what was funny about his accent. I said, \"Surely, Sing, you have got to realize how funny it is for me to look at your Chinese face and hear this southern accent coming out of it!\" He, he didn't think it was so funny! [194] And then I had a friend who, who tried to . . . my friend from New Orleans, Janel, told me of a guy who had been black-balled from a fraternity. I said, \"What's that?\" She said, \"You don't know what a black-ball is?\" I said, \"No.\" And I thought, \"Oh, oh, I guess I'm getting ready to feel stupid here, something I'm supposed to know that I don't know.\" I said, \"No, I don't.\" Se said, \"They've kicked him out of the fraternity.\" I says, \"Why?\" She said, \"Pshhh\"--That was Janel, she was always, \"Come on.\" I said, \"I don't know, Janel.\" She says, \"Maxine, isn't it obvious?\" I said, \"No, it isn't, Janel.\" She says, \"It's because he associates with me, and I'm your friend.\" I was stopped in my track. It was like you know this music they use on tv when the point is made, it's like, you know, this boom. Loud music in my head, it was like, \"What?\" My world blanked out for a minute, there I just . . . my stomach turned, that was just . . . the most devastating experience for me. I was angry. I was everything. What were these people doing? Who were they to do that? I became angry, I mean, I wanted to do something. I really wanted to do something then. You know, and Janel, \"Oh come on. Don't worry about it. ?ho needs those people?\" It was like, \"This is bigger than that, Janel. This is bigger than that.\" \"Pshhh, why worry about it?\" She could say that. Then I met Chris. What was Chris' last name? Marcuson, Chris Marcuson, from Slidell, who was also considered a misfit by the university. She only dated Latin guys. She used to ask me why was I so angry because by then I was angry about all of that, and I kept it inside because none of my white friends would let me talk about it. They were all, \"Eh.\" You know they want just enjoy being with us, do what we do. We'll take care of you type thing. Don't worry about all of that stuff. So no one would let me talk about being black, and that just got to be something inside of me that was building up. I was very angry by then. I had flunked out twice. My self-esteem had been lowered or at least threatened by\n\n7\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A then, and there were a lot of things that happened to me that I had no outlet for, no explanation for. Nothing had happened to me directly. It's like being anemic, you're not sick enough to be in bed, and no one can see you're sick walking around, and yet you're sick, very very sick. That's the way I was, I was walking around anemic. I was in trouble. I was hurting. I had no one. No one understood. No one knew. I had no real peer group. I didn't really belong anywhere. I had priced myself out of the market in every way. And . . . DEAN:[230] You didn't have a group of black friends to share this with? CRUMP: Oh, no, they were, you know, they, what could I share with them? I would have had to limit what I tell them because, you know, I still had white friends, and they didn't think much of that. Yolanda was okay with it, but it was still, I would, I could tell her some, but I really had no one that I could share the full experience with. Priests, nuns. I never went to Michael Cody. I probably could have shared the full experience with him. But for some reason, he seemed to be dealing with bigger things than what I could go to him with. So that just didn't seem to fit. The nuns, I thought, \"What do they know?\" \"What do they know? Their clothes cover their whole lives.\" So I just didn't have anyone. I kept it inside and I lashed out in ways that would make . . . white girls had this way of being able to giggle about anything. They learned a one emotion to everything, up, upbeat and above everything, nothing touched them until they cried about something that seemed irrelevant to me. When they said they were angry, it didn't look like anger to me. They would go \"Eh, this makes me so mad.\" I'm thinking, \"You're angry? You should see me when I'm angry.\" I never saw real expression. They didn't seem to have real deep feelings, and I started to get a little tired of this superficial way of relating. So I had a lot of problems within myself that didn't show on the outside to anyone that I could understand except the girls who would go, \"Ahh, Maxine, why does that make you angry? Come on!\" So it was like, \"You don't understand.\" That part of the experience was tough. So, I started to become unhappy and just wish that college would just be over. When I had an opportunity to get out, I was ready to go. I couldn't have taken another semester. DEAN:[258] So you didn't graduate? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Didn't go back ever and finish it? CRUMP: No. For a long time, I couldn't go back. It was too sore. I was too sore inside. I needed to heal. Then it was like, \"Go back for what? I'm in a whole new career now.\" By then I was in radio. I knew secretarial wasn't what I wanted, but I didn't know anything else there that I wanted. It never came a time when I could look back at LSU and say, \"What curriculum do I really want?\" It was like, \"None!\" So, when I got in broadcasting. Probably if had it been available then, I still wouldn't have taken it because I didn't think it was easy. The kids at school used to say, \"You should take journalism. It's easy.\" I used to think, \"Writing. I can't write. I can't think, let alone write. You've got to think to write.\"\n\n8\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A I was glad to get out into the boring plants. Then, I couldn't take that because I realized this is not for me. The first three years in that company, I was happy because it was a brand new company going on line so I got the . . . DEAN: What company was this? CRUMP:[272] Ciba-Geigy. A European based company. They had a lot of exciting things to it, and I got to use my skills there because it was brand new. I walked into an office with a desk and file cabinets and not the first paper. I had to put everything together. That was fun. Not very many college students get that opportunity. You go in there, and you take what they already have set up. I had a young boss, who was thirtyfour years old, and he was open to me bringing in my new ideas and doing them. So I had quite a privilege there. But after three years, that was not my career. Everywhere I went, having been to LSU meant something, and that was good. It was worth having gone. It has never not been worth it for me. I wouldn't have made another decision. I never regretted going to LSU. In fact, I always have been very happy about having gone there. It had a lot of happy moments for me and a lot of very tough moments. But I attribute it to a lot of my ability to think and move through society as it is, on its terms. DEAN: Well, that sounds to me like a closure point. CRUMP: [291] Okay. [End Tape 205, Side A. End Session II.]\n\n9","digitb":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections","source":{},"collec":{},"sourca":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections ( http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special )","type":{},"format":{},"imagb":{},"file":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.","cite":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections, LOUISiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.","to":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","relati":"http:\/\/louisdl.louislibraries.org\/cdm4\/index_LSU_SCE.php?CISOROOT=%2FLSU_SCE","typea":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"203.pdf","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2006-10-23","dmmodified":"2006-10-23","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"202","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"33551","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.03 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
      <transcript displayLabel="Transcript">Narrator: Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Interviewer: Pamela Dean Session II Transcriber: Barrett Campbell 14 July 1992 [End Tape 204, Side B. Begin Tape 205, Side A.] DEAN: [005] Okay. CRUMP: I didn't have a clue as to how to study in college. It was different than what I needed to study in high school. It was different in how I needed to prepare for tests. Because in high school, we were usually asked a lot of multiple choice questions, it seemed, and we rarely had to write out an answer to a question. When we did, it was a fact we had to answer. It wasn't very much thinking involved, as I recall it. I got to the university, and we had to think. Well, I wasn't used to that. I didn't know how to do that, quite, so I didn't know how to prepare for tests. I did not do well in Spanish because I had never taken a foreign language. But my instructor was fascinated with my ability to pronounce the words, and she said, "You pronounce the words so well, and you hear the sounds so well." She says, "If you'll will come to my office twenty minutes before class, I will tutor you." I did, and I don't even think I came very long, and my grades turned around totally. I mean, I went from an "F" to an "A", so I got a "B" out of the course. DEAN: Who was the professor, do you remember? CRUMP: I don't remember her name . . . I sure don't. Lovely woman. DEAN: Do you recall was she a full professor or instructor or graduate student, or . . . CRUMP: She was not a graduate student. She was either instructor or full professor, and she was a very, very heavy woman. Soft skin that looked peachy, northern accent. DEAN: Did you sense that she was taking an interest in you because you were black, and she wanted to encourage you? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Or simply that you had the potential. CRUMP: Didn't sense it at all. Yes. If it was because I was black, I'm glad, but I didn't know that. I thought she just sensed the potential, and she was right. I had that same potential for every class I took, but I did not have another professor like her. Had I had a little bit more of the tutoring that she gave I would have, then I would have made very good grades and would have graduated in four years, but I didn't. I was lost a lot of times. Totally lost. How I got out of most of my classes, I don't know. I must have been just naturally smart in some things because I just didn't know the system. I didn't know in

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A flunking a course to drop it. I didn't know if I got really behind to drop. I didn't know any of that. It seemed like there was no one there who knew to tell me that. My counselors were useless as far as I was concerned. They offered me nothing, nothing useful. DEAN: These were faculty advisors who were supposed to give you some clue . . . CRUMP: Right, yes. They gave me no clues. I got no help from them. They just sat there and listened to me and gave me nothing back. I didn't have anywhere to go. My parents didn't know anything about college, and so I flunked out, not knowing how not to flunk out. I had no idea. DEAN: What year was this? CRUMP: It was the end of the summer of my first year I flunked out, and I sat out for a semester. Then I came back and I was in for a year and a half, and I flunked out again. Then I came back and stayed until my fourth year and got hired because in the seventies, this was in seventy, they were hiring blacks. In this town, if you were black with clerical skills, you had it because they were putting all the blacks out front they could and all the blacks in offices they could. It was very hard to find any with clerical skills. We had not been to the vo-tech schools because there weren't any black secretaries. No one had the foresight to do this. I just imagined it. I didn't know that it was going to become possible. Southern's secretarial training was horrible. Horrible! I was so much more advanced than those students at Southern. I had done so much more than they had done. There's no way they could have beat me out for the job. DEAN: Tell me about some of the classes that you did take, both the ones you flunked and the ones you passed. CRUMP: I flunked math . . . that's, that's the one. I flunked it twice, and that was really my holdup. I needed a tutor, and I didn't know that, and no one knew because I did not understand the approach he was using in math. I thought I was just dumb in math. I wasn't. I wasn't. DEAN: What math class was this, Algebra? CRUMP: General math. I flunked general math. I was afraid of math in the first place because I never thought of myself as good at it because I made "C's" in it in high school, but I never flunked anything. This flunking business I didn't understand. DEAN: English? CRUMP: [53] English? I did well in it, for me. I got "C's" because we had to think. We had to write about what we read. Well, I had never done that. But I remember, this one professor told me, he said, he would be discussing the works that we had read. He would look at me and he said, "You look like you've got a thought on this." I would say, "No, I don't." I don't know if I did or not, but he would say this to me lots. He'd say, "You look

2

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A like you have a thought on this." He asked me to come to his office a couple of times, and I did, but I felt he was inappropriate with me. He sat too close to me. He asked me questions about fishing in my hometown, and if he came out to my hometown would my dad show him fishing areas, no, would I show him the fishing areas, and I said, "Well, my dad would show you." You know, and things like that, and so I felt he was inappropriate so I didn't like . . . DEAN: A little too personal? CRUMP: Yes, a little too personal. His knees touched mine a couple of times, too. DEAN: Oh. CRUMP: Yes, so. That was the only experience I had like that. I had heard of experiences like that, more than that. Actually if he had made more of an advance on me I would have had a hard time with it because I wouldn't have quite known what to do at that time, being my professor, you know. DEAN: This idea of sexual harassment was not something we knew about, right? CRUMP: No, no. It was that if he did it, it was your fault. You must have been sitting provocatively, had on too much makeup or something. He considered me as a thinker, but I wasn't. If I was, I wasn't aware of thinking. I was listening because I was fascinated at other people thinking and other people responding. I was lost, but I managed to get a "C". There were many classes that I was lost in that I got a "B" or a "C" in. How, I don't know. I had never felt that way before, lost. One of my favorite professors was Mark Carleton, a history professor. [71] DEAN: I know him well. CRUMP: Yes. He made history so interesting. I never knew history was so interesting. When Mark talked about it, and he was entertaining in the way he talked about it. You could tell he enjoyed it, and therefore I did. Even though it was a very large class, I wouldn't think of missing Mark's class. I think I got a "C" out of that, but for me, that was good! That was really good. I may have gotten a "B" out of that. I'm not sure. DEAN: Was this U.S. history or Louisiana history? CRUMP: U.S. DEAN: U.S. history. Did you take any other history classes? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Did you hear about T. Harry Williams?

3

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: Did you hear anything? What did you hear about him? I collect T. Harry stories. CRUMP: Now I can't remember, but I know that . . . I think he . . . was he . . . he was there then, because I remember some of the girls going to his house trick-or-treating. You know, they were saying, you know, "I trick-or-treated T. Harry Williams's." He was teaching there then? DEAN: Yes. CRUMP: Yes, because there were people who took his class. I didn't know to take his class. I didn't know about him, but they said it was wonderful. But since I . . . it just kind of went here for me, I didn't . . . this was about thinking, you see, and I didn't know about thinking. I didn't know about really, really getting into history. I didn't know about thinking about what Maxine wanted, you know, in a conscious process. I knew about it in spurts. I knew how to think in segments, but I didn't know how to flow into this will lead to this type thinking. I was just learning that. I was just watching people who could do that and I had no concept of what that was like. I really walked through in my sleep a lot there, not knowing I was, but I was absorbing nonetheless. I was absorbing. DEAN: Was Mark Carleton's class your best class? Or were there other classes that you did well and liked? CRUMP: Well, actually, Spanish was, I did the best in because I had been tutored. I understood how to study it and I understood how to listen in class for what I needed. That was fun. It may have helped me to understand some of my other classes better and what to listen for to be prepared for the test. Accounting is another one that destroyed me. That was when I flunked out the next time because I still had this fear of math. I had a very BORING instructor. He just didn't care. It was like he put the information out there. If you got it, you got it. If you didn't, you didn't. It fell out of his mouth and, I almost went to sleep in his class. He just didn't bother. He was extremely boring. I used to have nightmares about that class. I really did. Whenever I had a professor who took one moment to connect with me individually, I did well in that class. Swimming was one of those classes. [103] I got a "B" in swimming because I went in there frightened. I had taken first swimming class and had a very good instructor then, a woman, I don't remember her name, but she told me at the end of the class, she said, "You just started to really learn at the end of this class." She said, "I don't want you to stop now." She said, "I want to sign you up for the next class." So I went the next semester, and there was already a card in there for me for the thing, I said, "Oh, I guess I got to take this." So I went in there, they had boys and girls and it was like, "Oh, God!" So I went up to the coach, and I said, "Coach, I've finished beginning, but I didn't do very well in beginning class. These kids are already swimming, and I'm not going to be able to do this well starting out." He said, "I'm not going to judge you by the way they swim. I'll judge your progress." That was what he did, and I made a higher grade than

4

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A some of them who came in swimming. He had the right attitude for me. When he saw that I had some struggles at the very beginning, he put one of the lifeguards with me to work on my skills to get them up. Once I understood what the stroke was supposed to do, then I got it. I think I had been taught such backward ways, in a ways, such backward ways of learning. Sorry, but that was the way it was for my teachers. That I had had some screwed up styles taught to me, until I had to unlearn them at LSU and . . . I used to have to figure things out for myself, it seemed like, from the other teachers. So once I got it, I had it. Anything that, once you helped me understand what it is I'm doing here, then I could do it. In every situation where I had somebody work with me, then I got it. Not one math teacher, not one accounting teacher, not one physics teacher was that way. So those were the classes that killed me. Those were the only ones I couldn't pass. Because there was something in the concept that I never got. There was economics, everything that had numbers. Economics was a nightmare for me, too. I never understood the first thing. I didn't know what he was talking about. All of those professors seemed to not care, but it could have also been that I never connected with them, that I never went to them and said I didn't know or didn't understand. My understanding of it was so far away I didn't even know what to ask them. Only thing I could have gone to them and said, "I am totally lost. I haven't the faintest idea what you are talking about." But I decided that my education there may not have come at the academic level that I might have liked or my parents might have liked, but the education was no less invaluable. Invaluable to me. I admired those students, particularly those black students, who came in and just went right through with high grades and everything. [131] But they came out of good schools in Baton Rouge, for one thing, you know. I wasn't a dumb student, so I certainly can't say that it was because . . . you know that I'm excusing why they . . . but the schools in Baton Rouge were better. I mean, there were some really good schools because when we used to have to go to state competitions and things like that and compete with some of these Baton Rouge schools, we never beat them out. We had a couple of genius students at our school, and those are the only students that ever beat anybody out in competition at the other schools, but they were just geniuses. So I knew that there were some inadequacies in the schools that I went to. So many of these students, in fact, all of the black students who came the first year were, were the tops in their class, including me, but I was tops in the class of a school that was somewhat deprived. So I think I did well for what I came from, although I blamed myself at many points. I felt that maybe I wasn't working hard enough, didn't have good study habits, and that may have been true, too. I had some poor study habits at times. In a way, I thought that some of my poor study habits was because I didn't have a social life. I had so much time on my hands. I really had time to study. I just didn't feel like studying because something else was flat there. I started to miss a full social life. I was deprived of black students for the benefits I thought I got from associating with the white students to get the future that I thought I wanted. Because they it was limited where I went with them in terms of, I don't know, it just seemed to be some functions I was left

5

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A out of. Like I was never invited to a fraternity party, and that's what they had on weekends. You didn't have to be in a fraternity to go, but certainly no one was going to take me there because the sororities and fraternities were not going to accept me there at all. I would have been thrown out on my face, in the mud, probably. I mean, it was that serious. So, there were a lot of things like that I didn't get to go. When I went places with my friends, we went to a play at LSU, to a movie, to the game room, to bowling allies in town, to each other's dorms, or somebody's apartment. I could go to foreign students' parties. I became friends with a lot of foreign students, and I went to their parties in their apartments and stuff. I got to do that, but . . . DEAN: [158] Did you date at all? CRUMP: I had one date my first semester and one date my second. One date my first year and one date my second year. It wasn't until the summer of my third year that I started to date. DEAN: Who did you date those first two dates? CRUMP: There was, the first two, the first two dates were with the same guy, a friend of mine, my cousin's wife introduced me to him because he lived next door to her and he went to school at Southern. Bill Heidel. DEAN: So it was not an LSU student? CRUMP: No. He had his own car, a '65 Mustang, which was cool. That was the car to have. He was his mother's only son, and his mother was very, very snobbish about her son. DEAN: Did she approve of you? CRUMP: No. "I'm sorry, Bill's asleep." "That's okay, Mama I'll take it." Gee! DEAN: What didn't she approve of in you? CRUMP: I don't know, anybody with her son, probably. DEAN: I see. But later on, you did begin to date? CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: LSU students? Were they or no? CRUMP: No, he was from Southern, too. DEAN: He was from Southern.

6

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A CRUMP: I didn't date an LSU student . . . well, after that . . . after that guy, I dated an LSU student. Ralph Tyson, who is now a judge. We dated for the duration of the time I was there. DEAN: Were there campus-wide dances that you went to or anything like that? CRUMP: Yes, there were, sure did. People would ask me to dance, whites, foreign students. Jambalaya Jamboree. Especially in the late sixties, it was popular to dance with a black student then. It was just definitely popular because chances are she could dance. And I could. That got to be popular and so, yes, at big party functions and . . . just not fraternity and sorority, forget it. DEAN: They didn't start the black fraternities and sororities until after you had left, is that right? CRUMP: Right. It was in seventy-two, three, or four, somewhere in there. But I wouldn't have joined anyway. I had a friend, Sing Lee, Chinese, who was raised by southern whites, and he had a southern accent. I used to say, "Sing, I just can't get over your accent!" He could not understand what was funny about his accent. I said, "Surely, Sing, you have got to realize how funny it is for me to look at your Chinese face and hear this southern accent coming out of it!" He, he didn't think it was so funny! [194] And then I had a friend who, who tried to . . . my friend from New Orleans, Janel, told me of a guy who had been black-balled from a fraternity. I said, "What's that?" She said, "You don't know what a black-ball is?" I said, "No." And I thought, "Oh, oh, I guess I'm getting ready to feel stupid here, something I'm supposed to know that I don't know." I said, "No, I don't." Se said, "They've kicked him out of the fraternity." I says, "Why?" She said, "Pshhh"--That was Janel, she was always, "Come on." I said, "I don't know, Janel." She says, "Maxine, isn't it obvious?" I said, "No, it isn't, Janel." She says, "It's because he associates with me, and I'm your friend." I was stopped in my track. It was like you know this music they use on tv when the point is made, it's like, you know, this boom. Loud music in my head, it was like, "What?" My world blanked out for a minute, there I just . . . my stomach turned, that was just . . . the most devastating experience for me. I was angry. I was everything. What were these people doing? Who were they to do that? I became angry, I mean, I wanted to do something. I really wanted to do something then. You know, and Janel, "Oh come on. Don't worry about it. ?ho needs those people?" It was like, "This is bigger than that, Janel. This is bigger than that." "Pshhh, why worry about it?" She could say that. Then I met Chris. What was Chris' last name? Marcuson, Chris Marcuson, from Slidell, who was also considered a misfit by the university. She only dated Latin guys. She used to ask me why was I so angry because by then I was angry about all of that, and I kept it inside because none of my white friends would let me talk about it. They were all, "Eh." You know they want just enjoy being with us, do what we do. We'll take care of you type thing. Don't worry about all of that stuff. So no one would let me talk about being black, and that just got to be something inside of me that was building up. I was very angry by then. I had flunked out twice. My self-esteem had been lowered or at least threatened by

7

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A then, and there were a lot of things that happened to me that I had no outlet for, no explanation for. Nothing had happened to me directly. It's like being anemic, you're not sick enough to be in bed, and no one can see you're sick walking around, and yet you're sick, very very sick. That's the way I was, I was walking around anemic. I was in trouble. I was hurting. I had no one. No one understood. No one knew. I had no real peer group. I didn't really belong anywhere. I had priced myself out of the market in every way. And . . . DEAN:[230] You didn't have a group of black friends to share this with? CRUMP: Oh, no, they were, you know, they, what could I share with them? I would have had to limit what I tell them because, you know, I still had white friends, and they didn't think much of that. Yolanda was okay with it, but it was still, I would, I could tell her some, but I really had no one that I could share the full experience with. Priests, nuns. I never went to Michael Cody. I probably could have shared the full experience with him. But for some reason, he seemed to be dealing with bigger things than what I could go to him with. So that just didn't seem to fit. The nuns, I thought, "What do they know?" "What do they know? Their clothes cover their whole lives." So I just didn't have anyone. I kept it inside and I lashed out in ways that would make . . . white girls had this way of being able to giggle about anything. They learned a one emotion to everything, up, upbeat and above everything, nothing touched them until they cried about something that seemed irrelevant to me. When they said they were angry, it didn't look like anger to me. They would go "Eh, this makes me so mad." I'm thinking, "You're angry? You should see me when I'm angry." I never saw real expression. They didn't seem to have real deep feelings, and I started to get a little tired of this superficial way of relating. So I had a lot of problems within myself that didn't show on the outside to anyone that I could understand except the girls who would go, "Ahh, Maxine, why does that make you angry? Come on!" So it was like, "You don't understand." That part of the experience was tough. So, I started to become unhappy and just wish that college would just be over. When I had an opportunity to get out, I was ready to go. I couldn't have taken another semester. DEAN:[258] So you didn't graduate? CRUMP: No. DEAN: Didn't go back ever and finish it? CRUMP: No. For a long time, I couldn't go back. It was too sore. I was too sore inside. I needed to heal. Then it was like, "Go back for what? I'm in a whole new career now." By then I was in radio. I knew secretarial wasn't what I wanted, but I didn't know anything else there that I wanted. It never came a time when I could look back at LSU and say, "What curriculum do I really want?" It was like, "None!" So, when I got in broadcasting. Probably if had it been available then, I still wouldn't have taken it because I didn't think it was easy. The kids at school used to say, "You should take journalism. It's easy." I used to think, "Writing. I can't write. I can't think, let alone write. You've got to think to write."

8

Crump, Maxine - Tape 205, Side A I was glad to get out into the boring plants. Then, I couldn't take that because I realized this is not for me. The first three years in that company, I was happy because it was a brand new company going on line so I got the . . . DEAN: What company was this? CRUMP:[272] Ciba-Geigy. A European based company. They had a lot of exciting things to it, and I got to use my skills there because it was brand new. I walked into an office with a desk and file cabinets and not the first paper. I had to put everything together. That was fun. Not very many college students get that opportunity. You go in there, and you take what they already have set up. I had a young boss, who was thirtyfour years old, and he was open to me bringing in my new ideas and doing them. So I had quite a privilege there. But after three years, that was not my career. Everywhere I went, having been to LSU meant something, and that was good. It was worth having gone. It has never not been worth it for me. I wouldn't have made another decision. I never regretted going to LSU. In fact, I always have been very happy about having gone there. It had a lot of happy moments for me and a lot of very tough moments. But I attribute it to a lot of my ability to think and move through society as it is, on its terms. DEAN: Well, that sounds to me like a closure point. CRUMP: [291] Okay. [End Tape 205, Side A. End Session II.]

9</transcript>
  </extension>
</mods>
