<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 31</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/587</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>587</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/587/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 31","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WE S T E It N JOUR N A L,\n223\nMr. Drake, a resolution was adopted, expressing the thanks by singular good  fortune, the weather e,\n,1 the Society to the late corps of officers, for the able and\nfaithful discharge ol their duties. The members appointed\nfor regular exercises being absent, Mr. Forbes read an interesting voluntary on tho Indian Mounds in the vicinity of\nVatehcz. The Secretary read a letter from the Hon. Peter\n0 Thachcr, of Boston, accepting his election as honorary\nmember of tho Lyceum.\nThe resolutions to amend the constitution were then taken\nup, and, after much discussion, several important alterations\nwere effected.\nDrs. Cartwright, Blocksom, and Crocheron were elected\nregular members of tho Lyceum.\nThe following appointments were then made for the first\nWednesday in July:\nRev. 13. M. Drake, Lecturer.\nDrs. Monette and Cartwright, Essayists.\nOn motion, the Society adjourned, to meet June (3th in Natchez, at Mr. Dubuisson's office, at the hour of 4 P. M.\nS. C. MERWIN, Secretary.\nEXPEDITION TO THE NORTH CAPE.\n1'rofessor Parrot, well known for his travels to the Caspi\nan Sea nnd Caucasus, and  more  recently for his ascent of\nMount Ararat, made a journey, in the course of last summer,\nto North Cape, at the expense of tho University of Dorpat,\nfor the purpose of making astronomical and niagnetical observations, and of noting the oscillations of the pendulum at\nthe most northern point of the European continent.    Ho left\nllorpat on the tenth of July, and, travelling through Russian\nFinland by Wyborg, Kuopioand Uleaborg, reached Tornea\non the twenty-third.    In that remote little town, at the head\nof the Gulf of Bothnia, ho was surprised to find a comforta\nhie inn, and markets well supplied  with the produce of the\nsouth.    He proceeded on his route by an interesting navigation of three hundred and eighty miles up the rivers Tornea\nand MuontO, sometimes between hills  well-peopled and eul-\nlivated, but more frequently through thick woods.    The rivers, in some places, opened into lakes; in others, they fell in\nbold cascades.    At'length, he reached the sources ofthe Mil-\nonio, about one thousand four hundred feet above the sea, am\nclose to tho borders of the three kingdoms, Sweden, Norway\nand Russia.    Leaving his boat on  tho shores of tho  lake\nand placing his instruments and baggage on the shoulders of\n'iglit sturdy   Philanders,  M.  Parrot  crossed, on   foot,  the\nScandinavian ridge, through the most diversified scenery imaginable; patches of snow lying in  tho clefts of tho rocks,\nwhile at their feet was a most luxuriant herbage, with berries of many kinds, and the full bloom of a short, but vigorous summer.    The little   lakes and  cascades wero without\nnumber.    He had not advanced far through this wild scenery, before  he descried the  waters of Lyngenford, an inlet\nwhich runs a long way into tho land.    On it he embarked\nia a small boat, manned by Finlanders, to make a voyage of\nnearly two hundred miles to North Cape, which ho doubled\non the twenty-fiftli of August, in the face of contrary winds;\nbis little boat looking like a nutshell, ns he expresses il, beneath thai bold promontory.    On his arrival at North Cape,\ndearrd up, and his\nscientific observations were continued for twelve days, and\ncompleted under the most favorable circumstances. He had\nno sooner commenced his preparations to return, than winter\nset in with a violent gale, which confined him for ten days to\none of the small inlets on the coast. Ho subsequently made\nhis wny over land, partly on foot, partly in sledges, over the\nsnow anel ice of the rivers, lo Tornea, whence he returned\nto Dorpat in December, with, it may be presumed, a rich\nharvest of philosophical materials.\nI'rom Blltlman'l Jonrnicl-\nCaoutchouc.\u2014Much attention has been bestowed upon\nthis article, with n view ol discovering some solvent or mode\nof reducing it to a consistence capable of receiving any desirable form, or of being applied lo the surface of cloth in\nthe form of varnish, in order to render it water proof; but\nbelieving that no method has yet been made public by which\nit could be used with economy and facility, I am induced to\noffer the following, with the hope that it will be found both\nuseful anel interesting.\nI wish to premise, that all hitherto known solvents of ea-\ntchouc arc liable to objections. In a trial which I once\nmade, I found that oil of turpentine dissolved rate caoutchouc readily; and on having been spread on calico and exposed lo tho atmosphere, it remained glutinous at the end of a\nyear.\nAbout two years ago, I was induced to perform some experiments with caoutchouc, and I accidentally ascertained,\nthat if it he previously cut lino and immersed in common\nsulphate of ether or a solution of (some alkali 1 I used) carbonate of soda, two ounces lo a pint of water, for a week, and\nthen put into good new oil of turpentine, it dissolved with Iii\ncility; and when spread on cloth and exposed to a dry atmosphere, it speedily dries and assumes its original properties,\nusually in twenty-four hours.\nCalico, linen, or articles of clothing, may receive a coating with ihis solution, sufficient to render them waterproof\nwithout materially altering their general appearance or injuring their pliability.\nWhen less elastieity and more body is required, I hazard\na conjecture, that this solution may economically bo diluted\nor mixed with asphaltum, Venice turpentine, or some other\narticles soluble in oil of turpentine.\nAhza Andrews, M.  D.\nMeriden, Conn., Nov. 29, 1837.\nThe July Meeting of the Lyceum. The monthly\nmeeting for July will be held in the Methodist Church in the\ncity of Natchez, on the evening of tho Fourth of July-\u2014the\necturor being Rev. B. M. Drake, and tho essayists Doctors\nCartwright and Monette.\nThere could bo no time more suitable for the meeting of\nthe Lyceum than tho eve of our National birth-day.\nHeat of the Weather.    The best thermometers in\nNatchez, for a week past, have attained 93\u00b0 in tho shade,\nbstractcd from tho influence of tho sun's rays or tho reflee-\ntion from surfaces that have come in contact with sunshine\n\"\u25a0-\nAM,e\n.'- f '\nm&gt;\nA\n!!'!\nf\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"588.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"587","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1819678","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
