<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/479</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>479</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/479/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"100\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\nz \u2022\u25a0 ft '3\nit* nit \u25a0.''!\u25a0'\nI\nthem , tdding, that the only fault she' could find u iih the die-\n\u2022ionary was, that as soon as she became interested in one sub\nject, it went to another! Of two sisters in high life, whose\nfather had recently gone to Europe, it is related, that on be\ninn- asked to what part of Europe their father had gone, one\nreplied, to France ; the other immediately corrected her, by\nsaying, that he had gone to Paris, and not to France. Many\ninstances of a similar kind might be stated, showing the\nmortifying effects of a defective female education. What\ncheek eloes not mantle with shame at the bare recital of such\nhumiliating exposures of female ignorance ! What parent,\nof delicate sensibilities, would not be overwhelmed with con\nfusion, if a daughter should so dishonor her sex! What\nbrother, of proper feelings, could endure the mortification, if\na sister should so offend the ears of a refined and intelligent\ncompany ? The experience of such mortification would pro\nbably be so potent anargument, as to dispel from the mind of\nhim who suffered it, the last, lingering doubt, as to the importance of female education ; and would secure us an effectual ally in the cause we advocate. (\nThe cultivation of the female mind, greatly increases the\ninfluence of the female character in society. To this influence we owe all the delicate refinements, and chastened sympathies of social life. Whenever the female sex is degraded,\nnnd their influence destroyed, the male sex becomes so in n\ncorresponding proportion.    Cast your eye over the various\nbeing within themselves, they would no longer be dependent\nfor enjoyment, upon persons or circumstances. Unless jur.\nrounded by external sources of pleasure, uneducated females\nare apt to experience great uneasiness and misery. They arc\nsensible of a vacancy which they cannot fill up, except with\nsighs and fruitless complaints. For there are times to such\nwhen even novels satiate and cloy the appetite, and when\nmusic has lost its charms. Indeed, even gaiety and fashion\nthemselves, will at times lose their power lo captivate and\nplease. An \" empty void,\" called the ennui, is experienced\nand the sufferer can find no adequate relief, not even in the\nsympathies of kindred spirits.\nEven the external sources of enjoyment on which uneducated females are so dependent, are not always adequate to\nthe gratification of their desires, neither are they of such a\ncharacter as to improve the mind or mend the heart. The\nscandal of the female sex has been the theme of dramatist!\nanil poets, held up to ridicule by the satirist, and severely\nreproved by the moralist. But who nre they that, for the\nmost part, are given to this vice ? Are they not those whose\nmental cultivation is inadequate to a higher and moie commendable grade of conversation ? Elevate the standard of\nfemale education; kindle within their bosoms a zeal for knowledge and literary pursuits; let them taste the cup of intellectual enjoyment, and you do more to reform the cryino- vices\nof the sex, than all the lessons of the moralist, or the cen\ncommunities, and nations of the earth, for a confirmation of sures of the satirist, have hitherto effected,\nthis statement.    What is the state of society where to be a|    Old age, the haggard ghost that haunts the gay, the vain,\nthe giddy girl of uncultivated intellect,  is honored, admired\nwoman, is to be a slave, bound to the ignoble task of minis\ntering to the gratification of proud, domineering man 1 Such\nis the nature of the social system, that where it is legitimately acted out, the gentle and imperceptible influence of the\none sex, is found to soften down the asperities, and rectify the\nnatural uncouthness of the other. Her smile relaxes his\nrigid countenance, and expands his knitted brows. The music\nof her voice subdues his vociferous tones. And the mildness of her demeanor, tames the wild restlessness of his nature. Such is the legitimate influence of the female character in society. And in order to sustain this influence, and\nmake it effectual, it must be guided and controlled by a cultivated intellect. Knowledge is power; and although it is\ntrue, that woman really governs, while she seems to obey,\nyet her authority is in proportion to her intelligence and refinement.\nThe influence of female education is felt in elevating the\nstandard of mental cultivation in the opposite sex. It appeals\neffectually to the pride of men, even when it fails to awaken\na more commendable motive. If they would appear to advantage in the society of intelligent and well educated ladies,\nthey feel that they must increase their own knowledge, and\ncultivate their own minds. Vanity is a powerful stimulant\nin any cause. And the one sex are perhaps not more free\nfrom its influence than the other, although it may operate\nin a different manner upon each.\nSuch an education as we are contending for, would afford\nto females abundant employment and amusement for nil their\nand revered, when adorned with knowledge and education.\nOld age, the dread of youthful vanity and ignorance, the\nbane of pleasures that live upon flattery and beauty; old\nage, when able to instruct with wisdom, has thrown around\nit, a charm and an attraction which more than compensate\nfor the loss of youth and beauty. For what is beauty? Il\nis a fading flower thnt blooms upon tho cheek of youth. It\nis a fruitless blossom, that withers at ihe touch of time, and\noften instills poison in the bosom which it decks. What are\nthe pleasures of beauty ? They are the fragrance of the\nflower, which it sends forth only while it lives. But what\nis a good education ? It is a fountain of pleasure, sending\nforth its perennial streams to irrigate and beautify sociely. It\nis a jewel which is polished, not obscured, by the hand of\ntime. Youth must grow old, beauty will fade, flattery will\n:ease, or become insipid, even riches may take to themselves\nwings and fly away, but a good education remains, and improves by that which destroys more ephemeral attractions.\nIn this connection it may be observed, that education may\nbe called upon, in the providence of God, to subserve a more\nimportant and substantial purpose, than mere gratification or\npleasure. We have just said that riches may take to themselves wings and disappear. This reverse is often realized.\nThose who, in the midst of affluence, have studied accomplishments, merely with the view of becoming more attractive, and of ministering pleasure to the circle in which they\nmoved, have, in tho reverses of fortune, been compelled to\nleisure hours.    Tiny would have access to sources of plea-j resort to those accomplishments for the means of subsistence,\nsnre from which others are debarred.   And these resources] If accomplishments may be thus relied on, how much more","fullrs":{},"find":"480.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"479","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1915889","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.83 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
