<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/510</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>510</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/510/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":".SOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL\n149\nCartwright* ascribes il to \"a quantity of putrid bacon and\n[j, \"fan certain grocery on Main street; together with effluvia from the decomposition of vegetable matters, which may\nhave collected at the head of a water drain near the grocery.\nOthers believe a more rational mode of accounting for it may\nbe riven by supposing the general atmosphere was highly\nexcitable by the accumulation of miasm during the previous\nhot weather, and which became contaminated to a certain decree, so as to form malaria during the sultry weather of Sep.\nlember previous to the 15th ; end that in this state it formed a\nproper \"nidus'' for tho spread of infected air, oryellow fever\ninfection: thnt this infected air was carried out in large quantities in the goods, blankets, &amp;c, as well as new sources in\nibe beds and bedding, which were distributed in almost every\nhouse: that the crowded population, during hot, calm, sultry\nweather further contaminated the air, and the cases of yellow\nlever taken lo the town, also gave out their infectious exhalations, in n suitable atmosphere: ihat, under these circum-\n[Botes, the \"leaven\" introduced expedited the process, which\notherwise might have been indefinitely postponed.\nIt is unnecessary to inquire into all the contradictory statements which have been made in relation to the putrid bacon\nalleged. Wc doubt not they who gave the information contained in the Medical Recorder, were mistaken as to fads. It\nwas my fortune, previous to the outbreaking of the epidemic,\nto have occupied and slept in an office only three doors from\nsaid grocery, which I passed often every day, yet 1 never jier-\nceived any indication of putrid animal matters: and it is* probable that '.he bacon was not so completely putrid as to destroy\nits sale. But we havo shown that putrid animal matters do\nnol produce yellow fever, oven had they been present in this\ncase. It might moreover be shown, ihat among the first and\nmosttlialignant cases were these who lived most remote from\nthe grocery, or infected district; who had not visited the grocery at all; some of them being ladies: that there was really\nin this case no \"infected district,\" but the whole lown was one\nentire infected district. The ravine near the grocery is only\na gentle declivity, in which the rain water collects, and passes off down a deep ravine, or bayou as they are often called,\nwhich begins about one hundred and twenty yards north-east\nofthe grocery. Accumulations of any thing like city filth\nis absolutely out of the question.\nThe inquiry might bo mad\", why the yellow fever was not\ntarried from Natchez to Washington in 1823? To which 1\nWould reply, that in 1823 there More fewer porous woolen\ngoods taken out than in 1825; and in 1823 they were not so\nmuch crowded. Besides, in 1823, about the 10th of September, a very severe gale sprung up, and continued as an equi-\nnoctial, for two days, with rain, thunder, &amp;c.j but in 1825 the\nIrst two weeks of September were warm, calm, and sultry,\nThus in 1823 the miasm was wafted away, and the formation\nmalaria prevented; hence the infection of yellow fever did\nn(\" spread.\nAs to the cases which occurred at Haughton's, one mile\n'wm Natchez, we think it more plausible to suppose Ihe miasm which was gene-rated and accumulated in the bayoux,\nsettled along down them, until they reached the junction, near\n'Med. Record.,v.In.,p.846,4c.\nof\nHaughton's house: where also the banks overflow with the\nmiasm, or malaria, and thus produce yellow fever in those\nwho resided there, even if wo believe they had never been in\nNatchez. This we think more likely, than that the putrid\nanimal and vegetable matters, collected info the bayoux near\nNatchez, should remain there perfectly innoxious, until rains\nshould wash it down to Haughton's, where it would first commence to extricate the malaria or gas.\nDuring the years 1826, '7, and '8, there was no epidemic\nyellow fever in Natchez. However a few sporadic cases were\nseen each year, and especially in 1827, whin a number of\ncases were known to exist, so as lo cause alarm in some who\nfled to the country. There were about fifteen deaths in Nat-\nchezand vicinity, from yellow fever in 1827, seme of which\nwere traced to New Orleans for their origin,\nV. The Epidemic of 1829. This was the mildest\nepidemic of the kind which has prevailed in Natchez. The\nsummer of 1829 was generally healthy, until about the last\nof August and the first of September, when some cases in\nNatchez began to assume malignant symptoms. Several\ndeaths by malignant fever occurred in the city, as well as nt\nthe landing, between the first and sixth of September. On\nthe 8th of September, considerable alarm, prevailed in the\ncity, and tho Board of Health, after receiving the reports of\nthe medical faculty, advised the citizens to disperse. The\nreports of the physicians showed that there were then abcut\ntwenty cases of malignant fever under treatment in ihe upper\nilyund at the binding. The majority of the citizens immediately retired to the country and to Washington. The disease continued lo prevail moderately among those who re-\nmainid until about the last of October; a few cases occurred\nin those who returned into closed houses, as late ns the 8th\nanel 10th of November. During ibis epidemic, the whole\nnumber of deaths in the city, by yellow fever, did nol exceed\neighty-five or hint ty. The whole number of cases was probably near th rce hundred ; although many of them were mild,\nand assumed the character of high grades of bilious fever,\nattended with profuse discharge-of yellow bile.\nThe summer was rather wet, until the latter part of August: in September there was less rain ; the heat was often\noppressive, and the air sultry. No unusual form of disease\nprevailed in the country; but ibc health ef the country generally was as good as common at those seasons.\nThis year the yellow fever did not prevail much in New\nOrleans, until the 24lh of August; and it \/list appeared in\nMobile about the 20th of September.\nSo far as I have been able to learn, all seem at a loss to ascribe this epidemic to any adequate cause. .Some, however,\nseem inclined to ascribe it to the old, exploded one; viz: exhalations from earth recently exposed by digging down and\nleveling the uneven surface of the city. Doubtless the same\ngeneral causes which produced the other epidemics of Natchez in other years, produced this, independently of any local\naccumulations of filth or putrefiable matters: and of the removal of earth in leveling the streels of ihe city.\nFrom 1829 to 183V, there was no epidemic yellow fever in\nNatchez; although a'lew sporadic cases were seen occasionally under peculiar exciting causes; und frequent cases were\n: i;'.'\u00bb'\"V\nt ',,.'\u25a0 I;\n'. lr&gt;jk\n\u2022\u25a0\/'\u25a0\u25a0ii\nm\n' .!'\u25a0\u2022; i\n\u25a0Wm\ni ;.\u25a0 ), I\n... \u25a0 .ijr. i\n\"V  I I\nm\n :\t\n i\t","fullrs":{},"find":"511.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"510","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1624329","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
