<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/524</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>524</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/524/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":";'l*'.\"'}\nif'.'\nIf\u2022\n\u25a0 i \"ti\ntil \u25a0\nin '''\u25a0\u2022\n;|j .:\u2022     i\nk\n162\nSOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\ni' 'I m\n!\n-\n'\nIII\n\u25a0\u25a0\ni \/ \u2022\nwill not abandon the field, while every advantage is in ye\nfavor,\nTo prepare you for the noble work which lies before you,\nI have observed, that study, reading, and thought are necessa-\nry. And there is no study or reading, in my mind, more essential than that of history. True history is a record of past\nevents. It is the telescope by which we look back through\nthe long vista of time, and discover the different changes one\"\nepochs, which, in the story of the world, have marked its\nadvancement in civilization nnd refinement. It is a monument by which the memory of the dead is preserved 0\nhanded down to posterity. And the various epochs which\nhave been recorded in ihe history of the world, like antecedent and consequent, enable us to judge of the future by the\npast; and thus we are enabled to shun the shoals and quiell\nsands upon which the different nations and kingdoms of th\nworld have stranded. History is the ka.leie\/ascopc by which\nhuman nature is presented to us in all its varied forms and\ncombinations. We behold the mad ambition of kings ; th\navarice of the miser; the pride of the courtier j the passions\nof the sensualist; and the arrogance of the simple. It pre\nsents to us, in glowing colors, the judgment of the just; the\nlenity of the gentle ; and the forbearance and long suffering\nof the lender and merciful. And where is the person (man\nor woman) who has read, studied, and thought, en the subject\nof history, whose company will not be sought and admired,\nand whose conversation will not be interesting and instructing\nto every listener? And I care not whether his knowledge\nhas been obtained from the reading and studying of books, oi\nfrom observation, and the study of the broad volume of nature\u2014show me the person who has observed and noted carefully the things that have come within his or her observation;\nnnd I will show you a person who is no novice in die science\nof history, and one who will always be able to instruct and\ndelight,at least as far as matter is concerned ; nnd manner is\nseldom wanting in the fair. But we must think also, now,\nthere is no person but what finds it easy enough to read and\nstudy. But to think\u2014here is the difficulty\u2014people will not\nthink. If wc could only bring ourselves to think, then we\ncould accomplish almost any thing. It is an old saying,\nthat the learned think sometimes; the unlearned never. How\nfar this is true, I shall not undertake to say. But to become\na good historian, this faculty must be brought into requisition.\nThere is, perhaps, no study that improves the colloquial\npowers more than the study of history. And there is no faculty so fascinating an! enchanting as the faculty of conversing\nwell, especially when found in woman. There is a kind of\npoetry and charm in the soft and musical tones of a woman's\nvoice, by which man, spell-bound as it were, is led captive at\nher will. And were her knowledge equal to the gentleness\nand suavity of her manners, her power would be truly omnipotent. I would to God that she had this knowledge.\nThen there would be no moro libations to Bacchus, and no\nmore sacrificing to the infernal Gods; but a pure and holy\nincense would ascend from the altars of liberty, justice and\nhumanity, until our world should be freed from tho chains of\nignorance and superstition, and peace and good will to man\nreign from tho rising of the sun to the going down of the\nsame. But history is not the only study which shoal,! cl\nthe attention of the American fair. When time and oppon\nnity will permit, the mental and moral sciences, political ec\nomy, and even the ancient classics may be studied with r&gt;- t\nand advantage. These studies have a wonderful tendency\nstrengthen and invigorate the mind, and thus prepare you f\na wider and more extended sphere of influence.\nBut the fine arts come more immediately within von\nsphere. Hero a field is opened in which yoti may disnlsv\nall your talents and taslc, and occupy all your leisure time\n\u2014painting, drawing, music, instrumental and vocal,\u2014and I\nmay add horticulture as affording agreeable diversion amies-\nercisc for the body. These arc certainly valuable accomplish,\nments.\nBut, above all things, the study ofthe Bible is the not:\nuseful and instructing, ns it is the most correct &lt;md authentic\nhistory of man that ever was penned. The Bible is the\npolar star by which tho wandering pilgrim is guided safely\nto his father's house. But in all your reading and stud;,\nyon should so learn as to be able to impart your knowledge:\nand conversation is ihe only true medium of communication.\nWithout this, your knowledge is liko the miser's geld end\nsilver, locked up where it will rust and corrupt.\nNext to a well stored mind, on which, ns from a rich treasury, one can draw for all the weapons of conversation, is\nskill in using those weapons, or the mode of tempering\nthem. Demosthenes paid the great tribute of his-opinion to\naction,\u2014action, as the implement of oratory,\u2014by which he\nmeant gesture, tone, intonation, pronunciation, and nil tie\nconcomitants of a graceful deliver}'. There is not a man or\nwoman who cannot teach themselves the pronunciation ol\nllieir own tongue, and they may so learn it as lo pronounce\nit with elegance and ease. The French ladies have always\nbeen proverbial for llieir powers of conversation, and exhibit\nmore strongly the \"jeu d'esprit\" than any other people. Madam do Mairitenon, though embarrassed in circumstances;\nthough wanting many of the luxuries which graced the tables of her more wealthy neighbors, never failed to entertain her company well by the fascinating and interesting\nmanner of her conversation. The Athenian ladies were to\nwell versed in the arts that pertained to good speaking, that\neven the fisherwomen could detect ihe slightest error in pro\nnunciation or gesticulation. To make conversation good,\n'.he matter should not only be good, but the manner nnd action should be combined with it: the whole soul should be\nenlisted; the eyes, the countenance, and all, should Speak.\nThis is the electricity of conversation. \" As the spirit within plays upon the. lip, and runs rippling in all the currents\nof life, tho woman but of earth is exalted, in our eyes, lo ike\nspirit divine. Who has not even seen ugliness, when kindled up by conversation, made to blaze whh beauty? Bat\nwhen the eye of beauty brightens, and the lip quivers, anil\nthe cheek is suffused with a blush, whose heart docs not beat\nquicker, as ho feels the magic of the tongue? Then it\"\nthat conversation becomes, as it were, electric: it chases \u00abP\nthe sluggish currents of our blood, and links the spin!\nman with man.\"    Now what greater inducements can I now\nout to you in favor of female education, than have ahead)","fullrs":{},"find":"525.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"524","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1800573","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
