<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 44</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2268</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2268</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2268/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 44","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[44]\ndecide immediately on the adoption of some plan, for the construction of a m\ndirect aud rapid connection, than any now existing.\nAgain: of the progress and position of the Pacific States, the world, and it*\nhistory, does not afford a parallel. The discovery of the rich mines has enticed\naud congregated there thousands of people, of all nations, kindred and tonsuM\nreared and educated under various forms of government, many with unbr\u00ab]|J\npassions, unaccustomed to our institutions and laws, hard to govern in their n\u2122.\nsent position, which gives them the command of the commerce of the Pacific\nwith China, and with all Asia. Hence tbe more immediate the necessity of\nopening a great highway, facilitating trade, the interchange of commodities between tbe two oceans, and an immense population of consumers in the intermediate valley. This is not a new subject; it has been for a long time before the\npublic, discussed and commented upon in every quarter; but the positional\npresent assumed is different. We ask for these grunts to be made directly to\ncorporations, created and controlled within their proper sphere by state authority, involving no constitutional difficulties.\nTo illustrate : an eminent writer upon the subject of private corporations, remarks,\u2014only a few years since \" Professor Morse deemed the construction of\nan extensive electric telegraph impracticable, except by the general government,\nwho repelled him, as it had repelled De Witt Clinton, when he supposed the\nErie Canal could not be built without aid from the national treasury; hiid to\nthese refusals we owe the numerous telegraphs which are pervading our country,\naud the numerous canals and rail-roads with which the states have enriched their\nrespective sovereignties; improvements greatly mure extensive than the general\ngovernment could have accomplished, had it been ever mo willing. The United\nStates in their agencies seem naturally obdurate. In a degree proportioned to\ntheir unfitness, men in their aspirations naturally call upon some Hercules, instead of eliciting an energetic exercise of their own powers. But weevobe\nprinciples practically, long before we see them speculatively, or we should not\npersevere, as we do, in a reliance on the general government for what we term\ninternal improvements; and which, except for such reliance, would readily be\naccomplished to every profitable extent, by our states individually, or their people : a sufficient reason why our states increased so rapidly in power, after their\nseparation from Great Britain.\nPennsylvania and Michigan, which relied on state agency for the construction of\nrail-roads, became insolvent and unable to complete their undertakings; wMl\"\nthe states of New-York and Massachusetts, who constructed theirs by private\ncorporations, completed more rail-roads than the former states ever contemplated. Wise, therefore, is the policy which, by means of private incorporations,\nenables individuals to combine their resources, and thus to extend the sphere ol\npersonal efficiency, the great reservoir of all efliciency. .   ,\nIl is neither my province nor my pleasure to depreciate the claims ol r^a\nroutes, for a road through Arkansas, that may be, in the estimation of others*e*\"\ntitled to a priority of consideration by this Convention.    Yet, I trust to be excui\nfor asserting, in terms not to be misunderstood, that I shall here conscl\nand\ncommon country, by again reiterating, and pressing it upon the deliberate\nentioa^J\ndischarge what I conceive to be my duty to those 1 represent, to yi\njudg-\nit is ay\nment of the whole Convention, the pre-eminent claims which the route it ^ ^\npride and   pleasure to advocate (but only in general terms) possesses,   '\" . f\neasy and cheap construction of a main trunk road through the state, over a   '\"\ncompeting routes that may be advocated.    I state this, from some persona1\nledge of the country over which that road would pass, as well as from au i.^\nligation of the most material objections that have been heretofore raised a5jjL-\nits real merits, as compared with other routes spoken of.    It has the a TroWi\u00ab\nof being central; and will be of far more general benefit to the present ant       ^\npopulation of Arkansas, and to the country generally, than any other route   ^\nted.    Should it be thus appreciated  by this enlightened body, and TeoVte0^\u00bb\nrecommendation, as one of the links to connect the road terminating at 7ec0ll|d\nwith the Louisiana road in Texas, in its projected course to the Pacific, ' ^ ^\nnot fail to meet the approbation of a very   large majority of the people\nstate. .     gouth-\nI believe I hazard nothing in asserting, that in no other way can i\u00b0\u00b0","fullrs":{},"find":"2269.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2268","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"620238","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.59 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
