<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 21</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2218</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2218</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2218/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 21","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[21 ]\n__nV and Mowing up the waters of the White River, and crossing it at or near Bates-\n\u00b05 continue a north course, running through tbe fine agricultural and mineral region of\nW rib Arkansas and Southern Missouri. This will constitute the system of main trunk\n\u2122ctfl for the state. So soon as they are completed, branches will be run out at various\nUriiits tapping the different basins, and giving to each section of the state facilities of\nSheet 'rail-road communication with tbe Mississippi River.\nObjections have been urged against Helena as the eastern terminus, for the system for\nArkansas, because it does not communicate directly with the roads now in process of\nconstruction ]r(1ln Memphisto tbe south em Atlantic cities. This objection is found, on investigation, to be trivial in its character, for to all those wishing to communicate with\nMemphis they are offered an uninterrupted navigation, for first-class steamers, from Helena\nto Memphis, which can be run in five hours, making a difference of time between Little\nBock direct to Memphis, and by way of Helena and the river, of not more than three\nBy way of New-Orleans is the natural outlet for Arkansas products ; and when other\nthings are equal, her artificial lines of communication (as as her rivers do) ought to\npoint to New-Orleans. With her, Arkansas is allied by contiguity, association, and similarity of institutions, and nothing but the most perfect apathy on the part of New-Orleans\ncan \"dissever this unity of interest; but without New-Orleans will take hold and act\nliberally, the southern Atlantic cities will unite Arkansas with tbem by iron bonds, and\nthen hold her as in the hooks of steel. Memphis, Nashville, Charleston and Savannah:\nand last, though not least, Mobile, is beginning to bid for Arkansas trade, by proposing the\nconstruction of roads to cross the Mississippi at Memphis, and even 100 miles above these ;\nand if New-Orleans sleeps on a few years longer, she may awake, but it will be with a\nspasmodic effort, and she will quickly relapse again into the sleep of death, as in that time\nall the elements of her vitality will be taken from her by her more enterprising sisters,\nMobile, Savannah, and Charleston.\nShould it be found necessary at any future day to connect the Arksausas roads directly\nwith tbe roads east of tbe Mississippi, it can be done at much less expense by crossing the\nriver at Helena than at any other point, and connect with the New-Orleans and Nashville\nroad at Holly Springs, Helena being on nearly an air line from Little Rock to Holly\nSprings. The difficulties of crossing the bottom opposite Helena are less than atany other\npoint, in the knowledge of your committee.\nIn conclusion, your committee, feeling that all the statistical information necessary to\nstimulate the southern states to action, will go before the country in other reports upon\nroads,exciting now more attention if not of more ultimate utility, and through the address\nthat this Convention will send forth, will only in a few words urge the importance of\nprompt and efficient action upon the rail-road subject in all sections ofthe South.\nOur glorious confederacy has just passed through a critical period of her history.    But\nrecently die elements of discord were aroused and excited to a degree that made the\nheart ol the patriot to quail: but by the combined effort of the distinguished men of both\nties in Congress, oil was poured on tbe troubled waters, and peace and harmony were\nrestored to our threatened and distressed country.    But the struggle should learn us a\nsson, and prompt us to go to work, and render ourselves independent of tbe North, and\ntion\u00b0 US 3J Ciln We d\u00b0 tl\"3 B0 effectually as by opening all the artificial lines of communica-\nturi'        mav be necessary to develop our country.    On die heels of our roads manufache H^ e\"jerPr'ses wiH springup, and then we may proclaim our independence.    We will\naependenton the North for nothing; the North will be dependent on us for our cotton\nthe Nn\u00b0ai!' a'!d a3 we alwa&gt;'s t*6*1 freemen as freemen, we will treat our fellow-citizens of\nhave \u00b0      as. brothers ofthe same great confederacy ; they having no power over us, will\ni nnt0 *?\u00b0Uve to treat UB in any other way.    Then we can live together in peace, and\nexanml   ,  mt\"?strate tbe great problem of man's capacity for self-government, and let our\nthere 6        ? 'Cs \"J^uence on \u2122e rotten monarchical governments of the old world: and\nworld y t'ie mora' \u00b0f our course, an influence beneficial to the freedom of the\n411 of which is submitted.\nJohn Martin, Chairman.\n\"^essarvT^'lT- \u00b0 \u2014That tbe rail-road system we have proposed for Arkansas, is a\nfilicide t-1 1 1L1 tlle cllaiu \u00b0f the system for tbe South : and that from ihe direct as well\ni';!ri of ili'I b^efi's that the general government must derive by the construction of a\nA\u2014  ..    le main truriL-o   tint \\,a~ =;j :.. ...* ;-,il.. ,-..,.1\u2014l \\,\u201e .i.;- n \u201eti ;\u00bb .. i;lij.ral\ndotlr\u00bbtioii otT,U|trun!i3' tllat ber aid is especially invoked by this Convention, in a liberal\n'heir con \"t s'lo be granted directly to the companies that are or may be formed for\n\u25a0 and that her usual course of donating only the pnblic lands on the line\n4u&amp;ntitv \u00a3     '\" l\"18iristance to be deviated from, and the privilege granted of floating for","fullrs":{},"find":"2219.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2218","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"513717","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
