<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/503</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>503</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/503/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 17","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 UTH- W E S T E It N J 0 U R N A L.\n127\nFoe Hie Hcit.ih- Weclcni Journal\nLINES\nT\/aoslMcd from llic French of Vlrtoc lingo.\nThe Rose was once by Ihe Tomb addressed,\n\" Tell rne, gentle flower of love,\nThe fate of the dew that on thy breast\nFalls soft each eve from the sky above ? \"\nThe Rose lo the Tornb lluis made reply,\n\" Of those drops thai fall with Ihe evening shade,\nThe sweet and wondrous perfume is made,\nWhich I lling lo each passer by.\"\n\" Now tell me, in thy turn, I pray,\n0 solemn and shadowy Tomb,\nThe fate of the helpless sons of clay,\nThat crowd thy realm of gloom ? \"\nAnd Ihe Tomb's reply was given :\n\" Men's souls but enter my dnrk domain,\nThey rest nol there, tail go forth again,\nAmi are made Ihe bright spirits of heaven.\"\nErnest.\npriuinai., ok which the shove is a translation\nLa T'omhe dit a la Rose\u2014\n\" Des pleurs donl I'aube t'arrose,\ndue fais lu, fleur des amours 1 \"\nLa Roje dit a la Tombe\u2014\n\" due fais tu de ee qui tombe\nDans ton goutfre ouvert toujonrs?\"\nLa Rose dit:\u2014\" Tombeau sombre,\nDe ces pleurs je fais dans l'ombre\ntin parfum d'ambre cl de rniel.\"\nLa Tombe dit:\u2014\" Flour plaintive,\nDe chacpie ame qui m'arrive,\n.le fais un aage du ciel! \"\nJuin,lS37.\nPROFESSOR  MORSE'S ELECTRO-MAGNETIC\nTELEGRAPH.\nThe Morristown Jersey-man states that Professor Morse\naided by the ingenuity ol Mr, Alfred Vail, has succeeded\nin his important experiments to convey intelligence by elec\ntricity.\nThe Telegraph consists of four parts:\n1st. The Battery\u2014A Cruikshank's Galvanic Trough of\nsixty pairs of plate, seven by eigln and a half inches each.\n'il. The Portrulc\u2014An instrument which regulates the\nmotion of the rule. The rule answers to the slick of the\nprinters, and in it the type, representing the numbers to be\ntransmitted, are passed beneath the lever which closes nnd\nbreaks the circuit.\n3d, The Register\u2014An instrument which receives and re\neords the numbers sent by tho Portrulc from any distant sta\nlion.\n'lib- A Dictionary\u2014Containing a complete vocabulary of\n\"ll the words in the English language, regularly numbered.\nThe words of the sentenco \" Railroad cars just arrived,\n345 passengers.\" wero put into numbers from the dictionary;\nthe numbers were set up in the telegraphic type about as soon\n83 the same matter would have been in a printing office, ajid\npassed, complete by the Portrulc, in about half a minute, each\n\"roke ofthe Portrule, at one extremity, marking on the regis\nter at the other, a distance of two miles, instantaneously.\nThe spark at one end, and the stroke ofthe pencil at the other,\nwere simultaneous. \"On Wednesday evening,\" says the\neditor of the New York Observer, \" we saw the experiment\nperformed at the University, with ten miles of wire. It was\ncompletely successful.\" Whether it will prove equally successful for very great distances, is yet to be tried. The \"editor\nof the Observer says :\n\" This invention has two advantages over all other plans\nfor an electro-magnetic telegraph yet proposed. It uses but\none wire in conveying intelligence. It records, legibly, the\nintelligence conveyed. Both these advantages seem (o us\nimportant.\"\nArcs of Ellipses or Circles.\u2014Professor Muiler, of\nBerlin, has, in a late course of Lectures, offered a simple and\nmechanical explanation of the universal admiration bestowed\non these curves. The eye, he observes, is moved in its socket by six muscles, of which four are respectively employed\nto raise, depress, turn to the right and to the left. The other\ntwo have an action contrary to one another, and roll the eye.\non ils axis, or from the outside downward, anel inside upward.\nOn an object being presented to the eye for inspection, the first\nact is that of circumvision, or going round the boundary lines,\nso ns to bring consecutively every individual portion of tho\ncircumference upon the most delicate and sensitive portion of\nthe retina. Now, if figures bounded by straight lines, be\npresented for inspection, it is obvious that but two of these\nmuscles can be called into action, and it is equally obvious,\nthat in curves of a circle or ellipse, all must alternately be\nbrought into action. The effect then is, that if only one be\nemployed, as in rectilinear figures, those two have an undue\nshare of labor: and by repeating the experiment frequently,\nas wcelo in childhood, the notion of tedium is instilled, and\nwe form gradually a distaste for straight lines, and arc led to\nprefer those curves which supply a more general and equable\nshare of work to the muscles.\u2014New York Obs\nThe Great AuntinoN.\u2014Truly great in every sense of\nthe word! He has devoted the bost portion of his life upon\nthat herculean and magnificent work, \"The Birds of America!' which will be, whe-n finished, a proud and enduring\nmonument lo his fame; the almost discouraging circumstan-\nes under which he began it, his untiring industry and smell\nreward, present him to our claims under a peculiar aspect.\nSixteen years was the time proposed to complete it in, when\nthe first number was issued ; a period which, in itself, it would\nseem was alone enough to discourage both author and\npatron\u2014but with less than two hundred actual subscribers he\npersevered against every obstacle. Twelve years have\nalready elapsed since he commenced, and he has recently\nannounced that he confidently anticipates to finish the last\nnumber during the present year. What a vacuum it must\nleave when the noble and exalted labor of so many years is\nat an end ! But such a genius can never rest\u2014the spirit is\nalways struggling to tower\u2014to aspire beyond the every day\nrealities of life\u2014and it is well that it should so aspire\u2014it is\none of the sweetest passages in our existence\u2014it is ono ofthe","fullrs":{},"find":"504.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"503","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"2014148","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.92 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
