<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 28</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/584</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>584</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/584/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 28","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"mm\nI Mil\nfefi\njf;1;-i.\nifce\nf\nJB\n220\nSOUTH -AVE STERN   JOURNAL.\nh^i'l\n5 If\n.11 ':.\nthe learned who visit Egypt, and assist the inquiries of those\nwho have not that privilege They will be able to give olli-\ncial protection and aid where required, and at the same time\nlo prevent the destruction, of which the ignorance and the\ncupidity of the peasants and iho selfish vandalism of travellers have been too long the cause.\u2014London paper.\nFrom (.ockhart'fl l.if) of Scoit.\nTHE GREAT UNKNOWN REVEALED.\nFriday, twenty-third of February, 1828, was a memorable\nday in the life of Sir Walter Scott and in the annals of literature; from that day the secret of the authorship of the novels, which had partially disclosed itself on Constable's failure, became fully revealed lo the world. Sir Walter hat\nbeen requested by Mr. W. Murray, the manager of the Ed\ninbiirgh theatre, to preside on that day at the first festival ol\na charitable fund for theatrical artists in distress. He was\nsupported by Lord Fife, Lord Meadowbank, and many other\ndistinguished friends. One noble person having been prevented from attending, to whom the health of Sir Walter\nhad been assigned as a toast, Lord Meadowbank was suddenly asked to undertake the duty, and, remembering that this\nwas the first public dinner at which Sir Walter had appeared since his losses, took him aside to inquire whether ho\nwould consider it indelicate that allusion should bo made to\nthe parentage ofthe novels. Sir Walter, smiling, answered,\n\" Do just as you like, only don't say much about so old a\nstory.\" The speeches made on this occasion arc given from\nthe notes of a friend who was present, \"with greater accuracy,\" says Mr. Lockhart, \" than in the reports of the contemporary newspapers.\" We have not room for the whole, but\nwe give the most interesting passages. Lord Meadowbank,\nafter anticipating the enthusiasm with which the health oil\nSir Walter Scott was sure to bo received, and adverting to\nthe mystery in which any speaker must have veiled himself\nwho should, some time before', in proposing that health, have\nadvened in Sir Walter's presence to the then unacknowledged works, proceeded to observe that obscurity of allusion was\nnow no longer allowable. \" The clouds,\" he said, \" have\nbeen dispelled, the darkness visible has been cleared away,\nand tho Grcat Unknown, the minstrel of our native land, tho\nmighty magician who has rolled back the current of time\nand conjured up before ouv living senses the men and the\nmanners of days which havo long passed away, stands revealed to the eyes and the hearts of his affectionate and admiring countrymen.\" \u2022 \u2022\u2022\u00ab\u00ab\u2022 .. yye ou.c t0 |,jm) as\na people, a large and heavy debt of gratitude. Ho it is who\nhas opened to foreigners the grand and characteristic beauties\nof our country. It is to him we owe that our gallant ancestors and illustrious patriots, who fought and bled in order to\nobtain and secure that independence and that liberty we now\nenjoy, have obtained a fame no longer confined lo tho boundaries of a remote and comparatively obscure country it is\nhe who has called down upon their struggles for o-lory and\nfreedom the admiration of foreign lands. He it is who has\nconferred a new reputation on our national character, and bestowed on Scotland an imperishable name, were il only by\nher having given birth to himself. I propose tho health ol\nSir Walter Scott\"\nLong before Lord Meadowbank ceased speaking, the company had got upon chairs and tables, and the storm of an-\nplauso that ensued was deafening. When they recovered\nfrom the first fever of their raptures, Sir Walter spoke as\nfollows:\n\"I certainly did not think, in coming here to-day, that I\nshould have the task of acknowledging, before three hundred\ngentlemen, a secret which, considering that it was communicated to more than twenty people, has been remarkably well\nkept. I am now at the bat of my country, and may bo understood lo be on trial before Lord Meadowbank as an offender; and so quietly did all who were 'airt' and 'pain' conduct themselves, that I am sure that were the panel now lo\nstand on his defence, every impartial jury would bring in a\nverdict of ' Not proven.' I am willing, however, to plead\n'guilty;\" nor shall I detain the court by a long explanation\nwhy my confession has been so long deferred. Perhaps caprice might have a considerable share in the matter. I have\nnow to say, however, that the merits of these works, if they\nhad any, and their faults, are all entirely imputable to myself, Like another Scottish criminal of more consequence,\none Macbeth,\n\" ' I am afraid to think- what I have done;\n' Look on't again I dare not,'\nI have thus far unbosomed myself, anel I know that my confession will be reported to the public. I mean then seriously\nto state, that when I say 1 am the author, I mean ihe total\nand undivided author. With tho exception of quotations,\nthere is not a single word that was not derived from myself\nor suggested in iho course of my reading, The wand is\nnow broken, nnd the book buried. You will allow me fur-\nthor to say wilh Prospero, 'It is your breath ihat has filled\nmy sails;' anel to crave ono single toast in the capacity of tho\nauthor of those novels. I beg leave to propose the health ol\nmy friend Bailie Nicol Jarvie, and I am sure that when the\nauthor of Wavcrlcy anel Rob Hoy drinks to Nicol Jarvie, it\nwill be received with the just applause to which that gentleman has always been accustomed\u2014nny, that you will take\neuro that on the present occasion it shall be pro-di-gi-OUSl\"\n( Long and vehement applause.)\n\" Mr. Mackay.\u2014My conscience! My worthy father, the\ndeacon, could never have believed that his son would have\nsic a compliment paid to him by the Great Unknown !\nThe sensation produced by this scene, was, in newspaper\nphrase, unprecedented at the theatre. A few nights after\nwards the farce of High Life below Stairs was performed,\nin which one ofthe servants asking, \"Who wrote Shakspeare J \" is answered by another, \"Ben Jonson.\" Mi'- \"\nMurray, who played in the piece, diverted the audience by\nrejoining, \" No, it is Sir Walter Scott\u2014ho confessed it at a\npublic meeting the oilier day.\"\nDr. Ciiannino.\u2014The last number of Eraser's Magazine,\na work which is regarded as high critical authority in England, contains a highly complimentary notice of the writings of Dr. Channing. The writer commences with thin\nbold and candid assertion:\u2014\"Channing is, unquestionably,\nthe finest writer of the age.    His language is simple, ner-","fullrs":{},"find":"585.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"584","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1738952","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
