<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/532</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>532</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/532/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:05">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"i 4\nno\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\n.,\"U\n.\u00ab \u25a0.\n\"III'-,\nM\n1$\n;i|\nFor the South-Wenteni Joiiriw\nDESCRIPTION\n\u201e Tim MKTMobuT antcorcnv CHORCH, ON THI CORNER or iwhiian\nAND CAI10NDEI.ET UTIIEETK, IN NEW ORLEANS.\nThis church, from ils style nnd classic effect, has many\nclaims to the notice .of every person of taste in the arts of\ndesign. The dimensions of this edifice on the ground plan\nnre sixty-six feet two inches, by eighty-six feet eight inches.\nThe elevation is composed of a basement twelve feet in height,\nupon which rests the superincumbent structure, thirty-eight\nfeet high, to thctop of the entablature, and forty-seven to the\nnpex of the pediment of the Doric order, and surmounted by\nn steeple, in the Egyptian style of architecture, of one hundred feet in height, making the extreme height from the\nground to the top of the steeple one hundred feet.\nThe auditory is reached by two flights of granite steps in\nfront, one ascending from each angle of the basement, and\nparallel to the front, landing on a platform six feet wide and\nthirty-four feet long, from which the pronaos, or portico, is\nentered by an elevation of one step, and from thence on to\nthe floor of the auditory by the ascent of three steps.\nThe facade is composed of two columns and four antcr, arranged in ihe manner called anlis, after the first or most simple order of Greek temples. The portico is recessed within\nthe front, and is fifteen feet deep by thirty-four long, embracing in extent two columns and throe intercoluminations.\nThe columns are five feet in diameter, and twenty-seven\nfeet high. The antic are attached lo the wall of the front,\nwhich, being in advance of the inner wall of the portico,\nforms a space on each side of the portico, in which are the\nstairs leading lo the galleries.\nTho entablature is ten feet four inches high, and runs entirely around the building. The details of the order are\nfrom that sublime and unsurpassed example of the Athenians, the Parthenon. The angles of the pediment are furnished with acroterial ornaments of beautiful design. The\ncrown mouldings of the pediments return a few inches upon\nthe flanks, and terminate against lion heads, in imitation of\nthat peculiar feature in all Greek edifices, where there was a\npitched roof, the legitimate purpose of which was to carry\nthrough these heads tho waters from the roof of the temple.\nThe steeple, being in the Egyptian style, is perhaps, on\nthat account, one of the most novel and original architectural compositions in the union. It is composed of two square\ntapering columnal sections, resting upon a double plinth, and\nsupporting an octangular obelisk. There are two columns\non each front of the sections, recessed within the face\nand between the solid, square-tapering angles. The first\nsection is in proportion to the. pedestal or plinth, which\nmakes its columns short and heavy in appearance. Tin re\nbeing no cornice to this section, gives it the appearance of a\nsolid block with sunk pannels in each face containing columns, which, though singular, is pleasing and in good keeping with the general style. The next section is much more\nslender and light in effect, and is crowned with a cornice ornamented with winged globes representing time. The columns arc richly ornamented, and the angles of the sections\nfinished with arrowhead carved beads\u2014and likewise the\nangles of the obelisk, which is terminated by a curved finil\nthrough which passes the electric, rod, layering quickly to a\npoint of silver, without the usual appendages of a gilt (,,]]\nand vane. The basement of tho edifice is in imitation ol\ndark granite, and all above of white marble. There is\nsolemn and chastened grandeur of effect in this buihli,,,,\nthat reveals its purpose instinctively, and no other idea ran\nbe associated with it, than that it is a temple dedicated to the\nworship of Clod.\nA quietness and repose in its appearance, and a harmony\nin all its parts, irresistibly attract attention, while every detail\nbreathes the same bold and noble spirit of case and superior\ngrandeur. There is no intricacy, minuteness, nor doubt\nvisible at first sight, but every part strikes the beholder with\nclearness and power. It is the only building of the Doric\norder in this country.\nThe basement story contains a spacious lecture room, and\nfour large rooms for schools, &amp;c. The auditory contain!\nono hundred and thirty-two slips, and galleries on time\nsides, making it capable of seating from twelve to fifiern\nhundred persons. The pulpit is simple in form and orni\nment, but rich in imitation of marble and sold. Upon each\nangle is a splendid candelabra of marble which lights it.\nThe whole stands within a recess, which is spanned by a\nbold elliptical arch, supported by antic, and al! in imitationof\njasper. The coiling is divided into twelve small squarepan-\nncls, and one largo ono in tho centre, which is ornamented\nby a magnificent centre-piece. The whole interior is lighted\nby gas, distributed by thirty six burners, arranged'around\nIhe side walls, and breastwork of the galleries.\nThe designs were, furnished, and tho erection of the build'\ning superintended, by those accomplished architects, the\nMessrs. Dnkins.\nWe have lately heard of a new species of fly called the\n\"Mississippi Guards,\" which are said to be quite common\nin the eastern part of this state. This fly is very useful in\ndestroying the large horse-fly, which is so destructive to horsei\nand oilier cattle in the back part of the state. The guards\nire said to be furnished with u pair of scissors with Avbica\nthey clip the wings of the horse-fly and thus prevent them\nfrom pursuing their prey.\nIf any of our friends who are acquainted with entomology\nwill give us a further description ofthis fly, wo will be much\nobliged lo them.\nWc have received the papers sent by Professor Carpenter.\nrefercd to in his letter published in another pagcof the Journal\ncontaining his Lectures on \" Fossil Remains,\" read before\nthe Lyceum of Natural History and Senior Class of Low''\nma College.\nWc have read the Lectures over and founil them very interesting, and should bo glad lo publish them in full i\" llw\nJournal for the benefit of our readers, but have only rootttt\"\nan extract in the present number.\nWe hope the Professor's valuable discoveries will be the\nmeans of arousing public attention to these instructings\"\njeets.    We have long been convinced that if the nuincro\"'","fullrs":{},"find":"533.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"532","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1757662","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
