<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/598</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>598</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/598/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:56">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\nSOUTH-WESTERN    JOURNAL-\n233\nADDRESS\nOf James Shannon, President of the (.'ollepe of Louisiana, to the Qraduatlng\nClass, delivered on the 1,1th of June, 18.18.\nVotjNci Gentlemen :\nStanding, as you do this day, but one remove from the high\nhonor of being4ho first-born of your Alma Mater, to you the\npresent must be an occasion of deep interest. Fond memo-\nrv and joyous anticipation are no doubt actively engaged,\nenriching with their choicest treasures this brief, but consecrated hour. Gladly could I roam with you through those\nflowery meads, redolent wilh the fragrance of the past, or\nrichly enameled with enlivening anticipations ofthe future.\nSuch a ramble might, on this occasion, be most agreeable\nand interesting to you, to me, and to all who nre present.\nSlill, however, employment of a different kind may be more\nprofitable. And, as your education, during the period of\nyour connexion with the college of Louisiana, has regarded\nutility rather than entertainment, substance rather than show,\nit may be no less proper in itself, than in accordance with reasonable expectations, that the finish should correspond lo the\nbody of the structure.\nPermit me, then, on this occasion, so replete with interest,\non this hour, around which cluster SO many associations, rich\nwilh all iho vernal fragrance of memory, and lhc summer\nbrightness of anticipation, to fix your attention for a few mo-\nmenls on n subject fraught with Utility.\nThe Supremacy of Law is a topic, which, in all its connexions and bearings, involves the happiness of mankind in\nevery way, in which it is possible for happiness to be enjoyed,\nA little reflection will convince even the superficial observer, that the universe, wilh every particle of matter which it\ncontains, is governed by laws that are fixed and uniform in\ntheir operation. The tendency of fire is always to burn combustible substances; that of poison is to destroy, and that of\nwholesome food is to support animal life. These tendencies\nmay be counteracted by the intervention of other and adequate causes; but they are never destroyed. Tho gravity of\na cork is no less, when it ascends through water, than when\nit descends through the atmosphere.\nLook where we may through all the dominions of matter\nand of mind, the correctness ofthe foregoing sentiment is easily discovered. It will readily be granted, that there may\nbe found apparent exceptions to the uniformity of the opera-\nlion of Nature's laws. Slill, however, those exceptions, when\nproperly understood, will no doubt prove to be so many confirmations of the rule.\nTake an example. Iron sinks in water; and, yet, such a\nform may be given to it, as will cause it to swim on the surface wilh great buoyancy. Now, it is manifest to every tyro\nin philosophy, that there is no want of uniformity here; but,\n'hat the very same law, which causes the iron to sink in the\none instance, causes it to float in the oilier.\nExceptions, then, to Nature's laws may be regarded as anchor name for our ignorance of those laws, or of the manner\n'a which they operate in any given case.\nAll the rich stores of happiness, that God has treasured up\nm the universe for his sensitive creation, are contained in his\"\nvarious laws, and can be enjoyed in no other way, than\nthrough the uniformity of their operation.\nHence, if we would enjoy any blessing in the whole range\nof Heaven's gifts, we must place ourselves in harmony with\nthose laws, through the uniform operation of which, that\nblessing is to be enjoyed. Without food of some kind there\ncan be no nutrition. There is no way, in which the benefit\nof medicine can be enjoyed, unless it is introduced into the\nsystem.\nWhether the harmony in question be wilfully disregarded\nor ignorantly overlooked, in either case, misery, to a certain\ndegree, is the inevitable result. Thus, within a certain distance, fire imparts a grateful nnd refreshing warmth ; but this\ncan only lake place in harmony with those laws which have\nbeen impressed on it, and us, by our Great Creator. Disregard those laws, and vitality immediately suffers, if it be not\ndestroyed, by the intensity of cold on the one hand, or of heat\non the other.\nEven the most superficial thinker may be convinced by a\npassing glance, that, were the laws of Nature not thus uniform in their operation, all certainty, or even reasonable expectation of human happiness would be nt once annihilated,\nWho does not perceive that existence would bo intolerable, if\nit were altogether uncertain, whether the effects of arsenic or\nof bread, would result from whatever entered into the mouth;\nand whether to come in contact wilh those whom we delight\nto cherish as bosom friends, might not be the same as to tread\non a deadly serpent?\nIt is thus manifest, that if the laws of nature were not uniform in their operation, it would be impossible to make either\ncalculations or efforts for the promotion of our own happiness,\nor of that of our fellow-men.\nEvery law, under which man is placed by his Creator,\ntends to promote his happiness, when properly understood,\nand strictly obeyed. How vain, then, the complaints of Nature's rebels against the severity of those laws, which are\nmanifestly designed for llieir happiness, and without which\nthere could be no enjoyment. Whereas, misery results, and\nan result, only from their violation. The lawless and disobedient are, therefore, alike rebels against God, and traitors\nto their own happiness.\nA hearty and practical reception of this truth, would, in a\nlittle time, convert this desert into a paradise, this valley of\nwo into a garden of delights. On the other hand, a lawless\nspirit of self-will must, to the very same extent to which it is\nindulged, be productive of misery. If a man, either through\nignorance or disregard of the law of gravitation, steps off a\nprecipice one hundred feet high, not all the created power in\nthe Universe, can save him from destruction.\nHence, it is manifest, that there is no other way of securing\nhappiness, \"our being's end and aim,\" than by acting in harmony with tho laws of our Creator. Such action presupposes a knowledge of the laws in question. Consequently,\na knowledge of the laws of Nature, under which we are\nplaced, and a course of conduct in harmony with that knowledge, are necessary for the perfection of human happiness.\nInasmuch, then, as a law-abiding spirit involves the well-\nbeing ofthe whole human race,  it is no wonder,     ul   it\nVOL. I.\u2014X\n'\nfl\nii","fullrs":{},"find":"599.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"598","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1708180","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.63 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
