<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/566</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>566</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/566/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"202\nSOUTH-WEST E R N  JOURNAL.\nS'V .\nm\n\u2022?\nj\n'\u25a0OMcS\n\"Every question which respects .influences that act on the\ncommunity at large, is of immense consequence in our age,\nnnd especially in our country. Wc readily comprehend\nthat, in Europe, such mailers would be viewed with jealousy\nand'apprehension by Government, and indeed by nil in\nChurch and State, who are attached by interest, prejudice and\nfear, to existing forms and institutions. But in our country,\nwhere religious bigotry and superstition, political tyranny\nand persecution, are unknown ; where the People ore and\nown and do every thing, the progress of Society is among\nthe greatest of popular interests, among the highest of popular duties. The advancement of society in religion\u2014pure,\nhumble, enlightened; in knowledge\u2014practical, useful, benevolent; is then an obligation laid upon every man by the constitution of our state of sociely; and above all on those whom\nGod has endued with talents, has blessed with opportunity\nfor their cultivation, and has honored with the authority of!\npublic stations or the influence of private example,    'f\ninsensible to these truths, is not to realize that every man, [stop, till he rests in that calm sunshine, a premonition of tho\nhowever elevated or lowly, is one of the people, nnd that he peaceful rapture of tho seraphs\u2014these that we most love to\nof events is here implied,    Mind, in ils progressive dcvel\nments, is the subject-matter, and events are but the mnnifesta\nlions, the exponents of this Mind.    Thus History becomes\nthe instructor of nations ns nations, or of individuals stale*\nmen, so associated with the fume and character of their countries, as to bo their acknowledged, accredited representatives\nin the transactions of nations; but does not furnish that manual for daily conduct, which every man, as a self-dependent\nbeing, needs and asks for.\nThe public acts of public men, released from the influences\nof homo and domestic life, constitute the body of this science.\nTho private, untold, unshared thoughts of the ro\u00ab.\u00bbarenol\nknown; his unappreciated struggles with self\u2014Proteus-form\nself; lhc unbreathed triumph of success, of gaining new and\nwider views of the worlds before him; his steady, irresistible\nenthusiastic grappling with difficulty; his hopes nnd bis\ndespondencies, his helps and his hindrances; his lonely, labor-\n-1 ascent towards 'Truth, his path growing brighter at cverv\nhas duties to perform to all ihe rest\u2014duties commensurate\nwith his capacity and means.    To educate the people then\nis the great duty which is laid upon every one; for it is the n]] wjt], that last and strong! ,-l  loud of man with\nii ad, to dwell on,\u2014these in which all find a sympathy, which\nhew humanity in its strength and in its weakness, closing\nmost powerful and durable of all instruments which can be\nemployed to cany forward ihe advancements of society in\nvirtue and knowledge, as the fountains of prosperity and happiness.\"\nLet the excellence of the matter be the apology for the\nlength of the quotation.\nman, his\nmortality\u2014these cannot come within the range of History,\nShe cannot turn from her stately course, to watch and narrate\ntho growth of an individual mind, although the fate of an\nempire be predestine d in that mind.\nThis is the province and purpose of Biography\u2014this close,\nminute analysis of character\u2014this exact summation of par-\nAmong the means instituted by wise men and approved ticulars, this patient watching and tolerance ofthe wnyward-\nby experience for the promotion of this noble and Christian ness of Genius, finding- prophi cy in every act, the daivnings\npurpose, this sacred anel dignified duty, is the establishment of Truth through  clouds of error.    What aspirant after\nof Lyceums\u2014Associations for mutual and general improvement in science and in literature\u2014in every thing which improves, expands, refines the soul.\n'These institutions, while partaking somewhat of the esolo-|samo diilieulti\nric character of earlier and suspected associations, at the sain.' ris \" '\"  vl\nFame, what student of Philosophy, has not been cheered\nand re-invigornted when  wearied with labor, despondentof\nsuccess, he finds that others have felt and surmounted the\nhavo sunk under tho same depression and\n!\u2014have trodden in all its meanderings tlia\ntime exhibit their purposes and plans to all who affect similar'I1\"'1 which seems to lengthen out  before him indefinitely.\npursuits, and going even farther, challenge the inquest ofM^7\"'1 Wuat warmth of affection does he press the record lo\nlie scrutiny, and ask the support of public counti nance, ''is heart as a guide and companion in his solitary way.\nBut I cannot enlarge here, inviting ns this theme is.   I\npubl\nScience, Literature, the Arts\u2014every thing exercising I\nfully the mind\u2014all come within the wiele range of the comprehension of our Institution, It is therefore with less hesitancy that 1 come before you ibis evening, bringing what\nsome might consider matter irrelevant to the nature and design of Lyceums Still others\u2014and from such we look for\naid in establishing and maintaining our embryo society-\nothers, with tho Poet of Rome, take interest in every phase\nof human nature, considering nothing foreign to tho purpose\nof life which affects mankind\u2014\" nihil mc alienum pulo,\" &amp;c,\nHistory has been called Philosophy leaching by example,\nand Mr. Burke has called Philosophy the Queen of the\nsciences. From ibis we at once perceive the high purpose\nand province of History. 'The heavenly fire has enkindled\nin the hitherto skeleton narration, a soul and a spirit which\nenables it to walk abroad into the world, clad in its true dignity.    More, infinitely more, than a chronological relation\nproceed at once to the immediate obji et to which I have re1-\nquested your attention. As iho following brief narrative\nwas gathered from various sources, some part of which lean\nnot now refer to\u2014I have not thought it necessary to quote\neach passage and cite my authority :\nCharles Caleb Colton, as a man and as an Author, is the\nsubject of the crude reflections which I oiler you this evening. The materials for his Biography in our country arc\nscanty; what I have obtained can be condensed in few\nwords.\nHo was graduated at King's College, Cambridge, in 1S01,\nanil in 1818 obtained tho vicarage of Kcw and Petersham.\nHe possessed great talents, profound philosophical acumen,\npolished tasto and brilliant wit, equally great in conversation\nand in composition ; but his irregularities and eccentricities\nwere as remarkable, and entirely uncontrolled by the P\u2122'","fullrs":{},"find":"567.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"566","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1659469","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.58 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
