<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 29</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2136</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2136</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2136/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Section 3, Page 29","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"ADDRESS. 29\nleted to Cumberland, and is being vigorously pressed towards its ul-\n''T'VlC^nas aroused herself in the general rivalry of the times,\nJ'mrners her resources for the groat canal she has projected, for the\nnniTection of the James River and Richmond with the waters of the\nOhio It will touch the Ohio at a favorable point for navigation, and\ndestroy the competition of northern routes during the winter season,\nwhen their works are arrested. A canal boat at Columbus, Ohio,\nsays Governor Floyd, laden with pork, hemp, tobacco, or iron, would\ngreatly prefer going to Norfolk upon this canal, to passing through\nthe lakes and the Erie Canal, to New-York, if the market was as good\nat one place as the other, for the simple reason, that the distance\nwould be greatly shorter, and the navigation much safer from interruption by ice, and from the dangers of the lake. It is plain, therefore, that such trade as would prefer water carriage, and as now\nreaches New-York, from the heart of Ohio, would find its way through\nVirginia by means of her canal. It is now completed to Buchanan,\n194 rniles,*leaving a distance of 174 miles to be constructed to the\ngreat Falls of the Kanawha.\n\" The Virginia and Tennessee Rail-road will, when completed, form one link\nin a chain of road from New-York to Mobile ana New Orleans, most of which ia\nalready determined upon, and over which will pass a greater amount of travel\nthan this country has ever witnessed. It is the great line which must convey the\ntravel to and from California, from the Northern, Middle, and partly from the\nSouthern States, and over which much of the commerce intended for the Pacific\nby the Tehuantepec route will likewise be transported. It is worthy of all aid\nfrom the Commonwealth. When it shall be completed to the Tennessee line, it\nwill have penetrated a country of higher capabilities and greater extent than that\nthrough which the Baltimore and Ohio rail-road now passes to Cumberland.\nAnd should the Central rail-road decide to go to Cincinnati by Guyandotte instead of to Louisville, then the Virginia and Tennessee Rail-road will form a common stem for a branch either from New river, through Giles, Mercer, and Tazewell, to Lexington, Kentucky, or from Abingdon through the county of Russell to\nthe same city. The advantages of this connection I developed sufficiently at\nlength iu my last annual message, and therefore deem it unnecessary to repeat\nthem here.    There was a mistake made in the state's subscription to this work,\n,.'\u00ab[ \"\"S^1110 i*9 rectified, and which f earnestly recommend to be done at once.\n\" s''\u00b0nld the Central Rail-road reach Cincinnati, it will form the shortest line of\nad between that great city and tide-water, and will of course command an immense amount both, of trade and travel. It is a truly great work, and will be ultimately productive of great benefits to the state.\"\nTowards their fellow,eitizens of Louisiana and of New-Orleans, in\nparticular, the Committee feel that they have an important duty to discharge. Situated at the mouth of the largest river in the world, with\nits thousands of miles of tributaries connecting with the most fertile,\nand. wealthy, and thriving regions that the sun has ever shone upon ;\n\"sides being, in her own agricultural facilities, one of the most fa-\nored states in the Union, the progress of Louisiana has been but\nww m comparison with many of her sisters, whilst New-Orleans,\nDire VT \"Sc? the prou&lt;i emPorium and \"art of the immense em-\n1   e ot the West, sees her trade taken away by piece-meal, by a host\nera* ri?       \"Vals' until her rank is fast Passing from her, and the\nS ass threatens to grow again in her once crowded thoroughlares.","fullrs":{},"find":"2137.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2136","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"539919","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
