<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/545</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>545</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/545/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"182\nSOUTH-WESTE\ncent., on tl\nRN   JOURNAL.\n\u25a0M:\nii He.,\n\u25a0 't *M\ncould easily have raised the money at four per\nnt of the policy.    Shylock says ol\nsecurity of an assignmen\n' Antonio is a good man, yet his means are in supposi-\nargosy bound for Tripoli, another to the\nhim\ntion : he hath an   ,\nIndies; I understand, moreover, upon tho Rialto, he hath a\nthird at Mexico, a fourth for England, and other ventures he\nhath squandered abroad, But ships are but boards, sailors\nbut men ; there be land rats and water rats, water thieves and\nland thieves; I mean pirates; and then there is the peril of\nwaters, winds and rocks?' Now these are the very risks\nwhich tho contract of insurance is intended to cover, as clearly expressed in Marshall and our other writers, and as express\ned in the following clause inserted in all policies; to wit:\u2014\n1 Touching the adventures and perils which the assurers are\ncontent to bear, and to take upon them in this voyage, they are\nof the seas, men-of-war, fire, enemies, pirates, rovers, corsairs,\nthieves, robbers, jettisons, etc., barratry ofthe masters or mariners, and of all other perils, losses, and misfortunes, that have,\nand shall come to hurt, detriment, or damage of the said\ngoods, or said merchandizes, and of said ship or said vessel.'\nWith this precaution, Antonio's means would have been no\nlonger in supposition, but in certainty, and as good as hard\ncash, under deduction merely of the premium of insurance.\nFinally, when intelligence was received of Antonio's argosies\nbeing wrecked, it is plain that he might, undor the circumstances, have at once abandoned to the underwriters, and\nclaimed for a total loss. It is painful to see so many amiable\ncharacters in griefs and difficulties, which this simple and natural expedient would have obviated. My feelings at this\nreflection are something akin to those of a very susceptible\nmedical friend, who declares that he can never sit out Romeo\nand Juliet, from the thought that a judicious use of the patent\nstomach pump, in the last scene, would remove all distresses,\nand make two lovers completely happy.\"      \u00bb        \u2022        \u2022\nFor iho Snutli Wentorii Journal.\nTHE SEASONS.\nNO. 1.\nnv joiin p. shannon, esu.\nSPUING.\nBack to his northern snows and icy caves\nReluctant winter turns\u2014and frequent blasts,\nAnd rattling hail proclaim his tardiness.\nThe gladd'ning voice of happy birds is heard\nAmid the forest's broadly opening glades.\nA thousand streams come shooting down\nWith merry babbling, and Ihe bill-tops high\nWeleome, with smiles, the ruddy, orient sun;\nThe thousand echoes of the sprouting wood,\nWaked by Ihe choristers of nature's tutoring,\nEntwine the sounds, till in one broad glad strain,\nThey come a mingled gush of harmony\u2014\nAnd far amid the dells, break startling!}-\nUpon Ihe quiet ear of lazy silence.\nMark the young leaves! that yet not half assured\nPeep timorously forth;\u2014and thousand flowers\nShow sign of teeming life, which unconflned\nBurst forth at length to broad and glorious day.\nThe whlsp'ring breeze floats like a spirit-sigh\nUpon the bosom of the waveless lake\nWilli scarce enough of power to wak'e ils ripples.\nHow like a coy, and bashful ma idea seems Ihe flow'r\nHalf courted by ils breath 1   Now they entwine\nAnd now again il bends to let him pass;\nNow the inconstant woos another male\u2014\nAnd .-ill ihe plain is harmony anel hive.\nGay sunny April, smiling through her tears,\nIn robe of virid vesture clad, dances\nAcross the lawn, to meet her sister May,\nA brighter sylph, nnd with a rosier cheek,\nAnd laughing eye that melts in liepu'd bin.'.\nHark 1 from ihe broad and sunny woodland glade\nThe ring-dove murmurs forth his note of love;\nMellowed by distance, on the ear il (all?\nLike sigh of some departed spirit, as it hangs\nUpon the object of its care, from wo,\nAnd sorrow, to protect it.   Mark the rill!\nWhich, like a silver thread, winds through Ihe vale\nWhile rlow'rs bend low to kiss Its tiny waves,\nOr mirror on Its bosom all their charms.\nHow like to youth is joyous nature now!\nA world of sunshine !    Not one darkling cloud\nFrowns on so fair a scene, bul joy and song\nRule, sister spirits.    True, ihe balmy show'r\nDescends amain, but 'lis like tears of youth ;\nIt gladdens and refreshes, anel Ihe plain\nSmiles doubly sweel, and frequent verdure\nGlistens' like pearl-gemmed sparkling coronet.\nThe diamonds of the dew are not more bright,\nThau crystal rain-tears of the April show'rs,\nBack lo thy cell foul crime!   Nor dare lo hope,\nThai here thy poisoned breath may blow.   Back! back!\nLet blue-eyed innocence dance on beneath\nThe shade of April's wings, for here\nIs naught but master-work of God's own hand.\nFor llic Bouth.Wosloro .lournnl,\nI.F.TTEItS I-ItOM THE NOTES OP A BUCKEYE PIlYiilL'lA.V.\nTHE FIRST  CALL.\nMy Dear Frank:\nIn compliance wilh your request, I have determined to\nwrite out the notes which accidentally fell into your hands\nsince I took up my residence in the South; but to do so, I\nshall be compelled to encroach upon the time which Morpheus claims to be spent at his shrine; if, therefore, you\nshould find these scribblings as dull as the vapid mind from\nwhich they originated, you will please excuse them, my dear\nFrank, for no one else will.\nYou will recollect that in the fall of 1833,1 hung out\nmy shingle with \" Dr. Melmoth \" gilded on it in letters as\nbright as the yellow leaf itself and that in the village print\nwas to be found my advertisement with tho following N. B,\ndangling nt the tail of it: \"Dr. Melmoth may always be\nfound at his office, (one door south of the blacksmith's sbop.\n:md directly opposite the grave yard) except when absent on\nprofessional business.\" How I used to spend my weary lionrs\nwaiting for my first call, you have already heard, and now,\nit is my determination to give you, plcno rivo, a relation of\nthe case it was my province to take charge of and whicb\nwas tho first that fell into my hands after I had won my\nsheep-skin.\n'Twas in bleak December, that I was, at the hour of midnight, unceremoniously aroused from my slumbers, on tl'*\nnight of tho 20lh, when my waking ears were greeted will'\nthe loud enquiry\u2014\"is the'Doctor at home?\"    My reJ0\"1'","fullrs":{},"find":"546.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"545","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1643123","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.57 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
