<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/419</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>419</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/419/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"r\nSOUTH- W ESTERN JOURNAL.\nS3\nWe shall now take a condensed view of the posilitive vul-lhave been well taught to that age, reading natural science, or\nlie of classic study ; then notice some of the objections to the drawing maps with their instruments, or tugging at a knotty\nsame, and close by a comparison of its effects with those of puzzle in arithmetic, for amusement, or rather for tho pleasure of the mental exercise it produces. And the celebrated\nLocke, who understood better the buddings of thought than\nany English philosopher, and who only, of all metaphysicians, has demonstrated,\u2014he it was that said, \" Into whose\ncare soever the instruction of children is committed, one thing\nis certain, he should be one who thinks Latin and language\nthe least pari of education.\"\nAgain ; as a mental discipline, the study of language fur-\nnishes not that species of system,\u2014that gradation of thought,\nthat architecture of idea, if you please, which will be called\ninto action in our common reasoning.    It assists not to sift\ntruth from falsehood, but leaves the mind doubtful of its own\ndecisions, till the dixit of the instructor has settled the matter.\nAnd when done\u2014and the mind perfectly clear upon a point,\nlo what shall the truth or principle bo applied!   \"To the\nsolution of a similar difficulty\" forsooth! and. this lo another\nand so on\u2014all for the sake of learning the shades of meaning\nof a word, or something still more evanescent than a shadow.\n( I thank my stars\u2014mathematics do not deal in shadows, but\nin substance\u2014in thought, embodied, chained, TANGIBLE I \u2014\nPardon the digression.) When yourclassic student is brought\nlo reason,\u2014to exercise this noble, distinguishing feature of\nour nature, to what purpose shall he apply his rules of Latin\nprosody, or the conjugation of his Greek irregulars, or any\nprinciple derived from either?    \"But,\" it is answered, \"he\nwill bring to bear the philosophy nnd history ho has quarried\nfrom Iho dust of twenty centuries.\" My life upon il, he learned\nit from a translation; for I have seldom known a student who\ndid not get a hundred ideas from Itulliu, Gillies, Gibbon nnd\nLempriere, for one from his classic text-book.    Then all tho\nargument for classic study, (o introduce us to the  history of\nthe manners, and customs, laws, politics, etc., of the ancients,\nfalls to the ground.    But if classic study is no! adapted to\nchildhood,\u2014does not discipline properly the reasoning powers, nor apply lo  the common business of life, bow shall it\nanswer our first object of correct education?    The answer is\nunavoidable:  it docs not answer it, or does so in a very limited degree.\nMatters of taste, as connected with classic study, deserve\na further notice. Wo are persuaded, that correct taste in\nEnglish composition, can belter be attained from the aid of\nclassic literature, than by any other method. But wo ask, in\ncandor, at what sacrifice? Can it be done in boyhood, when,\nit is insisted, the memory is fresh and vigorous? Wc contend\nthat it cannot; for, as we have shown, the undertaking does\nviolence to nature; and all things else equal, ihe lad who studies the English Grammar, language and composition\u2014such\nas Addison, Steele and Irving,\u2014will write infinitely better at\nthe end of two years' application, than his mate, who learns\nlo hate Latin Grammar, to despise the Greek ( for no student\never dared to say he liked Greek Grammar,)\u2014to murder the\ntranslation of the Jugurthine war, and read the Anabysis with\ntranslation. Time\u2014a long time\u2014is necessary to conquer\nthe first impression of antipathy; and then docs he gain tho\nfirst item of utility.    Meanwhile a very competent know-\nthe mathematics.\nLanguage is but articulate sound, serving for tho interchange of thought; and, of course, those means by which\nthe attainment of the correct use of language can best be\nsecured, should have preference to all others. Now we conceive, thai, since the Hebrew, Greek, and Latin languages,\nlie at the root of most modern languages of enlightened na\nlions, the philologist, the lexicographer, critic or teacher of\n(ho philosophy of language, should study, not partially, hut\nthoroughly, these ancient languages. Moreover, observation\nand experience have taught me, that the amount of classic\nknowledge, attained in the ordinary college course, has gem\nrally the effect of making more elegant writers, by givin\nprecision lo luste and euphony lo sound. The height of per.\nfection to which the Greek language attained, the lofty beauty\nof its poetry, and the irresistible grandeur of ils eloquence,\ngive it high claims to the attention of those who seek eminence, in these ornamental departments of literature. In\nstances of excellence in poetry or eloquence, without tho aid\nof classic learning-, arc far from demonstrating that the latter\nwould not have materially heightened the former. None\ncan doubt that many of the most celebrated writers owed\ntheir distinction, almost exclusively, to classic learning.\nBut several objections exist, to the usual course of classic\nstudy, which we imagine cannot be successfully met, and\nwhich have led many worthy and learned men to the most\nuncompromising hostility to their study\u2014and here would\nwe take occasion to disclaim all appeals lo sophistry or elisin-\ngenuousness, in our objections. Gratitude for the low favors\nwe ourselves have obtained from this source, would forbid\nunfair opposition; therefore, our objections shall bo such as\ncool reflection and observation, aside from others' views, have\nled us to espouse.\nAmi, first, let us bring the classics to the great standard\nwe have adopted, ill defining the objects of education; name\nly,usefulness in life, and happiness in futurity. Now, in the\ndiscipline of the mind, where attempted very early, the study\nof language does violence to naliirc; for it diverts the mind\nfrom the material world aboul it, and directs it to sound! to\nthe philosophic relation of words to each other! None can\ndeny that the natural order, in mental development, is to commence with the things which first make impressions upon the\nmind. To arrest il then from things, and compel it to study\nwords, is to pervert the natural order. Compulsion in changing this tendency, reason would tench us, would produce disgust for the new; the subject of discipline then hastes the latter, and is compelled to neglect the former, and lose the precious moments when tho \"high seal of,character is set.\"\nAnd experience corroborates reason; for, out of some hundred lads, students of Latin and Greek, from ten years of age,\nwo have not met one, at tho age of twelve, who has learned\nto like either; and wo appeal to the recollection of our worthy opponent, or to the oldest, to say that he has often seen\nboys, at that age, studying their Latin and Greek for amusement.    Now nothing is more common, than to seo lads who|\ni,\neKii\nV  \\\ni ;v|\n;.'. I\n.,f ;\n- 'I.\n1","fullrs":{},"find":"420.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"419","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1853356","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
