<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Appendix, Page iii</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2144</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2144</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2144/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Appendix, Page iii","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"WESTERN  CANALS.\nr    * \u00ab\u25a0 to the  processes by which trade is  being carried from the western\n^4   ]Ew neglected to refer to die numerous canals now in successful opera\nffS-^^^fSfefnSE^, 60 feet wide, and6 feet deep; locks\n''\u25a0 ^rt\u00abffit    Ii connectsthe Chicago, which empties into Lake Michigan,\n;7;,l,'l    Vninnwat LaSalle,213 miles from the Mississippi.    The Illinois is  navigable\nwith tiie im     \u25a0 d 4 inonthB ]_,y steam (the ice season being excluded).\nj11 **JE*kand ErieCanal.-Ttes extends from Lafayette, about 378 miles above the\nJ\\   i7\u2122,iili   where it enters the Ohio, to Toledo on the Maumee, adjacent to Lake\n\u25a0        l  \u00ab lBTmiles long.    It is intended to complete the canal from Lafayette to the\nErie, ami is ^ ^ ^ ^^ Junction this canal intersects the Miami Canal from Cin-\n}hio itive . ba'ble the Wabash and Erie Canal is now complete to Terre Haute, on\n2\" Wabash-   The Muskingum Improvement extends to the Muskingum River, at or\nJar ZanesviHe, and is 91 miles long.\nI Sandy and Beaver Canal, connecting the Beaver River with the lake from the\nOhio    4   Mahoning Canal, being  a cross canal  of 83 miles long.    There is a canal\nXlled the Beaver and Erie, 136 miles long, connecting with the Ohio 28 miles below\nPittsburg ti,c connection with Lake Ontario is by the Welland Canal in Canada, and\nwith Ontario and Champlain by the New-York canals. The points of union of those\ncanals then, with the Mississippi, are as follows:\u2014mouth of Illinois on the Mississippi, 40\nmiles above St. Louis ; mouth of Wabash, on the Ohio, 130 miles from the Mississippi;\nCincinnati, on the Ohio, 550 miles from Mississippi; Portsmouth, on the Ohio, 589 miles\nfrom Mississippi; mouth of the Hocking, on the Ohio, 756 miles from Mississippi; Marietta, on the Ohio, 783 miles from Mississippi; at mouth Little Beaver, on Ohio, 924\nmile* from Mississippi.\n4, Tiie State of Wisconsin is now connecting the Fox and Wisconsin Rivers, which\nempty into the Mississippi and the Lakes by a canal of very short length. An exchange\nremarks:\u2014\" The above bids fair to become one of the most important public improvements over made in die United States. The connecting the great Lakes and the Mississippi river by a route navigable by steamers, must form an era, even in our present\nadvanced state of internal communication. A boat may then load at Buffalo for the Falls\nof St. Anthony, the Yellow Stone, or New-Orleans. The products ofthe great Mississippi\nvalley will have a direct and cheap route to the Atlantic cities by way of the Lakes. Emigrants may then embark at Buffalo or Oswego, and be carried by the same steamer to the\nspot where they wish to settle. Anew impulse will be given to the commerce ofthe\ncountry, andihe bonds of our Union made the stronger by the opening of this new route,\nwhich is soon to rival all other artificial lines of water communication opened in this\ncountry.\nINFLUENCES OF RAIL-ROADS.\nIt is m the nature of railroads to multiply commercial transactions, through the faci-\ni they offer, and even to create a business where none has previously existed; so\no hue, which, for the first few years of its operation, scarcely pays its expenses,\nhr   t\u00abiao        year5, prove Iucrative-    The Camden and Amboy Rail-road is in point.\n:i Mj238,000, completed 1830.    In three years the travel increased 65 per cent., and\ncost1of if'vIn lhree year?' from 1833 to 1837&gt; its nett earnings exceeded the whole\noilier m T    r \u25a0'    *\" ^\"3 \u2122ew rail\"roa^s claim the attention  of merchants   above  any\nto tran \u25a0*       \u2022nv&amp;stment, inasmuch as they create  the  commerce it is their business\nhanks    WI     k' therer\u00b0re' while yielding a better and safer dividend, are superior to\nfarmer  &amp;    at be\"efit9 tiie merchant and dealer, cannot but promote the welfare of the\nbvtlipL C\"   lla\"-roads offer an unsurpassed mode of communication, which, in effect,\ninall these1PL\"eS^ \"\"\"* speed of tbeir operations, doubles the amount of capital employed\nLei ueW'\u00b0r!eans and -Jackson Rail-Road, from the Letters of Col. Tarpley, of Miss.\nft-ftf rathe ViViT\"eSS ll1? road would do In tl,e fir8t Place lhe 60.\u00b0M b\u00ables of cotton\nThe cotton mil i - [\"'\",'\u2022 e,1&gt;' \"f Ll\"' l!i- ll,1,ck river' would b&lt;- xliippcl on (hit, direct line,\n^'\"'\"thijtt,,  I   ',;\",'\u2022'!- ll,c l,,le \u00b0f ^8 Big Black, ia Ma,!,,,,,,. Holmes, and Attala c\n\u25a0\"\"\"\"iiJiistolOdiiii l 7 e cig niucK, iu maiiiHon, Holmes, and .Attala counties,\n*\u25a0\u00bb \"' Jat-k&gt;ou     Tto ?\"'. ar\u00b0 n\u00b0W scut lo Yazo\u00b0 cit&gt;' am] tfaimrl;l \"'l,R *ldi&gt;l'ed, would be\n*\u00ab*ll M \u201ele u \u25a0 \u00bbJ\" \"WtaiiM is shout equal, the road better, and the difference in the cost, as\n*f\u00bb*PpUur and in \u201e g 6 markBt. a\u00bbd the condition of the cotton, the saving of expenses\n\"\u00bb&gt;\u00bb*\u2022\u2022 till,, toVeaM Urv\"CC| Would ,llakc il to their interna to haul cotton iii'tv miles to Jackson.\nCOu\"1\"- lying south Vr i \"t\u00b0\u00b0 \"ver at a Sorter distance. Now, add th,: lii.nim bales made in the\n*\u00abV 6ft, ,;,\u201e. ' ,.'' \u25a0\u25a0\" ,,7,H1: an(1 contiguous to thcroad, that would be shipped at half price,\n;\u00b0 HP-agate of 90 00(1 h\u201et' l ,'Ch Would be equivalent lo 20,000 shipped at Jack&gt;on. and we have\nr1\"1'1 Ibe Extern7-Lh i ,,U,t Tou]d&gt; ovcrv vear- P\"\u00ab \u00b0ver the whole line of ihe road. And\n\u25a0WM r\u00aby \u00bbafelv ' SySJ\" completed to its intersection with the Mobile and Ohio road, we\nr\"*y\u00abirorso w\u201euI. ' P\"r cent, to the amount. The miscellaneous down freights, for the\n\u00b0B\u00abt fairly Ull(ler \".\u25a0\"ta,i,ou\"t'omi1eh,asii requires time to raise stock, make orchards, and\nB \"t $25,000    ]u f,v ' lho Present population, we might very properly estimate\nuve years they would amount to double as much as the cottou would.    The","fullrs":{},"find":"2145.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2144","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"574572","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
