<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Exile</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name displayLabel="Artist">
      <namePart>Durieux, Caroline, 1896-1989</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">art</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Artist</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <edition>10 of 12</edition>
      <dateCaptured>2004-08-10</dateCaptured>
      <dateCreated keyDate="yes">1939</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Men</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Exiles</topic>
   </subject>
   <abstract displayLabel="Description">A Jewish exhile.</abstract>
   <note type="content">This lithograph is from theartist's "New Orleans Series". It is drawn with a lithographic pencil and using a brush with lithographic ink. One may note that the entire background is ink painted onto the stone by brush. The suggestion for the face in the print came from an experience in New Orleans. Ms. Durieux  had x-rays made while in New Orleans by a young x-ray technician. The technician was a Jew who seemed to have one of the saddest faces seen by the artist. As it was the time of Jewish persecution in Germany, the artist related his saddened features of those misfortunate Jews in  Europe. She used his face to represent the exiled Jew at this time of world trouble. The black background surrounds the face and adds to the feeling of dark sadness of the work. The background, related Ms. Durieux, is again a technical "device" used by the artist. The black area allows the viewer to become involved in the composition allowing the viewer's eye to create an outline for the face and head of the youth. "A technical device is used by the artist for the viewer's sake... a technical device belongs to the artist, not the viewer."</note>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="medium">Black lithograph</note>
      <extent>10-1/2 x 9 in.</extent>
      <internetMediaType>image/jp2</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
   <name type="corporate" authority="naf" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n97093352" displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
<namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.). Museum of Art</namePart>
<role>
<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
</role>
</name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>Caroline Wogan Durieux Works of Art</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Repository Collection Guide">http://www.lib.lsu.edu/sites/default/files/sc/findaid/d3827.html</url>
      </location>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-moa-cwd:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="https://www.lsumoa.org/ ">LSU Museum of Art, Shaw Center for the Arts, Baton Rouge, LA</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">E-mail artmuseum@lsu.edu with questions or comments</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the Louisiana State University Museum of Art. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <note type="preferred citation" displayLabel="Cite As">Caroline Wogan Durieux Collection at the LSU Museum of Art, Louisiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.</note>
   <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Accession Number">68.9.15</identifier>
   <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Object File Name">cd000148</identifier>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/CWD/id/125</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2004-08-13</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-11-14</recordChangeDate>
  </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <imageBitDepth>36 Bit-depth</imageBitDepth>
      <digitizedBy>PA</digitizedBy>
      <extentArchival>1:1</extentArchival>
      <colorMode>Color</colorMode>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>CWD</alias>
         <pointer>125</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/CWD/125/json"
                        timestamp="2017-01-05 14:12:45">{"title":"Exile","creato":"Durieux, Caroline, 1896-1989","date":"1939","subjec":"Men; Exiles","descri":"A Jewish exhile.","notes":"This lithograph is from theartist's \"New Orleans Series\". It is drawn with a lithographic pencil and using a brush with lithographic ink. One may note that the entire background is ink painted onto the stone by brush. The suggestion for the face in the print came from an experience in New Orleans. Ms. Durieux  had x-rays made while in New Orleans by a young x-ray technician. The technician was a Jew who seemed to have one of the saddest faces seen by the artist. As it was the time of Jewish persecution in Germany, the artist related his saddened features of those misfortunate Jews in  Europe. She used his face to represent the exiled Jew at this time of world trouble. The black background surrounds the face and adds to the feeling of dark sadness of the work. The background, related Ms. Durieux, is again a technical \"device\" used by the artist. The black area allows the viewer to become involved in the composition allowing the viewer's eye to create an outline for the face and head of the youth. \"A technical device is used by the artist for the viewer's sake... a technical device belongs to the artist, not the viewer.\"","editio":"10 of 12","type":"Image","medium":"Black lithograph","sizewe":"10-1\/2 x 9 in.","format":"jpeg 2000","source":"Louisiana State University Museum of Art (http:\/\/appl003.lsu.edu\/museum\/moa.nsf\/index\/)","reposi":"Finding aid for the original photographs: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/sites\/default\/files\/sc\/findaid\/d3827.html","rights":"Physical rights are retained by the Louisiana State University Museum of Art.  Copyright is retained in accordance with U S copyright laws.","cite":"Caroline Wogan Durieux Collection at the LSU Museum of Art, LOUISiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.","contac":"E-mail fhuber@lsu.edu with questions or comments","frame":{},"access":"68.9.15","langua":{},"object":"cd000148","item":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":"Homepage: http:\/\/www.louisianadigitallibrary.org\/cdm4\/index_CWD.php?CISOROOT=\/CWD;   List of images: http:\/\/www.louisianadigitallibrary.org\/cdm4\/browse.php?CISOROOT=\/CWD","image":"300 dpi","imaga":"36 Bit-depth","color":"Color","extent":"1:1","imagb":{},"file":{},"hardwa":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":"2003-11-25","digiti":"PA","publis":{},"digita":"2004-08-10","credit":{},"contri":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"43714139102003_277.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2004-08-13","dmmodified":"2008-03-19","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"125","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"2743556","cdmfilesizeformatted":"2.62 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
      <imageResolution>300 dpi</imageResolution>
  </extension>
</mods>
