<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/358</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>358</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/358/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"11-2\nS 0 V T II-WE8TE R N JOURNAL.\n\u25a0m\nall* \u25a0\u25a0}\u2022&gt;\"\nIrish origin) prevented him from reluming, but at the same\ntime treated him with great respect. 4. Other ancient accounts respecting the Icelandic hero Biorn Asf.ram.son,\nin his day one of the lomburg Warriors under Palnatoke,\nand fighting along with them in the battle of Fynsval in\nSweden: he also, in the year 999, repaired lo one of the\ncoasts of America, where he was detained in the same manner, but resided there as chief over the natives for about thirty years. 5. Account ol an Icelandic mariner, (Ii-ni.ElF\n(iiiDLAiinsoN, who was driven to the same coast in the year\n1027, and who was rescued from death or captivity by his\nshove mentioned countryman. 0. Extracts from the Annals\nof Iceland of the middle ages, in so far as they relate to\nAmerica, particularly Bishop Eric's voyage to Vineland\nin 1121 ; the discovery of new countries by the Icelanders in\nthe Western Ocean in 1285; an expedition from Norway\nand Iceland in the year 1288\u201490; and also a trading voyage from the ancient colony in Greenland to Marki.and in\nAmerica in 1347, as recorded by cotemporaries. 7. Ancient\naccounts of the most northern districts of Greenland nnd\nAmerica, chiefly visited by the Northmen for the purpose ol\nhunting and fishing; among these a very remarkable account\n(from a letter of a Greenland clergyman) of a Vovaoe of\nDiscovery undertaken by some clergymen from the Bishopric of Gardar in Greenland, in the year 1260, being\u2014as is\ncorroborated by an astronomical observation\u2014throuoii\nLancaster Sound and Barrow's Strait to regions\nwhich in our days have for the first time been made correctly known through the zealous exertions of Sir William Parry, Sir John Ross, and Captain James (.'lark Ross, and other\nBritish navigators. 8. Extracts from the ancient geographical works of the Icelanders, to which is added an outline taken in the thirteenth century, representing the earth in four\ninhabited quarters, 9. An ancient Faroish Ovaji wherein\nVineland is named, and allusion is made to its connexion\nwith Ireland. \"\nThere is another class of antiquities, to which allusion has\nbeen made, which are of great importance in elucidating the\nhistory of the North. They are lo the Scandinavian people,\nwhat the monumental inscriptions of Egypt and Greece are,\nin investigating their history. No architectural remains exist, like those of the latter countries, nor do their rude sculptures denote any proficiency in this branch of art. Like the\npeople by whom they were executed, they are marked with\nthe rudeness in their execution which characterizes their\nworks. In archteology, they are denominated 'Runes,' and\nconsist of rocks sculptured with ancient Runic letters, recording important events which have transpired in the countries where they arc formed. ' Runes ' are common throughout the North of Europe, and have also been found in Asiatic Russia, Siberia, and Tailary. In many instances, rude\nobelisks, from t.-u to twenty feet in height, are found with inscriptions, an I in others, smooth or natural-faced rocks on\nthe banks of rivers, or on prominent points in the interior.\nIn America, and particularly in the northern states, inscribed rocks are known to exist, which, in some respects, are\nanalogous to those of Europe and Asia. The most celebrated of these is the. Dighton Rock in Massachusetts.    It is situ\nated on the banks of Taunton river, and has, since the fl\u2122\nsettlement of the country, attracted the attention of the ami.\nfjuarians, both of America and Europe.*\nA BEDOUIN CAMP,\nn v   no.v.  j. s.   u u e k i n o m a m ,\nWe reached the Bedouin camp about sun-set, and our reception there was every thing that hopitality could dictatr\nOur bands were embraced, and the salutations of peace and\nwelcome exchanged a hundred times; but as no one claimed\nthe exclusive privilege of entertaining us, we were taken lo\na large square, formed by embankments of the soil, heighten-\ned by loose bushes, and completely sheltered from Ihe wind,\nwhere the elders of the tribe assembled to smoke their evening pipes, recount the tales of the day, and regale such guests\nas business or accident might bring among them from opno\nsite quarters.\nA young kid was immediately killed, and dressed upon the\nembers of a brush-wood fire; the milk of goals and camels\nwas laid before us in bowls, coffee was burned and pounded\nupon the spot, and the tobacco-purse of the venerable old\nsheik was replenished from his tent for our use. There was,\nn short, abundance for the hungry, rest for the weary, and\nsecurity for the apprehensive traveller, to be found beneath\nthe protecting shadow of their encampment, nor could the\nfeasts of the ancient heroes, which Homer so happily describes, have boasted a more unbounded liberality in iheir\nprovisions, or a more unadulterated hospitality in the rude simplicity of their preparation.\nDelighted with a conversation which brought me acquainted with their manners, customs, nnd opinions, and that, loo,\nfrom a source so satifactory as a large assembly of themselves, in which misrepresentations could not have passed unobserved, I was happy in prolonging our interview, and in\nremaining awake through the greater part of the night, engaged in mutual inquiry and reply.\nThe ground chosen for the encampment of this Bedouin\ntribe, was a gentle hollow of the plain, as it could scarcely do-\nsorvo ihe appellation of a valley; and their tents, to the number of about three hundred, occupied a space of less than two\nmiles in circumference. No other order was observed in\ntheir erection, than that of being all open to the eastward, 10\nreceive the warm and cheering beams of the morning sun:\nin summer, when the heats are oppressive, their openings face\nthe north, to enjoy the refreshing coolness of the winds from\nthat quarter. These low and brown habitations, formed of\nwoven goats' hair, differing in shape, size, and manner ol arrangement, and rudely supported by rough boughs of trees,\nand cord spun from the wool of their own flocks, were barely\nlarge enough to enclose their respective families at night, and\nshelter the infants and infirm in the day. Among the whole\nnumber, we met with none that covered ten square feel ol\nground at the base, though several of them were occupied by\nTin- Dlgltlo\nor Aesonct Rock, Willi its Inscription, forma tin- auujecl &lt;\"'\nmost curious ilisquisiiir.ii, in in,, volume of in.- Royal Society of Northern Attl-\nqiinri.-s, referred to. In, situated In a prominent point, In the immediate vicinity of ihe phce where ih,- Scandinavian colony was founded, ami appear' '\u2022 b\"'\nrecord of the vinil and OCCIipallCn of the country, hy lltojc hardy naTljatorti B\nthe tenth century","fullrs":{},"find":"359.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"358","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1753513","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
