<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 01</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/398</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>398</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/398/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 01","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\najubllsJeU Seml'tnonttlg, at Jflbc Hollars a Year, Og tlic Scffcraon fflolline anU 8\u00ae as I) Inn ton Jtjccuin.\nINTER   SYLVAS   ACIDEMIA   QUSRERE   VER1IM.\nVOL.   1.\nNATCHEZ, JANUARY   15, 183S.\nRKPOHT  OF THE COMMITTEE\nOP THE TRUSTEES OF lEPTERBON COLLEGE.\nAppointed by resolution of the Bonn] of the 3yd'August, 1837; which directed\n\"lo inquire into ihe causes which hitvc oiierttteil lo restrict the usefulness of\nJenerson Oolfege, lo Ihe education of the very limited manlier of students\nwhich hove been entered during Iho present year; nut! to recommend some\nmeans of acquiring for II, hi a greater degree, the confidence ami favor of the\npublic, as well as to ensure lis permanent populnrily and prosperity.\"\nIn prosecuting the enquiry which, by tho resolution of the\nBoard of the 22d August last, we were directed to institute\nfor the purpose of ascertaining the causes which have operated\nto limit tho usefulness of Jefforson College to tho narrow-\nsphere by which it se'ems to bo circumscribed. Your committee have been led td examine minutely into its organization, progress and condition.\nWe do not propose to inflict on you a detail of all the cir\ncumstances of its history, for more ihan thirty years, through\nwhich we have travelled; but merely to refer youv as briefly\nus possible, to such of ils most prominent incidents nSjj|re essential to our inquiry.\nIn the year 1802, Jefferson College was established by the\nLegislature of the Mississippi Territory, nnd invested will,\nthe inestimable privilege of being supported by voluntary\ncontribution from the public. With this; endowment, and its\ngood name, it commenced its career; nnd After0 (our through\nthis and an adjoining county, in quest of an abiding place,\n(wc believe it weqt no further,) it cventuully returnee! to its\npresent site, where it became permanently fixed: not, however,\nwithout various conlests in the community, for the possession\nof the bantling, including, of course, ihe benefits it was expected to confer, by iho apprccialion oLp&gt;operty, at the point\nof ils location. . \u2022 \u00a7f\nLearning, by this time, what was to bo expected from\n\"voluntary contribution,\" the trustees deemed it expedient to\nturn their attention to a source promising- to be more available, and endeavoured to take possession of a property in the\nCity of Natchez, which, in tho mean time, had been granted\nto tho Institution by the Congress of tho United State's; on a\npart of which there were said then to have been some inconsiderable buildings, previously occupied by the Spanish gov-\nernineni; ihe leases of which, it was thought, would aid in\nits support. They were met, however, by the conflicting\nclaims ofthe city; the authorities of which made application\nto Congress, and, incredible as it may seem, subsequently obtained a grant in its behalf of the same property. A suit at\nlaw, of about twenty years duration, expensive anil oppressive,\nto an institution without revenue, was the alternative; and\nwas terminated only a few years since by compromise.\nIt was.not, we believe, until about tho year 1810, eight\nyears after it was incorporated, that the Institution went into\noperation, by transferring to the College grounds a day school,\nunder the charge of a most estimable and respectable gentleman : In other words, the flag of the Washington Academy\nwas struck, and that of Jefferson College was hoisted in its\nstead. Tho standard of the Institution, all it had to bestow,\nfailed, we believe, as a rallying point to the friends of learning; it brought no increase of patronage, and whatever success was enjoyed, was attributable to the private woith and\nreputation ofthe gentleman at its head, for whose sole emolument it was conducted. From this period, n mixed school\nfor both sexes was generally kept up, with but little encouragement from the public, after tho gentleman, rilerrt tl\nto, abandoned the profession of instructor.\nAbout the close of the year IS 16, the Legislature commenced an experiment upon the disposition of the public to\nsustain our domestic institutions. It was thought, that, if-the\nInstitution could lie supplied with suitable officers, it would\nestablish a character and be patronized; and ihat such piifieii-\nage would, in future,'support it. It was in a dilemma; To\nestablish a character il was necessary to have students. To\nprocuro students it seemed essential that it should possess\ncharacter, The determination, however, was taken, to provide a salary for four years, to be paid to an indicated invid-\nual, annually, from the State Treasury, on his being Appoint-\ned the President. Accordingly, one of the most profound\nscholars in the Union took charge of the Institution. To\ngive better eflect to this experiment, and within the term of\nMr. McAllister's employment, the Trustees engaged, as a co-\nluborer in the institution, a clergyman ol high reputation lor\nliterary attainments; who, being from Princeton College, of\nwhich his father was President, it was thought lu's employment would be highly popular and advantageous.\nIn what manner these efforts were met by the public, ami\nwhat patronage they procured, is well known to many individuals in this Board. The fact is almost incredible, that,\nwithin this'period, ihe number of students sometimes did not\nexceed fifteen or Iwcnty.\nThe issue was, that the institution was heavily involved in\ndebt, and gained nothing in reputation.\nF.arly in 1819, by reason of a land mania then prevailing\nin Alabama, the Trustees were enabled lo realize a considerable sum on account of a Township of land, which ihe Sec\nretary of ihe Treasury had located for the benefit of the In-\nstilion, on the Tombigbee River. Elated with this success,\nand not doubting that the remaining instalments of the leases\nof those lands would be paid, the Trustees caused the present\nCollege edifice to bo ereclcd. It was, however, barely completed before the land-bubble, like others of more recent dale,\nburst; tho land reverted to tho College, and was found lo be\nvalueless. The Institution was plunged into a debt of about\nfifteen thousand dollars in this attempt to anticipate its resources\nand build up a College and provide Professors for it. The\nbuilding, however, was provided. This edifice, well built,\nomfortablo and commodious\u2014capable of accommodating a\nhundred students, at least; and how were these efforts of the\nTrustees met by the public 1 Did students flock to these halls ?\nBBA.r^r -rrrf\nBEH","fullrs":{},"find":"399.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"398","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1772152","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
