<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 18</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/504</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>504</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/504/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 18","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"lie}\nS Q U.T H -WE S T E It N   JOlJ K N A L\n\u00a7\nte\nil\nli\nil?lf.\nkit;\nbright, poetical parterres where wo love to linger. Audubon\nhas obtained thus far four hundred and seventy species of tho\nNorth American Birds. Ho has issued to his patrons seventy-eight numbers, each number containing five plates, the\nbirds\u00b0all drawn the size of life and colored to nature in ihe\nperfection of the art. lie has two guineas for each number,\nwhich will make the whole cost rather over eight hundred\ndollars. Of his subscribers upwards of eighty are in America, which argues well for the patronage of works in this\ncountry, which are truly deserving. Never have we taken\nmore decided pleasure lhan when examining this most superb\nundertaking of Audubon. Long may he live to enjoy the\ngood of all his labor !\u2014Boston. Morning Post.\nGirard College.\u2014The fifth annual report of the Architect of this magnificent edifice has been published, A Philadelphia paper says: \"The building proceeds wilh proper\nspeed; when completed it will prove worthy a pilgrimage\nfrom ihe most distant parts of the Union, being in fact the\nmost classical and beautiful erection of modern elate, whether\nin Europe or America.\"\nImfortant Discovery in Magnetism.\u2014A Mr. Poole,\nof Charleston, South Carolina, now residing in New York,\nit is said, has recently invented a Magnetic Quadrant by\nwhich he can give the latitude nnd longitude at any time or\nplace, without the aid of celestial observations. This is a\nnew and hitherto unnoticed phenomenon in the dip needle.\nGeological Survey  of Louisiana We learn that\na talented and influential member of the Legislature of Lou\nisiana (Mr. Penn,) has introduced a bill into the legislature\nof that slate, authorizing a geological survey. This state is\nalready known to be rich in iron ore, particularly the valley\nof the Ouachita; lead has been dug from the Tunica hills,\ngypsum of a superior quality has been found upon Thompson's creek; and that part of the state lying north of Lake\nPonlchartrain, in many of its districts, is rich in beds of mar\nand, we believe, small quantities of silver ore have also been\nfound there. Strong probabilities exist, that the extensive\nprairies in the south-western part of the slate contain valuable\nbeds of coal.\nNatural Coke.\u2014A bed of natural coke, seventeen feel\nin thickness, has been discovered near Richmond, Va., below\na bed of iron ore.\nTHE MONTHLY MEETING OF THE LYCEUM.\nThe Monthly Meeting of tho Lyceum, for April, will be\nholden in tho Natchez City Hall, over the Market, on Saturday, the 7th of April, at half past three, P. M.\nRev. B. M. Drake is the lecturer on that occasion, and T.\nJ. Johnston, Esq., and Professor Forshey, essayists.\nIt is anticipated, that tho ladies and gentlemen of Natchez,\nby a full attendance, will give a new impulse to the great interests of science and literature, and encourage the members\nof this industrious association in their kbord for moral and\nintellectual improvement.\nOBSERVATIONS\nMade eighteen houis bejore and after the Vernal Equinox, 1838.\nWashington, Mississippi.\nDstfl and hour.\n-,.,     |Wcl\nTl\"\"1bulb\nllaromoler\n.v clearness\n1\nWil.lt.\nc\nMarch 20th, 6 A. M,\n-ID i -\n29,77..1C\nw 1\n\"         li\n\u25a0111\n50\n\"    ..\"\n1        ,,\n\u2022\n\u00bb          7\n51\n51\n,:\n8\n57\n52\n\",79..\"\n\" 2\n\"          !)\n59\n52\n\",80..\"\n11\n10\n04\n51\n\"1\n\"        11\n115\n\"\n\",79..\"\n\"\nis\n73\n\"\n\",77..\"\ns w 2\n1 P. M.\n75\n50\n\"\n\u25a0i\n7C\n50\n\"75   *&lt;\n,eJ..\nli\nn\n70\n58\n\",74..\"\n\"\n\u2022l\n75\n58\n'\u25a073..''\n\"\n5\n73\n58\n\"    ..\"\n\"\n'\u2022        fi\n08\n58\n\"    ..9\n\"\n\"          7\n00\n58\n({               ((\n\"\n\"          8\n05\n50\n\"    .. 10\n!&gt;sw2\nEquinoctial ,.\nmoment.\n01\n54\n\",73..\"\n\u00ab\nMar. 20th, 10\n11\n01\n69\n51\n55\n\",74..\"\n(t            14\ns2\nit\n\"        12\n58;\n55\n\"   ..\"\n\"\nMarch 21st, 1 A. M.\n58\n55\n\u2022'   ..\"\n\"\n\"         2\n\"       :i\n\"       t\n57,\n57\n50$\n55\n55\n55\n\"   ..-'-\nII\n\"           5\n50\n55\n\"   ..\"\ns s e 1\n\"          0\n50\n52\n\",73.. 8\nti\n7\n58\n55\n\",75..\"\n\u00bb\n\"          8\n\u00abli\n5G\n\"    ..\"\n\u00bb\ny\n05\n57\n\"    ..\u00ab\nii\n10\n73\n02\n\",77..  G\n\"\n\"      n\n77\n01\n\"      .8\ns\n\"        12\n70\n64\n\"    .. 0\n((\n\"       i r. m.\n80\n00\n\",75..\"\nswl\n(1                Q\n81\n05\n.\"    ..\"\n(i\n\"       :i\n79\n05\n\",74..\"\n\u00ab\n4\n78\n01\n\",75..\"\n'&lt;\nREMARKS.\u2014Afaic*SO.5A.M.\u2014Smoky. AtO-do. 7\u2014Winds rising. S\u2014rtu\n9\u2014Wind falling, ei p. M\u2014Low streaks of strains. 7\u2014do. 0\u2014Sovoral P\u00bblc\nwliiic iiiciitorH will, loiiS lulls. March 'il, 5 A. M.\u2014Wander Ing slrolii-cuiiisl'i8-.\nB-elo.il,,. 7\u2014 do. do. 13\u2014Wandering scudding stratus, n-do.dd. 10\u2014Clouds\nthickening. 11-do.scatlorlng. A cistern SO fuel elcc|., te-iiiiioriCiircf'l\" A\"'11\n66 feci deep, temporaturo OH ZjUiacal light reaching across the \" irnlkr v\/,r\"\ncccrj clem orenlng.","fullrs":{},"find":"505.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"504","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1534198","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.46 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
