<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/424</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>424</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/424/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"%\n1: 1\"\";\n-'.\u25a0'\u25a0-iS...\nJ'*'1\n:'l-i,'\"'I!\nr\n!\u25a0%-;;\ni;lf'\n'   \u25a0!.    \u25a0\n177 -\nii'''\nr\nif\nI'\nI ii-\n\u25a0Vi *\nf    \u25a0 '\n58\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nThucydides and Xenophon, by Sallust. Livy and Tacitus. I that Byron, though not a profound scholar, formed his taste\nFirst on the list of English poets stands Milton, whose genius and style by a perusal of classic  writers,  however imperfect\nwas \"universal as his theme, as nature various, as heaven sublime ;\" who seems equally in his native element when rising\non venturous wing, he soars extrajlammnnlia mania mundt,\n\" Passe3 the flaming bounds of space,\nWhere angsls tremble while they gaze,\"\nascends the highest empyrean, scans the awful mysteries of\nthe Eternal Throne, and depicts the amaranthine bowers, the\nriver, and the tree of life of the celestial paradise; as when\nhe reposes amid the embowering shades of the garden of fids^ and describes the happy converse of our first parents, ere\nyet their felicity had been blighted by the fall; or descending to the dark abodes of guilt, and even opens to us the\ncouncils of Pandemonium, and discloses the dread secrets ol\nmay have been his attainments, or desultory his application,\nHow was his enthusiasm kindled when first he trod theckis.\nsic land of Italy and Greece,   nd viewed tht   battle-grounds\nof Marathon and Pl.itrei, and \" imoonquered Salamis\"!  With\nwhat rapture did he gaze on the bright isles of the iEgean \u25a0\nThe Isles of Greece! the isles of Greece I\nWhere burning Sappho loved and sung,\nWhere grew Ihe arts of war and peace,\nWhere Del,is rose and Phoebus sprung!\nHis poetry breathes the very inspiration of Helicon.    As to\nthe impurities which tire found in the classics, when we are\npointed to the poetry of a notion more pure and chaste, it will\nbe time enough to answer that objection.  Il is easy, however,\n, to obviate that difficulty, by the.use of expurgated editions,\nthe prison-house o  despair.    Milton was the most learned     , . *   , *      . _       .\n' .   .       , \u25a0     ,    \u25a0 ,    ti i    ,    \u25a0       i which have been provided for the purpose.    Em what shall\nan of his times, intimately acquainted with all the Latin and '. .      '    ' .   .\nwe say ol the abominations ol the Heathen mythology? They\nwho object lo the classics on this ground, would, on the same\nGreek authors, whom he loved, studied,  and  imitated, and\nfrequently  rivalled and excelled them  nil,    We know not\n,'        - , , ,,-,        \u2022 ,i   i principle, destroy Ihe finest  models ol sculpture, the V e,\nwhich most to admire, the exuberance of Ins learning-, or the '        r. \u2022 ,\nHercules, ecc., because they represent heathen gods and god-\nWith more than savage blindness and falsely Christian zeal, they would make nn auto da fe of the noblest monuments of ancient genius, because they contained the names\nof Jupiter nnd   Minerva,  Apollo and Mars,     fs it supposed\nnot a servile copyist, nor yet cramped by his knowledge of .\nthe ancients.     Why need we enumerate Pope, Addison,\nSwift, &amp;c? Indeed, with the exception of Burns, Bloonilield.\nand a few others, the brilliant galaxy of English poets, sing-, ,\n, . .    . ..  ,        ;    , it,        iibnt boys will become heathens, by reading heathen eocts?\nIy stirs of th.1 first mignituae, and whose milled  lustre so ,.     , ,      ,'-,,.       ,   ,       ,\n,.,.,.       .ii-        ,-       f, it hhouiiliioihmg be present! d to the mind butstrict naked truth?\nglonouslv irradiates the lionzoi ol our literature, were allj ,       .  .   .        , . ,   , ,      ,\nllien those works ol fiction which Mr. Grimke so highly\nrecommends, Scoll's novels and poetry, should share the same\nIfale with Ovid's Metamorphoses. Were the mind of man\nonly pure intellect, without either feeling or fancy, simple\ntruth would be sufficii nt, unanimatcd by expression, unadorned by the graces of style and elocution.    But nre not imagi-\ncl tssical scholars. Shakespeare, so often tuiuted us such, is no\nexception. This poet \"l nature, as he is styled, at whos\nbid ling the attendant spirits of heaven, earth, and lull, a;\npear, and act their parts in his drama, with inimitable propriety, whose fancy ascended the highest heaven of invention,\nan.I hiving exhausted the world of reality, proceeded to form\nimaginary worlds, and peopled lium with femes ol its own\ncreation, we are in leed informed by bis biographer, knew but\nlittle Latin and less &lt; In i k. but evi n that little, in the more\nthorough and finished systt in of English education, was pro-\nbably more than most of our American College graduates\nacquire. Hjovidently was deeply imbued with the spirit ol\nthe classics, and had fully entered into their feelings nnd character. His Romans are truly Roman, and his &lt; Ireeks acl\nas citizens of Athens or Lact demon would have acted. In\nour own country, whore do wo find tho most chaste an I \"I\ngant writers? Is it not where classical learning is most studiously cultivated. Even those who'arenot classical scholars,\nform their style from a perusal of authors who fashioned\nthemselves on classical models. [f classical learning is\nunnecessary, why have so few stars arisen to adorn ihe literary horizon with unborrowed lustre ? Because a few men, like\nFranklin, of transcend.mt abilities, have arisen io eminence\nand distinction without a knowledge of Latin and Greek,\nsome have inferred that they are altogether useless, llow\nfallacious is such reasoning-, and how absurd the conclusion\ntD which it laadsl How preposterous to imagine, that such\nmm became great, in consequence of a defective or erroneous education, when in truth they became so in despite ol\nit! \"Decipit cxamplar vitiis imitabile.\" Byron, we are told,\ndisliked Horace, and yet became a great poet. To this we reply,\nnation and the passions constituent parts of our nature, as\nwell as reason and judgment? Can any system of education be correct, which does not provide for their improvement\nand proper direction? We might here contrast the mathematics and tiie langiiagi s in this respect, hut we ri serve our observations for a subsequent essay, in which we design lo trace\nthe parallel more particularly. Suffice it to remark, at present, ihat though wo cannot give tho arithmetic of the classics,\nand compute their value in dollars and cents, yet arc we incalculably indebted to them in a thousand ways.\nf I'll  BE CONCLUDED IN Tin; NEXT M'.MI'.KIl.]\nPROCEEDINGS\ntn in- Missis -i|,|,i Assncl i i'.n- ii\u201e- prcimoilon of Education,\nThe delegates to this Association met, on Monday. January\n8, 1S3S, pursuant to adjournment, at the State House in\nJackson.\nOn motion of Mr. N. Lester, the Rev. M. Reid was called\nto the chair, and M. R. Dudley, Esq., appointed Secretary.\nThe importance of the object for which the delegates had\nassembled, having been stated by the Chair, on motion of Mr.\nDiibuisson, it was,\nResolved, That a committee of three be appointed to draw\nup resolutions for the consideration of this convention, and\nthat the same be reported al an adjourned meeting. Committee to consist of Messrs. Diibuisson, Lester, and Tift.","fullrs":{},"find":"425.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"424","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1812904","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
