<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/477</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>477</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/477/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\n\u2022: \u00bb&amp;\nw\ni!fl\n\u00bb\u25a0''.'\nii:l\n104\nSOUTHWESTERN  JOURNAL.\ncultivation of the intellect and the acquisition of learning\nmay, and sometimes do, become the means of injury to the individuals themselves, and to the community generally, nnd\ndo not necessarily lead to the study or practice of morality :\nwhereas a correct moral training fits the subjects of it lo become useful members of sociely, and its natural tendency is\nto dispose them to improve their minds. And above all,\nSuch a-trnining renders their eternal salvation more probable;\nas il is the instrumentality which God oidinarily employs in\nthe conversion of the heart.\nBut the standard of literary acquirements nmong femal-\nis fir too low. This is owing chiefly to the influence of a pi\nValent sentiment among the other sex; viz. thai it is both un-\nneccssary nnd inexpedient to elevate this stnndaiel above the\nordinary calls of that spline in which tiny nre tie stint d lo\nmove. This unworthy prejudice has manifested itself in the\nbestowment of opprobrious epithets upon such as have\ndared to venture on the forbidden ground of a more exalted\nand enlarged literature. The phrase \"blue-stocking,\" as\napplied to learned females, nrose from a very contracted and\npartial estimate of the female mind, and of ils legitimate vocation, if not from vanity and jealousy.\nBut we trust that this sentiment is passing away with the\nages in which it originated, and with the barbarous heathenism of which it is a remnant. Heathenism gave birth to,\nand nurtures that sliong public sentiment which, where ii\nprevails, decrees the milder sex to ignorance and servitude.\nThe light nnd inllu. nee of the gospel, wherever it has\nspread, have struck off tin if fillets, and redeemed them from\nthe bondage in which they were he Id. The Christian re-\nligioil elevates woman to her proper rank, and restores to her\nthe rights and privileges with which she was endowed by\nher Creator. As woman, therefore, should be the last to repudiate or neglect the religion to which she is so much in\ndebted, so she sho lid be among the first to cherish and cultivate literature, the handmaid and ally of Christianity. As\nthe one has restored her to liberty and rank, so the other,\nby its light nnd power, enables her to maintain them against\nfuture aggressions.\nFor what is civilization, but the result of education, in tin\nexpanded sense of that term ? A correct mental and moral\ntraining brings about that state of society, in which the\nrights and immunities of women are acknowledged and respected. Wc need not travel to other countries, or look back\ntoo'.her ages, for an exemplification of thistruth. Turn your\neyes upon the aborigines of our own land, nnd mark the\ncondition of the present generation Behold the servitude\nand degradation of ihe female sex, among the tribes that\nroam through our forests, and then learn to estimate your indebtedness to religion and literature. How beautiful and appropriate is the brief but comprehensive eulogy which another has pronounced upon the sex: \" latest at the cross, and\nearliest at the sepulchre.\"\nThat females nre not dcfHent in point of intellect is\nabundantly evident from the works of those who i. v.,\nfrom time to time, appeared before the public, in the character of authors.     Nor are their works confined to the lightei\nthe limited number of well educated females, have bundled\nwith skill and profound research, the more severe end nt.stiusc\npoints of mental and moral, as Well as natural science.\nThe term education is also too limited in its meaning, if it\nregard merely the acquisition of ideas.     The mental trninino\nwhich it properly incluih s, is far more impoiti.ru for all practical purposes, than the knowledge to be derived from books\nmerely.    For example, let a female peruse carefully and attentively, a work of close, analogical or analytical reasoning\nsuch as Butler's Analogy, Edwards on the Will, Euclid's\nElements, or Fearne's Essay on Contingent Remainders,and\nExecutory Devises, (provided she were  familiar with legal\ntechnicalities,) and we venture to affirm that the training arid\ndiscipline which her mind would derive from such u siu.lv,\nwould be of far more nvail to  her, than all  the ideas she\nwould acquire from the bonks themselves.    Whin the mind\nis thus subjected to a severe discipline, it is expanded and\nstrengthened ; the life, the vigor, the freshness, wilh which il\noperates in the cone.ption, arrangement, and elucidation0\/\nthought, are vastly more to be desired than that dependent\nand torpid reliance upon the thoughts of other men, whicht\nmere book reader betrays, however grout may be the rude\nand undigested mass of borrowed ideas which he may thus\nhave obtained.    It is one thing to read,anil it is quite aiiotliei\ntiling to study.    We should mingle our own thoughts, as vre\nproceed in a work, with those of the writer.    We should\nclose Ihe hook, even in the middle of a sentence, and follow\nout, by meditation or writing, the train of thought which a\nword, or phrase, or sentiment of the writer, may have stig.\ngested to our own mind.    The mind should be thus habituated to independent and original thinking, and be taught lo\nmove onward in its own t-tn ngth.    A child must be lailghl\nto walk by nn occasional reliance upon ils own ability, so the\nmind must frequently be thrown upon ils own resources, and\nbe left without the extraneous aids and. props on which it\nwould otherwise rely, and become enervate and subservient\nFemales commonly discover great timidity in committing\ntheir thoughts to paper, but perhaps they could not accustom themselves to a more profitable exercise. This will\ncourt thought, and lead to method and perspicuity. A correct style, a readiness and felicity of expression are the results of careful practice; and when chastened with that peculiar delicacy with which the female mind tempers its own\nconceptions, they become doubly attractive and impressive.\nSuch we apprehend to bo Ihe legitimate meaning ofthe\nterm education, when applied to the intellectual faculties; for\nthe acquisition and multiplication of ideas by no means a-\nhaust its signification.\nTo what extent the education of females must necessarily\nbe carried, in order to answer the ends for which it is 1*\nstowed, I do not venture to determine. Their situation nne.\ncalling in life, beintr so different from those of the othersci,\nmust have due weight in deciding this question. It is. a\nthis account, unfair to settle ibis question by iho rule s which\nipply to the other sex, and equally so, to estimate their I1'!\"\"*\nmd acquirements by a comparison with those of the opp'!l\"\nsex: for the latter commonly receive their education with In.'\n1\nbranches of literature, but some, and nol a few, considering | view to some particular vocation, which determines the c\nhat'","fullrs":{},"find":"478.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"477","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1775816","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
