<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/421</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>421</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/421/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"\\r\nS O U T H - W K 3 T E II N JOURNAL.\n|,jbi(j\u2014and have recommended the study of things, instead\nof words; of natural philosophy, of the arts and sciences,\nrather than that of philology and the classics. We have\nbeen gravely told, that the pursuit of classical learning, is a\nuseless wasle of time; that it is calculated lo contract the\nmind, by a too minute attention to the study of words, which\nought to be directed to ideas, of which words are merely the\nvehicles ; and that it has a tendency to pervert the taste, corrupt the morals, and deprave the heart. These are serious\nand weighty charges; and, could they be substantiated, would\ngo far towards justifying the clamor which has been raised\nagainst the dead languages, as they are called. This sentiment, sanctioned by so high authority, has been echoed by\nthousands, who have no adequate knowledge of that which\nthey thus gratuitously condemn. A blind man judging of\ncolors, or a deaf man, of the harmony of sounds, would be\njust as rational, as an ignoramus, or superficial sciolist, deciding on the merits of the great original writers of Greece and\nHome, which arc as far beyond his comprehension, as they\nare above his censure. The vulgar prejudice, indeed, seems\nto regard Latin and Greek as a kind of black letter, or mysterious something, having no connection with the system 01\nnature, or human affairs, as unintelligible and as useless as\nEgyptian hieroglyphics, as if the classics were studied merely for the sake of the form, or sound of the letters, and not\nfor the stores of taste, knowledge, and sentiment they contain.\nThese modern Vandals, would wage a war of extermination\nagainst the Latin and Greek authors, the finest monuments\nthat remain of ancient genius, which, like the Venus of Praxiteles, and the Apollo Belvidcre, still stand forth to the admiration of the world, as models, in their kind, of unrivalled\nexcellence.\nSuppose the classics discarded from our systems of education, and again banished to the; cloisters of monks and schoolmen ; or preserved, like other relics of antiquity, only in the\ncabinets of the curious, what shall we substitute in their Stead?\nShall they be entirely superseded by the mathematics and\nnatural philosophy ?    Far be it from us to depreciate the exact\nsciences.    Their utility, both from the intellectual discipline\nwhich they furnish, and their various and important applications to the every day practical business of life, has been ably\nportrayed by the learned gentleman who preceded mo in this\ndiscussion, and are admitted without controversy.    We wish\nnot to undervalue mathematical and scientific studies.    To\nscience, indeed, we nre unspeakably indebted.    It has added\ninfinitely to mini's accommodation, in every department.   The\ncompass, Ihe telescope, the microscope, the air-pump, the elec\ntricul machine, have given to man new faculties, and opened\nnew worlds to his view.   The lightning-rod of Dr. Franklin\nand the safety-lamp of Sir Humphrey Davy, by which thousands of valuable lives have been saved, are prouder trophies\nof the triumphs of science, than the pyramids of Egypt, or\nall the monuments of Grecian and Roman antiquity.    The\nsteam-engine alone has accomplished more for the benefit of\nmankind, than the united achievements of ancient art and\ngenius.\nFor what, then, do we contend, when we maintain that the\nsciences should not bo cultivated to tho exclusion, or even the\ncomparative neglect, of polite literature ?    We maintain that\nthe sciences should not supersede the belles lettres, as they are\nthe best foundation on which to erect the lofty superstructure\nof science; and that scientific studies should be postponed, until a considerable proficiency has been made in classical learning.    It seems necessary to urge attention to this point, as the\nsciences seem to have become nowall the rage with many in our\nown country, as they were recently in France ; and Latin and\nGreek have been proscribed and banished, as enemies, doubtless to science and religion, from some of our higher seminaries of learning.    Experience, however, that only sure test\nof truth, abundantly refutes all the thousand plausible objections, and satirical reflections, about teaching dead languages,\nand words, instead of things; and has led, in France, as it\ndoubtless will, wherever else the attempt may be made to discard classical learning, to an abandonment of the former theory on the subject, and a restoration to the classics of all their\nimmunities.   It is the dictate of nature, that words should be\nstudied in childhood. At how early an age, do we learn, almost\nas by instinct, our mother tongue!   Subjects requiring strong\nintellect, should be postponed, until the mind has attained a con.\nsiderable degree of maturity.    Then words, formed into sentences, their connection, dependence, and relations to one another, may with advantage be considered. These, surely, are things\nof importance, and necessary to the Understanding of subjects\nofthe first importance, such as geography, history, &amp;c. Low\nmuch a knowledge of the ancient languages facilitates the understanding of our own, may be inferred, when we state, that\nthe whole number of words in the English language, is estimated al from one hundred and thirty to one hundred and forty thousand.    Of fifteen thousand primitives, more lhan two-\nthirds are derived either directly from the Latin, or through\nthe medium of the French.   The remaining one hundred and\nfifteen or twenty thousand are compounds, resolvable mainly\ninto Latin and Greek, and must be etymologically analyzed,\nbefore they can be thoroughly understood, and their significant\ncy, and exact meaning ascertained.    Of what avail is all the\nimposing apparatus of science, microscopes, telescopes, electrical machines, air pumps, nay the array of the whole Encyclopaedia, or circle of the arts and sciences, including botany,\nmineralogy, us well as entomology, and conchology, or the\nscience of bugs, worms and shells, wilh the addition, if you\nplease, of phrenology, that fashionable modern science, el id\nomne. genus,\u2014of what avail, I say,are all these to a lad twelve\nor fourteen years old, when he cannot comprehend even the\nnomenclature, the very terms of the arts and sciences, which,\nunfortunately, are borrowed, almost without exception, from\nthe Latin and Greek languages?    We are aware, that the\nattempt has been made to bring down the language of science\nto the comprehension of infants; but we fear this mode of instruction, to the exclusion of the good old classical, is extremely deceptive.    This Encyclopaedia kind of education, may\nindeed gratify parents with an idea of the wonderful profi-\niency of their children, but cannot, we humbly conceive, be\nproductive of any solid improvement.    To the acquisition of\nany really valuable attainment in science, masculine powers of\nmind, and maturity of judgment, are indispensably requisite.\nThe dead languages, so often abused by the ignorant and su-\n%\\\n&gt;&lt;\n,41 .  '.\nSi\n- 14\n1\n'J\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"422.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"421","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1806120","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
