<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/350</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>350</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/350/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"0 U TH.-WE STERN   J'i U I) N A I,\naces, was, \"It is just us uias.-a pleases,\"\u2014perfectly willing\nto be knocked down, kicked, or abused in any other way.\nthat ore's spleen might suggest, so that they were paid lor\ntheir submission by the preseiltof a rupee.\nAs soon as the news of the arrival of a new ship had been\nbruited about, we were visited by all kinds of jugglers, necromancers and musicians, all equally anxious to do something\nfor our amusement, and all equally averse lo any rejection of\ntheir kind proffers for our entertainment. The jugglers of\nthis place are probably no! excelled in skill by any in the\nworld. They perform their legerdemain with a perfection\nthat will deceive the most rigid scrutiny, 1 bail one of them\nbrought to my room, and there seated on the Hour, directly\nbefore me, I watched him with tie- closi st attention, without\nhopes to propitiate the favor of heaven, and earn eternal honors hereafter. This eminence overlooks a large extent of\nbeautiful country, generally flat, but here and there relieved\nby undulations, that serve to destroy the lameness of a nr,\nfeet level. The delicacy of the scenery, the softened vista of\nobjects rendered enchanting by the distance, together UlIj\nthe proximity or the sacred fire, which is perpetually sending\nup its holy incense as an oblation to the throne ol' the most\nhigh, conspire to consecrate this spot to martyrdom, and lo\ncast around it a melancholy and unearthly enchantment\nwhich raises the soul above its attachment to the thinc,s \u201ef\nearth, and reconciles it to the separation or those ties that bind\nit to mortality.\nOn the road between Madras and the mount, the friends of\nbeing able to detect him in the least particular;  lor.  so per- the lamented bishop  Ileber, have erected a very handsome\nfectly was  he enabled to elude my vigilance, that the rogue)cenotaph in commemoration of their respect for his virt\ncontrived to put a loathsome looking snake into my hand,\nwhich I hud extended for a piece of cork that he held between his thumb and finger. This surprised me the more,\nas he wore no garment about the upper part of his body, in\nwhich it might have been concealed; he performed a hun\ndred other tricks mid antics, that want of time will not permit me to mention. There were other fellows who exhibited themselves out of doors in the performance of foats of tin\nexnmpled dexterity. 1 saw a fellow balance himself upon an\nunsupported pole, about eight I'eet high, and, in that position,\n(which he preserved without apparent effort,) dexterously\nthrew into the air three large swords, and caught them again\nas they descended. He then took a large round stone, weighing eight or ten pounds, and threw it with great force liir\nabove his head, and caught it again exactly upon the back or\nhis neck, where it lodged as firmly as if it had been received\nin a socket, lie then lay down upon his back, and, taking\na three-pronged, spear-pointed instrument, hurled it into the\nair. and allowed the weapon to fiill directly upon him; but\nhis dexterity had so directed it, that the spears, in their descent, passed one on each side of his legs, and buried themselves in the earth, without wounding him in the least. This\nrash I'eat he performed several times, until we desired him to\ndesist, and we dismissed him and his companions, after giving\nto each a dram of brandy, which, however contrary to their\ncreed, they plainly evinced was not contrary to their tastes;\nfor three of them drank oil'a pint or raw brandy, without\none drop of water or other diluent.\nOne or the first things that a stranger is apt to notice in\nMadras, is the beautiful smoothness of the streets and of the\nroads in the vicinity. No heavily loaded wagon or cart is\npermitted to travel on them; and by this precaution, they are\npreserved in a fine condition for carriages and vehicles of\npleasure. One of the most beautiful of these roads, is that\nleading to the Mount of St. Thomas, an eminence about ten\nmiles from Madras, so called from being the reputed spot\nwhere the saint was crucified whose name it bears. In commemoration of the sacred event, a small Catholic chapel\nhas been erected upon its summit, and upon the altar of the\nchapel a fire is kept constantly burning, attended by a holy\nfather, who thus in humble solitude, has devoted himself to\ni lod, and by the penance of his estrangement from the world,\nand talents. Almost every spot in India abounds with the\nremembrance of the labors and virtues of this worthy mntl\nand to none could they more appropriately erect a monument\nthat should transmit to posterity the honorable distinction of\nhis name and the glory of his episcopal labors.\nThe evening after our return rrom St. Thomas, we strolled forth to visit the bazaars; to peep into the temples and spy\nout if possible the manners and customs or the natives. During our rambles about the city, we encountered a number of\nyoung persons, male and female, preceded by a man riding\niqion a very small Brahmin ox, blowing a trumpet, followed\nby others on foot, making hideous noises on other wind instruments. These were followed by girls bearing baskets,\ndecorated with flowers, anil chanting some words to which\nthe discord or the wind instruments, seemed a very appropriate accompaniment. Our curiosity prompted us to make inquiry respecting the object and nature of this procession, and\nwe learned that the girls were bearing presents of congratulation to one of their young acquaintances, who had recently\nbeen admitted to the rights and privileges or a woman.\nThe precocity of physical development, induced by a warm\nclimate and by peculiar habits of life, is no where more\nstrongly exhibited than among the natives of the East Indies,\nmil particularly of those on the coast of Coromandel. It is\nno uncommon occurrence to see mothers or not more than\neleven or twelve years or age, healing children in theirarms\nso delicately small that one might almost imagine that Dean\nSwift's story of the Ijilliputs was no fable.\nHaving transacted our business at Madras, we weighed\nanchor, and by*the assistance or favorable winds, were in a\nfew days oil\" the sand heads or the Hoogly. Here we hove\nto and anxiously waited for a pilot to guide us safely through\nits dangerous passes. We were not however doomed to wait\nmany hours, as the pilot schooners are ever on the alert to\nrender their assistance to vessels going up the Hoogly, and we\nsoon descried something, moving down toward us like a spirit\nupon the fiice of the waters, which proved to be the wished\nlor pilot vessel; its boat was soon manned and pushed oil,\nbringing to us a pilot, not a rough man, in sailor's garb, as I\nexpected (o see, but a person of very gentlemanly appear-\nanco, bringing with him a leadsman, servant and appurtenances to boot\u2014such as trunks, bags, dressing cases, segar.-,\n\u25a0E","fullrs":{},"find":"351.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"350","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1775954","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
