<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/528</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>528</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/528/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:05">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I''\"J Jirt\n\\66\n5 O V T H - W E 9 T E \u00abN  JOURNAL.\nIii\n.\npatient of repose, makes friendship with (he vine, expands its\nvernal buds, sends forth ils spiral tendrils, and clothes the naked arbors with a rich covering-of luxuriant leaves j and when\nPomona loads ripe autumn with her offering of mellow\nfruits, within the purple grape hoards up its new-earned treasures. Here it delays awhile, and when the husbandman\nwould change the nature of his fruit, und turn ils mellow\njuices into wine, our little drop again finds occupation. It\ntransfuses tho affinities that were in play in the grape juice,\nand constitutes a new order of combinations, which result in\nthe formation of a new principle, a curious and powerful\nproduct, which, if employed with rational and becoming mod\neration, constitutes a pleasant and enlivening draught, that an\nimatcs the body, calls forth the piquant energies of the mind,\nand may be made the harmless and appropriate symbol of a\nfriendly offering: but if abused, it wields a mighty and a\nfiendish mastery o'er the fate of man, who too oft bends the\nsuppliant knee in servile worship at altars built for human\nsacrifice, and there, without emotion, hears tho inexorable\ndoom, that oceans of bitter tears, wrung from ihe broken\nhearts of disappointed hope, cannot avert. From spirit our\nlittle drop returns again to water, and, in their turn, goes\nthrough each grade of vegetable growth, from high to low-\nestate, neglecting none, and, with its Protean powers, to each\nand every one performing equal duty.\nBut its powers are by no means limited to that scries of\nactions, which appertain exclusively to vegetable organization. It is equally capable of superintending and conducting those combinations of matter which result in the formation of animal structures. From the simple zoophile up to\nthe perfect and more exalted formation of man himself, every\nchange of structure, every variety of animal matter, bone,\nmuscle, the vital fluid, blood, tho brain itself, are all the products of our little talisman. With a spirit of ubiquity, il\npervades each part, and from the first budding forth of vl\ntality, until the full development of vigorous maturity, its\nunwearied energies are constantly employed. Now it is\nconjoined witii that set of vital movements that are devoted\nto the growth of the animal; at one moment taking up and\nsaturating itself with new principles; al another depositing\nthem in their proper order; again, we see it decomposing\nand carrying off' the worn-out atoms of the frame, and in its\nturn, replenishing and filling up the wasted vigor of some\nexhausted function.\nWhen we consider that man, the self constituted lord of\ncreation, derives his sustenance from the same source, and is\nindebted to the same creative energies, for the. perfection of\nhis form, the endurance of his functions, and the vigor of his\nnerves, as is the little worm that crawls upon the earth and\nbites the dust, we must be impressed with a humiliating\nsense of our own insignificance, and stand mute with astonishment at the power, which can develope such varied results, with so few and such simple agents.\nWe may watch the progress of our deop through (be human frame; first imbued with some nutritious particles extracted from the food, it enters the little vessels appropriated\nto the chyle and rapidly passes to the heart, where it mingles with tho current of lifo which circulates through every\nvessel of the frame; now in the heart itself, it sustel:, .., i\nassists the never ceasing action ofthis important organ main\ntains its vigor and supplies its wants, while it distributes wilh\nimpartial diligence the perennial current of vitality. [yM1\ndrawn to the curious structure of the eye, it helps to fom\nand fashion this inimitable instrument, floating in the armi.\nlino humors that fill tho anterior chamber of this organ-;,\ncollects the scattered light-beams that impinge upon the surface and bears them to the lens, thereto be refracted nnd then\ntransmitted through the vitreous humor, lo be finally arrant\ned with beautiful precision upon the walls of the sensitive\nretina, from whence, the optic nerve, with prompt obedience\ntelegraphs the picture to the mind.    Having thus gamboled\nwith the light, and witnessed the imponderable fluid beating true portraits of distant and inaccessible objects, it passes\nto the ear, and hides itself within the curious labyrinths of\nthis auditory structure ; here listening to the. din of confused\nnoises it carefully assigns lo each its respective origin ot\nlakes delight in the harmonious concord of soft and mellow\nsounds, or forsooth, it listens to those vows that youthful\nhearts reciprocate when first the tender buddings of affection\narc bursting into bloom : or when the interest of novelty is\ngone, and capricious love's ephemeral life has closed, it\nwakes to close attention, and carefully marks down each bitter and unkind reproach, and makes those sounds, thai once\nould send their melodious impulse to tho heart, grate like\nthe harsh discords of recriminating tongues.\nThe ever changing susceptibilities of our drop, may successively direct it to every oilier organ of the frame, until it\nhall have passed not only through the secondary and subordinate parts of the system, but through the brain itself; here\nit watches over the mysterious unity of mind and matter, eliminates the actuating passions of the soul, and is conversant\nwith the secret agents of the illimitable thought. These\nnever ceasing mutations may carry it through every link in\nthe grand chain of animated nature, and if confined to one\nindividual, in the series, it will superintend every action,\nevery organ and function, administer to every necessity and\ndesire; hold equal supervision while the elastic frame of\nyouth bounds freely o'er the ground, and when the shortened step of after years proclaims a change; preside wbilethe\nhalcyon days of youth are prodigal of smiles and sunshine,\nor when misfortune's lowering clouds o'ertakc decrepitude,\nthere will it be to make disease more poignant, and in the\nactive joint, that knew no pain, breed rheum and crabbed\ngout. It may mellow the voice of manhood and float upon\nthe words of friendship or of passion; it may soften the ruby\nlip of infancy, and exhale upon the breath of innocence, lo\nbe again condensed and sparkle ns a tear within the modest\neye of beauty, or sit as an emblem of sorrow upon the wan\ncheek of the distressed.\nFor Iho WoulliWcBlorn Jon'\u2122'\nIMITATION.\nWe often bear it said\u2014by the most superficial observers\nloo\u2014that man is an imitative being.    No saying can be moie\ntrue.    It is a maxim long ago established by Aristotle himself, and more and more confirmed by time and observation.","fullrs":{},"find":"529.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"528","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1765625","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
