<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/374</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>374</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/374/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n13\nguide-board set up at the entrance of an avenue which leads to\njj\u2014.-. &gt;p0 uie Jd,jrc.umv&lt;\u2014jn flaming letters\u2014painted by one\nofthe members\u2014great was the wonderment ofthe little town\n\u2022 if Bungay. It had not quite subsided indeed when I reached\nhere. The country boys still stop in the lane to cypher\nout, 1 saw a knot of them the other day.\u2014They made it out\nat last to be a \"Lyckem-pla.ee,\" and that was all they could\nmake of it. I dare say it was taken for a school\u2014or an Insane\nAsylum.\" \t\nA Clerical Lyceum.\u2014The junior ministers of the\nMississippi Conference have formed themselves into a Lyceum\nfor m intal improvement, There was a meeting ofthe Lyceum\nhe! I during the late session of the Conference in Natchez.\nVale Pastor!\u2014Professor Wilson, the editor of Blackwood's Magazine and the author ofthe \"Nodes Ambrosianie\"\nof that publication\u2014yea, the \"vera Shepherd himsel,\" is\nsuffering that dreadful calamity which often soenns to impend\nover men of genius; he is demented. As Swift too truly feared\nfor his own case, so has it happened to Professor Wilson\u2014\n' \"iodic at the top first.\" Farewell, then, to the author ofthe\n\" Lights and Shadows of Scottish life!\" farewell to the racy\nperiotls of that flowing and eloquent pen ! The mind that\npit-sided in the temple has departed. The flame of intellect\nhas flickered from the urn\u2014mid now all is darkness.\nCOLLEGES IN THE UNITED STATES.\nThere are at present ninety-five College's in the United\nSia! 'S, divided rather unequally among the several States.\nWe have not the names of all theso institutions before us\u2014nor\nis i material, we suspect, in regard to many of them, whether\ntin y have any namoor not. A good College will he known\nby its reputation; and tho moonshine institutions, or modorn\npatent machines for turning out unkempt leather heads upon\nthe world, should be forever anomalous.\nThe following list shews the number of Colleges in each\nslate:\u2014\nMaine, 2; New Hampshire, 1; Vermont, 3; Massachusetts, 3; Rhode Island, 1; Connecticut, 3; New York, G;\nNew Jersey, 2; Pennsylvania, If); Delaware, 1; Maryland,\nI. District of Columbia, 2; Virginia, 5; North Carolina, 1;\nSouth Carolina, 2; Georgia, 1; Alabama, 3; Mississippi,\n3; Louisiana, 3; Tennessee, 5; Kentucky, 7; Ohio, 11\nIndiana, 3; Illinois, 5; Missouri, 0; Michigan, 2.\nIn noticing the distribution of these institutions in tho differ\nen; States, the fact can scarcely escape observation that the\nolder and better educated Stales have the fewer Colleges\nthey may have the better ones. Used as mediums of elevating and improving the minds of a recent population, the Colleges of some of the now states may have their value equal to\nthat of indiflcrent grammar schools; but it would be better if\ntheir titles bore some relation to their literary standing. A\npompous, titled, but unendowed and obscure institution burlesques Ihe time-honored name of College, and disrobes it of\nits classic and moral associations. It is the harlequin aping\nthe celebrated actor, and earning a laugh at the expense of\nmerit and genius.\nWe are friendly to well endowed and firmly established\nColleges in the different sections of the United State's; but, by\nthe foregoing list, it would seem that some single States have\nnominal Colleges enough to supply (if they were good for\nany thing) half the territory ofthe Union.\nGiuaro Colleoe.\u2014'Phis edifice, sacred to the education\nofthe orphan, is rising in grandeur by the impulse of that\nprincely bequest which has immortalized the name of the\ndonor and will entail upon him the blessings of future generations. The exterior walls of the noble pile have risen to\ntheir full height, and one of those marble pillars, six feet in\ndiameter at the base and sixty feet in height, which are to\nsurround the entire edifice, has been fitted to its place. The\ninterest of the immense bequest is only permitted to be expended in the building. From this cause, and from the\nlength oftime necessary to build permanently, the college will\nnot be finished in less than two years from this time. When\ncompleted, one writer says, it will be a wilderness of marble.\nWithout doubt the structure will beggar the appearance ofthe\nbe'st college edifices in America, and compete with, if not excel, the proudest halls of instruction in the old world.\nMr. Cache, the President elect of Girard college, is now\ntravelling in Europe, preparatory to bis labors over these\nhalls sacred to charity and learning.\nTin: Annular Eclipse ok the Sun in 1838\u2014This\nremarkable eclipse will occur on the 18th of September next,\nand will present tho annulus, or luminous ring, to all those inhabitants ofthe United States between whom and the Sun's\nexact centre the moon shall pass. The eclipse will be annular over a space 42(1 miles wide. Tho annular path will approach the United States from the Northwest through Luke\nSuperior, Wisconsin Territory, Michigan, Lake Erie, the\nNortheast part of Ohio, the Southeastern part of Pennsylvania, ihe Western part, of Maryland, Northern part of Vir-\ninia. Southern pari of Maryland, Eastern shore of Virginia,\nnd thence Southeasterly into the Atlantic Ocean. It will\noccur between 3 and 0 I*. M., and will present nothing more\nthan a partial eclipse of the Sun to those living on either side\nof the pre scribed path across the territory of the United Stales,\n-120 miles in width.\nEur the Soutliweitern Journal.\nTHE POET'S DIRGE.\nBury me deep in the ocean wave,\nLet tin, mermaid o'er me weep,\nLet the lotus grow round my quiet grave,\nThe bed of my long last sleep.\nLet naught ofthe hollow world be seen\nWhere my bleaching bones shall be -,\nBut lay me down in the silver stream\nOfthe murmuring summer sea.\nThere's nunc that will drop a friendly tear\nWhen the exile's race is run\u2014\nNil hand will plant o'crmy lonely bier\nThe child of a summer sun.\nThe autumn strips the lolly tree,\nBut the spring returns again,\nThe dew descends on the pearly lea,\nAnd refreshes the .sunburnt plain.","fullrs":{},"find":"375.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"374","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1682915","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.60 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
