<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/530</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>530</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/530/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:05">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"Illll\nML \u25a0\u2022\n168\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\nii\nm.\nIf:\nif\nIf\n1  1* 'f*\ni ;\u25a0\/-,, ,,\n' \u25a0'. j; ;\u25a0.*!\/\nfeet from the surface the fossils of this part of the country\narc generally found.\nTho fossils lately found are as follows: 1st. 1 lie right\nhalf of the lower jaw of a small mastodon, with the third\nmolar entire. 2d. One entire molar of the upper jaw of an\nadult mastodon, considerably worn by chewing. Weighs\nseven pounds. 3d. A fragment of a molar similar to the\nlast but double the size; it must have belonged to one of\nhuge dimensions. 4th. The third molar of the right upper\njaw of a horse; it is one fourth larger than any similar tooth\nin the largest of our horses; it was found with the last mentioned fragment of a mastodon's tooth. The discovery of\ntho horse's tooth is important for two reasons, first, because\nthey were not inhabitants of this continent at its discovery;\nbut it is more important from its size; as Baron Cuvier says,\nthat of all the fossils of this kind he had seen, not one of\nthem would indicate an animal of greater size than the ass\nor zebra. With respect,\nYour obedient servant,\nW. M. CARPENTER\nEXTRACT  OP AN ADDRESS\nDe-levered before llic AMphic Union SociehJ of Williams College, Mass., al llic\nAnnual Commencement, In August last, b&gt;- Edtcari Everett, Governor of llic\nancle.\n\u2022 * * The province of education, ill which we may\nnil labor, and in which the effects to be immediately hoped\nfor stand in some assignable proportion to the means employed, is the improvement of the minds of the mass of the people. This is the second question, to which 1 alluded, in the\ncommencement of my remarks, may not a great increase be\nmade in the number of those who receive a good education\nand may not the education of all be made much better; 1\nmean much more thorough and extensive as lo the knowledge\nacquired, and much more efficacious and productive, as to the\ntraining ofthe mind? These questions, I am persuaded\nmust be answered in the affirmative. It is at once melancholy and fearful to reflect, how much intellect is daily perishing from inaction ; or worse than perishing from the false\ndirection given it in the morningof life, I fear we do not yet\nfully realize what is meant, when we speak of ihe improvement of the mind, I fear it is not yet enough considered by\nlegislators or parents, that there dwells, in every rational being, an intellect endowed wilh a portion ofthe faculties, which\nform the glory and happiness of our nature, and which de\nveloped and exerted, are the source of all that makes man to\ndiffer essentially from the clod of the valley. Neglected and\nuncultivated, deprived of its appropriate nourishment, denied\nthe discipline which is necessary to its healthy growth, this\ndivine principle all but expires, and the man whom it was\nsent to enlighten sinks down, before his natural death, to his\nkindred dust. Trained ami instructed, strengthened by wise\ndiscipline, and guided by pure principle, it ripens into an intelligence but a little lower than the angels. This is the work\nof education. The early years of life are the period when\nit must commonly be obtained; and, if this opportunity is lost,\nit is too often a loss which nothing can repai\ntilled this year or the next, although a crop or two be losl tl,0\nevil may be remedied.    The land with its productive quali\nmay\nIf not ploughed and planted this year, it ,\na loss winch nothing can repair.    It is usual to\ncompare the culture of the mind lo the culture of the earth. I pampered, self sufficient ignorance\nIt the husbandman relax his labors, and his field be left\nties remains.\n: the year after. But if the mind be wholly neglected during- the period most proper for ils cultivation, if it be suffered\nto remain dark and uninformed, its vital power perishes -\u2014for\nill the purposes of an intellectual nature it is lost. It is asjr\nin earthquake had swallowed up the uncultivated fallows- it\ns as if a swollen river had washed away, not merely the stand.\ning crop, but the bank on which it was growing. When tho\ntime for education has gone by, the man must, in ordinary\ncases, be launched upon the woild a benighted being,scarcely\nelevated above the beasts that perish; and all that he could\nhave been and done for society, for himself, is wholly lost.\nAlthough this utter sacrifice of the intellectual nature is\nrarely made in this part of the country, I fear there exists even\nhere, a woful waste of mental power through neglectof education. Taking our population as a whole, I fear, that there\nis not nearly time enough passed at school;\u2014that many of\nthose employed in the business of instruction, are incompetent\nto the work;\u2014and that our best teachers are not sufficiently\nfurnished with literary apparatus, particularly with school libraries. If these defects could be supplied, I believeafen-\nyears would witness a wonderful effect upon the community;\nthat an impulse not easily conceived beforehand, would be\ngiven to individual and social character,\nI am strongly convinced, that it behoves our ancient commonwealth, to look anxiously to this subject, if she wishes lo\nmaintain her honorable standing in this Union of States. I\nam not grieved, when I behold on the map the enormous dimensions of some of the new States in the west, as contrasted\nwith the narrow little strip which comprises the good old\nBay State. They are bone of our bone, and flesh of our\nflesh; their welfare is closely interwoven with ours; in every\nthing that can promote their solid prosperity, I bid them God\nspeed with all my heart. I hear without discontent the astonishing accounts of their fertility;\u2014that llieir vast prairies arc\ncovered with more feet of rich vegetable mould, than oursoil\non an average can boast of inches; and I can bear to hear it\nsaid, without envy, that their Missouri and Mississippi, Ihe\nmighty Abana and Pharphar of the Wesl, are better than all\nthe waters of our poor old New England Israel.\nAll this I can bear; but I cannot bear that our beloved native State, whose corner-stone was laid upon an intellectual and\nmoral basis, should deprive itself, by its own neglect, of iho\ngreat counterpoise to these physical advantages. Give the\nsons of Massachusetts,\u2014small and comparatively unfertile as\nshe is,\u2014the means of a good education, and they will stand\nagainst the world. Give me the means of educating my\nchildren, and I will not exchange its thirstiest sands nor its\nbarest peak, for the most fertile spot on earth, deprived of those\nblessings. I had rather occupy the bleakest nook of ihe\nmountain that towers above us,* with the wild wolf anil the\nrattlesnake for my nearest neighbors, and a snug link school-\nhouse, well kept, at the bottom of the hill, than dwell in a\nparadise of fertility, if I must bring up my children in Mf'\nA man may protect\n'Saddle Mountain., between Wllliamatown anel Aclaiis","fullrs":{},"find":"531.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"530","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1877371","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
