<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 42</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2266</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2266</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2266/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 42","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[42]\nevidence in favor of the security of tbe road, and the ability of every secti\nof our country to build roads without resorting to borrowed capita], even to m^\nthe road-bed, so fatal to many of the most important enterprises in this count*\nWhen the people properly understand its effects upon themselves and th\ncountry, they will come out in a mass in favor of the measure, and one seiuimem\nwill pervade the minds of all, creating a spirit of commendable rivalry in ait\nindustrial pursuits, which must in time revolutionize in sentiment the whole South-\nwestern states, build up manufactories, and advance us iu all our agricultural and\ncommercial relations, (and engraft upon our people an awakened system of home\nindustry and sell-reliance,' making us more respected both at home and abroad\nand no longer tributary to the other states, and the rebuking influences of their\ncitizens,) producing within our own borders all the necessaries and comforts of\nlife, as good and cheaply as they can be procured abroad, truths that must press\nthemselves upon every patriotic mind.\nThe Gulf of Mexico may justly be considered the heart of the ocean, throash\nwhich must pass the commerce, travel, and mail facilities of Europeand the Eastern\nstates, onward over the Isthmus routes to the Pacific shore.s, until the completion\nof oar proposed system of rail-roads from New-Orleans, over the fertile prairies of\nOpelousas. on to Texas and to the Pacific by the El Paso and Gila route, and from\nthe Mississippi River, opposite Memphis, to Little Rock, and Fulton, ou Eed\nRiver; thence to a converging point to intersect ihe New-Orleans road in Texas,\nnow deemed the most feasible and advantageous routes for a great national\nhighway, to connect and bind together the two great oceans of the world.\nFrom the great length of these roads, as also from the conformation ofthe counuy\nthrough which they will pass, other rail-roads will spring up, which will be\ntributary to, and not rival, having the advantage of connecting a whole system of\nrailway s between these great oceans with the commercial metropolises of the valley\nofthe Mississippi\u2014New-Orleans on the one hand, and Memphis on the other, by\nwhich the trade and travel of whole states beyond will find a channel to these\ngreat centres of business.\nLouisiana cannot hesitate as to what she ought to do, now that Tennessee hat\ncome out so nobly in support of that great internal improvement cause, which\neven in its infancy, in connection with the ocean steamers, guarantees to IM\nAmerican people the commerce of the seas and the supremacy of the world.\nPremising that long before the meridian sun of this generation shall shine upon\nus, over the fertile plains of Louisiana, Arkansas, Texas, and California, a grew\nhighway will spring into life, for the thronging emigrants of both worlds,\u2014andW\nthe abounding products of its soil a capacious outlet,\u2014returning the tribute \u00b0]^Tf,\ncommerce to these states from which they had sprung, its magmtude in the I \u25a0\nness of its growth, beyond human conception, passing through a mild, salubrio\nlatitude, which can never be obstructed by snows or ice, and other imped\"**11\nincident to higher latitudes. m\nArkansas looks with confidence to this Convention to devise ways and .rn^.\"\nbring to the early consideration of Congress a proper application, emanating ij\nand concentrating the power and influence of the South-western states, anrt o\nthe other states of this Uuion, that can be enlisted in the cause, for a gi'B11 !\n\" right of way ' throughout the whole extent of these projected roads, a11    \" 2oi.\ngrantsof land in aid of their construction, on a scale commensurate with 'he ^.^\ntude of the proposed work, from one extremity to the other. In view ol l\"**e Q'fot\ngrants of lands to be set apart mainly as a sort of sinkingjfuiid for tbe Plirc'lilL,t ihe\niron rails aud the equipment of these roads, it is deemed feasible to cons'       irt\nwhole work by individual enterprise, through tbe fostering aid of the ^y^k\nstates under different corporations, a system of improvement far more 1\" .* ^\nand effective in   new countries than could be obtained by the  direct       |,lic\ninfluence ofthe Federal government, which too often, if not always, give3    j ^\nworks a political aspect, if not in the end fatal to the enterprise its   J^\nducing wrangling and contention irreconcilable, and otherwise by e\npatronage exciting the just fears of every patriot. oinenI*'\"\n1 beg the indulgence of the Convention to be specially heard, for a in ^ ^]0it\nthis place, on behalf of the state of Arkansas and her people, for a\". anin*\"\nname I have the honor to address you ; and to state, in this connccu' y o\u00bb&lt;\nportant matter, that I hope will not escape the particular attention o","fullrs":{},"find":"2267.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2266","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"622923","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.59 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
