<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/527</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>527</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/527/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"! (il] 1 n \u25a0W R S T E R N \u25a0 J 0 U R N A I.\ngrea\nt designs ol\nf the Creator, and the comfort of mankind,\nl(.r,\npromoting that distribution of heat upon the surface of the\nearth which protects vegetables and animals from too sudden\ntransitions of temperature, nnd guards against the inevitable\ndestruction'that would result from the rapid transformation of\n\u00abnoW nnd ice into water nt the commencement of the warm\n,eajon. It is a peculiarity to which vegetation owes its very\nexistence, for without it the warm regions of the south would\nkparched lo barren wastes, and the north cursed with an\neternal and irreparable sterility.\nWe may trare our drop, filled with the expanding ether\nheat, borne high into the subtile regions of the air, there\nfloating as an airy vapor, or condensed into a fleecy cloud,\nnow approaching near, and then receding from the earth,\nuntil the chilling current of some northern blast, shall wrest\nfrom it the power that gave it wings, when down to earth\nprecipitate it falls, to wet the parched ground; to take from it\nredundant heat, and be again converted into vapor, and again\ncondensed, to fall not in the form of water, but as snow in\nsome northern clime, where it gives out the warmth acquired\nin ihe hot regions of the south, and, by another power inherent in ils nature,  protects nnd cherishes the soil beneath it,\nrestrains the radiation from the surface of the earth, and thus\nprevents that diminution of temperature that would be fatal to\nboth brute and plant.    Here it reposes, until the increasing\nheat of the summer solstice, gives warning that its fostering\ncare is no longer required, and, again imbibing some excess\nof heat, resumes once more the fluid state, and, by its soften-\nin? power, prepares the soil for the germination of the seeds\nthat it bad protected (luting the winter; or it becomes a flowing stream, the little ramus of some mighty river, first rippling as a brook, next flowing through a verdant meadow,\nnoiv swollen inlo an angry stream, it drives its foaming waters o'er beds of lugged rocks and crashing timber; still\ngliding onward, it spreads forth into a smooth and placid current, quiet but majestic, and upon its broad bosom bears the\nrich products of man's industry, till finally we trace it emptying ils teeming waters into the wide and unfathomable\nocean.   Here it buoys up the leviathan of the deep, or on\nlUtranquil surface bears commerce, with her richly laden\nships and overflowing cornucopia, or, perchance, swellin.\ninlo rage, as if disdaining to be made the quiet instrument of\nman's ambition, it lashes with portentous violence the stubborn shores, and ils wild waves resurge upon each other, and\nwith impartial vengeance bury whole fleets   in the deep\nabysms of its angry bosom.    Tranquility again restored, and\nthe ebullition of its passions calmed to rest, it is again exhaled\nto heaven, and, as a diamond drop floats in the sunbeam, to\npaint the seven-striped arch which God set in the sky ns emblem of his covenant with man; or as a cloud of dark and\nthreatening aspect hangs o'er our heads, with lightning on\nits brow and thunder in ils breath.    But these portentous\n\u00bbgns forbode no evil; for, soon bursting with its own weight,\n[I falls down upon the famished and parched earth, to slake\nits thirst, and resuscitate the dormant germs that lie scattered\n\u00b0\" Us surface.    Mark it now in the descent, and you will see\nII falling upon (hat insignificant and worthless seed, nn acorn\nof\nmysterious and inscrutable\nmovements, which, conjoined\nwith the genial warmth of the solar rays, develope the Intent\nand slumbering energies of the germ. These movements\nput into action ihe powers of vitality and the seed sends forth\na radicle, and a stem with tiny foliage, whilethe drop is busily passing up and down the plant, now imbibing nutritious\nparticles from the soil; entering at the root, it passes up the\ntrunk, administering the different principles held in solution\nto the eliminating vessels; ascending to the leaves and evaporating from their surface, ii carries off any excess of heat\nthat may result from the action of the sun : falling again upon these leaves, imbued with the carbonic acid of the atmosphere, it furnishes a principle necessary to the vegetable, but\nnjuriousto animal life, and, by this compound action, both\npurifies tho air we breathe, and furnishes nutriment to the\nplant.\nThus it continues to perform an uninterrupted series of\nduty, from the first effort of the germinating principle, until\nthe worthless embryo shall have become a large and magnificent oak, with its lofty summit reaching to the clouds, and\nits wide branches spreading to the wind, beneath which the\nbirds of the air may find shelter, and the bcasls of the field a\ncool and umbrageous repose; while the tough fibres of its\nligneous trunk, furnish a material that may be fashioned lo\nsubserve the wants of man, from the humble service of a cottage table to the proud ship of national defence. Elated\nwith success, and proud of the majestic product of its industry, our little drop seeks for some other object upon which to\nexhibit the versatility of its genius; from the majestic and\npowerful, it descends lo the beautiful and chaste; and first n\nparched and drooping rose bud becomes the subject of ils fostering care; expanding into an extremely delicate and subtile vapor, it enters the minute pores of the rose leaves, softens the vessels, dilutes the thickened juices of the vegetable\nlaboratory, touches the secret spring that sets the whole machinery of vegetable organization into action; and the dying\nbud lifts up its drooping head, the verdant calyx grows brighter, the blooming petals expand blushing to the sun, while tho\nwhole air is redolent of their fragrant breath. Or perchance,\nwhile wandering up and down with charitable intent, it spies\nafar the valley's pride bending its lovely head beneath tho\nwithering influence of the noon-day sun, to which, with\nompt benevolence it hies, and pours ils renovating balm up\non the scorched branches of the fainting lily, gives fresh impulse to the shining leaves, wipes off the arid dust that was\nclosing up the pores, and snatches the desponding plant from\npremature decay. Satiated with beauty and refinement, our\nbusy drop forsakes the service of these floral queens, and,\nwhile the silent shades obscure the night, escapes, to seek for\nhappiness in change; but indolence corrupts the fountain of\nits chastened pleasures, and, with a bitter spirit of misanthropy, it seeks a refuge within the poison vessels of the fabled\nUpas. Here, emulating ils former industry, it sets about con-\ncoding noxious and naic'otic odors, charms for weirds, and\nleadly potions for the doomed. It percolates through every\navenue and hidden recess of its secret labyrinths, until, well\nversed in all the mysteries of its new abode, again it seeks the\n-' .1.\nO  \u00abj*\"ii   mill.   U1&amp;1\"1I1111.,UIH  UI1U  .VUIUJICCO  DCVU,  tin  uuviu    \u25a0 ~' \u00ab\u00ab-\u00ab  -\u2022-  ,, ( .\n)'&lt;\u2022\" Please, then and there il immediately institutes a series day, basks as a dew drop in the morning sun, and. again in*\nI","fullrs":{},"find":"528.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"527","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1767786","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
