<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/383</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>383</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/383/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T II - W E S T E R N J 0 U R N A L -\n21\nTHE PERIODICAL AND NEWSPAPER PRESS\noe the Unitro States.\nKa C*jay, read before tlio Jeftbraon College ami Waflbtngton f.ycouin, on Solui.\n,lny, Bcntenibor2, 1837.,  Ily L. A. BssANCOtf, Esq-, Editor of tho free Trader.\nMr. President, and Gentlemen ov tiih Lyceum:\u2014\nThrown upon your indulgence, with brief space of lime for\npreparation, having been abscntand aiduously engaged except\nIbr the past two days, I would still manifest my sense of respect to this association, by selecting a theme for an essay, which\nshall combine general interest with useful information\u2014and,\nfor this end, permit me name \" The Periodical and Newspaper Pressofthc United Slates\" as a subject with which I have,\nto some extent, become professionally acquainted, and which\ncannot fail lobe interesting to an audience' of Literary Ladies\nand Gentlemen, however feeble may be my power in illustrating the subject.\nThe Art of Priming is one of those trophies of modern\ntimes, won from tho field of human invention, which freshens\nl.'ie laurels obtained in nil prior time, and rescues, from the\nmouldering ruins of the post, all that is worthy ol preservation ;\nwhile, at the same time, it leaves behind, at an almost immeasurable distance, the literature of antiquity nnd the proudest\nachievements of ancient philosophy. It was lo have been expected that an art so potent, which has justly been called \"the i i \u25a0' ,' \u2022 11 i i\n1 . . i, \u201e , hi . i \u25a0 lumbus was a mountain ol snow\u2014a virgin world dressed 0111\n\u25a0t,t preservative ol all arts,   should have irivcn a powerful im- \u2022  ,.      , -.      ,      ,- ,                 ,        ,        . ,.,      ,,,, \u25a0\n1 , .1,11. I in the white rube nl  her espousals to  Immortality,     I Ins\nlietus to mind, have opriiedncw vislns ol ihoiiirht, anddiivcttdl    \u25a0   \/,,        ,        ,\u2022   \u00bbi        t.i       ,,,-,- \u25a0',\n' .       ,     , \u25a0 \\might nave been lus idea, although 1 think it more in keeping\ntin intellect ol mankind into new and no bier channels.    I do!   -,t  , \u2022 -,-  ,     , \u2022 t- , ,   ,,\nwiih Ins siu-er, il the stormy image m Ins mind bud been a\nlititstiiten truism when I repeal that  Ihe Press more nearly     . . ,   .   ,   r , ,   . . 11.1.1 ,- 1\n- ,   , \u2022 ,'  whirlwind ol dust, shaking rudely the leaves ol autumn and\nle.ulizi s the idea ol the lever of A re hum di s, Willi which, (if he\nen 11 Id find a Inh-ruin) he' was to movo tho world, than any oth\nivory or invention that is recorded in I...   \t\nu-     ,1     ' 1   ,        1 , ,1        ,1    1 modes of action.    If American genius chooses lo fashion its\nWere there but one language spoken upen the earth, tno uc- . .\n,-,i \u2022 1 ,111,1 11      irrcnlness through the instrumental!! vol tho periodical ornews-\ntun ol this moral engine, upon the world ut luierc, would re- .....\nThese general remarks only go to show the omnipotence\nof tho Press, and the extent of English literature, 0\/which\nAmerican literature is a component pari. And one of the\npopular and most effective modes in which the Anglo American literature operates and displays itself, is, through the medium of the Periodical and Newspaper Press. America, the\nland of freemen, isal.so the home of free thought and the freedom ofthe press. If not the With place, it is the nursery of\nnewspapers. It has more periodicals mid newspapers in proportion lo its millions of inhabitants than any other section of\nihe Globe. Refined France', with her thirty millions, has not\nhalf the number of newspapers nnd periodicals that the fourteen or fifteen millions of our own country have; nnd the\nUnited Kingdom of Grent llrit.ui falls far short of tho proportion which wo find in tho United States.\nIt was snoeringly said by a lending Uritish Review, a fvw\nyears since : \"As Ibr American literature, it consists of a storm\nof newspapers.\" Perhapslho idea, present to this sarcastic reviewer's mind, was one of those old fashioned snow storms :\ncountless flakes filling the heavi lis with fleecy, fringed, broad,\nleafy floats, obscuring the vision nnd piling the earth knee\ndeep with ihe feathery burden, nnd falling still faster and\nthicker, wider and deeper, until tho whole continent of Co\nst rowing them in anger over the land.\n.- ,   i-    1 1 The (renins of any people will naturally seek out its own\nliscovcrv or in vent ion thui is n eo rth d in Uieunnnls ultimo.' '\ntblotli\nepofnn unbroken wave across the broad sea.\npaper press, mill ns surely attains ils end in that way, who bus\n,, 1 1 iiii ,1 .   a right to complain or the cause to sneer?\nI'ulsation alter pulsation would bo thrown boniihe centroto '\ntlie distant extremities, till the feeling of mankind would bo     Venice, pre-eminent amidst her other honors, has Ihat of\nalike and knowledgcthesame. Difference oflanguage,lhegreat originating newspapers, in 153G, nearly a hundred years bc-\nbarrier which more effectually divides nut ions than tho Alpine j line the settlement of Jamestown and Plymouth,    The first\nchains or the pili s of the Andes, interrupts this flow of com- paper was called Gazelle from iis price, which was a small\nmunication between the various sections of thocivilizcd world,'copper Vcin'tiaii coin called Gazetta.    It was first issued in\nwhile, ut the same time, (probably on the principle of division mnnuscrip!, ns tho government of that city would not then per\nof labor) it may have a tendency to enrich tho mass of Intel-mil tho diffusion of printed in us.    Thirty volumes ofthis\nlectual acquirement or accumulation, which busy translators \" Father ofnowspapors\" are now to In- found inn Venitian Li-\nand linguists are hourly transferring to the common treasury brary.    This paper was spoken of in other countries ns a\n10 In: diffused again over ihe earth through such mediums ns '' Hill of News'' sent from Venice every month to all places\nan- the most common to large masses ol mankind,    For ex- when-1 hi' merchants nl' ihat city traded.    The first printed\nample, ihe French language being spoken or nnd by the best paper was in London, fifty two years after this, during the 111-\neducated people of all civilized countries, it affords a medium vasion ofthe English channel by the Spanish Armada ; hut\nfor the diffusion ofthe philosophy, and modes of thinking, of the first regular weekly newspaper ever  printed in the world\nihat acute and refined country almost over the whole eurth.\u2014\nThe English language is, perhaps, n still more diffused and\ninfluential medium, being the language in which the Magna\nChar la of the barons of King John, and the Declaration of\nAmerican Independence were penned, nnd, therefore, the language of liberty and freedom of mind. It is also at the present time, in the highest degree, the language of Maralime\nTrade and discovery, thus extending its influence fromthe straits\nof Babel mandcl in the cast, to the Oregon in the west.\nwas in London in 1020, coeval with the English settlmenls\non this continent in Virginia nnd Massachusetts. Ten years\nafter this, a paper on the same plan was established in Paris.\nFrom this period the history ofnowspapors is like the growth\nofthe mighty oak', without any pause, mini,ally expanding\nand widening in proportion lo the growth of mind, of science\nand of freedom. At first the progress was slow. One hundred years after the establishment ofthe first weekly paper in\nLondon there was a eluily paper established in that same city;","fullrs":{},"find":"384.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"383","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1760742","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
