<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/467</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>467</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/467/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 17","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T II - W F. S T E R N j o u R &gt;;\n95\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\nNATCHEZ,  FEBRUARY 28, 1838.\nMEETING OF THE LYCEUM FOB, MARCH.\n|,i consequence of inclement weather, We learn that the\nMonthly meeting of the Jeflerson College and Washington\ni.vi'ium, hi's been deferred until 3 o'clock, P. Ml, on Satur\ntl.i'y, March 10th. The lecturer is President Dubuisson, his\nihemo Eloquence.\nProfessor Wyche will read an Essay on the Sacred Wri\ntin\"s.   Other voluntary contributions may be expected.\nId's highly probable that the meeting of the Lyceum for\nApril will be holden in the city of Natchez.\nJEFFERSON COLLEGE.\n^- We learn that it is contemplated to suspend the college\ncourse of study at this institution, and devote all ils revenue,\nfur some time to come, to the erection of college buildings,\nunder the supposition that a collegiate corporation requires a\nbody, as well as a soul; and that when edifices worthy of genius anil science shall have been completed) the guardian spi-\nlits of the Academic halls, the \" pennies loci,\" shall return\nagain to participate in a brighter destiny.\nTO CORRESPONDENTS.\nWe are not entirely certain, whether that beautiful \"sketch\nnf love,\" \" Sappho's Leap,\" was originally written for the\nSouth-Western Journal, or only transcribed for it from some\nether publication. Will our correspondent please to be specific on this point, in all communications for ihe Journal 1\n4\nCOUNTY CONVENTION OF TEACHERS.\nWe understand that there will be a Convention of Teachers, and other gentlemen of literary attainments, in the city of\nNatchez, on Saturday, the 17th of March.\nThe object of the Convention will be. to enter into some\n:.\"-ticnil arrangements Ibr the promotion of the interests of\neducation in Adams county, and to elect a delegation to meet\nthe State Convention nt the next session of that body. No\nresults but good ones can be anticipated from such a meetin\nof the friends of education and moral improvement in this\nanility.\np it ci j i; e: T r. n\n-MILITARY,  SCIENTIFIC AND CLASSICAL  ACADEMY\nWe have understood that Professor Forshcy, of Jefferson\n( allege, proposes, if sufficient encouragement shall be given,\nto open an academy in the city of Natchez, for the accomplishment of young gentlemen in the classics, mathematics, civil\nengineering, and military tactics.\nMilitary discipline and uniform, will be adopted by the stu-\ni.i'iits for their hotter government, for invigorating the system\nm the acquisition of manly and soldier-like accomplishments,\nM well ns to accustom the youth of our country to the use of\narms\u2014those stern arguments to which resort must be had in\n'he last appeals of freemen.\ncounty. The noble and public-spirited volunteer companies\nof Natchez, should extend their patronage to an institution of\nthis class, so well calculated to fill their ranks with educated\ncadets,   y\nTHE LIFE AND WRITINGS OF WASHINGTON!\nThese noble volumes, are, at once tho best monument of the\n\" Father of his country,\" and of the perseverance, fidelity, and\nresearch of the aci ompljshed biographer and historian, Jared\nSparks. The work is comprised in twelve volumes octavo,\nof about 000 pages each, elegantly printed on fine paper, with\nfine and beautiful binding. Each volume is illustrated by\nengraved portraits, fac-simile's, plans nnd sketchings.\nSparks, in compiling the Life and Writings of Washington, has taken the best method\u2014that of making the illustrious\nman his own biographer. The style of his writings has he-en\nfaithfully preserved,\u2014and, more than thai, it seems to have\nbeen imitated by the compiler, in those connecting narrations\nwhich fill up the chasms between detailed events, It is nil\nlike Washington,\u2014plain, substantial, sensible, without nn\nexpletive for eflect, an ornament for display, or an excrescence\nfor the priming knife of a severer and more critical age,\nThe departments of record, in the governments of England\nand Prance, were searched, by the indefatigable author, for\ncollateral oflicial correspondence, thus enabling him to settle\nach disputed point of cither policy or fact.\nSparks may truly say, \"Exegi monumentum I\"\nWe sincerely believe, that n well-trained body of classical\n\"ltd mathematical cadets would be the pride of the city andlmits of the bluffs, sweeping away from the view.    Bloody\nThe Eternal River.\u2014We have never viewed n\ngrander spectacle, than that which the mighty stream, rolling\nits vast floods along our city to the deep, now presents. The\nMississippi, even'in its mildew moods, is terrible. When it\npours along ils dark waters, beneath the gentle gloamings of\na midsummer's sunset j or when its gliding ripples are burnished by the silvery effulgence of the midnight moon, its\ncourse is still mighty\u2014fearful, resistless; and we think of iis\nfir, lonely journeying, and the scenes it has witnessed, and\nwe look upon its placid surf tee shadowed by the forests of its\nbanks, and it seems to us in all its majestic magnificence, only\nas the giant slumbering from his labor.\nRut when (he beautiful spring time is over, arid the balmy\nmoonlit evening of summer is past, and Autumn's shadowy\nglory is no more; when Winter broods over desolated nature, then it is that the \"terrible Mississippi \" assumes nil ils\nfe'arfulness of aspect, and we realize ihat we are gazing upon\nthe mightiest stream, with but a single exception, that flows\nupon our globe. All then is linmiiigli el grandeur\u2014sublimity\u2014magnificence. Turn your eye even now, reader, over\nits troubled surface, and what a spectacle of grandeur does\nihat mighty mass of voliuncd waters present! The opposite\nhoro is desolate, and bleak, and cheerless\u2014the naked banks\nrise steep from the rushing stream, mantled with ice\u2014the\ntrees are leafless and drear\u2014at intervals, through their bare,\nweather-beaten trunks, you catch a glimpse of an ancient\nmound upon the smooth prairie, while faraway in tho blue\ndistance, standing out against the dim eastern horizon, are\nperceived the long line of white cliffs, or the rounded sum-.\ni\"-'&gt;'U\n;\u25a0\u25a0: t-i\n|'M-U\n\u2022. i.M*\n. '\u25a0. vfc'f,\n:' \u25a0; i'M\nMl\n,fi\n\u25a0'm\nI\n.'\n'.\n!","fullrs":{},"find":"468.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"467","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1836947","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
