<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/436</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>436</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/436/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T H - W E S T E R N J O U R N A L.\n69\nof whom, we shrewdly suspect, in a few years forget even the\nGreek alphabet, we should not bo inclined to place a very\nliie-h estimate on ils value. We readily grant that an inaccurate and superficial knowledge of Greek, or indeed of any\n1 other language, is of little use. But why should it bo inaccurate, why need it be superficial? Though it is not to be\nexpected, nor perhaps desired, that every one should rival a\nPoison, or a Parr, in the profundity and extent of his attainments, yet why may not bis knowledge he thorough, as far as\nil extends? Accuracy should never he dispensed with, hut\nshould he rigidly exacted. He that shall learn to construe'\nami parse, with facility and correctness, even the Greek Tes-\nlamcnt, and the easy works of Xenophon, the Anabasis and\nt'viopieilia, will have acquired no mean amount of know-\nIt jge He will carry with him besides into every other de-\niiarttncnl of study, to every other subject, the same habits of\naccurate analysis, and exact thought. Those who doubt the\nutility of Greek, as part of a general system of liberal education, will not deny its indispensable necessity to the student of\ntheology, whose profession is to expound tho sacred records\nwhich contain the charter of our salvation; whim they recollect it was the language in which our Lord and his apostles\nspoke and wrote, and thnt the best translation of the Old Tcs-\nlament, and the one which most illustrates the New, is tho\nScptuagint.\nIt has been proposed to substitute Hebrew, and modem\nlanguages, in place of Latin and Greek. We would prefer\nseeing these superadded to a classical course, hut not superseding it. When Jupiter speaks, says Cicero, it is in ihe dialed of Plato When Jehovah, may the Christian say wilh\ntruth, condescended to hold converse with his creatures, it was\nin the appropriate language of bis chosen people, the laconic,\nexpressive, and majestic dialect of the Hebrews, which compensates for tho scantiness of its vocabulary, by its fulness of\nsignification, in which every word contains a world of meaning, conveying not only the principal, but all the accessory\nideas. It is unnecessary to expatiate on the transe'oiidunt excellence of this consecrated language. Its beautiful simplicity fits it alike for the expression of the tender, the pathetic,\nand the sublime. In these respects, the sacred writings, independently of their divine authority, in the opinion of ihose\nbest qualified to judge, far surpass all Greek, all Roman excellence, Wo hope this study will soon be introduced into\nall our colleges.\nShall we substitute modern languages and authors? They\ncannot furnish the same intellectual discipline. They arc not\nsu highly polished and finished. They are not the acknowledged models of taste, and standards of criticism. Time has\nnot yet pronounced a verdict in their favor; nor can they\ncompare with the Latin and Greek writers, crowned ns theso\narc with the laurel of assenting lime, by the unanimous agreement of all ages and nations.\nThe (irecian and Roman writers are, with the exception of\nthe sacred records, and a few unimportant fragments, all that\nremains of the history, and embodied thought of the world\nIbr 40110 years. What do we know of the history of Egypt,\nAssyria, Persia, Tyre, nnd Carthage, except what we derive\nhorn the historians of Greece and Rome?    Had they not\nbeen thus preserved, and ejiiialmeo, so to speak, the last memorials of them would have perished, and nothing would\nhave remained to tell that they ever existed, but a few broken\ncolumns, and their almost obliterated inscriptions. The finished productions of mind alone, like itself, are immortal. Go\nnow to the Eternal. City, once the world's imperial mistress,\nand view the crumbling monuments of her former magnificence, her temples, amphitheatres, aqueducts, and triumphal\narches, which barbarian fury and Christian zeal, have nearly demolished, and then contrast with them the works of her\nimmortal writers, which have escaped the ravages of five, the\nsword, and all devouring time. While the former are dilapidated anil decayed, the latter still remain in all their pristine\ngrandeur and beauty, and will remain to the end of time the\nadmiration and delight of all ages.\nRome, indeed, no longer sways the iron sceptre of military\nor ecclesiastical despotism, over a submissive world, but the\ndominion of her deathless writers yet continues. It is truly\nm imperium sine fine* hounded only by the limits of civilization, and the duration of time itself. As subjugated Athens\ngave law to her haughty victors the Romans, in matters of\ntaste and philosophy; so Rome,in tuin, subdued her barbarian conquerors by the. humanizing influence of letters and\nthe arts. The light which once so gloriously illuminated the\nhanks of tho Ilissus and the Tiber still sheds its mild, its benign radiance over the nations. The ephemeral productions\nof the modern press, enjoy, for awhile, the sunshine of popular favor, live out their brief day of fashionable celebrity, and\nthen expire. One system of philosophy yields to another,\none hook of science supplants another: and they successively\nfall, as new discoveries are made, into neglect, or oblivion.\nOver the classic writers of Greece and Rome, time has lost\nits destroying power. It only makes us more sensible of the\nmerit of works which address the feelings and fancy, as well\nis the reason and judgment. Slill sports the playful muse of\nAnacreon, with the Loves and Graces, amid myrtle groves,\nmil beds of roses. Wedded to immortal verse, still breathes\nthe love, still live the fires of the poetess of Lesbos, the \"burning Sappho.\" Nonomnismoriar,] I shall not wholly die, exclaims the sweet bard of Vcnusiiim, when, in the enthusiasm\nof poetic inspiration, he measures the extent and duration of\nhis own fame by that of the Roman Empire. His prediction\nhas been more than verified. His works have survived the\ndestruction of tho Capitol, which the Romans fondly hoped\nwould be eternal, and his fame has extended beyond the Ultima Thule of antiquity, beyond the Atlantic, isles, beyond the\n\"ocean-flood,\" to new-born nations in the far distant West.\nHe lives, and will forever live, enshrined in the gratitude, the\nadmiration, and affection of the lovers of genuine poetry\nthrough nil succeeding ages.\nShould the classics be discarded from our systems of instruction, they would he replaced, probably, by an education\nmerely commercial and mechanical, or, at best, but scientific\nand military, and barbarity might soon prevail where now\nflourish the studies of humanity.    There is danger lest we\nft\n\u25a0I'-l\nsi\u25a0\n.!: hi\n:; \"\u25a0\n' lis\ni  i'S\nh\n'I\/is ego vrc mrtas rr.ru in ^ tlCC temporaponn ;\nImperiumaineJlne dedi, Virgil, \/En. I., v. 278-?.\ni Sue Horace, concluding ode of ihe third booh, cjcji monumentum, &lt;$c-","fullrs":{},"find":"437.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"436","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1789568","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.71 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
