<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/346</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>346</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/346/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S G V T li W K S T E K IN\nJ 0 Ij K N -A I.\n!\nbles; and it is equally certain, that he, in some wayhad obtained crude and erroneous accounts of events recorded by\nMosesFrom these materials he composed his Theogony,\nwhich very soon after became a text look in pagan theology.\nFables, which, related in prose, would have been ridiculous,\nby the charms of his verso weie rendered fascinating and\ndelightfulThe moral, if moral he intended, was overlooked by the enchanted reader; he received fable as truth, and\nadopted it as an article of his faithHomer followed, and\nusing the same deities as the machinery of his inimitable\npoems, attached new and increased importance, by the grandeur of his \"surpassing genius.\" Olympus and Ida became\nthe residence and court of Jove; Cyprus, the favored seat of\nVenus; Vulcan established his officinvm in \/Etna; and At\nlas groaned under the weight of the skiesMany fables o(\nHomer, which were doubtless understood by his hearers,\nwhen the wandering minstrel recited his detached pieces,\nwhich, afterwards, having lost their point, or moral, were\ntaken as sober truthHomer was the perennial fountain,\nwhence flowed a thousand streams through all the poetry of\nthe ancient worldlie was the sun from which all lesser\norbs derived their borrowed light, All the influence which\nwas created by the poetry of Greece and Rome, is traceable\nto this grand sourceHow far Homer ruled the ascendant\nin Grecian literature', is well understoodHis Iliad and Odyssey were the foundation on which was reared that bi aiiliful\nsuperstructure which continues to instruct, eh light, andcharm\nthe world, It is the eflect on character of which I speak.\nWhen Pisistrntus obtained the supreme power of Athens, the\ncharacter of that afterwards refined and gallant city was not\nformedHe had become acquainted with the works of the\nIonian bard, and must receive credit for collecting and arranging them in proper orderThe Iliad and Odyssey became\nknown to the Athenians, and were read with avidityThe\nspirit of the people changed, and the fate of Hippins mid\nHipparchus, may, in part, have been the result of the\nintroduction of the works of Homer into Athens\" Homer,\n(says Agis,) is the poet of the Spartans, because he teaches\nmen how to light; llesiod is the poet of the Helots,because\nhe teaches them lo work.\" No one, even at this time, can\nread the Iliad, without being wrought up lo the highestpitch\nof enthusiasm, by its fire, sublimity and beautyThe reader\nmust he-come a Greek or a Trojan: he must fight on the side\nof Hector or Achilles, and weep over the premature fate of\nPalroclus or SarpedonNow if a poem, written three thousand years ago, narrating the history of a siege\/, and sacking\nof a city, in which we can take no other interest than common sympathy, can have such an eflect, what must have been\nthat influence on the people who spoke its language, whose\nancestors were the heroes immortalized in its pages; what\nvast influence must it have had on an ardent, enthusiastic people like the Greeks? Who will say it is visionary to suppose\nthat Leonidas,and Aristides, Cimon and Agis, received their\nfirst lessons of patriotism from the magnanimous, yet unfortunate Hector? Alexander had always a copy of Homer in\nhis tent, during his campaigns; and boasted himself an imitator of Achilles, and, like his fierce prototype, was guilty oi\ndeeds of cruelty and blood  The K )rnan Scipio did the same,\nthough he improved upon the model, and softened down its\nasperities.\nBut, in a religious point of view, these two poets exerted\nan influence still more lasting and pervadingAs a knowledge of the Jewish faith increased by intercourse with din\nEast, the Greeks, and their servile imitators, the Roman,\nborrowed, from thissublime source, many beautiful fragments\nof their creedThey affected to despise the credulity of t|1(,\nJews\u2014their poetic genius induced them to seize with avidilv\nevery thing that suited their tasteAfter the Christian religion had opined a new dispensation, the Grecian mythology\nwas so firmly established, that all the reasoning of i&gt;)iilasci-\nphy could not defeat its advocatesThe ludicrous, and\ntherefore more caustic satire of Lucian's dialogues, was alone\nable to make men ashamed of their childish superstititon\t\nliven after Christianity was established by law, when the\nbishops of Constantinople and Rome controlled almost entirely the sceptre's of the e-nslorii and western empires, ninny\nof these ancient fibles still clung to the churchNay, even\nno classical scholar can witness the ceremonies, or read tin,\nhypoehrapbul doctrines of the Greek and Roman churches,\nwithout discovering a very strong resemblance to mythology, from the pontifex to the vestal, from the sacrifices of Juno to the worship of CeresThe reason 1 would give for\nthis inordinate love of mythological fables and ceremonies,\nis, their poetical origin and natureNothing but the severest system of ethics, can ever eradicate such deep impressions.\nThe poetry of the Romans was but the reflected image of\nthat of the GreeksVirgil was but a copyist of Homer ami\nTheocritus, and by consequence lost the fire and energy ef\nhis great prototypesHowever, in refinement of taste, the\nson of Mantua has no superiorThe age in which he lived\nbecame remarkable for literary excellenceAnil nil will\nadmit that the corrupt and pusillanimous Octavius became a\nbetter sovereign and a more upright man, after his acquaintance with the virtuous and modest poetHorace and Ovid\nhad a tremendous influence on the morals of RomeIt\nwere impossible to estimate the evil caused by the \"De Arte\nAmandi.\" Enough, that even the licentious citizens of the\nimperial city were scandalized by it, and the exile of the\nhard shows that he was fearedHorace, in his Satires,\ncreated a salutary check- on minor vices: but it is very much\nto be doubted whether this was not more than counterbalanced by some of his odes1 need enumerate no more of the\nprofane poets: the above remarks, with little modification,\nwill apply to all the rest.\nThe poetry of the Hebrews will sustain the position I have\ntakenWhen the descendants of Israel passed the Red Sea,\nand, from its eastern shore, beheld the hosts of Pharoah overwhelmed by the waters, through which they had passed in\nsafety, had Moses returned thanks to the Deity in plain prose,\nhis followers would have been outraged by his apathyBy\nthe beautiful ode composed for the occasion, he swayed all\nhearts, and fashioned all feelings as his ownMoses knew\nwell the human heart, and power of music over the passions\nof an ignorant and stubborn raceThe commencement of\nthe song is surpassingly beautiful   \" I will sing unto the\nBM\nW","fullrs":{},"find":"347.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"346","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1774638","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
