<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/499</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>499</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/499/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S O U T H - W E 3 T E R IN   JOURNAL.\n123\nconnecting the same ruling passion of his soul with the heaven lie hopes for, likening the; love; of tho world lo coin,\"\nwith that ho hail known on earth: such a revelation might\ni\u201e. considered trcasonablo to ihe sex\u2014nevertheless it would\nhe,(lie fact, and he, who might bo condemned for making it,\nwould be a martyr to the cause, of truth.\nThe expression of such a sentiment must bo somewhat mor-\nlilVin\" t\u00b0 'he self-pride of those whose wayward fortunes, or\nmore wayward vices, have divorced them from this influence,\ni|ie guiding star of innocent youth anel virtue; but we fearlessly make it, for the purpose of introducing and sustaining the\nleading proposition of the lecture, which is, that as powerful\nand as universal ns female influence is, it is no more so than\nnature and its creator intended it to bo. The \"help-meet for\nman\"\u2014the being without whom Eden was lonely, and the\nfirst and most beautiful garden of the young earth no paradise', in the more refined and intellectual circles of our renovated nature, holds but the station to which her God assigned\nher. The first symptom that the frozen gloom ofthe dark\na\"es, which succeeded tho Vandal irruption over tho Rom\nempire and the destruction of letters, was breaking, seemed\nlo have been a romantic and chivalrous deference to female\ncharms\u2014the feeble re-kindlings of that holy flame, which,\nat first,burned so purely in the pastoral stale of society, prevailing in oriental countries, before the corrupt and ponderous\nmonarchies crushed the: heart out of tho innocent and happy\ninstitutions of patriarchal life.\nIn the foundation lecture before this Institute and Lyceum,\nwe learned what was the great charter of female rights. It\nwas torn from monkish cells, covered with the dust of centuries, by the intrepid Luther, anel opened to nn admiring\nworld; it was the book of God! Raised to a proud mental\nequality with man, assigned to a sphere equally important,\nthough not the same, the progress of the intellectual condi\nlion of woman, during the three: last centuries, has been on\nward and upward. Her influence; has increased, in a direct\nratio, with her moral and intellectual culture, establishing the\nfact, that, to her, as well as to man, \" knowledge is power.\"\nThe references to history will be brief\u2014as it is a fact, that\nhistory, at best, is strikingly deficient in detecting the true\ncauses of great and prominent events. The sources of influence are often hidden, while the event stands in bold relief\non the historic page.    The ten years' war before; the walls of\nicate\nicr pros-\nIn the presence of woman, blasphemy is rebuked.    She is\ntho sweet pleader for virtue\u2014for religion\u2014for the del\nmill amiable courtesies and charities of life.    In\nence, the; cruel become humane; the audacious, meek; tho\nproud, humble; and tho obstinate,yielding.\nYet, in the exercise of this widely felt, omnipotent influence, we cannot but feel, that, as each planet has its own orbit\nin which it only can wheel its round, so has woman her orbit\nand her peculiar sphere,\u2014in which, as the loveliest gem on\nthe brow of night, the evening star, she may shine the brightest, as well as the mildest,\u2014out of which she must be only u\nwandering star \" to which the mist of darkness is reserved\nforever.\"\nAdmitting, as all reasonable beings must, the intellectual\nequality of the sexes, it will not follow, of course, that there\nis a physical equality\u2014a parity of bone, and muscle, and\nsinew, and nerve. When the notorious Frances Wright, the\nrenegade of her sox, made her daring attempt to disorganize\nsociety, by reversing its customs; when her large, expressionless eyes looked out in the morning for the speculations\nof tho day; when her brawny arms essayed to hold the\nplough, guide the carriage, crack the whip,\u2014while some\npale-faced, unsexed thing, once called a man, might have delicately made the tea, stitched the napkin, or plaited the ruflle;\nwhen her voice was heard in halls and theatres, the brazenfaced advocate of infidelity, or dealing out the slangwhang of\npolitics and abolitionism,\u2014she lost both the influence and the\nsex of woman. Thenceforward, belonging- to neither sex,\nshe was a physical and moral monster of unknown gender\u2014\nlike some huge, petrified megatherium,dug up from the monstrous relics of a world that perished in ihe wrath of the deluge. No wonder that this last experiment upon outraged\nreason and propriety should have ended in \"the laughter of\nscorn nnd the jeers of the world.\" Well might the Wabash\nrise in the strength of its autumnal power, and sweep, from\nits polluted banks, the name and the last vestige of New Harmony !\nIroy, is not the only ono fought for the sake of a woman.\u2014\nTho victory over tho chivalry of Egypt, which could not be\nworthily celebrated, on the farther shore of the Reel Sea, until\nMiriam took up tho response of triumph, with timbrel and\nMng, is not the only instance of female patriotism, glowing\nWith the fires of genius, and melting into liquid melody.\u2014\nTho faith and consecration of a Hannah, furnish not tho only\ninstance in which a mother has raised up and given to her God\na prophet\u2014an auointer ol kincs\u2014a greater than a monarch,\nen i .\ntaking female influence, ns it operates in its legitimate\nsphere, and in mass over its wide field, shall we be accused\n\u2122 presumption when wo say, that it is mightier, in its silent\n\"fects, than tho countless hosts of the crusaders,  beneath\nwhose feet the earth trembled, as knight, and templar, and\nP\u00ab&gt;ud paladin darkened Asia with their bannered millions I\nWe have ventured upon the incidental remark that there\nis a peculiar sphere in which woman is only in the legitimate\nexercise of her transcendent influence; wo venture further\nwhen we say that political power is not one of her rightful\nprerogatives. Sully, that politic premier of France, well\nknew the power of female influence, and retained in the patronage of government some of the most beautiful and accomplished of the sex, who were sent to foreign courts, as distinguished travellers, and sometimes even under the recommendation lo foreign sympathies of a mock banishment, for the\npurpose of effecting changes in foreign policy favorable to\nFrance. But this was generally done at the expense of that\njewel which shines the brightest in the female crown of moral beauty. In the task of enticing, by tho blandishments of\nperson and manner, the magnates of other lands, these female\nplenipotentiaries bartered innocence, if they had any, for po-\nitical eflect, and, like the silly insect that loves the taper,\nwere doomed to perish in the fires they kindled.\nIn venturing still further, wc have, at least, the consolation\nto know that there will bo no sensation al the court of St.\nJames, nor will it ever be known at the foot of the throne ol\"\n\u25a0Ml\n\u25a0 -,&gt;Si\n'',('\u00ab,frJN\n' \u25a0 \u25a0 yd\n;\u2022':\u00a3)\u2022&lt;\n;' .1'. I\n\u25a0\u25a0'   in\n. :'.\u2666,E\nm\nm\ni-,ii,l\n.\u2022;i'.J'tl\nI\ntl\n\u25a0     \u25a0-\u25a0:.\n\u25a0 :,\n' 1","fullrs":{},"find":"500.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"499","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1811845","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
