<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/605</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>605</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/605/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"tSP\n. \u25a0&lt;   :\u25a0 '\n{'\u2022''-\u25a0\nW '\u25a0\nH \u25a0\u2022:\u25a0'.\n11'''\n\u25a0\u25a0\"\u25a0-\n'If'\n\u2022;;\nI'e\nJ;'\nIf1'\n7\n'ty'\n''V\njjj'i\n\u00a7\ni\n1:1,\n'\u25a0\n'\n\"'\n:l\nlv\n'\nII\n\u25a0i\n11\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\ncation by visible illustration, and is embraced in the plan practised with most signal success, by Pattabozzi and Fellenbug,\nof Switzerland, and Mr, and Mrs. Wright and others, ol Edinburgh.\nThe advantages of knowledge, you all know, and can appreciate. Knowledge is power\u2014yes, it is moro, 'tis health,\n'tis riches, 'tis happiness. External nature presents lo the\nmind of man, a vast assemblage of powers and influences,\nbeyond his feeble capabilities of resistance. Ocean's rolling\nbillows, the lightning's fiery course, the volcano's belching\nthroes, nnd tho tempest's fury, he cannot stay. But guided\nand aided by the lights and powers of knowledge\u2014\" he can\nlay his hand upon old ocean's mane, and play familiarly with\nhis hoary locks. He can, with the thunder, talk as friend\n*o friend, nnd weave his garland of the lightning's wing, in\nsportive twist the lightning's fiery wing.\"\nTho volcano's po\\-ers drive his swift-winged car, and the\npuffing steamboat: n.id the whitening sails of every sea, present iEo' is chained to his foaming keel. Then knowledge\nis powe r. And, further, it is health. I have no hesitation in\naffirming, that a generally diffused knowledge of tho laws\nof health, ofthe nature and qualities of the influences around\nus; and of their proper relationship to tho human constitution, would make diseases, 'ike angels' visits, few and far be-\nIwoen. You may think this is a strange declaration from\none who fattens on your calamities, and whose bread is the\nprice of ministering to those diseases. But it is not therefore the less true. The business of ihe philanthropic physician does not cease with the administration of tho bolus, the\npill and the emetic. He has\u00bba higher duty to perforin, in contributing, from his knowledge of disease and ils causes to the\nprevention of human suffering. But hero his efforts are all\nparalyzed by the lamentable fatuity and ignorance that prevails on this subject. You study ihe structure of the houses,\ncastles, and temples of every clime.\u2014You explore the bowels of the earth,\u2014you trace the meanderings of every river,\nand the lakes, gulfs, and seas of all countries. Yet, of the\nhouse you live in, your own body, you know nothing. Its\ncovering, its frame work, its apartments, ils running streams\nits reservoirs and fountains, its beautiful exhibition of the perfection of the natural organic laws, you have never studied.\nThis ought you to do, and not leave the other undone. This\nis the point to begin at, lo enjoy the full tide of healthful vigor and activity, of which your physical powers are capable.\n( I hope some medical gentleman will pursue this subject.)\nAgain\u2014Knowledge is wealth. Wealth does not consist\nso much in the accumulation of a specific amount of properly, as in Iho number of sources or means wo have at command, of ministering to our comfort. These, sources, or\nmeans of comfort and enjoyment, are opened in perpetual\nfountains, by widely diffused practical knowledge,\nMan, in a state of nature, is brought into being a helpless,\nhomeless wanderer; gathering a precarious subsistence from\nthe fruits of the forest; and sheltered from the rudo winds and\npitiless storm by his thatched wigwam. But let the lights of\nknowledge dawn upon his benighted intellect, and he beholds\nin tho earth upon which ho roams, a thousand capabilities ol\nministering to his wants.    Where before he discovered noth.\ning but barren, burning sands and rugged mountain cliffs ho\nand diamonds, and iron, and all\nn\nnow finds gold, and silver,\nthe variety of metals and precious stories, ready to be made\nsubsidiary to his every enjoyment. Gravitation enables him\nto make the dashing, foaming cataract perforin the labor of a\npro-\nthousand hands.    The winds waft him tho riches and\nducts of every land.    In fine, all the natural and physical\nlaws, unfolded to him by knowledge, are rendered subservient\nand willing caterers to his case and wealth.\nFurther, and in conclusion\u2014knowledge is happiness. In\nillustrating this branch of our subject, it is necessary that our\nnotions of happiness should be enlarged and rigidly defined,\nWhat, then, is human happiness, or in what does it consist?\nEndless speculations and differences of opinion ever have,\nand elo yet exist on ibis subject. One individual tells you it\nis only to bo found in a savage state of nature ; and novelists,\npoets, and even philosophers have dwelt in songs of sweetest\nmelody on the \"paucity of its wants, the simplicity of its pursuits, and the solidity of its pleasures.\" It is here, wc are\ntold, unsophisticated nature revels in all the luxury of prime-\n,-al innocence. Unlearned in crime, undebauched by effem-\nnucy, unpractised in the duplicity, treachery, and cunning of\ncivilized life, the spirits, free as their own mountain breeze,\npialf delights, constant, and without alloy. The sensualist\ntells you it can only be found in sparkling bowls, in sumptuous racy viands, and in tho revels of the seraglio. The\nmiser points to his heaps of shining gold, and says, behold!\nthere is happiness. The poet and the philosopher tell you it\ncan only be found amid Parnassian flowers and Acadcmus\nshades\u2014that fancy, reason and judgment are every thing\u2014\nthat health or sickness, riches or poverty, pain or pleasure,\ndo not even enter into the account of human happiness. Another assures you it is all summed up in these three words\n\u2014wife, children, and friends. And still another, that\nit consists only in the observance of moral tlulies. Now,\nthese positions are all wrong; and the errors consist in the\ndisjointed, one-sided and superficial views taken of human\nnature.\u2014One has looked at man only as animal, another as\nsocial, another as an intellectual, anel another as a moral being.\u2014They have seen these faculties of his nature in lively\nand pleasant exorcise\u2014they havo indulged in the pleasures\nof sense, they have, mingled amid tho sweets of social intercourse; they have drank at ihe Pyercan Spring, and they\nhave experienced the calm peace and joy arising from a conscientious discharge of moral duty. But they have looked\nat these sources of happiness, one at a time\u2014as isolated,\napart, ono from the other, and incapable of being enjoyed all\ntogether. The perfection of human happiness consists in lhc\naccordant exercise of all the powers, physical, intellectual,\nand moral. This constitutes the highest point of human perfection on earth ; and as man is a progressive being, the continued and illimitable development of those powers, purified\nand spiritualized, will, no doubt, constitute his never-failing\nhappiness in the abodes of the blessed.\nIn tho constitution of our faculties, God has designed our\nmoral nature for the study of Himself, our intellectual for the\nstudy of His works, and our animal for the preservation and","fullrs":{},"find":"606.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"605","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1852269","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
