<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/497</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>497</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/497/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH.WES T E R N JOURNAL.\n121\nFor thfl Selulh-Westorn Journal.\nAGENCY   OF   THE   DEITY   IN   THE   MATERIAL\nUNIVERSE.\nIsity, becontii\ninuod.    !\u2022 or certainly a mere divine willing, without a divino impulse given, could never, according to all hit-\n. '\"an analogies, put a world in motion; and neither can a mere\nThotnrh changes are constantly taking place; around us,i,\/;,\u2022;\u201e\u201e \u201e,;\/\/;\u201e\u201e. ,,.,,i,,\u201e\u201e \u201e       ,\u25a0       , \u25a0\u2022  \u25a0 ,\niiioii;,!! en \u00bbb     ^ j ol ,    ,\"' \\aivine wmmg, without a continued dtvine impulse, continue a\n,arn,ony and regularity we find to be every where maintain- workl i\u201e motion, maintain the harmonious\ned. The heavenly hosts wheel their trackless courses with\ninieleviating exactness nnd order: tho seasons perform their\nappointed circuits: the myriads of animated existences, crowding \"every portal and avenue \" of this busy world, live their\nlittle hour, and are gone to make room for their successors.\nThrou'diout the whole universe all is harmony, System\nand law seem stamped upon the very face of nature. Its\nvery jarrings and discords are instinct with order and beauty.\nBlind indeed must be he, who, in all the operations of nature,\nso multifarious and intricate, yet so unchanging and constant,\nran see no directing power, no moving, controlling principle,\nbut chance; who can look out upon the broad face of the\nuniverse, noting every change, and watching the progress of\nevery event, and believe that all things are casual; that th.\nvery system of nature is chained to the car of a blind and\nsoulless contingency.'\nBut how is this beautiful and harmonious system of the\nuniverse lo be maintained ? Where, or in what, does the\nmoving, controlling, and governing power reside?\nMany and diverse theories have been advanced by philosophers upon this subject. Some indue matter with qualities\nof life, making certain active powers essentially inherent in\nit, from whose action result all the phenomenn of nature.\nBut this scheme of materialism is altogether baseless, as has\nbeen frequently and fully shown. Other philosophers toll\nus, that the phenomena of nature result from the action of\ncertain powers, not indeed essentially inherent in matter, but\nwhich were communicated lo it by its creator. But this theory finds few supporters. Indeed both, to free themselves\nfrom absurdity, should have advanced a step farther, and coa\nlescod with another theory, which supposes that matter has\nmind; that all motion results from, anel is maintained by, a\nmaterial intelligence. Kepler, who adopted this last theory,\nsupposes thai the planets are indued with minds, fur more\ngrasping and acute than our own, and that, in order to regulate their own movements, they have the power of making\nobservations upon the apparent diameter of the sun.\n1'hc planets, then, are animals\u2014and if so, there may be\nno absurdity in supposing, that the planets originated, and of\nthemselves maintain llieir own motions. But, if this is not\ntrue: if they are not animals, then, to say that the planets\nhavo minds, conveys to us no more knowledge, than to say\n!'iat they are obedient lo the power of gravitation or attrac-\niction of every\npart, control all tho changes of matter, cause life lo die, and\nout of death bring life.\nBut in comparison with all these theories, how simple,\nbeautiful and sublime, how consistent with the light of reason,\nand tho teachings of the; word of Ood, and how consonant\nwith the feelings of every devout, unprejudiced, and Christian\nheait, is the doctrine which supposes all ihe phenomena of\nnature to be the immediate effects of the Divine agency that,\nnot only was the mighty building of the universe reared by\nthe hand of Deity, but that, were his upholding power\nwithdrawn for a moment even, the vast and finished edifice\nwould heave from ils broad and deep foundations, and tho\nworld, now so beautiful and harmonious, become an univer-\nsal wreck, one mighty chaos ? How vague, confused, und\nuncertain, are. the notions commonly entertained in regard to\nthis subject? Wo examine the operations of nature, we explore its deep and wonderful mysteries; we view the thronging multitudes of animated beings, which now cover the\nearth; we turn our gaze upward, and as our eye wanders\nfrom planet to planet and from sun to sun, our minds struggle,\nin vain, to grasp \"the terrible magnitude ofthe starry :.kics;\"\nwo turn back to ages far gone down on the stream of time, and\ntheir rccorelstell us ofthe same operations, tho same changes,\nthe same vast and complicated movements, the same busy\nworld, and the same starry heavens; and wc feel that duration\nand permanency are Stamped upon the whole system of nature, and that this permanency is essential and inherent. Wo\ndo not feel, to adopt the eloquent language of the author of\nthe Natural History of Enthusiasm, \"that the massy pillars\nof creation, with its towering superstructure, and ils high-\nlion.\nOther philosophers tell us, that the universe is but one vast,\nm'ghty, and complicated machine, formed with such exquisite\nSkill by the hand of Deity, that being once put in motion, it\nmoves on harmoniously, and, unless stopped by the hand of its\nCreator, forever. This theory, though, in fact, differing little\nfrom the two first mentioned, has had, under one form or other, many able and pious supporters. But since, strictly speal.\n\"'=' '\"alter possesses no other power, but the negative one of\nt'teri'ia, the impulse, first given bv the Deity, must, of a neccs\nwrought embellishments, and its innumerable tenants, are absolutely destitute of intrinsic permanency, and that the stupendous frame, with its nice and mighty movements, is incessantly issued tWKJMjfrom the fount of being.\"\nWe talk ol \"the laws of nature\" as if, in the beginning,\nthe Creator ordained certain regulations, in obedience to\nwhich th e universe was to move on forever We seem to\nregard the Deity as a far-off Being, who, having made the\nworld, and stamped certain immutable laws upon its fiame,\nretired into a state of inactivity and rest, almost totally re gard-\nless of the concerns of his new-born universe, or busied himself in the creation of other worlds, rearing the magnificent\nsuperstructures of new systems. This phrase,\u2014\"the: laws\nof nature\"\u2014wo clothe, as it were, with an active, living energy; wo make it an all-pervading, ever-operative power,\na mighty, controlling, mysterious agent. In obedience to its\nmandates, the planetary systems roll on, ceaseless, untiring.\nIt speaks, and the ocean, calm and \"gentle as an infant's\nslumbers,\" becomes instinct with a fearful, resistless energy.\nIt breathes upon the land, and its wintry chain is snapped\nasunder, the earth decks itself in its beautiful garments, flower* are wreathed into garlands, and smiles and gladness wait\non \" the bridal of Nature.\"    It rides\u2014and the clouds are its\nVOL.  I. Vllt,\n-'' '\u25a0\u25a04 *i\n' c#3\u00bb\n\u25a0 *M3\n' \u25a0 'V if\n\u25a0;jl'-|\n;'i- ;'|\nIt J\n:.\u00a3\u25a0\n'il*;\n' i'.'ViR!\n\u25a0   \u25a0\n\u25a0  \"if\n. cl ''&lt; fel\n\u25a0\n'\n.    j","fullrs":{},"find":"498.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"497","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1809400","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
