<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/385</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>385</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/385/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T II - W ES TE It N J 0 UItNAL.\n21\nTHE PERIODICAL AND NEWSPAPER PRESS\nor Tin-. Unitbo States,\n\\siN.-w, rettd before ibo Jefferson College unil Wasblnirton Lyceum,on Stttui.\nrlny, September?, |83?., iiv i.. a. Ubhancon, Esq-, Edlior of (in- I'reo Trader,\nMr.. Phesident, and Gentlemen of the Lyceum:\u2014\nThrown upon your indulgence, with brief space of time for\npreparation, having bei n absent,mil niduoiisly engaged except\nfor the past two days, I would still manifest my sense of re-\nspe'et to this association, by selecting a ihemc for an essay, which\nshall combine general interest with useful information\u2014nnd,\nfor this end, permit me name \" The Periodical and Newspaper Pressoflhc United Slates\" as a subject with which I have,\nto some extent, become professionally acquainted, and which\nThose general remarks only go to show the omnipotence\nof the Press, anil the extent of English literati! re, of which\nAmerican literature is a component part. And one of the\npopular and most effective modes in which the Anglo American literature operates nnd displays itself, is, through the medium of the Periodical and Newspaper Press. America, tho\nland of freemen, isnlso the homo of free thought and the freedom ofthe press. If not the biilh place, it is the nursery of\nnewspapers. It bus more periodicals and newspapers In proportion to its millions of inhabitants than any other section of\nthe Globe. Itefined Franco, with her thirty millions, bus not\nhalf the number of newspapers and periodicals that the fourteen or fifteen millions of our own country have: and the\ncannot fail to be interesting to an audience of Literary Ladies ,- -.  i t--     t       ,.,,       ,, \u25a0     ,- ,,   ,.    .'      ,. ,\nUnited Kingdom of Great Bntan falls fnr short of tho propor-\nnnd Gentlemen, however leeble may he my iiouer in illnstru-   . ,. , ,.   , .     .     ..   .    , _\n\u25a0   ' Hon which welnitl in the I nitid .Mates.\nting the subject. ,\n.   .     . .I, \" was sneenngly said by a leading British Review, nfeiy\n'Ihe An nl Printing- is one of those trophies ol modern \u2022        .,,-',      '\u25a0      ,-. -.       \u25a0      ,-\n.        \u2022        ,. , i yours since : \"As lor American literature, it consists of a storm\niniies, Willi limn llie lield ol luiniaii niveii'ii,n, whieb Ireslu ns]   r .,   ,,    , ,     -. ,.\nn     -     . ol newspapers.    I'erhnps the idea, present to this sarcastic Tc-\niho laurels obtained in all prior lime, and rescues, from the   \u25a0       ,     \u2022  T ,- ., ,, ,-  , \u2022\n, i, i    . \u2022      viewer s mind, was one ol those old fashioned snow storms:\nmotlldennir rumsof thepast, all tliui ,s worlliy ol pn-sei vntioii:; ,      ,, .     ,.,..     ,,    , .,   , ...      , ,       ,\n.     \\ ,-   ,      '     I        \u2022 countless flakes filling Iho heavens with fleecy, fringed, broad,\nwhile, at the same time, it leaves behind, at mi almost iminca-h   ,.   ,,   .      ,       .       ,      . - ,    .,.     ,, ,  ,\n.    . lenly floats, obscuring tho vision and piling the earth knee\nsural) 0 distance,  the lileralnre ol anliinnly and the iiroui est! , - ,    ,,     .-   ., t      , ,   ,. ... -,,   ,.   , ,\n..,.,,', deep with   the feathery  burden, nnd  lulling slill   laster   and\nachievements ol niicn nt philosophy.    Il was In have been ex-,,. , -, , t ' ,-, ,,       ,   , - ,.,\n1 ,. i  ,      .     i   , thicker, wider mid tli eper,   until the whole  ceuitiiii lit  ol Co-\nmi ctcd tluil mi nit so poti nl, which has pislly bei n callt tl \"ihe t      , .   \u25a0      ,- -     - n i i\n1 .       .,,\u201e,.' .    .     nimbus was n mountain ol snow\u2014a virgin world dressed out\nart preservative ol all nils,   should have given a powerlul im- \u2022   ,i       i \u2022,       ,       e i i    .     , .  t-        ,\u201e, \u2022\n1 . -,,,,- l in tue while robe nl  her espousals lo Immortality.    Ibis\nnetus to mind, have openednew vistas of thought, and dire'ctcd    -  ,,,       ,       ,.   -,       \u201e       ,  ,  ,- , \u25a0 \u2022',\n1 ' \\miglil have been ins idea, although I think it more m keeping\niln  intellect ol in.nikiiiil nilo new and in,bier eh tiiiuls.     I do     -,   ,- ...   ,      , \u2022 &gt;.       .   ,,    ,,\ni with Ins sneer, i! Iho stormy image in Ins iniiul hud been a\nhut state a truism when I repeal that tin- Press moro nearly,   i . ,   .  ,   P ,   .   ,  , . , , , ,. ,\nii .      , \u25a0 \u2022 ,     i \u25a0 i       ,'   whirlwind ol dust, shaking rudely the leaves ol miliiimi and\nrealizes the idea of tho lever of Archimedes, Willi which, (if he ,, ,   ,    ,\n,,   , strewing them in nnger over the land,\ncould find a fulcrum) he was to move tho world, than any oth-\ni, ,i   , \u25a0 i  i \u2022   ,i ip.\" The genius of any people will naturally seek out its own\nor discovery or invention that is recorded in thcannnls ollune,       ... , .       *\n...     .i     ' i  .        i i .i        ,i    , modes of action.    If American genius chooses to fashion its\nWere there but one language spoken upen the earth, tho nc- . .      .\n,-,i \u25a0 i ,i ii.i ii       greiilness through the instrumentality of thcperiodicalornows\"\ninn ol ibis moral engine, upon the world nt large, would re- .\n, ,  ., ,-ti .tit        nnner press, nnd ns surely attains its end in that way, who has\n.-\u2022enible the sweep ol an unbroken wave across the broad sea. M   '.    '\ni, i   ,-       e        i   . it ,   ,i ,-      ,T ,   a right to complain or the cause to sneer ?\nPulsation niter pulsation would bo thrown hum tho cintreto '\nthe distant extremities, till the feeling of mankind would be Venice, pre-eminent amidst her other honors, bus that of\nnlikcandknowledgethesamc. Differenceoflnnguago,thcgrcat originating newspapers, in 153G, nearly a liuntlrcd yenrs be-\nbarrior which more effectually divides nations than the Alpine fore tho scttlemi nt of Jamestown and Plymouth, Tho first\nchains or the pili s of the Andes, interrupts this flow of com- paper was called Gazelle from its price, which was a small\nmunication between tho various sections of thocivilizcd world, copper Vcnitian coin called Gazctta, It was first issued in\nwhile, nt the same time, (probably on the principle of division manuscript, ns ihe government of I bat city would not then per\nof labor) it may havi a tendency to enrich tho mass of intel-mil tho diffusion of printed news, Thirty volumes of ibis .\nlectual acquirement or accumulation, which busy translators \" Father ofnowspapors\" nre now in In- found in a \\ enilinn I ,i-\nand linguists are hourly transferring to the common treasury brary. This paper was spoken of in other countries as a\nin lie diffused again ever ihe earth through such mediums ns '' Mill of News'' sent from Venice every month to all places\nare the must (\u2022\u2022milium lo largo m.-issi s nl mankind. Fnr ex. where tho merchants nl' that city traded. The first printed\nample, tin- French language being spoken or rend by the best paper was in I den, fifty two years after this, during the in-\neducated peoplo of all civilized countries, it affords a medium vasion ofthe English channel by tho Spanish Armada; but\nfor the diffusion of tho philosophy, and modes of thinking, ofthe first regular weekly newspaper over primed in tho world\nthat acute and refined country almost over the whole earth.\u2014 Mas in London in IG20, coeval with iho English sediments\nThe English language is. perhaps, a still n diffused nnd on ibis continentin Virginia and Massachusetts.    Ten years\ninllui ntial medium, being the language in which tho Magna after this, a paper mi tho same plan was established in Paris.\nChiiri:i of the barons of King John, mid the I leclnration of From this period ihe history of newspapers is like the growth\nAmerican Independence were penned, and, therefore, the language of liberty and freedom of mind. It is also at the pro-\nsent time, in the highest degree, the language of Maralime\nTrade and discovery, thus extending ils influence from the straits\nof Babel mandcl in the east, to the Oregon in the west.\nil'the mighty oak, without any pause, annually expanding\nand widening in proportion to the growth of mind, of science\nnnd of freedom. At first the progress was slow, tine hundred years after the establishment ofthe first weekly paper in\nLondon there was a daily paper established in that same city ;\nmmt","fullrs":{},"find":"386.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"385","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1781452","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
