<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Transcript Crump 203A</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Special Collections Online</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-sce:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <note type="preferred citation" displayLabel="Cite As">LSU Special Collections Online, Louisiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.</note>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/LSU_SCE/id/197</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2006-10-23</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-11-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>LSU_SCE</alias>
         <pointer>197</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/LSU_SCE/197/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-02 09:47:14">{"title":"Transcript Crump 203A","creato":{},"date":{},"dates":{},"publis":{},"contri":{},"subjec":{},"descri":{},"notes":{},"langua":{},"transc":"Narrator: Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Interviewer: Pamela Dean Session I Transcriber: Barrett Campbell 8 July 1992 Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Tape 203 Side A DEAN: [005] Alright. We're back again. CRUMP: My dad do and say things like when he had his nightclub, he would have his deliveries made at the house. Because a lot of the nightclubs in town were also stores, and so they were open all day. So they made deliveries there. Dad's was only a straight nightclub, and it was open only in the evenings. So his deliveries would be made at the house. We would sign for products and things like that, and all of us were designated to do that. Dad would tell us how to behave with them, you know that we were to be polite, we and we were not to accept any mistreatment. Well, none of them mistreated us. They were all very nice to us. But I remember they would say things to him, like they would call him \"Hoss\". He would just call them \"Hoss\" back. I never understood what the \"Hoss\" was, but he said it was something white men did to black men is call you \"Hoss\". So he called them \"Hoss\" back. I remember there was a man next door that was knocking on the neighbor's door. He asked Dad, \"Do you know if Willie Hall is home?\" And Dad says, \"No, but his wife is there.\" He said, \"But I don't know her name.\" And Dad said, \"Her name is Mrs. Hall.\" Those are the kinds of things he used to have to think to do. The man looked really baffled. He's like, \"I'm not going to call this black woman Mrs. Hall, excuse me.\" So he just left. He just walked away. My mother never told them her first name, so they would just say good evening. She wasn't going to have them calling her Pauline. Anyone else, but not . . . it was for the reason that they wanted to use her first name. DEAN: Right, right. CRUMP: So those are the kinds of little things I used to see my parents having to do, and Dad never said \"Mr.\" anyone. He just say, \"I don't 'Mister' no white man.\" Because it was required to say, \"Yes sir\" and \"Mister,\" and he wasn't going to do those things. So he didn't \"Mister\" anybody. Everybody was whatever their first name was. Of course, they first named him, but he first named them, too. Unless they called him \"Hoss,\" then he called them \"Hoss\", too. [Crump and Dean laugh] It's only funny now. It's really terribly stupid, you know, that that kind of oppression was even leveed on anyone for whatever reason. So after living through all of that and seeing all of the things that I saw, what could LSU do to me?\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 203, Side A DEAN: You didn't think it would be more fun to be in a group of . . . CRUMP: Black kids? No. DEAN: Black kids like yourself where you . . . CRUMP: [044] No. No, because my mother was probably going to send me away with so many restrictions. They weren't going to let me live on campus at Southern because they didn't trust the dormitories there. At LSU, they were going to let me live on campus. I was looking at the advantages. I'm going to be away from home, be living on campus. At Southern, I'd have to commute. The thought of commuting just . . . I could imagine myself being tired because I was anemic. So tired was something that I got very easily. The thought of traveling back and forth in the car to school everyday was just tiring. To think of coming home and studying college work in the midst of my brothers and sisters who were in high school and elementary school . . . DEAN: Had your father gotten the house built by then? CRUMP: Yes, the house was built in '57. DEAN: So you did at least have a little more room? CRUMP: Yes, I had more room, but still not enough for college work. I just felt like college needed to be totally separate. Something in me . . . DEAN: Not with six kids in the family. CRUMP: [052] Yes, yes, I wanted to be away from there. I had had it. I was done with that. My brothers were wild. The fact that I was going . . . When Dad took me to LSU and I saw the campus and I saw how pretty it was, I wanted to go there. I didn't think about how I was going to be treated because that . . . I saw what I was going to like about it. I saw a pretty campus with good buildings, and I saw the dormitories. They looked good and clean and solid, and I was going to have my own room. That's all I thought about. I was going to be going to a school that's credible and one that where my mother trusted me to live on campus without the restrictions. When I was in high school, I didn't get to hang out with my friends anyway, except at school. DEAN: Oh really? CRUMP: Yes, so I wasn't used to a big social life anyway. DEAN: [065] Had you done any dating in high school? CRUMP: Very little. Very, very little. There, I think boys had come to the house, and I had gone to the prom. I'd get to go to some games and see them there. No one had picked me up and took me to the game. Once, in [my] senior year, when our class gave a supper,\n2\n\nCrump, Maxine - Tape 203, Side A I got to go for a ride in the car with my boyfriend and my girlfriend's boyfriend, and we had more fun! Just fun, you know, it was like, \"What does my mother think is so bad about this?\" [Crump and Dean laugh] And I got to go on the senior class trip but not with my boyfriend, I had to ride the bus with the rest of the kids while he drove in the car because my mother didn't trust me to ride with him. DEAN: Where was the trip to? CRUMP: A beach not very far from us. It was a day's bus ride. It was nothing. It wasn't even a nice beach. It was a made up beach. DEAN: Well, there aren't any beaches in Louisiana. CRUMP: Yes. It was the only beach the blacks could go to. We couldn't go to the other beaches in Louisiana that were also made up. This one was even worse made up, but we enjoyed it. DEAN: Well, we've been going for quite a while now. Do you want to stop now and set up another time? CRUMP: Sure, we can do that. DEAN: To, to go on with the LSU, per se? CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: Is that all right with you? CRUMP: Yes, that would be fine. DEAN: [083] Good. Good. [End Tape 203, Side A. End Session I.]\n\n3","digitb":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections","source":{},"collec":{},"sourca":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections ( http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special )","type":{},"format":{},"imagb":{},"file":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.","cite":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections, LOUISiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.","to":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","relati":"http:\/\/louisdl.louislibraries.org\/cdm4\/index_LSU_SCE.php?CISOROOT=%2FLSU_SCE","typea":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"198.pdf","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2006-10-23","dmmodified":"2006-10-23","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"197","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"14765","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.01 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
      <transcript displayLabel="Transcript">Narrator: Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Interviewer: Pamela Dean Session I Transcriber: Barrett Campbell 8 July 1992 Maxine Crump 4700.0117 Tape 203 Side A DEAN: [005] Alright. We're back again. CRUMP: My dad do and say things like when he had his nightclub, he would have his deliveries made at the house. Because a lot of the nightclubs in town were also stores, and so they were open all day. So they made deliveries there. Dad's was only a straight nightclub, and it was open only in the evenings. So his deliveries would be made at the house. We would sign for products and things like that, and all of us were designated to do that. Dad would tell us how to behave with them, you know that we were to be polite, we and we were not to accept any mistreatment. Well, none of them mistreated us. They were all very nice to us. But I remember they would say things to him, like they would call him "Hoss". He would just call them "Hoss" back. I never understood what the "Hoss" was, but he said it was something white men did to black men is call you "Hoss". So he called them "Hoss" back. I remember there was a man next door that was knocking on the neighbor's door. He asked Dad, "Do you know if Willie Hall is home?" And Dad says, "No, but his wife is there." He said, "But I don't know her name." And Dad said, "Her name is Mrs. Hall." Those are the kinds of things he used to have to think to do. The man looked really baffled. He's like, "I'm not going to call this black woman Mrs. Hall, excuse me." So he just left. He just walked away. My mother never told them her first name, so they would just say good evening. She wasn't going to have them calling her Pauline. Anyone else, but not . . . it was for the reason that they wanted to use her first name. DEAN: Right, right. CRUMP: So those are the kinds of little things I used to see my parents having to do, and Dad never said "Mr." anyone. He just say, "I don't 'Mister' no white man." Because it was required to say, "Yes sir" and "Mister," and he wasn't going to do those things. So he didn't "Mister" anybody. Everybody was whatever their first name was. Of course, they first named him, but he first named them, too. Unless they called him "Hoss," then he called them "Hoss", too. [Crump and Dean laugh] It's only funny now. It's really terribly stupid, you know, that that kind of oppression was even leveed on anyone for whatever reason. So after living through all of that and seeing all of the things that I saw, what could LSU do to me?

Crump, Maxine - Tape 203, Side A DEAN: You didn't think it would be more fun to be in a group of . . . CRUMP: Black kids? No. DEAN: Black kids like yourself where you . . . CRUMP: [044] No. No, because my mother was probably going to send me away with so many restrictions. They weren't going to let me live on campus at Southern because they didn't trust the dormitories there. At LSU, they were going to let me live on campus. I was looking at the advantages. I'm going to be away from home, be living on campus. At Southern, I'd have to commute. The thought of commuting just . . . I could imagine myself being tired because I was anemic. So tired was something that I got very easily. The thought of traveling back and forth in the car to school everyday was just tiring. To think of coming home and studying college work in the midst of my brothers and sisters who were in high school and elementary school . . . DEAN: Had your father gotten the house built by then? CRUMP: Yes, the house was built in '57. DEAN: So you did at least have a little more room? CRUMP: Yes, I had more room, but still not enough for college work. I just felt like college needed to be totally separate. Something in me . . . DEAN: Not with six kids in the family. CRUMP: [052] Yes, yes, I wanted to be away from there. I had had it. I was done with that. My brothers were wild. The fact that I was going . . . When Dad took me to LSU and I saw the campus and I saw how pretty it was, I wanted to go there. I didn't think about how I was going to be treated because that . . . I saw what I was going to like about it. I saw a pretty campus with good buildings, and I saw the dormitories. They looked good and clean and solid, and I was going to have my own room. That's all I thought about. I was going to be going to a school that's credible and one that where my mother trusted me to live on campus without the restrictions. When I was in high school, I didn't get to hang out with my friends anyway, except at school. DEAN: Oh really? CRUMP: Yes, so I wasn't used to a big social life anyway. DEAN: [065] Had you done any dating in high school? CRUMP: Very little. Very, very little. There, I think boys had come to the house, and I had gone to the prom. I'd get to go to some games and see them there. No one had picked me up and took me to the game. Once, in [my] senior year, when our class gave a supper,
2

Crump, Maxine - Tape 203, Side A I got to go for a ride in the car with my boyfriend and my girlfriend's boyfriend, and we had more fun! Just fun, you know, it was like, "What does my mother think is so bad about this?" [Crump and Dean laugh] And I got to go on the senior class trip but not with my boyfriend, I had to ride the bus with the rest of the kids while he drove in the car because my mother didn't trust me to ride with him. DEAN: Where was the trip to? CRUMP: A beach not very far from us. It was a day's bus ride. It was nothing. It wasn't even a nice beach. It was a made up beach. DEAN: Well, there aren't any beaches in Louisiana. CRUMP: Yes. It was the only beach the blacks could go to. We couldn't go to the other beaches in Louisiana that were also made up. This one was even worse made up, but we enjoyed it. DEAN: Well, we've been going for quite a while now. Do you want to stop now and set up another time? CRUMP: Sure, we can do that. DEAN: To, to go on with the LSU, per se? CRUMP: Yes. DEAN: Is that all right with you? CRUMP: Yes, that would be fine. DEAN: [083] Good. Good. [End Tape 203, Side A. End Session I.]

3</transcript>
  </extension>
</mods>
