<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/435</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>435</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/435/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"68\nSOU T II - W E S T E R N   J 0 U R N A L.\nw\n\u2022m\n'\u25a0;.g:;*\n:..gi\n'\u25a0\u25a0i-i:\nti''- f\n&gt;|!|\n\u25a0\n;.\n\u2022 \u2022.\nIr''\nii\n|V;\nof his day, do not lie against our American system of education, in which, besides the ancient languages, are usually\ntaught English Grammar, Geography, History, Arithmetic,\nand Algebra, nnd the various other branches of pure mathematics, Natural Philosophy, Natural Science, &amp;C. Indeed\nsuch is the attention paid to these subjects in many of our\nschools, that the classics have been almost entirely superseded.\nThe path of the classical student is strewed with flowers.\nHow many are allured to the love of learning and a studious\nlife by the charms of poetic diction and sentiment, who are\ndeterred by the repulsive aspect ofthe elementary mathematics, which address themselves neither to the feelings nor the\nimagination? The Belles Lotties scatter roses amid\nihbrns of\u2022 abstruse disquisition, smooth the asperities of the\nrugged road, that leads to the summit of iho hill of science',\nand light up an attractive smile, even on the gloomy countenance of scholastic philosophy. They bind their graceful\nwreath around iho austere brow of science, lend attraction to\nvirtue's august form, and insinuate into the heart, by all ihe\nsoft aits of reason and rhetoric combined. Like the harp\nof Orpheus, they can reclaim the barbarian, and soothe the\nsavage by the melody of eloquence. They have contributed\nmore than the sciences to humanize and lo civilize mankind.\nIn the classics especially, all the matchless harmony of numbers, all the glowing imagery of fancy, are employed for the\npurpose of enforcing truth, and recommending virtue. The\nmuses and the graces, with their sister train of kindred virtues, may be said lo lead on their votaries through the flowery fields of classic literature, whose ways are indeed ways of\npleasantness, and all whose paths are peace. Far retired\nfrom the bustle of commerce, the strife of politics, and the\ndin of arms, the student contemplates the bright examples of\nancient sages, heroes, patriots, and statesmen, who adorn the\nannals of Grecian and Roman history. Familiar with such\nexamples, he goes forth into the world full of noble and generous emulation, an enthusiast in the cause of truth and honor.\nPox, the illustrious English orator and statesman, spent a\ngreat part of his boyhood, under the direction of his father,\nin studying the lives of statesmen and heroes, as recorded\nand contrasted in the parallels of Plutarch. Lord Chatham\nalso, whose Roman virtue, and more than Roman dignity of\neloquence, are the admiration of the world, owed much of tl\ngrandeur of his ideas, and his enthusiastic ardor in the cause\nof liberty, to the models with .which he was early familiarized, and to which be applied himself con amore during his\nwhole life, ill the celebrated works of the Chaeronean biographer. What excellent lessons are presented on tho instruct,\nive page of this admirable writer, for the education of youth,\nwho may there learn to imitate the legislative wisdom of a\n.Solon and a Lycurgus, and be led to emulate, while they admire, the wonderful achievements of Roman and ol Spartan\nvalor? Indeed, were I to select the ancient book (the Bible\nalways excepted ) best calculated to excite the youthful mind\nto all that is great and good, I should unquestionably, beyond\nall others, recommend Plutarch's Lives.\nWriting, arithmetic, a smattering of French, a little Latin,\njust enough to huvu it to say that be once studied Latin, with\na few superficial accomplishments, such as dancing, musir,\nfencing, &amp;C, are. generally thought quite sufficient for th,,\ncomplete education of a gentleman. With this, or even a\nmuch inferior preparation, many consider themselves fully\nqualified lo discharge, with credit to themselves and their\ncountry, ihe highest offices of state. And though, unforln-\nnntely, such'men nre sometimes raised, by tho frolic of for.\ntune, quotirs fortuna voluit jocari, to stations of great dignity and importance, yet it is usually only to expose them to ridicule and a constant and painful sense of their inferiority and\nincompetency for the task which they havo undertaken, ,\\\nsuperficial education has auendency to create a spirit of levity. This spirit, when fostered by the perusal of novels nnd\nthe other light and worthless literature of the day, is well calculated to form a frivolous and trifling character, a flippant,\nconceited coxcomb, who enjoys bis happy self-love without a\nrival, and the admiration of his wonderful person without a\nsingle one to envy his felicity.    How contemptible is such a\nharacterl How unworthy a rational being-, born to ocl\na dignified and serious part in the great drama of human\nlife ! Mankind are too apt to lose sight of all that is heroic,\npublic-spirited and magnanimous. Modern times have formed to themselves a virtue rather polished than sublime', that\nconsists in petty courtesies, rather than the tranquil grandeur\nof an elevated mind. It is by turning from the pelit-mailres\nof the present day, lo men like Fahricius and Cain, thai wo\nare brought to recollect the dignity of human   nature.    A\nreatparl of ihe prejudice against the study of Latin and Greek\nin our own country, has originated from the very inaccurate and superficial manner in which they are usually taught,\nShould the student be so fortunate as to comprehend the meaning of an author, by a wretched pronunciation he loses a\ngreat part of his beauty and harmony. It is high time thai\nthis barbarous intermixture of long and short syllables, this\n\"Connecticut Latin,\" as Mr. Jefferson terms it, should be banished from all our schools. The mischiefs inflicted by superficial, tasteless, and indolent teachers-, are not confined to the\nsphere of their direct influence, but extend to the cause of\nclassical learning itself, which is thus made to suffer for faull!\nnot its own, nnd the imputation of defects which do not attach\nto a correct system of instruction. We think, however, thni\nwe seethe dawning uf a brighter day, when classical learning, being presented in all its native beauty and intrinsic excellence, shah be duly appreciated and properly cultivated,\nThe labors of Professor Anthon, and other eminent scholars,\nhavo contributed greatly towards rescuing this branch of literature from the neglect into which it appears lo have been falling, and by elucidating the obscurities of the more difficult\nlUthors, anil pointing out their various beauties of style and\nsentiment, have tended to diffuse a justor taste, and a more\ncorrect mode of studying the classics, in no respect has the\ndefectiveness of our American system of education been so-\napparent, as iho manner in which the study of the Greek\nlanguage has been usually prosecuted. By many, indeed,\nthis study is thought totally superfluous. The common notion\nof Greek comprehends in it nil that is difficult, horrid, un-\noutb, useless, and pedantic, Were we to judge of its utility Ly the attainments of many of our college graduates, some","fullrs":{},"find":"436.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"435","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1899379","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.81 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
