<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/453</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>453</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/453/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"90U T H - W E S T ERN   JOUBNA 1,\nthe chief cause of yellow fever, is embraced in Dr. Caldwell's\n\"Dissertation upon Yellow Fever;\"* viz. that whenever\nthe mean heal or temperature is steadily up to 80\" Fahrenheit,\nor above, for forty days or more in succession, yellow fever\nwill be produced; but if the same mean temperature be maintained for only twenty, thirty, or even thirty-five days, there\nivjll be no yellow fever, provided there be no \"epidemic constitution in the atmosphere;\" which ho has not explained\nThis, at first sight, might appear plausible; but facts com\npletely confute the arguments. We nted not go further than\nlo our own city for the facts. According to a meteorological\ntable given by Dr. Perlee, f the medtl temperature of July\nand August, for sixty-two days, in IS 14-IS 16, and 1818, was\nsteadily from 80\" to 83\", yet no yellow fever occurred in Natchez in either year. In 1817, the mean temperature of July\nwas 80\" for thirty-one days, and August 77\" for thirty-one\ndays, giving a mean temperature of 78^\" for sixty-two days,\nand vet the yellow fever prevailed malignantly. In 1819,\nthe mean temperature of both July and August, sixty-two\ndays, was up lo only 79\" each month, and the mean of September for thirty days, was 75,\" and yet the yellow fever prevailed with great mortality, having become epidemic on the\n14th of September. We might cite authority without end,\nto show the same facts in other places every year; hut we will\nadduce only one more from Natchez, as obtained from the\ntables of Dr. Tooley and others. In 1824, the mean temperature of July was 80\" for thirty-one days; of August,\n82{\" for thirty-one days : together sixty-two days, averaging\n84,\u00b0 and yet no yellow fever occurred in Natchez that yenr.f\nIn 1825, the mean temperature of July was 81\" for thirty-one\ndays; and of August 83J\" for thirty-one days: averaging\n82\u00b0 fur the whole, or 2\" less than 1824, yet the yellow fever\nprevailed with great mortality. If the miasm of yellow fever\nwere the result of any change of moisture, or of TEMPERA-\ni em: solely, which the thermometer would indicate, then we\nmight avert it by watering the streets, to reduce the tempera-\nlure: nr, al least, we might be able to fbrelel its appearance,\naim escape in time,    1 Jut this has not yet been done.\nThere is, doubtless, more or less of it general \"epidemic\nconstitution ofthe atmosphere\" existing at certain times, over\n.'in extensive scope of country. This peculiar state of the\natmosphere, will doubtless predispose the inhabitants to diseases ol t certain type, and they will be afflicted epidemically,\nwhere ibe particular locality is favorable, and the requisite\nexciting causes are brought into action. Hut as regards yellow fever, wo believe the peculiar condition of ihe general\nalmosphero, which precedes it, can he observed, and guarded\nagainst, by proper and timely precaution, and the avoiding and\nremoving what are admitted to be exciting causes. This\n\"epidemic constitution of the air,\" can bo nothing else than\n'he \u2122o,\u201e. of Hippocrates; or the \" seminarium e. c\/elo di-\nmissum\" of Diemerhrceck, if it be not from some physical\n\"use; and the present state of medical science is such, that we\naro not satisfied with an explanation which implies mystery.\n\"is Mod.and Phys.Momolrs,Lexington, 1820,p, 111,'.'. Ac.\n'Chapman's Mod unci Phys. J, v, 3, p. 17.\n\u2022in IS84, then-wore 13 days with rain In July: 3 days in August, and 6 in Sept.\nIn l*B,thcro woro lit   \"      \" \"      11    \u2022\u2022     \" 5   \"\nWhether yellow fever infection can bo imported, and disseminated in an impure air, is a point upon which there is\nless difference of opinion, than upon the origin of the miasm:\nfor, although many contend for its local origin, and the non-\ncontagious character of the disease, yet there are but few who\ncannot perceive, and must admit, that when the miasm, or infection, is once generated abundantly, it may bo introduced\ninto impure air, and there spread the disease. But few remain who are not able (o perceive, that persons may be infected with yellow fever, who sleep in beds or blankets, taken\nfrom highly infected air, or which have likewise been used\nas the death-bed of yellow fever patients.\nAs we have saitl that yellow fever is a commercial disease,\nwo will show to what extent it is so, and in what manner it\nobtains thnt character. In our citation ol authority, we have\nbeen careful to depend upon those who range themselves as\nthe advocates of the domestic origin of the disease, and not\nupon those who have been steeped in the doctrine of contagion. This fact, we hope, will give duo weight to the authority which we adduce.\nAll testimony tends conclusively to establish the point, that\nships which have been long at sea in tropical latitudes, have\noccasionally become thoroughly infected with yellow fever\nmiasm or infection, either while at sen, or while in port: and\nthat this infection has occasionally been so concentrated as to\nhave produced yellow fever in its most aggravated form, in\nthose who have gone on board from shore; and that such\npersons have taken the yellow fever, and died of it in from\nfive to ten days after they breathed the infected air of the\nship; although, at that time, none of the sailors or hands on\nthe ship, were laboring under that disease. In this manner\ndoubtless, in some instances, litis yellow fever begun to prevail in sea-ports, among the many who daily, unconscious of\nthe infection, visit such ships while in port. In this manner,\nin many instances, have the first twenty or thirty cases been\ntraced to intercourse with an infected ship, or to goods from\nthe same. These first cases are generally persons near the\nwharves, draymen, day-laborers, and others who are engaged\nin assisting to unload the cargo. It is perfectly immaterial\nwhether the ship brought the infection from a foreign port,\nor generated it during her voyage. If the air in her hold\ncan be disseminated about the wharf or even if it will cause\nthose who visit tho ship to die of yellow fever, it certainly is\nan imported disease to those who suffer.\nA ship can certainly become infected, nnd much more completely than a house, or a district of a city. On shipboard,\nthe air below is necessarily close for want of ventilation.\u2014\nWc will not travel over all the mass of testimony which\nmight be adduced: but will cite only a few instances in our\nown country, which are conclusive: for one unquestionable\ncase, is as amply illustrative of the principle, as twenty.\nDr. Tully,* one of Ihe most scientific physicians of Connecticut, gives an account of a number of cases of yellow\nfever at Knowles' Landing, in August, 1706. This is a village on tho Connecticut river, about six miles below Middle-\ntown, containing a population of about two hundred souls,\n\u25a0  t'H\n\\ ^ 1\n'\u2022   4\n\u2022   i'i\n\u2022 Sao Med. sn.l Phys, Jour, of New York, vol. I, p. 153-9","fullrs":{},"find":"454.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"453","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1736805","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
