<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/519</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>519</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/519/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m-i\n158\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL-\n,,&amp;W   \u25a0   ,[\nTil'\nif\nliBr*\npi\n\u25a0'i fA\n!l;::\ni. -84-\n: i'i'H\u00ab.'\n- . 'j*\u00bbii\n.\u25a0'\u25a0\u25a0;'..\nm&gt;\nswiftness; sometimes crossing before our bows, sometimes\ndarting along under the bank, and sometimes shooting across\na track of moonlight. Very often there was only one per-\n,on in the canoe, as in the instance I have elsewhere men\nlioned of a woman who was supposed to be going on u visit\ntwenty or thirty miles up the stream. 1 could hardly have\nconceived of a solitude so intense as this appeared to me, the\nbeing alone on that rushing sea of waters, shut in by untrodden forests; the slow fish-hawk wheeling overhead, and\nperilous masses of driftwood whirling down the current;\ntrunks obviously uprooted by the forces of nature, and not\nlaid low by the hand of man. What a spectacle must our\nboat, with its gay crowds, have appeared to such a solitary\nWhat a revelation that there was a busy world still stirring\nsomewhere; a fact which, I think, I should soon discredit il\n1 lived in the depths of this wilderness, for life would become\ntolerable there only by the spirit growing in harmony with\nthe scene, wild and solemn as the objects around it.\nAt eleven o'clock, on the ninth and last day of our voyage,\nwe passed Paducah, in Kentucky, a small, neat settlement on\nthe point of junction ofthe Tennessee and Ohio. Smithland,\nat the mouth of the Cumberland river, soon appeared; and,\nas we wished to ascend to Nashville without delay, we were\nglad to see a small steamboat in waiting. We stepped on\nshore, and stood there, in spile of a shower, for some time,\nwatching the \"Henry Clay\" ploughing up the river, and\nwaving our handkerchiefs in answer to signals of farewell\nfrom several of the multitude who were clustered in every\npun of the noble vessel.\u2014Miss Harriet Marlineau.\nsense, and as the typo of lovo, unity, and a state of peace, i\nperfect happiness, But they have a poor idea of the Dec\nand the rewards which are destined for the just made nerf\nwho can only adopt the literal sense of an eternal concert\na never-ending birth-day ode. I rather suppose this shouIJ\nbo understood some commission from the Highest, some dm.\nto discharge with the applause of a satisfied conscience\nThnt the Deity, who himself must bo supposed to feel Ion\nand affection for the beings he has called into existence\nshould delegate a portion of those powers, I, for one, cannit\nconceive altogether so wrong a conjecture. We would (hen\nfind reality in Milton's sublime machinery of the guardian\nsaints, or genii of kingdoms. Nay, we would npproachio\nthe Catholic idea of the employment of saints, though with\nout approaching the absurdity of saint-worship, which do-\ngrades their religion. There would be, we must suppose\nin these employments, difficulties to overcome and exertion,\nto be made, for ull which the celestial beings employed would\nhave certain appropriate powers. I cannot help otvnfas\nthat a life of active benevolence is more consistent with my\nideas, than an eternity of music. But it is all speculation,\nand it is impossible lo guess what wo shall do, unless we\ncould ascertain the equally difficult previous question, what\nwe are to be. But there is a God, and a just God\u2014a judgment and a future life\u2014and all who own so much, lei them\nact according to the faith that is in them. I would nol, of\ncourse, limit the range of my genii to this confined earth.\nThere is the universe, with all its endless extent of words\nDiary of Sir Walter Scott.\n1SELIEF IN THE DEITY.\nThere is nothing more awful than to attempt to cast a\nglance among the clouds and mists which hide the broken\nextremity of the celebrated bridge of Mirza. Yet, when\n\u2022ivory day brings us nigher that termination, one would almost think our views should become clearer. Alasl it is\nnot so: there is a curtain to be withdrawn, a veil to be rent,\nbefore we shall see things as they really are. There are\ntew, I trust, who disbelieve the existence of a God; nay, I\ndoubt if, at all times and in all moods, any single, individual\never adopted that hideous creed, though some have professed\nit. With the belief of a Deity, that of the immortality of\ntlio soul and of the state of future rewards and punishments,\nis indissolubly linked. More we are not to know of: but\nneither are we prohibited from all attempts, however vain,\nto pierce the solemn, sacred gloom. The expressions used\nin scripture are, doubtless, metaphorical, for penal fires and\nheavenly melody are only applicable to beings endowed with\ncorporeal senses; and, at least till the period of the resurrection, the spirits of men, whether entering into the perfection\nof the just, or committed to the regions of punishment, are\nnot connected with bodies. Neither is it to be supposed that\nthe glorified bodies which shall arise in the last day, will be\ncapable of the same gross indulgence with which ours are\nnow solaced. That the idea of Mahomet's paradise is inconsistent with the purity of our heavenly religion, will be\nreadily granted ; and see Mark xii. 35. Harmony is obviously chosen as the least corporeal of all gratifications of tht\nEXPERIENCE.\nExperience\u2014word so lightly used, so little understood1\nExperience\u2014mysterious spirit I whose result is fell by all,\nwhose nature is described by none. The father warns the\nson of your approach, and sometimes looks to you as bis offspring's cure, and his own consolation. We hear of you in\nihe nursery\u2014we hear of you in the world\u2014we hear of you\nin books ; but who has recognised you until he was your\nsubject, and who has discovered the object of so much fame,\nuntil he has kissed your chain 1 To gain you is the wort\nof all, and the curse of all; you are at the same time necessary to our happiness, and destructive of our felicity; yon\nare the saviour of all things and the destroyer of all things,\nour best friend and our bitterest enemy; for you teach M\ntruth, and that truth is\u2014despair. To wake from your bright\nhopes, nnd feel that all is vanity\u2014to be roused from your\ncrafty plans, and know that all is worthless, is a bitter, but\nyour sure destiny. Escape is impossible; for despair is the\nprice of conviction. How many centuries havo fled Since\nSolomon, in his cedar-palaces, sung tho vanity of man\nThough his harp was golden, and his throne of ivory, to\nfeelings were not less keen, and his conviction not loss complete. How many sages of all nations have, since the monarch of Jerusalem, echoed his sad philosophy! yet the vain\nbubble still glitters, and still allures, and must forever. The\ngenealogy of experience is brief; for experience is the ch'1\"\nof thought, and thought is the child of action.    We cannot\nlearn men from books, nor can we form, from written\nJc","fullrs":{},"find":"520.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"519","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1850184","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
