<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 6</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2203</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2203</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2203/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 6, Page 6","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[6]\nConvention all reports, projects or plans, for improvements in their respect'**\nstates, to be read, and if desired, discussed, and referred to the appropriate oene_\nral committees.\nMr. J. E. Caldwell, of Louisiana, made a motion, which was carried, that th\u00bb\nseveral states be now called on to present their projects.\nThe following was offered by Mr. Albert Pike, of Arkansas, and on his motion\nreferred to the Committee on Resolutions.\nResolved, That this Convention is profoundly penetrated with tbe conviction\nthat the state of Louisiana and the city of New-Orleans are deeply interested] ig\nthe develepment of the resources of such of the South-western states as lie west\nof the Mississippi River, in the increase of their population and production, aad\nin securing to the city of New-Orleans, for all coming time, by energetic me*\nures promptly taken and steadfastly pursued, the great and growing trade of that\nimportant region, for which Providence has done everything, and Man, hitherto,\nlittle or nothing.\nResolved, That the Committee on Routes be instructed to inquire in regard to\nthe agricultural and mineral resources of the slate of Arkansas, and those portions of the states of Texas and Missouri, the trade of which can be permanently\nsecured to the city of New-Orleans, and what roads are contemplated in those stata,\nin the building of which, that city is, in fact, interested.\nResolved, That the Committee on Ways and Means are instructed to inquire id\nwhat manner aid can be extended by the state of Louisiana and city of New-\nOrleans towards the construction of such roads.\nResolved, That this Convention will urge upon the people and the legislatureof\nthe state of Louisiana the importance of becoming acquainted with the great natural\nresources of those states, of aiding in their development by all proper and legitimate means, and of opening channels by which their trade shall flow permanently\ninto the city of New-Orleans, instead of being diverted soon, and diverted forever,\nto the Atlantic cities; to which end they will urge the state of Louisiana to draw\ncloser the bonds which unite her with those sister states ; to assure them of her\nearnest and cordial co-operation and sympathy in their plans of improvement, and\nher warm interest in their prosperity and welfare, and to pledge to them her aid,\nher encouragement, and her kind offices, and those of her citizens and ol her Representatives and Senators in the Congress of the United States.\nThe following, offered by Mr. W. M. Burwell, of Virginia, was adopted:\nResolved, That the Committee on Routes inquire into the expediency of recognizing and recommending to public patronage the South-western National railroad, commencing at New-Orleans and terminating at Washington City, passing\nthrough the states of Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, Tennessee, Virginia, and offering the shortest line of mail and travel transit between New-Orleans and New-\nYork.\nThe following preamble, resolutions, &amp;c, were offered by Mr. It- S. Gladney, of Mississippi, and on motion of Mr. Walter, they were referred to the\nCommittee on Routes, with instructions to report to-morrow morning.\nKentucky, Tennessee, Missouri, Florida, and Alabama wore not prepared\nwith any projects. The call of Mississippi was responded to by the Rev. *\u2022\nBradley, who offered the following resolutions :\nWhereas we live in an age in which the rail-road system is the great hbor*\nsaving machinery in the way of transportation and travel, controlling direct!]\nthe commercial world, and indirectly affecting all the pursuits of h^i ^\nconsequently, the wealth, education, civilization and power, both political alio\nmilitary, wherever it exists ; therefore.\nResolved, That the great interests of the South and West require that \"j*\nenergies should he put forth in planning and constructing great systems \u00b0'r.31\nways, for the purpose of giving a proper direction to their commerce, develops*\n' all their natural resources, establishing and building up manufactories, lXiCt&amp;l\ning their wealth and population, and maintaining their power, their influen\nand their institutions. ^\nResolved, That the friends of therail-road system should first direct their eflo\nto those great and leading trunks, which, from their length  and location,^\npoints which they connect, and the country through which they pasS'   -a|\nrender it certain, that they will he highly important, not only in a comme","fullrs":{},"find":"2204.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2203","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"581803","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
