<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/445</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>445</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/445/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"\u25a0 M\n---.. ;*\n76\nSOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\nTor. A solid slope of the finest sand drifts and extends on\nthe sea face from the base to the summit (about six hundred\nfeet) ut an angle of about 40 degrees with tho horizon.\nThis is encircled or rather semicircled, if the term is allowable, by a ridge of sandstone rocks rising up in a pointed\npinnacle, and presenting little surface adapted for forming an\necho. It is remarkable that there are several other slopes\nsimilar to this, but the sounding or rumbling, as it has been\ncalled, is confined to this alone. We dismounted from our\ncamels and remained at the base while a Bedouin scrambled\nup. We did no' hear the sound until he had attained a considerable height. The sound then began rolling down, and\nit commenced a strain resembling the first notes of an yEolian\nharp, or the fingers wetted and drawn over glass\u2014increasing\nin loudness as the sand reached the base, when it was almost\nequal to thunder.\nIt reached the rock on which wc were seated, and caused\nour frightened camels (animals you know not easily alarmed)\nto start off    1 was perfectly astounded, as was Capt.  M\t\nand the rest of the party. 1 had visited it before in the winter month, but the sound was then so faint as to be barely\nevident. But now the scorching heat of the sun had dried\nthe sand and permitted it lo roll down in large quantities. I\ncannot now form the most remote conjecture as to the cause\nof it. We must not, I find now, refer it to the sand falling\ninto a hollow; that might produce a sound, but could never\ncause the prolonged vibrations, as it were, of some huge harp\nstring, I shall not venture on any speculation, but, having\ncarefully noted the facts, I shall lay them, on my arrival in\nEngland, before some wiser head than my own, and sec if he\ncan make any thing out ofHHem.\"\nWASHINGTON'S LIFE-GUARD.\u2014THE PASSAGE OF THE\nSCHUYLKILL.\nthe Cit-tii Recollection\nui.l Prlvnl\nof Washh\nMemoirs of lite ljf\u201e \u201e\u201e,] (.-|ia\nTin- life-guard was a major's command. Oibbs ol Rhode\nIsland, a gallant officer, and celebrated martinet, Major Colfax\na line young man from New-Jersey, and much esteemed in\nthe army, Captains Grymes and Nicholas, of Virginia, brave\nand valued officers, lieutenant and ensign, with one hundred\nand eighty picked men, rank and file. The uniform, blue\nwith white facings, white under-clothes, and black gaiters.\nThe horse-guard was detailed from various corps during\nthe contest. In the earlier campaigns, from Baylor's regi\nment, which was called Lady Washington's Dragoons\u2014\nuniform white, with blue facings, &amp;c. The life-guard, al\nways attached to the head quarters, was admired as well fo\nits superior appearance as for its high state of discipline, it being considered, in the olden time, a matter of distinction to\nserve in the guard of tho Commander-in-chief.\nThe life-guard was borrowed by favorite officers for several\nimportant expeditions. In the affair of Barren Hill, May,\n'78, the life-guard formed a part of the troops under the Marquis de Lafayette, who, recovered of the wound he received\nin the preceding campaign, in '78 made his debut in arms as a\ngeneral officer. The position of Barren Hill becoming extremely hazardous, on account of two heavy columns of the\nenemy that were marching to intercept the communication of\nthe Marepiis wilh the main army at Valley Forge, the young\nGeneral determined, by a gallant dash between the advancing\nlolumns, to reach the ford on the Schuylkill, and thus secure\nlis retreat to the main army. Hero let our narration pause,\nwhile we pay a well-merited tribute to the memory and services of Allen McLane, to whose untiling vigilance in watch,\ning the stealthy approach of the enemy's columns toward\nBarren Hill, and promptness in attacking them on their route,\nthe Marquis was mainly indebted for success in the celebrated\nretreat that shed such lustre on bis first command.\nIn Allen McLane, wo have the recollection of a partisan\nwho, with genius to conceive, possessed a courage even to\nchivalry to execute, the most daring enterprises; who ever\nranked with the foremost in the esteem of the chief, and was\nconsidered by the whole army as one ofthe most intrepid mil\ndistinguished officers of the war of the Revolution.\nWhen the retiring Americans reached the ford of the\nSchuylkill, they hesitated in attempting the passage. Lafayette sprang from his horse, rushed into the water waist deep,\ncalling on his comrades to follow. Animated by the example\nof their youthful General, the soldiers entered the river, the\ntaller men sustaining the shorter, and after a severe struggle\ngained the southern or friendly shore, having suffered but inconsiderable loss.\nMeanwhile, the enemy were inclose pursuit, and the commander-in-chief fearing for the detachment, which consisted\nof his choicest troops, including the life-guard, dragged his\nartillery to the rocky heights that commanded the ford, ami\nopened upon the enemy's advance, checking them so far as lo\nenablethe Marquis the better to secure bis retreat; and there\nwas one feature in the martial spectacle of the passage to the\nSchuylkill of rare and imposing interest: it was the admired\nform of Washington, at times obscured, and then beheld amid\nthe smoke of the cannonade, as, attended by his generals and\nstaff, he would waive his hat to encourage the soldiers in their\nperilous passage of the stream.\nOn the morning of the battle of Monmouth, June, '78, a\ndetachment from the life-guard, and one from Morgan's riflemen, lodhy Morgan's favorite, Captain Gabriel Long, made\na brilliant dash at a party ofthe enemy which they surprised\nwhile washing nt a brook that ran through an extensive\nmeadow. Seventeen grenadiers were made prisoners, anil\nborne off in the very face of the British light infantry, who\nfired upon their daring assailants, and immediately commenced a hot pursuit; yet Long displayed such consummate\nability as well as courage, that he brought off his party, prisoners and all, with only the loss of one sergeant wounded.\nMorgan was in waiting, at the out-post, to receive the detachment on their return, having listened, with much anxiety,\nto the heavy fire of the pursuing enemy. Charmed withthe\nsuccess of the enterprise, in the return of tho troops almost\nunharmed, and in the prisoners taken, Morgan wrung the favorite captain by the hand, paid bis compliments to the officers and men of his own corps, and of the life-guard, and tli'11\nthe filmed Leader of the Woodsmen indulged himself in I\nstentorian laugh that made all ring again, at the bespattered\ncondition of the gentlemen, as he was pleased to term the life","fullrs":{},"find":"446.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"445","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1883473","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.80 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
