<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/550</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>550</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/550/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"tion in the middle of the day of about two hours. They\nwere engaged in the attentive and anxious discharge of the\nduty they had engaged to perform, from half past eight in\nthe morning, until six o'clock in the afternoon. They ascertained that the number of pupils connected with tho institution during the past year, is about seventy-eight. These are\narranged into four classes, and designated Primary, Sophomore, Junior and Senior.\nThe Primary Class is under the instruction of Miss Colton.\nThe number of pupils connected with it is about thirty.\nThey arc generally little children from five to nine years of\nage.   This class was first subjected to on examination.\nThey had been taught spelling, reading anel Bible History, together with the elements of Arithmetic and Geography,\nThere are two rules  adopted  in every department of this\n|    Institution, which are considered by the Committee indispen-\nI   sable to all sound and successful instruction.\nThe first rule is, to reduce all science to its simple elements\nand most obvious principles. And the second rule is, that\nfirst principles must be thoroughly understood, before the\npupils are allowed to engage in the study of such as are subsequent, dependent, and complicated.\nBy a rigid adherence to the first rule, a knowledge of the\nmost abstruse anel difficult subjects is rendered comparatively\neasy, even to the infant mind. This truth was recently exemplified in the instruction of little children in the principles\nof .Music, by Mr. Johnson in this city. It was also fully apparent throughout this examination. Adherence to the second\nrule, confines the operations of the mind to real, substantial,\nprimary and important subjects of knowledge', until ihcacqui-\nsition is made, and prevents superficial and imaginary acquisitions, which may possess all tho beauty of some of the pass-\nlag visions of the night, or of the clouds, with their endless\nvariety of forms and colors, which sometimes adorn the western sky, but leave iho mind as barren as the arid sands of\nllic desert. The eflect of an adherence to these rules was\nfully evident in the examination of tho little children, who\nconstituted the Primary class. The Committee observed\nwith pleasure, that, at this early period, they have not only\nacquireel a knowledge of spelling and reading, but also of\nthe elements of Arithmetic and Geography.\nThe method of instruction adopted, is such as gradually to\nunfold and invigorate their intellectual faculties; and they\nlearn to think and understand, whilst they are acquiring positive knowledge of important subjects. The teachers in this\ninstitution are greatly aided in carrying out their system, and\nin adhering to their favorite rules, by the great improvement\nin modern school books, which have actually rendered that\nPossible and easily attained, which was deemed generally\nimpossible.\nThe next class, which is under the instruction of Mr. Bru-\nner, excited, in many respects, a high degree of interest. It\nconsists of about twenty little girls, from nine to eleven years\nof age. Tho committee wero exceedingly anxious to sec\nwhether the intellectual faculties of these little pupils were\ncapable, even under the new method of instruction, of analyzing and comprehending the principles of the higher\nhrar.-H-is of science, to the study of which they had been in-\nic name\nc promising appearances\n) enquiries awakened a\ntroduced. At the last examination, they were without a name\nI hey were then told that if they would study well, and deserve a name, they should have one, as well as the two higher\nclasses.    In the report of the Committee at their last examination, ,t was said,    \" They promise soon to occupy the high\nposition now maintained by the Junior and Senior Classes\"\nWhether these liltlo pupils had actually conquered the difficulties of tho sciences with which they had ventured to grapple, and secured a triumph ; whether they deserved th\nto which they aspired;  whelhe\nhad become a reality; each of these\nlively interest and some anxiety in the minds of th'o Committee.    They were consequently highly gratified with the\ndevelopments of the examination.    They saw with pleasure\nthat the proficiency of this class in Arithmetic, Geography,\nand English Grammar, so far as they had gone in these several branches, bore ample testimony to the zeal and industry\nwith which they had pursued their studies.   And their examination on Natural Philosophy, embracing ihe properties of\nbodies, and the various kinds of attraction and  motion,  rendered it evident to the Committee, that, notwithstanding their\nage, they were well acquainted with these difficult and abstruse subjects, so far as they had progressed, and that they\nwere emulously treading in the footsteps of the higher classes.    The examination of this class of pupils exhibited to the\nCommittee, in a most interesting point of view, the ability of\ntheir teacher, the zeal, industry, and success of the pupils,\nnid the complete triumph of the system of instruction pursued.   These pupils indeed do richly deserve to be dignified\nwith iho name of Sophomore, to which they have aspired,\nand for the attainment of which they have so faithfully and\nsuccessfully labored.\nThe Junior and Senior classes are also under the instruction of Mr. Brunei-, anil arc composed principally of young\nladies\u2014there being about twenty connected with the former\nand eight with the latter.    The study of English Grammar\nhad been continued by both of these classes and completed by\nihe Seniors.    These two classes have pursued the study of\nNatural Philosophy together.    The examination in this department of science embraced the properties of bodies\u2014attraction, motion, hydrostatics, hydraulics, pneumatics, acoustics, optics, &amp;c.    Besides the usual mode of examination by\npieslionand answer, several of the young ladies were calhd\nupon to present their views of some one of these subjects in\na continuous manner\u2014somewhat in the form of a lecture.\nIn every instance, this exercise was performed without hesitation, and the subject was defined, explaini d and described by\naccurate and appropriate language, in a manner concise, lucid and satisfactory.    In Chemistry, the Junior Class was\nexamined on Caloric, Light, Chemical Electricity, and Galvanism, and Chemical Attraction and Affinity.    The examination of the Seniors embraced not only these subjects, but also about one-half of the whole course in Chemistry, as pre\nscnted by Dr.  Comstock.    In addition to this, the Senior\nClass were examined on the first six books of Colburn's Algebra.    And it is expected that they and some of tho other\nclasses will soon add to their other acquisitions a knowledgo\nof the Latin language.\nr;","fullrs":{},"find":"551.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"550","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1790616","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.71 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
