<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 34</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2259</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2259</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2259/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 34","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[34]\nwater o f the Mississippi 28 740 feet higher than that of the Washita.   W(&gt; ava-i .\nourselves of this law to obtain high ground for our line wherever the streams\nin the proper direction.    More space has been given to the discussion of this \u201e\nofthe route than will be to any equal extent of the remainder, for the reason ft\nlittle knowledge and much misapprehension exists on the subject of the prac.:at\nbility of ways through the \" Mississippi swamp,\" and because the observatin*\nmade have general application to other parts of the swamp than that over which\nthe  line was carried, and probably to the whole region subject to overflow\nformed by deposit from the Mississippi River.\nOn leaving the swamp, our line passed near the residence of Captain Knox\nover Prairie Mer Rouge, and in a distance of four miles came to an abrupt rise\nfrom the plane called the Red Hill, which is the border of a range of hills slated\nto begin at Pine Bluff, on the Arkansas River, and, running southerly, to cross the\nBayou Bartholomew about 12 miles above Prairie Mer Rouge; whence, con.\nturning to the south, they cross our line and diminish in height, until they are km\nin a table which reaches the Washita, near the plantation of Senator DownB. We\npassed through the town of Bastrop, which is built on these hills, and found its\nelevation to be sixty feet above the prairie, and about one hundred feet above\nthe water of the Bartholomew.\nTwo miles beyond Bastrop we strike that bayou at Point Pleasant, sixty feel\nlower than Bastrop, but still above high water ; we then followed the general\ncourse of the bayou on good ground all the way to the Washita, crossing Bayon\nSaira and Bayou Bosuf, which now discharge their waters into the Washita, but\nwhich, in high stages, reverse the direction of their flow and assist in carrying it\noff. These will require bridges. By following the bayou, we are carried three\nmiles to the south, out of our way, to Collier's Point, the place selected lor\ncrossing the Washita ; but we avoid by this two crossings, with draw bridges, of\nthe Bartholomew, in case we continue to Collier's; or one if we consent to cross\nthe Washita at the village above Collier's, which is an inferior place, and involving heavier expenditure. The line from Knox's just described, and which waa\ntraced on the|ground, is not the one proposed for construction. The bends of\nthe Bartholomew are too abrupt, and the Bastrop hills would require deep excavation. I would, therefore, starting from Knox's, leave Bastrop about two milei\non the right, or north, and run through the foot of the hills, where they have\ninferior elevation; thence to the southernmost point of the bend of the Bartholomew, on the plantation of Senator Downs, when we fall into the line as traced on\nthe ground. From this southern point we turn northerly three miles, until we\narrive on the bank of the Washita, opposite to Collier's Point, which, as befort\nBtated, is the place selected for crossing. This projected line is on lower ground\nthan that actually traced, being sixty feet lower opposite Bastrop than the ground\noccupied by that village : this is judged of by the depth of Beauchamp's well,**'\nhis brick.yard ; but the greater directness, easier grades, and lighter excavation\nthrough the hills, serve to sanction the selection of the route.\nThe material composing the Bastrop Hills is sand and clay ; the water stratum,\n80 feet in depth, is a fine white sand.   The clay is good for brick-making,aD\nmany are made in the vicinity.    Where we strike the Washita, we are on a ta\nabove the highest rise of the river, with a fine bluff (Collier's Point) still uign\nthan the table, on the opposite side, and no bottom land whatever.\nThe river, at the highest water-line, is 600 feet across, and at the low wa\nline, 310 feet. The bed is composed of sand and coarse gravel, from the e\u00aes D\nshore to ihe middle, beyond which is a rock-reef, extending diagonally\nstream to the western shore. At this river, at this point, the Mississippi a .\"coB.\nends, and the hilly country, frequently with rock in the hills, begins- au&lt;j ^\ntinues to the Red River. The Washita River rises in extreme fl00,,i feet\nabove the low water mark, and has, when low, a depth of from 9| tof ioD&lt;r,\nin the channel at Collier's Point. The bridge to span it should be b'00 teet o\npiers sixty feet high; and as the river is navigated, the bridge should he i^(\nvided with a draw.    Beyond the Washita we\" are on the ridge betwee\nstream and the Loutre, a tributary entering about six miles below our.J^e fi0Cie\nWe turn northwesterly, and continue on or near the crest of the riog oate*i\n\u25a0even miles, when it becomes necessary to decide whether to cross the ]yror\nand get on the ridge between it and the D'Arbonne, and then turn nortn","fullrs":{},"find":"2260.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2259","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"604769","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.58 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
