<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 20</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/609</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>609</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/609/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 20","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"w.\n240\nSOUTH- W E S T E R N JOURNAL.\n;V\n\u25a0it\n\u2022\u25a0\u00bb.\n.'t\nk-\n, 1\n1'\n: '\n'(\nY,\nV-l\n-i\n'-:\n(fl:\nI \u25a0.\nl',ifi\nI\n11\n1\n1;\n\"Those Moors, those Moors I\" I often exclaimed when\nstealing, as I passed along, peeps at those charming recesses;\nthey were assuredly the most tasteful of men. To them we\nowe whatever is allied to poetry in the construction and decoration of private and public edifices in Spain, with tho exception of the Gothic cathedrals. The watch-tower rising above\nihe mansion\u2014the castellated wall\u2014the Patio\u2014the inexhaustible combinations of fancy displayed in the arabesques which\nthey have left behind them in the sculptured arches of their\n,'ates and doors\u2014their very objection to live upon ground\nfloors, which were either wholly unoccupied or used as store,\nrooms for lumber of every kind\u2014all bespeak a highly civilized people\u2014people of a much more elevated tone of genius\nihan tho Spaniards, who expelled them from the land they\nhad almost made their own.\nThe Moors I The next inquiry was, whence did they\ncome ? From Africa. Who taught them those arts in which\nthey excelled? That was a question I could not answer to\nnir own satisfaction, until I beheld in the painting of Thebes\nand Alabastron, as copied by Wilkinson, houses and villas constructed in precisely the same style, wilh tho Patio, the fountain, flowers, tho awning, the towers, the castellated walls, the\narabesques\u2014every thing, in short, for which I had given credit\nlo Moorish taste\u2014and all carried to perfection in that mysterious Egypt three thousand years before the Moors were\ndriven out of the Peninsula!\nTho observers of thoso systems of manoeuvring which pre\nvail, especially in the higher circles, and which have some-\nlimes politics for their object, bul more generally the formation of desirable connexions by marriage, have ascribed to\nmodern ingenuity tho establishment of thoso female archery\nsocieties, got up for the purpose of displaying the figures of\nbeautiful debutantes in their most graceful attitudes before\ntheir wished for admirers. It is pleasant, at all times, to bo\nable to do justice to thoso who have been the object of much\naltimny. Tho Theban paint.' igs display ladies of rank\namusing themselves precisely in a similar manner, with this\ndifference only, that they held the bow in the right hand and\ndrew tho string with tho left. It was in this manner also,\nhat the ancient British archers used that weapon, so formidable in llieir contest with foreign and domestic foes.\nLet it be borne in mind that we arc still speaking of a period\nnot later than fifteen hundred yea,s before the Christian era,\nind under this impression let us view, if wc can, without as-\ntonishment, tho signs of advanced civilization which wc behold throughout thoso wonderful memorials, the Theban\nsculptures. Ladies, elegantly attired, are seen seated on\n\u25a0 hairs, and on fautcuils of ebony und other rare woods, inlaid with ivory, nnd sometimes covered with rich brocades,\nwith leathern cushions, and all the devices of modern luxury.\nThey had, moreover, that most delectable of all provocatives\nt( repose, tho kangaroo chair, which ninety-nine persons out\nof a hundred would pronounce to bo quite a modern invention. The legs arc formed frequently in imitation of those\n&lt;if tho lion or the goat; the backs arc high and concave; and\nin some of the larger fautcuils tho arms are remarkably\nlold and graceful, consisting of the figur of the lion, or\nsome other wild animal.    Tho easy chairs have handsome\npillows of colored cotton, painted leather, or gold and silver\nlisstic. Their footstools scarcely differed in form or elegance\nfrom those seen in our best furnished drawing-rooms: their ottomans' were remarkably splendid, the cushions being covered with leather or cotton cloth, richly colored, nnd the biso\nbeing formed of wood, ornamented with the figures of cae-\ntives. Their couches or sofas were in every respect a-\nclegant as their ottomans, and similar to those now in use in\ncivilized countries. They had wooden rests for the head of\nwhich many specimens may be seen at the Museum. Sonm\nof their tables appear to have been remarkably beautiful,especially their round tables of metal or stone, sustained by the\nfigure of a slave. Our upholsterers would do well to study\nthese specimens of antirme furniture, from which they mWii\nderive many suggestions for improvements that would appear\nto tho multitude of purchasers altogether novel!\nOno of the most decided tests by which the progress of a\ncommunity in civilization maybe proved, is their mode of treating the female members of their families. It is amongst barbarians only, or tribes little advanced beyond the savage state,\nthat we find mothers and daughters universally secluded from\nthe ordinary walks of life, and compelled to perform offices\nof a menial description. In the most ancient ages of Egypt,\nof which tho sculptures and paintings of Beni Hassan or\nThebes afford any memorial, we find the ladies, in the better\nranks of life, bearing tho same relation of equality to the\nlords of the creation as they do at this moment in France or\nEngland. They sometimes sit together on the same couches\nand chairs; generally, indeed, in the same room, the ladies\nherd together, as is very much the case in South America.\nBut this circumstance argues no difference in point of station.\nThey havo their attenelant slaves, nnd all the tokens of respect\nand luxury around them. Some of the Theban frescoes\nhave preserved their memorials also, which arc often found\nto bo tho accompaniments of a matured state of society, namely, an addiction to excitement by the produce of the grape.\nWe have representations, not only of gentlemen taken home\nby their servants in a state of the most helpless intoxication,\nbut also of secret festivities among women of rank, during\nwhich the slaves are as busy in supplying the basin as the\nstewardess of a steamer when there is a swell in tho sea.\nTho fading flower, depending from the feverish hand, tells a\nsad talc of indulgence not very consistent with a patriarchal\nstage of society. It should bo remarked, however, that ancient Egypt was distinguished for its delicious wines, as well\nas for its beer, which was of an excellent quality\u2014temptations not to be resisted.\nIn Mr. Fenimoro Cooper's delineation of London life, a*\nhe has been pleased to designate his slight acquaintance with\na few peers and gentlemen, ho has given some elaborate criticisms upon the various intonations ofthe raps inflictcdupon\nthe knocker of his door by tho footmen of his visitors.   So\nlfuldid he become during his brief experience in the notes\nappropriated to every order, that he deemed himself qualified\nlo judge at once, upon hearing Ihe peal of sounds, whether his\naller was a duke, a marquis, an carl, a baron, a commoner,\nor a dun. No doubt the American conceived that, in describing these matters for the benefit of his countrymen, he was","fullrs":{},"find":"610.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"609","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1870571","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.78 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
