<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/481</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>481</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/481/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"108\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\nness and familiarity would soon dissipate their apparent attractions, and would doubtless lend us to appreciate more\nhighly the real advantages which they possess.\nThe declaration of our Lord and Saviour, that a prophet\nhath honor save in his own country, embodies a principle as\nupplicable to the subject before us as to any otherThe prac\ntice of which we speak, makes this state tributary in litera\nlure to the northIt is an acknowledgment of our inferior!\nty in tho facilities of education, which is doubtless true; but\nit need not be trueThis practice helps to make it trueIt\nenervates the sinews of literary enterprise at homeIt undervalues our actual resources, and discourages all effort to\ndevelope themThere is no good reason why this state and\nthis city should not possess adequate facilities for education\nin all its branchesThe wealth, intelligence, refinement and\nenterprize of this community, seem lo demand ihat the effort should be made, and seem, to promise that the effort\nshall be successfulLet the State of Mississippi consult her\ntrue interest and honor, and she will no longer make it necessary to bow down and do homage to the superior facilities of other stalesHer patriotism, her enterprize, and her\npolitical influence command the respect of other sections of\nthe country, and shall her literature, the bulwark of our political strength and respectability, be suffered to languish or\npine away in insignificance? On the contrary, let the standard of education be lifted highLet her resources be made\navailable, and let her facilities be multiplied, till she shall at\ntract to her own bosom the youth of other states, that sin\nmay train them up for usefulness, and send them back as\nblessings to the society from which they came.\nThe remaining evil to which I will allude, relates to the\npractice of frequently changing the teachers of your childrenIf the claims of every new establishment should induce parents to make this change, it will operate most unfavorably upon the progress of the pupilsWhen a teacher\nbecomes acquainted with the mental habits and abilities of his\npupil, and when the pupil becomes familiar with the teacher's\nmode of instruction, the principal difficulties in the way of\nsuccess arc removed, and the progress of ihe pupil is increased in a very perceptible ratioBesides, these frequent\nchanges operate to the discouragement of those teachers from\nwhom the pupils are taken, and tends ultimately to break up\nthe institutionPermanency in a seminary of learning, is an\ninvaluable characteristicIt strengthens confidence, increases\nzeal, and affords an opportunity of completing what has\nbeen commencedBut this practice, of which we speak,\nmust always give to our institutions an ephemeral character, and render abortive what might otherwise be successful.\nIt is to bo hoped that the day is not far distant, when this\ncity shall bo ns famed for its facilities in the education of females, as it is for its refinement and hospitality: and when we\nshall no longer send our daughters to other states, as witnesses and messengers, to publish our destitution and barrenness.\nLet the commendable pride of Mississippi be touched, let her\nhonor be appealed to, and her gallantry will be as distinguished for educating the fair sex, as it now is for honoring\nand admiring them.\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\nNATCHEZ,   MARCH  ]C&gt;~ IMS.\nAGENTS WANTED.\nOne or two gentlemen of responsible chnracter and p]eas.\ning address, are wanted as agents, to obtain subscribers and\ncollect subscriptions for the South-Western JournalAnv\nyoung gentleman, who can satisfy the Executive Committee\nof his qualifications and integrity, shall receive letters of in.\ntraduction to gentlemen in various parts of the State, whose\ninfluence will be exerted to favor and facilitate his views.\nApplication may be made at the office ofthe South-Westcin\nJournal, corner of Main nnd Canal Streets, Natchez.\nTHE SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nIt is the intention of the Executive Committee of the South.\nWestern Journal, to give rather more variety to the stucceedimr\nnumbers, bydevoting nearly one-half the space to shorter editorial and selected articlesThe design is not to give a lighter\ncharacter to the publication, but a more practical and varied\noneThe limits of the Journal will not permit essays of\ngreat length, or those continued through successive numbers,\nwithout the danger of substituting a monotonous sameness for\nthe lively and pleasing variety, which the public taste justly\nrequires in the periodical literature of our countryThe\nsame care will be taken in the preparation of the shorter articles as in the longerA few brief papers will be presented\non rural economy, embracing the best modes of cultivating\nornamental shade trees and shrubbery,\nWe have a gentle hint for our poetic correspondents\u2014\nwhich, (ns mediocrity in poetry is abhorrent both to the godsam!\nto men.) we venture to press at this timeMore credit would\naccrue to most writers of poetry for periodicals, if they would\nselect every tenth line they write for publication (a premium\ntithe)and burn the remainder: that is to say, the subtraction\nof nine parts from ten makes the tenth ten limes as valuable\nas the whole would have been : thus 10\u20149\u00aba\u00bb 10 X 10= good\npoetry I\nTHE TEACHERS' CONVENTION.\nA county convention of Teachers and friends of Education was organized in this city, on Saturday, the 17th instant,\naswill be seen by the official report, publishi I in the present\nnumber of the JournalFifteen members s ^.icd the constitution, and paid their initiation feeThis, we believe, will\nbo a working societyThere seemed to be a strong disposition evinced by some of the members to institute a censorship\nof the character and qualifications of teachers, through which\nthey must successfully pass, before they could be admitted to\nthe confidence of the publicSome such measure as this will\nmore properly come under the action of the State Convention\nat Jackson.\nComplimentary.\u2014As extremes often approach eaco\nother, we have real pleasure in recording- of the New UP\ncans Picayune, that it is as much distinguished for its life\npiquancy, and entertainment, as (according to its statement)\nthe South-Western Journal is for its devotion \" to the deepe'\nand more abiding interests of the useful sciences, and of th*\ncause of education in all its grades.\"","fullrs":{},"find":"482.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"481","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1859920","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
