<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Special Delivery Cameras</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Special Collections Online</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-sce:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <note type="preferred citation" displayLabel="Cite As">LSU Special Collections Online, Louisiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.</note>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/LSU_SCE/id/269</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2007-04-20</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-11-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>LSU_SCE</alias>
         <pointer>269</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/LSU_SCE/269/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-02 09:47:13">{"title":"Special Delivery Cameras","creato":{},"date":{},"dates":{},"publis":{},"contri":{},"subjec":{},"descri":{},"notes":{},"langua":{},"transc":"Special Collections Cameras Detailed information about each camera in the photo from left to right. (far left) Camera: Rainbow Hawkeye Vest Pocket Type: Folding bellows camera Model: None Date: 1930s Manufacturer: Eastman Kodak Format\/Film: 127 rollfilm Lens: 4 stops via rotating slide f11 Shutter: T\/I Notes: This line came in various colors, including rose and green. Camera: Stereo Graphic Type: 35mm viewfinder stereo camera Model: NA Date: Introduced in 1956 Manufacturer: Graflex Inc., Rochester, New York Format\/Film 35mm Lens: Graflex Graflar f4\/35mm Shutter: Guillotine Type: shutter between lenses. Speeds of B and 1\/50 Notes: As early as 1841, photographers experimented with stereographs, using cameras with two lenses to record images at slightly different angles. When seen in a stereo viewer, the two images are seen as a three-dimensional picture. Interest in stereographic photography has waxed and waned, with periods of popularity in the 1850\/60s, the early 1900s, and late 1940s\/early 50s. Representing this latest period was the Stereo Graphic, a fixed-focus camera using lenses focused to different distances.\n\nCamera: Mycro Type: Miniature Model: I Date: 1938-40 Manufacturer: Sanwa Co. Ltd., Japan Format\/Film: 16mm Lens: Mycro UNA f4.5\/20mm Shutter: Behind-the-lens shutter. Speeds of B, 1\/24, 1\/50, and 1\/100sec Notes: This camera is an early example of miniature 16mm format cameras that became popular from the late 1940s through the 60s. The Mycro was produced from 1938 through the 1950s.\n\n1\n\n(far right) Camera: No. 1 Brownie Type: Box Model: NA Date: Introduced in 1901 Manufacturer: Eastman Kodak, Rochester, New York Format\/Film: 117 rollfilm Lens: Meniscus Shutter: Eastman rotary. Speeds of T and I Notes: One of several models produced through 1916 based on the original Kodak Brownie box camera first manufactured in 1900. These cameras had a wood reinforced cardboard body and slip-in film back. 117 rollfilm produced six 2 1\/4 by 1  in. exposures. The name \"Brownie\" may have come from popular illustrated poems and stories by Palmer Cox using figures called \"brownies.\"\n\n2","digitb":{},"source":{},"collec":{},"sourca":{},"type":{},"format":{},"imagb":{},"file":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"rights":{},"cite":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections, LOUISiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.","to":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":{},"relati":"http:\/\/louisdl.louislibraries.org\/cdm4\/index_LSU_SCE.php?CISOROOT=%2FLSU_SCE","typea":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"270.pdf","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2007-04-20","dmmodified":"2016-06-06","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"269","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"12117","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.01 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
      <transcript displayLabel="Transcript">Special Collections Cameras Detailed information about each camera in the photo from left to right. (far left) Camera: Rainbow Hawkeye Vest Pocket Type: Folding bellows camera Model: None Date: 1930s Manufacturer: Eastman Kodak Format/Film: 127 rollfilm Lens: 4 stops via rotating slide f11 Shutter: T/I Notes: This line came in various colors, including rose and green. Camera: Stereo Graphic Type: 35mm viewfinder stereo camera Model: NA Date: Introduced in 1956 Manufacturer: Graflex Inc., Rochester, New York Format/Film 35mm Lens: Graflex Graflar f4/35mm Shutter: Guillotine Type: shutter between lenses. Speeds of B and 1/50 Notes: As early as 1841, photographers experimented with stereographs, using cameras with two lenses to record images at slightly different angles. When seen in a stereo viewer, the two images are seen as a three-dimensional picture. Interest in stereographic photography has waxed and waned, with periods of popularity in the 1850/60s, the early 1900s, and late 1940s/early 50s. Representing this latest period was the Stereo Graphic, a fixed-focus camera using lenses focused to different distances.

Camera: Mycro Type: Miniature Model: I Date: 1938-40 Manufacturer: Sanwa Co. Ltd., Japan Format/Film: 16mm Lens: Mycro UNA f4.5/20mm Shutter: Behind-the-lens shutter. Speeds of B, 1/24, 1/50, and 1/100sec Notes: This camera is an early example of miniature 16mm format cameras that became popular from the late 1940s through the 60s. The Mycro was produced from 1938 through the 1950s.

1

(far right) Camera: No. 1 Brownie Type: Box Model: NA Date: Introduced in 1901 Manufacturer: Eastman Kodak, Rochester, New York Format/Film: 117 rollfilm Lens: Meniscus Shutter: Eastman rotary. Speeds of T and I Notes: One of several models produced through 1916 based on the original Kodak Brownie box camera first manufactured in 1900. These cameras had a wood reinforced cardboard body and slip-in film back. 117 rollfilm produced six 2 1/4 by 1  in. exposures. The name "Brownie" may have come from popular illustrated poems and stories by Palmer Cox using figures called "brownies."

2</transcript>
  </extension>
</mods>
