<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 4</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/365</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>365</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/365/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 4","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\ndungers that open force cannot resist, receives bis due meed of\npraise. Both may do much to honor their country: But it\nis tho steady, silent efforts of the unobtrusive citizen, that form,\nstrengthen and dignify the national character.\nNever since the creation of the world, has there been such\na universal thirst for knowledge.    \" From tho rivers to the\nends of the earth,\" from the mountains to the sea, the desire\nseems insatiable. Among people, over whose benighted minds\nscarcely a ray of intellect has ever beamed; over whom superstition, with her iron sceptre-, has long ruled, enthroned in\nbloody rites nnd surrounded by revolting ceremonies, the way\nis open for the introduction of science and religion.    The cry\nfor truth comes floating on every breeze.    All are alive lo\nthe glorious hope of moral and mental revolution.    This may\nhe the direct agency of an all-bountiful providence, or it may\nhe the legitimate results of the benevolent efforts now making\nby American and European Christians.    Be the cause what\nit may, the effect is astounding.    The whole mass of human\nmind isin motion, and, like the ocean tossed by storms, it cannot be restrained.    Mighty swell after mighty swell breaks in\nresistless thunder over kingdoms and empires ;\u2014thrones, and\nprincipalities, and powers, that seem founded in adamant nnd\nh mss, quiver under the deafening shock ; and their sandy foun\ndations are laid bare.    Despots are making their last desperate\nefforts to arrest the rapid advances of mind.    They mio-ht as\nwell attempt to \"gather the beams of ihe noon-day sun and\nweave them into a mantle of darkness;\" ihey might as well \"-o\nstand upon tho beach, and tracing u line in the sand with theii\nsceptres, say to the ocean, \"thus far shall thou go and no firth\nor;'' they might as vvellgoto (he giant cataract of the North\nand say, Niagara, stand still!    Nay, the cataract may be si\nlince.1, thestormy sea may he calmed, the \"sun may he turned\nlo darkness,\" but Ihe intellect, once awakened, cannot bo restrained,    liaise obstacles high as heaven, it will surmount\nthem ; sink barriers deep us ihe centre of ihe world, it will up-\nstand forth redeemed and disenthralled. But this influence\nwill not stop here; it will pass through Europe, Asia and\nAfrica, and move on until every nation and tribe under heaven, shall feel tho renovating spirit of our free institutions,\nbreathe the pure atmosphere, and Freedom find a home\namong every people.\nBut it is not our political institutions alone that are held\nup lo tho gaze of the world. Americans are too much disposed to think, because their country is esteemed the polar\nstar by which all steer to the sure haven of political liberty, that\nill is done that need be done. They are grievously mistaken who think so. We cannot remain stationary a single\nmoment. If we improve our advantages, wc shall advance\nwith the same rapidity that has characterized our rise heretofore. If wc neglect them, our fall will be covered with double shame.    It argues want of magnanimity to rest content,\n\" To be known because our fathers were.\"\nThe founders of our republic began a glorious work, which\nwc, their descendants, must finish or destroy They achieved,\nby the sword, our independence; it remains for us to earn a\nreputation for learning and intelligence. Our claims in this\nrespect must not bo too arrogant: Honor must be clearly deserved before it is received. Military fume alone cannot\nrender a nation illustrious; nor can the excellence of political institutions alone. Athens could not boast as many free\nmen as some of our smallest cities, though, in inhabitants,\nshe far out-numbered the largest; yet Athens ruled Greece,\nand formed the taste, and softened the manners of her fierce\nconquerors; and victorious Rome yielded a willing obedien\nto the superior genius of conquered Greece. If our coun\ntry obtains a reputation for intelligence, commensurate with\nour political, moral and religious institutions, it will occupy\na higher grade in the scale of nations, than any other on\nearth.\n,.,\u201e\u201e ,,, .,, \u2022    . Tll\u00b0 factor of a nation is over estimated by its institu-\n.      ...    - .      .,.,,. . tions of learning.    Tho number and standing of universi-\nA  spu-it of free insti.utions accompanies this universal lies, and colleges, and schools being given, it is easy to pro-\nwakening of mind  rem to.slum er of age.    Our com- nounco with mathematical certainty, what is the 2e of    -\nry s example has not been lost on the world.    Its influence ciely.    But societies for the promotion of scion       nd the\nlas extended far and wide.    It passed through France, and arts, and literature, are stronger evidences of a ,l,inki~\nri En^7anTm ,r  ^VTT    * *\"* ^   ^''T are the nurseries ^f hold and independZ^\nhrough England, and as umvillmg as Englishmen may he they excite a stirring spirit: they keep the intellectual cur\nto acknowledge the lac, to our revolution and the spirit ,', rent from stagnating. -        ' 1\"t,llLCtUal cur\nengendered, must ho traced all the recent reform* ni ,..,!\u201e.       \u25a0 i i ,\n, Spain felt it, and feels it still.    Her eh,     ,-v     -a 1 f  , 7 \u00b0 P\u00b0mt \u00b0\"1 ^ imm\u00b0diate' and S0m8 '\nla d torpid and cold under the chil, '     , \u25a0 S, '\u00b0 KmoUs b\u00b0MmgS \u00b0f SUch associations as this.    The\nsuperset 2    h m \u00a3 2,  v\" n\u00b0d' %*\u00ab 7 T* \u00b0' 1 \"\"\"\"\"^ *'\" * I'r0110rti\u00b0\"ato &lt;\u00b0 &lt;h\u00b0 \"** ^\n\u201e,,   -tri,-.     Thf \u201e ,     letiuipa'id prepares for industry of its members.    And if we can by our united\nI L\u00a3 ' i -\u00a3S;^ \"i,,1 \" ?** \u00ab\"\u00ab\"\u25a0 *\u00bb \u2014 * diligence within oivS\nthe din of arms, and the ro r of art1 y I 0 HoTe I\" \"' T \"** \"T^0\" ^'^ \"\"\u25a0 \u2122 sha\" d\u00b0 0Ut\nh\u00bbg recluse to matins: the groans ' h V , - va i 1 \" 7 \" VT^ T\u2122 ^^ \u00b0d 'h\u00b0 \u2122\u2122 M ^\nwild shriek of the distract,   mother mil   I \"^ It c2\\   r      ,TP ^ ^ \u00bb mMy insta\"&lt;*s \u2022 wrought im-\nthe expiring infant, may ascend to heaven o   , T    improvements, as if by magic.    We need not parti-\nthe sacrifice\": tho    ajs my g 1 lo   from ho    ire nlr T      T    ^ \"\"* \u2122 ^ \"^ *\" \u00b0f di\u00bbPP\u00b0\u00bb~.\nther Numantia: the blood o\/p u       IriZTolZ   7        \u00b0\" 7*\"\" \"\" \"* * \"&gt;*\" '\u00b0 **\"\nstreets of another Astuto-    But the J\u2122Jill Z. , . &gt;\"*' gentl\u00b0men'commonco \u00b0\u00ab duties with alacrity, and\nhoi of peace will hang on tho r Wng Xud and Sn 717 '^ \"\"' b\u00b0 \"\"&amp; \u2122\u2122P\u2122\u00b0* * \"&gt;c consideration,\nthe devoted victim of'civil and S^tXISHS ?\" W^ * Mh ** \u00b0f *\u00bb*\n. ermitme, gentlemen, in conclusion, to add, that I sincerely","fullrs":{},"find":"366.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"365","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1525819","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.46 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
