<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/438</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>438</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/438/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n71\npass into the infected district, and breathe the atmosphere so\ninfected with yellow-fever miasm, will contract that disease;\nand that it will dovelopc itself in their systems in five or six\ndays, as a general rule : and that this disease may be de\noped in such persons, even in its most aggravated forms, at'\nany place to which they may have travelled in the interim\nwhether it be far or nearIt is also admitted, that those who\nreside in an infected district, and have continued to breathe\nihe air while tho infection or miasm was weak, or generating\nin small quantities, acquire a partial immunity, by becoming\nnaturalized, or acclimated to it; but that they also will take\nthe disease, and die from it, when tho miasm becomes more\nabundant, or more virulentThis is exemplified every year;\nfnr healthy, unaccliinated persons have contracted the disease in cities and places, while the resident inhabitants were\nhealthy, or not affected with yellow fever.\nIt is also known and admitted by all parties, that when yel\nIon- fever is epidemic in any part of a city, that the infected\natmosphere, when confined in a close room for several days,\nat a temperature of not less than 80\u2122 of Fahrenheit, loses\nnone of its properties, but often acquires a new degree of virulence   As before observed, it is known that this miasm, or\ninfection, when it exists in abundance, as it does in all infected places, diffuses itself into every recess and interstice into\nwhich common air can penetrate   Hence every chamber,\n'  every alley, street, avenue and cellar, within its limits, becomes alike infected during an epidemic   It diffuses  itself\nalso in beds, bedding, and bales of blankets, and other porous\narticles, which always contain much air: and when retained\nin th\"se, in a suitable temperature, it often acquires an increased virulence, in like manner with that which has been con-\nliaed in close rooms   But when, in addition lo  the infected\nair of the rooms, the beds are saturated with tho secretions\nand exhalations of human bodies in disease, it is called fomi-\ntes,orfames, and is, decidedly, in all infectious diseases, more\nmorbific lhan the infection diffused in the open air   In yellow fever, the exhalations from the diseased body unquestionably add to the virulence of the infected air, when so confined: hence this kind of infection, (or fames,) is more deleterious\nto all who breathe it, than the infection of the open air.\nliya careful estimate and calculation, it will bo found, that\na common feather bed, when stirred up loosely, contains from\ntwenty to twenty-five cubic feet of air, varying according to\nits size; and each pillow will contain from two to four cubic\nled of air; the feathers, if reduced to a solid, constitute less\nthan one-twentieth of that bulkBlankets, and other clothing, contain air likewise in proportion to their textureNow\nall these articles, in an infected district, become charged with\nthe infected air of that district, just as they do with common\nhealthy air, in a healthy seasonThe confinement of the infected air, so as to prevent its dispersion in the general atmosphere, increases its power of producing disease, in proportion\nto the closeness and the temperature in which it is kept: and\nBS yellow fever miasm and infection are destroyed by a temperature below 40\" Fahrenheit, it will acquire new virulence\n\"\"Iy when its temperature is above that point, and most at a\ntemperature between 85 and 00\" Fahrenheit   Now, if the ~    IT \u201e,\n,1   * floe Quarterly Jour, of ForMeq, ror April, w\u00ab,\n\u00b0pen air of a certain district be capable of producing a cer'l   (Medical Recorder, vol 9, rp37,33,33.\ntain disease in those who breathe it, and if the air contuined\nin beds, &amp;c, bo of the same quality, but more virulent, why\nshould not this infected air, transported in such nrlicles to on-\nother place, bo capable of producing the same disease in those\nwho there breathe it,as well as nearer the source of infection ?\nIt would be a paradox if the mere act of transportation should\nneutralize its morbific properties,\nWhen a person sleeps upon u bed, or upon porous articles\nof bedding, whether charged with healthy or infected air, he\nof necessity breathes more or less of it: his body presses out\nof a feather bed an equal bulk of air, which settles around\nhim, and is respired with the common air of the roomOther portions of it are likewise pressed out by each movement,\nor change of position, and are likewise respiredThus, in\nsleeping upon a bed one night, in all probability an individual\npresses out and respires all the air which it previously contained, whether healthy or infected.\nThus fir it matters not from what source, or in what manner the poison of yellow fever is produced; or in what manner it produces its effects upon the human systemWc will\ncall it infection, and, for the sake of argument, admit that it is\nproduced from any source which may suit the fancy of our\nreaders; still it must be admitted that it can produce the disease called yellow fever, wherever it is respired in its undiluted state; or when only moderately diluted with sultry,\ncontaminated air.\nAs to the peculiar nature and composition, of this malaria,\nor poison of yellow fever, we know nothing, except by ils\neffects upon the human systemOf its qualities, we know\nonly by induction ; and some of ils general laws are deduced\nfrom repeated observationIn its effects upon the system, it\nissupposed by Baron Larrey* and others, and the supposition\nis sustained by my distinguished friend DrOartwright.t\nof Natchez, that it is respired, and from the lungs, through\nthe medium of the ganglionic system of nerves, produces its\ndeleterious effects upon all the functions of animal and organic lifeThose, deleterious effects, taken together, constituto\nyellow fever.\nWhether bodies laboring under yellow fever, are capable of\nthrowing off any exhalation or effluvium possessing or deriving morbific, properties, is a point yet disputed, although\nthe general practice and the piecautions inculcated, even by\nthose who profess to believe it strictly non-contagious, tend to\nconvince the unprejudiced, that all parties admit the principle, although they deny tho factThe general admission,\nof those who disclaim either side of the question, is that,\nwhin yellow fever makes its appearance as nn epidemic in\na city, or in a district of a city, each additional case tends\nstill further to contaminate the air, or in either words to increase the virulence ofthe infection which is abroadNone\nbut those who havo been much conversant with yellow\nfever in the southern part of the United States or in the\nWest Indies, should hazard an opinion to the contrary ; even\nthen their observation and discernment might bo questionableIf a body, or any number of bodies, laboring under\nthis disease, can have any agency or influence in rendering\nWl\n\u20221\n\u25a01\n'ii\n\u25a0l\n\u2022i\ni\ni-j\n4\n\/J\nn\nT\n\u2022I.\nM\n'   ''&lt;\n!\nft\ni\n\u25a0&lt;'\u2022\u25a0    l\nj\ni\nnfl","fullrs":{},"find":"439.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"438","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1763041","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
