<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2123</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2123</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2123/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 14","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"14 ADDRESS\nher. She finds among us consumers of her bread-stuffs and provision.\nto an enormous extent; and when she becomes, as she is destineda\nbe, the great manufacturing centre of the world, her material and her\nmarkets will be found in this quarter.* Her interests will be ^\nserved by a more immediate connection with us, and she will find*\nready to co-operate heartily in every enterprise which shall make fa\nher interests and progress. New-Orleans, in every period of her hi*\ntory, has been the emporium of the West, and New-Orleans tfl\nonly give up that distinction after the most unremitting and Hen^\nlean struggles have exhausted her energies. The sceptre has not yl\ndeparted, and if her citizens are true to themselves, the sceptre shall\nnot depart. As the West grows in population, she must consunjj\nmore of valuable goods favorable to rail-roads; her rivers, in favorM\npopulation, are rather an advantage than an impediment to their cafe\nstruction, and roads may be constructed from the levels existing, j*.\none-half or one-third the cost of the roads in the East.\n\" The West in sixty years will probably contain one hundred ml\nlions of people. The East will then have but twenty millions\/ fl\nWest, in its level surface, cheap materials, and free right of way, ma*\nbuild the best class of rail-roads, at less than half the cost of the\nEastern rail-roads, and run trains on them at a greatly reduced ei\npense. The West offers now the first choice of routes\u2014a choice that\na few years will show to be of immense advantage to those who wiseM\navail themselves of it; In number and variety of exchangeable prffl\nducts, except manufactured goods, the Western rail-roads will oljl\nviously have the advantage of the Eastern, for freight, and in manufi^\ntures the prospects of a great increase is not less for the Western thai\nthe Eastern states. In her auxiliary means of commerce, her navigable rivers, lakes and canals, the West proffers additional induccmenffl\nto the construction of roads.\"\nA well informed authority further remarks of the construction of\nWestern and Southern roads. \"The cost of constructing infl\ndifferent parts of our territory, containing a primitive soil, broken hi\nabrupt hills and deep valleys, is very great. Here but few natuiaj\nlevels are to be found; and the excavation for their tracks sometime!\nwidening along the valleys of rivers, thus prolonging the distance froui\npoint to point, have to be made frequently through stony hu\u00ab\nwhich are often blown up at great expense; tunnels are to be seejj\nthrough solid rocks, and viaducts over the frequent streams. Tb\u00ab\nmust necessarily be the case throughout the greater part of Neff'\n#The facilities for manufactures iu the West, from the cheapness of labor andoffoj^j\nthe abundance of coal and iron, and the saving in transportation, have already attract**\nthe attention of capitalists in New-England, and found a place among the discussion5?\nthe manufacturers of Great Britain.    There can be no doubt that the seat of cotton nHflj,\nfactures in America will be on this side of the mountains, and the able arguments'^\nstatisticsof Hamilton Smith, of Kentucky, have unanswerably shown it.   The cxperime\nat Cannelton, Indiana, has answered   the highest expectations.    In the  Sotith-westf\nStates manufactures, under the new and liberal spirit of enterprise which is ^a   ^Jj\namong us, must be stimulated into a very high development.    What we want ,B a jj\njudicious heads to take the lead.    Even a single resolute and enterprising man coo*\nwork a revolution here.","fullrs":{},"find":"2124.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2123","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"547906","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.52 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
