<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/352</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>352</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/352/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"135\nSOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\nmn\nquins and equestrians, moving about in search of health and\npleasure. These beautiful roads are watered night and morning, by men who carry water from the tanks in bottles made\nof goat skin ; by this process the atmosphere is cooled and\nthe dust settled, rendering a promenade upon the roads 'extremely inviting nfter the debilitating heatofa tropical day.\nIn observing the manners and customs of the natives, 1\nwas forcibly impressed with the uir of antiquity, with which\nevery thing seemed to be impressed; every custom and habit\nteemed to be a perpetuation of the same that have been in existence from time immemorial, faithfully transmitted from\nlather to son, and from generation to generation, without the\nslightest deviation from the original. Indeed, a rigid adherence to ancient forms, to caste, and to hereditary trades and\nprofessions, is one or the strongest features in the Brahmin\npolicy and religion. The wise founders of the Hindoo religion, foresaw that a policy which would give employment lo\nevery member of a redundant population, and specifically assign to each the nature or his occupation, was the only means\nlo prevent the distress accruing from the introduction or improvements and innovations or any kind tending to diminish\nthe number of laborers or materially shorten the lime for the\nexecution or any branch of industry. The result or such a\npolicy was the division or the people into a variety or distinct\nclasses, denominated castes. These divisions have been scrupulously preserved, and every individual is extremely averse\nto the performance of any duty not assigned to him by his\nparticular caste or profession. I once directed one of my\nbearers to lead to me a dog that was tied in the yard; he oh\njected to comply on the grounds that he would be transcending the duties of his order, and would consequently lose cast\nbut this fastidiousness is often a mere subterfuge, in order to\navoid doing any thing for which they are not specifically engaged. But, nevertheless, there is a tenacity in their adherence to the principles laid down and inculcated by the policy\nand religion of Brahma, which all the august power or the\nEnglish government, and all the force of an example,\nstrengthened by a relation like master and slave, now exerted\nsince the time of queen Elizabeth, have not been able to\nchange. Nor have the ministers or catholic and protestant\nChristianity been more succcssnil in their efforts to subvert\nthe foundations upon which these religious and civil customs\nhave been erected. For hundreds of years have they withstood the attacks of the sanguine advocates of the tenets of'\nChristianity, but so far from gaining proselytes, these latter\nhave too often only exhibited to the Hindoo the insincerity of]\ntheir pretensions, and by their course of lifo, riveted upon the\nheathen a stronger belief in the infidlibility or his own no\nlions of Divinity and in the superiority of his own modes of|\nreligious worship. Some humorous stories are related of|\nthe happy versatility with which some of the rigid promulgators or the christian faith, have relaxed in their observance\nof the stern precepts of religion, and with an easy grace, fallen into the habits of a country and people not a little loose\nin their adherence to the rules or a strict morality. A fow\nyears ago, a company or pious ladies in Boston, a band o(\\\nchristian philanthropists, viewing with painful emotions, the\ncalamitous ignorance that enshrouded the heathen mind and\nobscured the light of revelation and the radiance of that \u00abni\nwhich is to free the world from the bondage of darkness ft.\nled out a missionary, who with liis self-denying spouse, h,-|.|\nhimself prepared to disseminate ihe principles of chlisliam'h\nwheresoever a proper field might open for his labors. Al\nthat lime, the sickly climes of the east held out honorableit,,\nducements to those who had consecrated themselves to tb.\ncause of religion, and as the most appropriate sphere ford-\nlabors of so devoted a servant, Calcutta was fixed upon as tin\npoint from which the light of his missionary efforts wast\u00bb\nradiate upon the inhabitants of that benighted country. ijj,\nsuccess, no doubt, was equal to that of hundreds who had ,ltt,.\nceded him, but the number of his converts, it was never n;\u00bb\ngood fortune to learn. My acquaintance with him was alio-\ngethei of the convivial order, and I can bear ample testimony\nto his hospitality, which it was my good fortune to enjoy spy\noral times at his villa, near Calcutta, where the brilliancy of\nhis soirees, and the excitement or cards, music, wine unJ\ndancing, were wont to make the merry hours pass briskly on.\nThere is another custom, barbarous and cruel in itself, but\nholy in the eyes of the Hindoo, and consecrated to him by its\nantiquity, which the severe enactments of English legislation\nhave had but little influence in preventing. I have allusion\nto that religious infatuation which prompts the deluded widow to purchase exalted honors for herself hereafter by a\ndreadful immolation upon the pyre or her deceased husband.\nAll widows do not subject themselves to this dreadful ordeal,\nbut occasionally some woman, more ambitious or immortal\nfame than her fellows, comes forward as a voluntary sacrifice\nto gratify the tastes of a people who exult in the exhibition of\nany torture that is endured as a religious penance. I waj\ntwice deceived, when I expected to be present during the ceremonials or this painful rite, for the native who had promise!\nto give rne secret information of the contemplated burning;\ntook the precaution of informing me too late, that I might not\nhave it in my power to prevent the ceremony by any him\ngiven to the officers of government.\nThe higher castes of Hindoos usually hold themselves aloof\nfrom all persons save those of their own order. They will\nhardly condescend, under ordinary circumstances, to enter a\nroom when you are sitting- at meal, and would feel themselves highly degraded by touching any vessel fiom which a\nChristian had eaten : but they will sometimes so far lay aside\ntheir prejudices, as to give sumptuous entertainments, at their\nown houses, to their American and European friends. I\u00ab'M\nonce invited to attend a route, given by a rich Banyan, \u00abl\u00bb\ntransacted the business for our ship. This native has a palace-like residence, about three miles from Calcutta, situated\non the bank or the river Ganges, decorated with every improvement that can conspire to render it a place or delightful\nretreat: superb avenues, bordered by trees or magnified])\nsize; porticoes or exquisite taste and beauty: immense tanks,\nfilled with fine fish,\u2014are a few among the many attraction!\nabout this inviting spot. The internal arrangement of hu\nhouse was in a style comporting with the taste of the ground*\nand betokened the high estimate that the proprietor set upon\nthe conveniences and luxuries of living. The entertainment\nwas gotten up with a magnificence, that wa\u00bb in perfect keep","fullrs":{},"find":"353.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"352","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1801090","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
