<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/447</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>447</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/447/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"WF\nIII\n%\n&gt;|\n' -ic'*-\nI; 'i:f &gt;\n1 I  \u25a0   fk     rt\nHIP\n1\n78\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\nAnd there he sits alive, and gaily shakes,\nIn his full hands, the blossoms blue and while.\nAnd smiles, with winking eyes, like one who wakes\nFrom a deep slumber at the morning light,\nFor tho rtnutli-Wesicni Journal.\nTEARLESS SORROW.\nMr. Editor:\u2014\nThe following beautiful reply, made by Anthony Pasquin,\nEsq., to a person who rebuked him for not shedding tears at\nthe death of a female friend, has been translated into severa'\nEuropean languages. Will you lend your aid to preserve so\ntouching nn expression of refined feeling, by giving it a place\nin the \"South-Western Journal ?\"\n\" Cold drops the tear which blazons common woe;\nWhat callous rock retains its chrystal rill 1\nNe'ir will the softened mould its liquid show\u2014\nDeep sink the waters that arc smooth and still.\nOh! when sublimely agonized I stood,\nAnd memory gave her beauteous forma sigh,\nWhile feeling triumphed in my heart's warm blood,\nGrief dranl: the offering ere it. reached the eye.\"\nby every effort of thought nud experiment, to investigate Ihe\ncauses even of seeming trifles, yet each discovery leads deeper\nand deeper into the labyrinths of mystery, exciting, more\nand more, the restless inquirer till, bewildered by the might,\nthe majesty and mercy of an adorable God, he seeks rest at\nhis feet, and bows, in humble submission, and says, \"Father,\nthy will be done! \"\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nFnr the South-Western Journal.\nTO A LADY,\nOn hearing her sing the popular ballad, entitled\n\"HOME,   SWEET  HOME.\"\nSing not of home, oh, lady I\nFor, though dulcet is the strain,\nTo my sad and lonely bo3om\nIt but sends a throb of pain.\nA wanderer, o'er earth's desert waste,\nCondemned, through life, to roam,\nThe joys you sing I ne'er must know\u2014\nAlas, \/ have no home !\nAnd, oh! that once a home was mine,\nTis belter to forget.\nThan, o'er the thoughts of happier days\nTo pine with sad regret;\nOh, memory! let thy tortures cease,\nTill that wished hour shall conic,\nWhen, in a brighter, happier world,\nMy soul shall find a home!\nNATCHEZ,  FEBRUARY 15, 18.18.\nTO READERS.\nIt is but justice to remark, in regard to the forensic essays\nof Professors Forshey and Wyche, that the portion of the\nnegative, contained in the present number, has been prepared\nsince the original discussion, as will be seen from its examination of several arguments ofthe affirmative. The rejoinder\nof the affirmative may be expected at an early date.\nCAMBRIDGE UNIVERSITY IN ENGLAND.\nThis venerable institution is a confederation of seventeen\ncolleges, united in a body politic, bearing to each other relations not unlike thoso of the different states in the great\nAmerican confederacy. There is much rivalry between the\nvarious colleges. Trinity and St. Johns seem to be the most\npopular, in consequence of their more ample endowments.\nThis \" unum e pluribus\" has its senate house, where all\ndegress are conferred, elections held, and collegiate honors\nannounced.\nB. II.\nFor iho Souih.WoMorn Journal,\nTHE BETTER USES OF MIND.\nBY  A  LADY.\n\u25a0Then Is nothing bcatcUM hut mind.\"\u2014Miss IUyxm.\nIt is mind that gives us hope,\u2014hope of Heaven; that\nmust elevate us with the angels; that teaches us his will\nwhom we are to serve; to estimate the boundless extent of\nhis ever-saving mercy; to estimate the justice of an awful\nsentence on a disobedient, fallen race, and the extent of that\nlove that gave an only son to die, that we might live, and preserve his law unbroken!\nIt is mind that teaches us to love and serve him; that calls\nforth every emotion of devotion from the grateful heart, and\nteaches us to look with impatience for the day, when each\nshall account for the talents with which he hasbecn entrusted,\nand shall receive his reward accordingly. It is this mysterious emanation that leads us from depth to height, and over\nendless space, culling, abstracting, combining, and seeking,\nTHE THEORY OF WARM  CURRENTS  OF AIR.\nThe philosophical fact, that warm currents of air are frequently encountered in many parts of our country, generally\nduring the latter part of the day, or at night-fall, was stated\nby Jefferson, in his celebrated notes on Virginia. His investigating mind did not attempt to account for them, and the\ncause that produced them has been variously defined.\nThese warm currents of air are generally so rapid in their\npassage, and so transient in their stay, that they usually fail to\nalfect the most sensitive thermometers, although they are\nsingularly palpable to the senses. One, in walking half a\nmile after sundown, will often cross the path of half a dozen\nof these gushes of warm air, which seem to be gathered in\nmasses of definite strata or formations.\nA late writer on Meteorological phenomena, in the Knickerbocker, ascribes these currents to the aggregating nature ol\n;aloric, disposing it to move in massrs, while in the act of being dissipated through the atmosphere. The unequal action\nof the son, upon different portions of the atmosphere, towards\nnight, when its relative position throws direct quantities of\nloric upon portions of air, while it is withdrawn from\nothers, may account for the unequal temperature of aerial\nstrata, which require some houis after dark to equalize.\nThe writer, to whom we allude, traces some affinity between the warm, atmospheric currents and the phenomena of\nelectricity ; and supposes that the warmer and colder strata of\nthe air may have something the same relation to each other\nas the electric positive and negative.    He also supposes that\nJ.","fullrs":{},"find":"448.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"447","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1841364","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
