<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2209</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2209</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2209/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 12","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[12 J\nMadisonville and Jackson Road ; the Vicksburg and Shreveport Road ; the New\nOrleans and Nashville Road.\n10. For Texas.\u2014A road from a point on the northeast part of the state (\u00ab\u00bb.\nnecting with the Little Rock and Fulton Road,) to run on the dividing ridge of\nthe Sulphur and Red River to the ridge between Bois D'Ark and Sulphur; then*\nto Dallas, and to connect with the New-Orleans and El Paso Route. The cop.\ntinuatiou of the New-Orleans, Opelousas and El Paso Road through Texas.\n11. For Missouri.\u2014The road from St. Louis westward ; the Hannibal and. 8t\nJoseph Road.\nOn motion of Mr. Burwell, of Virginia, the resolution and schedule of nil.\nroads submitted by the Committee ou Routes, were taken up seriatim.\nThe resolution and first section of the schedule were then taken up and\nunanimously adopted.\nThe second section being under consideration, Mr. J. R. Anderson, of Virginia,\noffered an amendment to conciliate several delegates, which was rejected.\nMr. Wm. Campbell, of Kentucky, offered an amendment, which was adopted,\nproposing a route from Paducah, at the mouth of the Tennessee River, to the\nTennessee State Line, to intersect the road fro n7 New-Orleans and Mobile.\nOn motion of Mr. H. L. Hyams, of Louisiana, the resolution and scheduleof-\nfered by the Committee on Routes were taken up, as amended, and unanimously\nadopted.\nThe following, offered by Mr. J. R. Anderson, of Virginia, was passed :     ]\nResolved, That, as the sense of this Convention, a railway and water communication across the Isthmus of Tehuantepec is of national importance, and especially so to the whole Southwest.\nMr. J. S. Hays, of Mississippi, presented the following resolutions for Mr. B.\nL. Acee, ofthe same state, and moved to lay them on the table till (j o'clock, I.\nm., which motion was carried :\nResolved, That the connection ofthe Southern Atlantic seaboard with the Pacific Ocean, by means of a rail-road, is a great American measure, of commanding\nnational importance, and worthy of governmental favor and assistance.\nResolved, That the highest commercial and political considerations hnperiouslj\ndemand the early construction of this important national highway ; and that in the\nopinion of this Convention, the Congress of the United States cannot make a more\njust and judicious disposal of the public domain lying within the south of California, than the appropriation of a large and liberal portion of the same forthe\ncompletion of this great undertaking.\nResolved, That it is the sense of this Convention that the most eligible and\npracticable rou^e for said rail-road is from San Diego, or San Francisco, on HW\nPacific coast, by way of El Paso, to the State of Texas.\nResolved, That a committee, composed of one delegate from each Btate rep**\nsented in this Convention, be appointed by tbe President ofthe same to draft \u2022\nmemorial to Congress, setting forth the advantages and practicability of said prt\"\nposed road, and asking the appropriation ol fifty millions of acres ofthe pub\"\u00a3\nlands, lying in the State of California, for the construction of this great Southwes\nern railway.\nResolved, That three persons be appointed a committee by this Conven\nto present said memorial to Congress during its present session, and urge bett\nthat honorable body the early consideration and adoption of such measures'*8\nsecure, without delay, the accomplishment of this truly national enterprise.      \u201e\nThe following preamble aud resolutions were offered by Mr, W. S. Camp06 '\nof Louisiana: i_\nWhereas the City of New-Orleans is the great commercial entrepot, J-*0* od j_\nof Louisiana but also ofthe states of the great valley drained by the M'ssl9f.^,\nRiver; and whereas the States of Arkansas,  Mississippi, Texas, anilI the o.\nwith in said   vallov   ha un \u00bba i] ivoj-.fr a n in teres t no 1 fiuicion.i    ;\u00ab  il...   I rn'illt.lt S ill'0\nwithin said valley, have as direct an interest as Louisiana, in the facilities al\nto both the foreign and domestic commerce, which naturally seeks New-Or\nas an emporium for barter, distribution, or export;   and whereas, the u&gt;al,'.gt\noutlet ofthe products and importations of the Southwest is within the JUI!'. . gej.\nofthe State of Louisiana, and, as a consequence, all goods and comniod jtie\nported aud imported through that channel are effected by her laws, w'lic'n jjjd\nencourage or impede the growth, commercial prospects, military streug","fullrs":{},"find":"2210.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2209","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"578163","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
