<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2220</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2220</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2220/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 23","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[23 j\n\u25a0Rnil-road of Georgia have determined to seek a continuation of their line to\n9****!^\u2122 {be Golf of Mexico\u2014\n0-oe l'\"1.'11    Li jt Resolved, That the projected road from the terminus of the South-\n^erciore,    ^. g.eorgia&gt; ^ t]le waters of Pensacola Kay,  would greatly promote the\n' .'' . youth, aud receive the cordial sanction of this Convention.\n\/ That'we earnestly recommend to the favorable consideration of the na-\n7,t. this railway, as one which will be highly important to the naval station\nBOiial goven ^ ^e security of the increasing commerce of the Southwest.\nI That the members in Congress, from tbe several states, are solicited to\n.. 7&gt; obtain suitable grants ofthe public domain for this connecting link be-\nmtic and the Gulf, and for all similar purposes of public enterprise and im-\nBATON   ROUGE    PROJECT.\nWhereas at die South-western Rail-road Convention, held in the city of New-\nOrleans in the month of April, 1851, a report was made by the committee ou plans and\nich it is stated that \" the distance from New-Orleans to Jackson via Pontchar-\nmiti Rail-road, Lake Pontchartrain and Madisonville, is 173 miles, of which distance\na'tkiat M miles will be steam ferry. By the located Sine of the old Nashville Rail-road,\ndie distance is 192 miles. By a route recentiy surveyed by Mr. Phelps, passing above\nLake Maurepas, the distance will be about 200 miles; and by a proposed line up tbe\nriter to die vicinity of Baton Rouge, the distance from New-Orleans to Jackson will be\nabout 213 miles. The latter route avoids difficult swamps, extensive draw-bridges across\nanigsble streams, and passes through a fertile and well-improved country. The majority\n\u25a0: unittee are of opinion that the road via Baton Rouge may be constructed in die\nmost substantial manner from New-Orleans to Jackson for two millions of dollars, and\nthat the shorter lines would not cost materially less. The cost of the road from the state\nline of Louisiana to the town of Jackson will be die same on either route, and may be estimated separately at one million of dollars! !\"\nAnd whereas the said proposed route presents advantages, certainly not lo be overlooked, in entering upon a vast sy tern of internal improvements, in which it is confidently\neipected all the energies of the state and of the people of tbe state will be promptiy ami\nefficiently enlisted,:\nThese advantages being\u2014\n1(1. That throughout its whole course such road will pass through a densely populated\nsod fertile country, the inhabitants whereof are not only able but willing to contribute\n\" die formation of tbe road.\n3d- That by touching the Mississippi at tbe city of Baton Rouge, easy and speedy communication can at all seasons of the year, and under all circumstances, be had with the\nOrleans,\nid. That in the event of an overflow of the Rr-er Mississippi at any point between the\n;s of New-Orleans and Baton Rouge, a rail-road, whether passing the latter place, or\nT if \u00ab^ '\"r0m the ^ver Mississippi, so as to cross the River Amite near its entrance into\nor to cross the pass between Lakes Maurepas and Pontchartrain, must be\nlole to destruction, or at least to great damage ; and therefore it is highly desirable that\n''owncwpjopoaeiltobe constructed should touch tbe River Mississippi at a point\nlabie to inundation, in order that there may under no circumstances be any delay or\n4rtTl0D '\" t,lt; transPortatio11 of' passengers 'and freights to New-Orleans,\nbank  F h   ti^ exfeil&lt;hng the road from New-Orleans to Baton Rouge, along or near the\nthe hi\u00b0h     i      er Mississippi to Baton Rouge, it will have the advantage of passing over\noverfl^ ^      ls&gt; avoiding swamps, and not liable to any obstruction or damage  from\nBthTn n0E, common to die other routes proposed.\nWD, Miss*\"11- - r\u00b0Ute \"a ^atcm B-0USei Passing from that place towards the city of Jack-\nlanL g&amp; '^'PP1' over a comparatively high country, free from swamps, not traversed by\n'\"dereble *\"*' ^\"'^ at ^le same ['me not requiring excavations or embankments to any con-\n**\u00b0*\u00bbiry wj3*16\"1' cao be constructed at less expense than one passing through a low\n^\u25a0farnVm ^1manv and extensive swamps must be encountered, and several navigable\nttb, Th\u00bb!h    britlSed-.\nty 1*e Bat     R corl-\",rat'0'1 now proposed to be created, can avail itself of the work done\npo\u00abQ rouie\u00b0nk      \"e. an&lt;* Clinton Rail-road Company, which consists in opening the pro-\nto^ twenty61     *\" lll'ny m'^a$ or upwards,   cutting off the timber a width of one hundred\nit tf1' PrePar\u2122g the road for laving tbe superstructure for about fourteen miles,\nii i    j*11\u2122!13 alld SOTtsi cmtiug ditches on each side of the road, and throwing\n,',:!? the centre, so that at the present time the superstructure can be laid for that\n\u25a0''\"' towar 1   i\u00b0UtT any considerable expense, and the course of said road being on a direct\nis Jackson, Mississippi.","fullrs":{},"find":"2221.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2220","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"604259","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.58 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
