<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/440</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>440</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/440/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n'\n73\nextent of the exceptions to the general rule. It is in this\ntrack we presume to tread. In pointing a local cause sufli\nt-ieiit to contaminate the air of a city, or district, it became him\nto urge upon them the ngency of those prominent cause\nwhich they would most readily admit, until such time as more\nlight might be let in upon the subject; and when the preconceived opinions of contagion might be so modified as to\nensure a patient hearing and consideration. Hence he di\nreded public attention especially to putrid animal and vegeta\nWc matters in the city, about the wharves and shipping, and\nto city filth :\u2014matters which were perceptible, and withal re\nvolting to llieir senses, and which, of course, would chain\ntheir attention. But now, when the barrier of error has been\nbroken down, we may begin to examine the subject more m\nimtcly, and, if possible, fix the precise limits where truth and\nerror meet. To contribute to this end is our object, and we\nhope wo shall be beard patiently and with a desire to arrive\nat truth, more than to establish or confute any particular theory or set of opinions. The grand fundamental point eon-\ntended for by Dr. Rush, is, that the yellow fever is and has\noften been generated by the local circumstances inourcowi-\nmercial cities. But he admits, that, under certain circumstances, it may tend to reproduce itself. He admits that it\nwill not spread from a few cases in a pure air, and that in nn\nimpure or miasmatic air it will spread. This miasmatic air\nhe contends is produced from animal and vegetable putrifac-\ntion, in certain states of weather. We also say yellow fever\nwill spread, and become epidemic in an air strongly charged\nwilh miasm; but wc ascribe the miasm to a different cause.\nDr. Rush says, \"yellow fever is not contagious (infectious? ) in its simple state1, and spreads exclusively by means of\nexhalations from putrid matters, which are diffused in the\nair. That it docs not spread in the ( pure air of ihe ) country, when c:; ried thither from cities in the United States:\nThat it does not spread in yellow fever hospitals, when they\norosituated beyond the influence of the impure air in which\nit is generated. * * That it generally requires the co-operation of an exciting cause, with miasmata to produce it.\"\nMed, Repos. v. G, p. 15G, &amp;c.\nIn relation to yellow fever patients, confined in close, sultry, filthy rooms, where the exhalations and excretions arc\nsuffered 10 accumulate, ho admits it to be infectious. He\nsays, \" 1 have heard of two or three instances in which the\nyellow fever was propagated by these means, in the country.\nremote from the place where it originated, as well as from\nevery external source of putrid exhalation.\" I hid. p. 157.\nDr. Hush says, or admits, that yellow fever may be contracted by \"a person sleeping in the sheets or upon a bed\nimpregnated with the sweats and other excretions, or by being\nexposed to thesuiell (breathing?) of the foul linen or other\nclothing of persons who bad the yellow fever.\" \"That it\nWas onco produced in Philadelphia from the effluvia from a\nchest of unwashed clothes, which had belonged to one of our\ncitizens, who had died with it in Barbadoes: but it extended\nno further in a large family, than to the person who opened\nthe chest.\" He accounts for this happening so seldom, by\n\"the superstitious dread of contagion, which has generally\nproduced great care not only in washing sheets and clothes,\nand airing beds supposed to be infected, but frequently the\ntotal destruction of them by water or fire!' Ibid. Here the\nmost eloquent champion of the non-contagious nature of yellow fever, and one of the most learned retiologisls admits all\nthat we contend for: that an effluvium is generated from a yellow fever patient, which is capable, under favorable circumstances, of reproducing that disease, in those who breathe it.\nHis explanation of the modus operandi, does not accord with\nour views of the subject: the fact is important. Still we do\nnot consider it essentially a contagious disease, notwithstanding these facts, which our own experience and a mass of authority might swell to a volume: but it convinces us of the\nnecessity of cleanliness, ventilation, and precaution.\nAnother important fact admitted by Dr. Rush, is one furnished him by Dr. Otto: viz.\u2014\"In the autumn of the year\n1798, it (a malignant remittent fever) prevailed upon the\nshores of the Delaware, in Gloucester county, New Jersey.\nA mild Remittent prevailed, at the same lime, on the high\ngrounds, a few miles from the river. During this time, the\nDoctor observed, if a poison who bad taken the yellow fever\nin Philadelphia, afterwards came into a family near the river,\nthe same disease appeared, in several instances, in one or\nmore branches of that family: but where persons brought\nthe fever from the city, and went into a family on the high\ngrounds, where the mild remittents prevailed, there was not a\nsingle instance of a yellow fever having been excited by them\nin any of its members.\" Med. Repos. v. G, p. 1G0. This\nis an important admission, and one which every unprejudiced\nperson, who has been conversant with yellow fever, will also\nidmit: and in substance it is precisely what I contend for;\nviz: that, in an infectious air, yellow fever may spread, without proper care. And Dr. Rush further says, that \"the city\nof Philadelphia has furnished, in all our yellow fever years,\nmany additional proofs of the correctness of Dr. Otto's remarks \" What is it but personal infection, added to an infectious state ofthe atmosphere? For when, as Dr. R. observes,\nthe atmosphere is highly infectious, or \"charged with the\nmiasmatic effluvia, or ' pestilential exhalations,' a single ease\nof yellow fever will excite it in a whole family.\"  Ibid. p. IGO.\nDr. Tilton, an old physician of great celebrity, during and\nsoon after the revolutionary war, in speaking of the yellow\nfever which prevailed at Wilmington, Delaware, August,\n1798, says, \"no one doubted it having been brought from\nPhiladelphia, in infectious or bad air, in boat;, shallops,\"\netc. He says it began about the water's edge, and spread\ngradually up to tho highest streets: having first appeared\nearly in August, it became epidemic by the middle of September.* Dr. Geo. Monroe, speaking of the same epidemic,\nsays it was clearly traced to an infected vessel from Philadelphia, then at the wharf, and that part of tho town near the\nwharf suffered most severely.! The atmosphere being in a\nsuitable condition for propagating the disease, the air from the\nvessels acted as a leaven. It must be borne in mind, that these\nfacts arc not adduced as evidences of contagion, nor do the\npersons who detail them consider them as evidences of contagion, but as showing clearly that the bad, infected air of\ndiips, as well as other localities, may be so diffused about a\n&gt;',\nII\n:,'i\n1\nA\n..i\n,1\n\u25a0J''\nk .,\nI\n'.,'' I\n4\n\u25a0   I  I.\n,i\n\u25a0Med. Hep. vol.3, p. 188-130,\nt Ibid, p. 136,\nvol. 1.\u2014v.","fullrs":{},"find":"441.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"440","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1739064","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
