<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 27</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2224</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2224</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2224/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 27","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"L 27 ]\nfriends of this measure that it shall stop short of some point on the Ohio\nggaei by th* . who can then estimate its importance and value? It is estimated\njfiitfoear ow \u2022 ^ hundred million of sou's will people the Mississippi valley. To\nthat i\" 5 0Ais great empire this road is to penetrate. It will there connect, intersect,\nihe AflW* , lhe arteries and trunks of that stupendous system of railway, eS tending from\nor trass al![ 'board to the great West. Every important city of our republic is stretch-\n^eAdant' .^ ^^ tQ tll;s p0jnCt ail(i to this point is tins road to be directed. It will\nin* f\"*u\\f3iS3ippi ofthe half million of human beings that are annually borne on its surface.\ni\u00abo'*e*1^lt]1 0C the Ohio will be given tbe traveler a choice as to the mode of his\nAt tiie \u00b0,our city. Who can doubt as to his choice between the \" floating palace\" and\n\u25a0**B9flt\u00b0*jCarV The expense will be the same, but expedition, safety, and comfort,\n\" -ae Kho themselves with tbe locomotive.\nw iv will the travel over this road be great, but the commerce upon it will be\n'^\"wduable. But little is yet known of the resources and wealth ofthe Central\n\u00abEl but that little promises a complete revolution in the manufacturing world. On the\nSiofthe Ohio, the Wabash, and the Illinois, will be found the spindle and the loom,\ni \"t vill rob Manchester and Lowell of their strength. Food is found there iu the\ntest abundance, and cheaper than any point in the known world. The coal bed of\n\u00a3\" Central West will yield inexhaustible quantities of fuel at a price of half the cost of the\n'me article at Manchester or Lowell. Water for dying is found as pure as that of the\nu . or the Merrimac; madder, the principal ingredient for coloring purposes, can be\n* n\"t[iere as cheaply and abundantly as any point in the world ; quercitron and sumac\nireabundant; fine clay and stone for building is inexhaustible; and last, but not least,\neotton can be delivered there at 15 per cent, less cost than at either Liverpool or Boston.\nThese are not the only advantages which this region will possess. In a few years an immediate and direct communication will be opened by railway with every important city on\nthe Atlantic seaboard, giving her facilities of placing in her factories tbe few light articles\nnot found there, and of sending to all parts ofthe country the products of her spindles and\n\u25a0 her looms. How can Lowell meet and vanquish this competition? She obtains her\ncotton from the interior ofthe Mississippi Valley, through New-Orleans. Her coal is\ndoe out of the mountains of Pennsylvania. Her food and flour are carried from the great\npain-fields ofthe North and Central West. Her dye-stuffs are imported from Europe and\nSouth America, and then the product of her looms are sent for distribution to tbe very\npoints from which she draws her cotton and her food, her flour and her coals. England\nand New England, the mother and the daughter, must yield forever the sceptre of manufactures to the sons of the Central West. From this point, over this road, through New-\nOrleans and across the Isthmus, must pass the fabrics that will clothe the millions of Asia,\nWbocan doubt, then,the importance of this road to New-Orleans?\nThe undersigned does not deem it necessary to say anything in relation to the benefits\nwhich would be conferred upon the sections of country through which these roads would\nrespectively ran. This point is daily discussed by both people and press, and the benefits\n\"\u25a0all classes of citizens fully understood. In the construction ofthe system of roads, pre-\nnted by the resolutions, the state of Mississippi is deeply and vitally interested, and aid\nImrnher will be necessary for their completion. It is believed that aid will be furnished\nTh  r amp-e imernal improvement fund.\ndue foregoing report is respectfully submitted to the General Committee on Routes.\nMost respectfully, your obedient servant,\nH. W. Walter.\nLOUISIANA ROUTES.\n0 the Committee on Routes.\u2014\npoi^ ^   . tlemen : I beg leave to submit a project for a rail-road leading from Shreve-\n^y suhm'tt13! ^ tenn-iiiate at Lake Providence, Louisiana.    A project having been al-\n^siss'tmi1 l v- i    a rail-road from Shreveport, by Dr. Young, to intersect the River\nSiting at tl sljurg, * should not now trouble the Committee with another report,\n\u00bbnd nc advi,e aaD)e point, did I not believe tbe terminus of the contemplated road bad,\nt0D*idf\u00bbTo,i   n \u2022-' Prnhably taken without being in possession of, or not having maturely\ni SSt   **acts Vs relation to tbis road-\n\u00bbad ||i1]e 0fa^mPt to impress the committee with the importance, the great necessity,\n^airman offhiroad' as that has been so ably and eloquently done already by the\n: \"hall only att mmittee of North L ouisiana, on tbe road above referred to; therefore\n?Qt ^ute and*\"^ *\u00b0 S'10W tne ^\"eat ProPriety an(i advantage of giving this road a dif-\n, * will first sf  ^H^itius, and my reasons for so believing.\n01 fte conven- ' ao Gai^ as 1824, tlie ^eat necessity of\" a road to the Mississippi,\nnience of the inhabitants of the northern parishes of this state was discovered,","fullrs":{},"find":"2225.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2224","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"476885","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.45 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
