<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/353</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>353</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/353/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S O U T H -VV E 3 T E UN   JOUKNA I,\n137\nins-with the character ol the establishment; every nicety\nand luxury was displayed, that the country could afford; choice\nml costly wines; the richest and most beautiful conserves\n,1111 the finest fruits, were spread before us in profusion, The\ncourteous, though dignified Hindoo, looked on complacently,\nmingled with the. guests, and engaged in conversation, whicl:\nhe enlivened by his pleasing wit; but he. never deigned to partake of the delicacies that had been spread for our gratification. He even scrupulously avoided touching anythingthat\nhad been handled by the unholy fingers of his guests, but I\ncould not help suspecting, that he had too much good sense to\nrelinquish to his paynim friends all the good things that\ngastronomy has invented for the world. Indeed his rich\nlooking complexion, and well developed proportions, bore\npractical testimony against his ascetic abstinence. The\namusements or the evening consisted or rough music by native' performers, who emulated each other's skill by making\nall kinds of hideous noises upon wind instruments, adapted\nboth for the nose and the mouth. During the concert, a troop\nof dancing girls made their appearance, tastefully dressed\nami decorated with large silver rings upon their arms and\nankles, and suspended from their noses and ears, which kept\nup a constant jingling during the exhibition of their performances. Their dancing consisted of active gesticulations\nwith their feet and arms, and a variety of constrained postures and proportions, which, upon the whole, seemed very\nmuch in accordance with the harsh sounds called music to\nwhich they were moving.\nNear Calcutta, resides one of those Hindoo princes, whom\nthe crafty policy of the English government has permitted\nto enjoy a nominal existence.    But the once powerful authority or the Rajah has departed with the usurpation that made\nhis ancestors slaves, and subjected his hereditaments to the\ncontrol of foreign potentates.    The residence of this princ\nis usually denominated the Rajah's garden, and is acccssibl\nto all strangers who will observe the formality of leaving a\ncard at his house.    Of these he has a great number, some\nwith names of exalted personages, of which he is not a little\nvain.    His demesne is handsomely enclosed, and tastefully\nlaid out in well kept walks.    The garden, in lieu of the\nusual decorations of such places, is lilted up with spacious\nand commodious cages, in which are confined a multitude or\nanimals of great variety and beauty, wdio seem to have lost\nnothing or their natural fierceness by the kind or imprisonment to which they are here subjected.    Other apartments\nare fitted up for birds or most singular and beautiful plumage,\nWhile the tanks afford accommodation to fishes and aquatic\nhinls.    Of the latter,  I noticed  several  fine specimens of\n'he black swan.    Among his animals, arc a few or the large-\ntailed sheep rrom the Capo or Good Hope.    Two or three\n\u00b0f Iheso sheep had tails of such enormous size, that it was\nfound necessary to relievo the animal of the weight, by means\n\u00b0' a contrivance like  a cart, fastened to the sheep by means\n\u00b0' straps, and in this way dragged about with the tail in it.\nWhen I witnessed this singular and laughable spectacle, it\nforcibly brought back lo my recollection the words of the\nol\nnursery song, that I used to hear when a little child:\u2014\nLnlle Bopecp has lost his sheep, and don't know where to\nfind them.    Let them alone, aud they'll come home, a dragging their tails behind them.\"\nHeretofore the lucrative trade of the east has been a prolific source of wealth to the merchants engaged in that business, and many persons have amassed immense- fortunes in\nthat country, some of whom have returned to Europe, to enjoy their ill health, and disburse their treasures;  but  others\nhave become so wedded to the habits and luxuries of the\neast, that they arc unwilling to encounter the disruption ol'\ntheir old associations and the formation or new ones. Among\nthose who have learned to be contented with the place where\nthey acquired the means or purchasing pleasure, is an opulent Spaniard, formerly a merchant or Calcutta, but now residing a few miles below the city, at an elegant villa upon\nthe bank or the Ganges.    There he lives in all the splendor\nof an eastern nabob, keeping for his amusement two or three\nelephants, trained   to the sport or tiger hunting.    Several\ntimes a year, mounted on one or these powerful and sagacious\nanimals, and attended by his servants,  he makes excursions\ninto the adjacent country, and, attacking the tiger in his native jungle, drives him from his retreat, and 'mid the exulting\nyells of the native population, forces his untameoble nature to\nyield sovereignty to man.    A tiger hunt is an occasion of no\nsmall interest to the natives, as this prowler of the wilderness\nnot unfrequently makes incursions into the villages, carrying\nofl goats and bullocks, and when pressed  by hunger, he is\nnot fastidiously particular in  avoiding their children, and\nwhen the huntsmen  are known  to be in pursuit of one of\nthese terrors, they turn out with spears, knives, and other\nmissiles,  to assist, if it be necessary, in his extermination.\nThe elephant is prepared for hunting, by having a frame\nwork, something like a carriage body, firmly strapped upon\nhis back.    It is denominated a houda, and  usually contains\ntwo compartments: one in front, with a seat large enough to\naccommodate two or three persons; and the other for the servants, who stand behind and  load the rifles.     During a visit\nthat I was paying to this gentleman, news was brought that a\ntiger or immense size was prowling about one or the native\nvillages, a mile from his residence.    The next morning we\ngot all ready and started at day light, pursuing a rough road\nthrough the woods and bushes, until we arrived at the aforementioned village.    Here we were met by a great number\nof natives, armed with spears, knives, and bludgeons, who\nhailed our approach with shouts and acclamations of joy.\u2014\nWe then took the direction of a jungle a mile and a half\nfrom the village, the elephants pushing along at a sweeping\nrate, seeming to feel that they were in pursuit of some object\nof great interest.    We had not proceeded far in the jungle,\nore the elephants gave intimation of our approach to the beast,\nby a restless movement of the proboscis and a quicker step,\nflu's put every one on the qui vivc, and while awkwardly\nlooking about, 1 was startled by the report of a rifle, fired by\nmy companion, whose keen and practised eye had discovered\nthe tiger skulking at the edge or a thick body of long grass\nand reeds.    A shout from some natives, and a loud yell from\nthe elephant, followed the report of the rifle, and I turned\nny head with the expectation of seeing the body of\"a dead or\ndying ti\"-er; but with astonishment I beheld the terrific moa-\n\u00b0 VOL,   I.\u2014IX.\n\u2022 htm\n\u25a0ml\ni   .\nI\n1\ni\nHi\ntkl'i'J\nmi\nm\n-'V-.M\n... C\n.. y \u25a0 &gt; I\nimi\nII","fullrs":{},"find":"354.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"353","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1638294","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
