<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 26</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2223</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2223</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2223/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 26","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[26]\ndistance, i9 worth more than ten million of dollars annually. This valley, W!,l\nwealth, population, and resources, is now the forced tributary of Mobile. The Co\ntion of this road will give to that commerce a new direction, aud place it upon the wj,\"1*\nof New-Orleans. Not only is the commerce of this section of country considerable u?\npresents inducements for the construction of a road that can scarcely be found jD i~\u2122\u2122|\nnation on any other route. Its population is wealthy, industrious, and pub]ic.Jp*\nIts prairie surface is so level, that grading would scarcely be required for somea^\nmiles. Nature seems almost to have prepared it for the superstructure of the rail*\"'\nNew-Orleans must certainly be false to her best interests, if she neglects this roadtSl\npiercing a country, presenting an inviting surface for its track, wealth to construct 7j\ncommerce to support it. What has been said of Mississippi may with equal proptie'hL,\napplied to Tennessee. This road would penetrate tbe wealthiest section of the ^Z\nstate. It would call back to this city the highly valuable commerce of Middle TenneSi\nwhich is now seeking a market at Charleston. The cotton, wheat, tobacco, provis^,\nand mineral products of that section of tbe country, would be transported over thism*?\nand with the cotton and trade from Mississippi, would actually add to the comaeS\nof New-Orleans, in value, not less than twenty millions of dollars annually. Much oft\nlight but valuable commerce of Nashville, about to pass by Chattanooga to Char!eit\u00bb\nwill be retained _for your city. The merchant and citi\/.en of Nashville must find a aw\nspeedy and certain route to his exporting and importing city than that afforded by-Jj\nuncertain navigation ofthe Cumberland River, If this road is not constructed, Namigh\nwill inevitably turn her attention to Charleston. The construction of the Nashville aid\nLouisville Rail-road will complete the link in this great chain tiiat will place thee*\nmercial tributaries of Lake Erie within tbe influence of New-Orleans. By this rand,ni\nthe Mississippi and Ohio rivers, New-Orleans can become the successful rival of Kt\u00bb\nYork and Boston, and call back the millions of commerce that has left her for tine\ncities.\nTbis road will pass through the eastern portion ofthe manufacturing country of tit\nCentral West, and bear over its track a large portion oi' the products of the spin'dlesad\nlooms that must soon be found there.   Whilst the undersigned believes, that the comment\nof this road would be highly valuable as a source of revenue to the road, he is satisfied\nthat the travel upon the road would be not only an inexhaustible source of revenne,l\u00bb\nwould contribute greatly to the wealth of New-Orleans.    Ohio, Indiana, Kentucky,kf\nportions of Tennessee and Mississippi, would send their population over this road to t\u00ab\ncity.    The man of business or pleasure, from the eastern and north-eastern Atlantic*\nboard, whilst in the West, would find here his speediest and safest mute to Ncw-OneM\".\nBy means of tbe railways extending to and circling Lake Erie, Boston and New-Yin\nwould be placed within some three days' journey of the wharves of this city.   By*\nroad, and the railways projected and constructed across the mountains, our citizens ww*\nbe speedily and safely transported to Washington,  Baltimore, and Philadelphia,   w\u2122\nwould be the effect of all this upon New-Orleans 1    Her now vacant houses wonli w\nfilled with active tenants.    Her shops would be crowded  with the talent and beaul\nother states, who would spend millions in the city, and give to her additional thousand\nactive and industrious citizens.    New-Orleans would cease to be tbe mere distrihuW*\nthe wealth and commerce of other ports.    She would become a producing city; ami\nmanufacturer, the mechanic, and the artisan, would join with the merchant andlheo\nto enrich and populate the city of his adoption.\nIn reference to the rail-road proposed in the resolutions, running from Canton\nwardly and   centrally through the state  of Mississippi, the   undersigned will P*  ^\ndeductions  made  by him from reliable statistical  information now before him.\ncitizens of Mississippi, living upon the line of this road, have evinced during the PB, ^\na deep interest in its construction.    They have ascertained the length of the to*\nabout 173 miles, and that the cost of its construction and equipment will not e*c\nmillion seven hundred and fifty thousand dollars.    The number of bales of ^l^rei\nin the counties through which the road passes was, in 1850, one hundred and Of\nthousand four hundred  and eighty-eight bales.    The population of the co\"\"^',^\nto 124,231.    It is estimated that nollcss than 93.0131 bales of cotton will pass   grt^[\nover the road.    The income derived to the road  from this source alone, at s11   ^-jjfj\ncost of 95 cents for transporting each bale, is ^S,:i7'i, which, with  a return tr**\"\"**' -^i\namount, would yield annually to the road $176,75*,  for freights alone.    Th'3 es   Jj*\nbased alone upon tbe conveyance of cotton and return freights, exclusive of ! jLjm\u00bb\nofthe dairy, the farm-yard, the orchard, and the infinite variety of commerce Pj*\nwhich would be raised iu a section of country so highly favored by nature as L-**  , ^M\nsissippi.    At some point on the northern boundary line of Mississippi this \"\u25a0\"'ye*\ncross the Memphis and Charleston Rail-road ; and whenever tlds is effected, die    ^p\npassengers that would annually pass over the road could not fall short o\u00a3 50,0j' -.^ t *!-\ndersigned is satisfied from tbe statistics before him, that this road would?\nrevenue,\nrVl.t  '\n\u2122\u00abd, derivable from the sources above indicated, of not less than thirteen pe eJteu\nthe capital invested. Such would be the results from this road, were it ne\\nVrgrth\nbeyond the connection with the Memphis and Charleston Road.   It is not,\nl,o*\u00ab*","fullrs":{},"find":"2224.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2223","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"566902","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
