<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU LibrariesSpecial Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/553</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>553</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/553/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU LibrariesIn accordance with UScopyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or commentsSee instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"-tort \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\nI III\nS3    M-   \u25a0'\u25a0\nIf-\nIf.\nI*\nI'\n1?\n-i'.,-\ni :ife|i\"\nj |;tr\n\u25a0 \u25a0\u25a0 a Mi\n\u25a0Iii\nii *' *\u25a0\u25a0\nii\n190\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nand near the residence of his son, Walter Irvine, junior, the\nmound is located.\ndied  from   the\npottery, pieces of human and animal bones, charcoal, and the\ndebris of the top of the mound and of those smaller tower.\nThe appearance of the mound, as approaches\nFayette road, is that of a long straight battery of earth, with\nsloping, regular front and platform at the top, with some mod-\norate elevations or towers upon the  terrace, tho whole of\nwhich is overlooked by on abrupt tower at  the western end t\nwhich would seem to have been almost entirely washed\naway.\nBeneath the rubble, on digging inlo the sides of the mound\nno remains of pottery or bones were to bo found.\nYears ago, gentlemen, who then resided in tho vicinity of\n\u25a0 mound, saw evidence of the existence of a fosse at tho\ntowards Natchez, rising nearly as high above the terrace or foot of the mound, at least on the eastern end; probably a\nplatform as that does above the circumjacent plainThe ditch originally encircled the entire mound, which might hav\u00ab\noutline on Ihe southern side, first approached, is of the most j been filled to any depth with the rain water that would neccj.\n, earned off by tho\nthe mound, its\nimposing and martial characfr   The traces of design nre sarily fill on so large an area as five, acres, car\nso apparent that every observer must  involuntarily feel that rubble roofs of tho sides    The terrace  of I\n\"    sides, and the fields around it, having, for more than half a\nthis is other than a natural erection   So enormous a pi\ncither thrown up or carved from a primitive hill, in the singular shape in which time still spares it to remain, must have\ncentury,been cultivated by the plough, it would not be wonderful that nearly all the traces of n continuous ditch should\nbeen the creation of heads that planned, and of n countless have been filled up.\nmultitude of hands that labored through long periods oftimcThe pottery found upon the surface of the sides, or from\nThe magnitude ofthe mound is such that its relative heights one to two feet below the surface, is of a rare and oftentimes\ndo not at first impress the visitor with their full proportions: beautiful structureIt is generally in broken pieces\u2014yet\nbut, after a struggle up the steep face of the mound to the large enough to show the shape and curve of the circumfer-\nnce of the vessels of which those pieces were partsIn\nsome cast's, the beauty of the shape of the vessel was strikingly evident, and could not bo surpassed by any modern manii-\nbroad terrace, which in its turn becomes the base ofthe great\nwestern tower and of four other smaller mounds or towers \u2014\nafter a glance at the general outline ofthe foundation mound,\nwhich bears the resemblance of a parallelogram, having a facturerIt was not glazed, but perfectly smooth, as if some\nregular southern side, and nn irregular bastion front on the preparation had been spread over the surface of the material,\nnorth\u2014and after walking over the terrace which includes an'previous to the hardening processThe outsides of most of\narea of about five, acres, gazing up at the stern western tow- the vessels were ornamented with lines, sometimes drawn par-\ncr, itself a parallelogram, (once perhaps a regular anel per- allel to the brim, five or six circles, in the space of an inch in\nfeet one) of about five rods in length by three in breadth\u2014width, extending round the bowl; or by figures of triangular\nthe mind becomes fully aware ofthe vastness of the creation dines and checker work, elaborately covering most of the out-\nand renders a full measure of homage to the proud unknown sides of the vesselsThe potter}' was made of various raale-\nnation thai left behind them such a mysterious hieroglyphic rials and of different colors; some reddish and brick-colored;\nof power, speaking a language of grandeur; yet without a others slate-colored; others whitePieces were found dial\nrelict of a single word that the present ago may translate were made of sea-shells, ground into fine lamina, and held\ninto the elements of aboriginal history   When walking on together by somealfinitive ingredient not yet analyzed.\nthis vast terrace one can but think ofthe thousands who trod\nthe same earth centuries ago, of the battle sonus that might\nTho smaller mounds, upon the terrace of the larger one,\nare irregularly situated at various points on the bastion or\nhave rolled in thundering volumes into the still air above, of battery walls, like look-out or watch lowers   Near the fool\nthe channts over the dead, of the ceremonies of a wild and1 of the one situated at the north eastern corner was found a\nmysterious worship\u2014and of the dreadful hour, when, before|numberof human skeletons, about one or two feet beneath\nthe tempest of battle, or the angel of tho pestilence, national\npower melted away, and the surge of empire, in its flow to\nother lands, ebbed from this mural throne, leaving it voiceless and a desert.\nThe height ofthe great terrace from its base, is forty-five feet\nby nieasureinent.aiid ofthe great tower above the terrace, thirty-\neight feet\u2014making eighty-three feet in all, above the plain.\nThe sides of the larger foundation mound are to a considerable extent, if not wholly, encased, about one foot beneath\nthe surface or tho soil, with a sort of rubble, resembling slack-\nbaked bricks, without much regularity of form, as if laid upon the original steep faces of the mound, to prevent the washing away, in sudden showers, of the soil'Phis rude roofing,\nformed of a clay base, and sometimes mixed with hair or\nmoss, like modern mortar, may once have been continuous, or\nit may not have been otherwise than it is now found ; in either\nease it was a sufficient security against tho action of rain wa-\n\u25a0    The soil above this rubble was filled with fragments of\nthe surface of the earth, with the heads lying in an eastern\ndirection, with some exceptions, where one skeleton would\nbe found lying across anotherThe bones were lying M\nposition, having never been distill bed since interment\u2014although the plough has, for years, thrown up human bones\non the terrace of this mound in great abundanceTho\nlength of time that has evidently elapsed since burial, had\ncorroded most of the bones so that they crumbled under tho\nhand anel exposure to the air; yet, with great care, a cranium\nwas extricated from its bed that preserved sufficient consistency to show ils form, and prove the fact of its aboriginal\noriginIt was indisputably the compressed skull of a Flat\nHead Indian, or one whose head, in infancy, had undergone\nthe compressing processThe forehead was wide and lofty,\nand the compression had taken effect chiefly on the back par'\nof the head, bending the skull over with a short curve which\ncould be distinctly traced in the circular line which such a\ncompression  would naturally  make     Drawings of the","fullrs":{},"find":"554.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"553","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1820165","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
