<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/373</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>373</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/373/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"12\nSO^TH-WE'STERN JOURNAL.\nI\nings\u2014nothing daunts him\u2014the House may ring with cries\nof order\u2014order!\u2014unmoved\u2014contemptuous\u2014he stands amid\nthe tempest, and like an oak that knows its own gnarled and\nknotted strength, stretches his arm forth and defies the blast.'\nObituary.\u2014The celebrated Rev. EDWARD DORR\nI iRIFFIN, D. D, former Professor in Andover Theological\n.Seminary, Pastor of Park street church in Boston, and late\nPresident of Williams' College in Massachusetts, is no more,\nThis great moral and intellectual luminary was hidden from\nmortal eyes by death in Newark, New Jersey, on the 8th of\nNovember last. In the next number of the Journal we shall\npresent a sketch of the character of this distinguished orator\nand theologian.\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nNAT).'Ill-:\/:,  DECEMBER 15,  1837\nTO SUBSCRIBERS AND CORRESPONDENTS,\nThe Terms of this Journal are five dollars a year (or for\n21 numbers)payable in advance, on the delivery ofthe first\nnumber, All remittances and communications for tho Journal\nare lo be addressed lo Professor J. A. Van Hoesen, Natchez.\nCommunications for insertion in tho Journal, which do not\ncontain remittances or the names of Subscribers, should, to\nensure attention, be postpaid.\nTho South Western Journal will be regularly mailed to all\nSubscribers living out of the city, according to such directions\nas we shall receive. Subscribers living in tho City will be\nsupplied by a earlier.\nTO THE PUBLIC.\nIll consequence of ihe almost entire prostration of all kinds\nof business in the city of Natchez, during tho prevalence of\ntho dreadful opidemic, the Executive Committee of the Jefferson College and Washington Lyceum were not able to\nred \u25a0\u2022\u25a0in ihe promisoof the appearance of the South-Western\nJournal in the months of October and November. Wo feel\nconfident that a generous community will appreciate tho apology, which, under such circumstances, we now make with\nthe full hope of a favorable response, and an entire acquittal,\nin the public mind, of any dereliction of duty on the part of\nthosegentleincn ostensibly pledged to the fulfilment of this trust,\nWe now present, to the attention and patronage of the en\nlightened community of the South-West, a JOURNAL, to\nbe devoted to the scientific and literary interests of the Southern section of the great vale of the Mississippi. We ask\nthe aid of the learned, the accomplished and the patriotic, in\nmaking our enterprise an honor to the literary character of\nihe citizens and ihe institutions of Mississippi, Occupyinga\ndepartment, which is, at present, filled by no kindred journal\nin the South West, and emulous to represent an interest entirely separate from, and superior to, the commercial ami political movements ofthe times,\u2014we shall truly need the fostering attention and the substantial patronage ol'all the friends\nof learning, education and intellectual improvement, lo sustain our infant enterprize, and to shape it to a happy accordance with the taste and genius of a chivalrous and accomplished community.\nTo justify the reasonable expectations of thepublic, we have\nit in our power to pledge the mental resources and the industry of an association of literary and scientific gentlemen, whose-\nbest powers will be expended in the effort to advance the\ncause of improvement, and worthily lo represent the intellectual taste ofthe Southwest. In an enterprise so arduous and\nresponsible, is il too much for us to solicit the patronage of tin-\npublic at large\u2014our personal friends\u2014and to invoke the aid\nof genius and of liberality lo cheer the commencement of our\nlabors, that the seed may be sown in hope and the harvest\ngathered with satisfaction and profit ?\nIn presenting this first number ofthe South Western Journal to the public, justice to ourselves compels us to say that it\nhas been prepared for the press under rather unpropitious circumstances, and will serve rather as a specimen of the materiel\nand design of our publication, than ns a measure ofthe spirit\nand devoledness, which, wo hope, will enrich succeeding\nnumbers.\nThe \" esprit elu corps, or, rather, the full scope and intent of\nany journal, is rarely entered into and attained in the commencement. To shape and fashion, after a high intellectual\npattern ; to embody the ideal image and purpose ofthe mind;\nto bring out the fitting proportions and nice adjustments which\nshould ever belong lo the creations of the intellect,\u2014must, of\nnecessity, be the result of time, reflection, experie'iice1, and the\nsanctions of public approbation.\nWith these reflections wc submit this, the commencement\nof our Journal, to the notice ofthe friends of science and letters in the Southwest\u2014not doubting hut a generous patronage\nwill defray the expenses of the publication\u2014the only pecuniary boon which is sought\u2014wjiile all the reward we seek is\nthe mutually delightful intercourse which may be opened,\nby our enterprise, of mind with mind; of ihe readers with the\nwriters; of both with those intellectual pleasures that strengthen with acquaintance and mature with time. ,\nThe Monthly meeting of the Lyceum.\u2014The last\nmeeting of the Jefferson College and Washington Lyceum\nwas attended in the College Hall on Saturday, November 2d.\nJ. S. B. Thacher, Esq. of Natchez, read a Lecture on ihe\n\"Philosophy of tho Law\" and Professor (.'. G. Forshey\nread a paper on \"Meteoric Showers,\" which appears in this\nnumber ofthe Journal.\nThe exercises at the next meeting, on the first Saturday in\nJanuary, will be a Lecture by Mr. G. V. H. Forbes, and\nEssays by Messrs. Dr. J. W. Monette and Judge Jennings.\nLyceum in England.\u2014An intelligent correspondent of\nthe Philadelphia National Gazette has found a Lyceum in\nBungay, Suffolk county, England\u2014the first and only one\nover established in our mother isle. The writer thus playfully\nannounces his discovery:\u2014 \u00ab\n\" But what is more amazing, they have fbimetl here a bona\ntide New England Lyceum \/\u2014the first that I have heard of\nin this country; and what is more to the purpose, though but\na year old, it is flourishing, and full of hope. People stared\nterribly at first. Men were thought fools that talked in its\nfavor     When a room  for  the meetings was secured, and a","fullrs":{},"find":"374.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"373","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1823587","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
