<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/474</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>474</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/474/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"i  Ijffl\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n101\ndiscriminating; and we would suggest that the manner in\nwhich the infection was decomposed, was for want of the\nmalaria or infectious air, which alone will afford it a suitable nidus for the fermentative process. Hence the wisdom\nof free ventilation with the sick, as inculcated by all who\nhave been conversant wilh this fever; and the reason why\nit is not known to spread, in a country air; and why in u\ncity the malignity of the cases and the succession of cases\nincrease with each case attacked in sultry hot weather, unless the people fly.\n,1. When infected air is confined in rooms, &amp;c. it is not\ndestroyed by any degree of cold short of 40\" Furtnheit; and\nlo destroy it entirely nothing short of 32\u00b0 will suffice.\nHence it often occurs that the infected air of houses produces yellow fever in those entering them even after feost\nand ice; for a mild frost will take place at 40\u00b0\u2014and al\nthough the temperature in the open air may be reduced to\n3&gt;\\ yet the temperature in closctl rooms is most probably\nnot below 40' or 45 J. To destroy infection requires the temperature reduced 15J or 20\" lower than is requis.te to neutralize simple miasm.\n5. This infected air is supposed lo be more volatile thai\nmiasm to be volatilized by the sun and partially condensed\nin the cool dews of night: hence when there is much infection in the air it may be more dangerous to be out at\nnight than in meridian day. Thus the night-watches gen\norally suffer severely.\n(j. The infection insinuates itself into blankets, feather-\nbeds, woollens, and other porous articles, and in this way\nmay be carried from one place lo another. But the infected air thus transported will produce ihe disease only in\nthose who breathe it before it is diluted with common air:\nit might spread when taken into a close room and kept in\nstagnant warm air.\n7. Like miasm it is heavier than common air; and settles in low damp places, and bayoux; so that when there is\nbut a moderate quantity in the general air it abounds i.i such\nplaces, in proportion to their depth and width, and the declivity to tii ir margins, until its surface conies upon a level\nwith tn.it diffused abroad. Thus when abundant it may be\nten feet deep near tho margin of a bayou, and not more than\nthree feet deep one hundred yards distant.\n8. It is mpposed to adhere in some manner to wood and\nsuch like bodies, especially, more than to brick, stone, plus-\ntor, etc. Hence we find wooden houses more frequently become infected and remain so even after one or two frosts; because it is more tenacious of wood, which maintains a highci\nspecific temperature than stone or brick walls. Hence the\ngreat difficulty of disinfecting ships until cold weather completely neutralizes the properties of the infection.\nWe will here make a few remarks again upon the generation of miasm on board ships in tropical climates. Tin\nconfined air in the holds of ships is more likely to be exhausted by respiration, nnd charged with human effluvia than\neven a city ; especially where there are many souls on board,\nwho aie often confined below on account of storms and\nwinds.    In them thorough ventilation is extremely difficult,\nand the temperature is almost constantly up to the miasm\npoint. The infectious air is thus rapidly formed in many\ncases, and in this state, a vessel arriving at n port where yel.\nlow fever prevails, will be ready to receive the leaven fiom\nthe infected air of the city, either by the crew visiting the infected districts on shore or by the introduction of the infection in the form of fomes in goods. The United States frigate General Greene, before referred to, is a good illustration.\nThe temperature at sea in tropical latitudes is seldom below 80' of Fahrenheit, and often from 90' to 100' according\nto the degree of reflection and concentration ofthe sun's rays.\nBy a register kept by Dr. Thos. Rodman,* embracing thirty observations between the first of November and the fifth\nof December, at 12 o'clock M. each day, between latitude\n22\" north, nnd 22\" south, it was ascertained that the lowest\ntemperature of the air was 79' and the highest in the shade\nSO\"'. The lowest temperature of the si a below the surface\nwas 78 =, and the highest 84\u00b0. 'Ihe mean temperature of\nthe air timing that time, at 12 AI. was 83\", nnd ofthe water\n81\u00b0 Thus the temperature within vessels while in tropics\ncannot be low enough to destroy or neutralize miasm, much\nless infection: the former requiring a temperature of 50\u00b0\nand the latter of 32e Fahrenheit. Thus, however slowly it\nmay be generated, it continues to accumulate until the ship\nenters a northern climate. Tin's register was kept during a\ncool healthy season, when no disease was generated on Loaid,\nby hot, culm and sultry weather: of course a much higher\ntemperature in these respects is often experienced on board\nships in the tropics; and the miasm and infectious air is often generated where no animal or vegetable putrefaction\nexists.\nThe generation of miasm in cities, as has been before remarked, has taken place under every variety of circumstance\nus regards animal or vegetable decomposition; as well as\nwhere neither existed. Under all the circumstances which\nhave been presented to our view, we cannot conceive it possible for such a general morbific agml, lo be eliminated liom\nsuch a diversity of sources and each so limited in their nature\nand extent as those to which it has been ascribed. As well\nmight we expect to see a territory inundated by a rivulet as\nto believe the atmosphere of a city should be infected with a\npestilential miasm from a few bushels of rotten coffee, a few\nbarrels of oysters, a dead horse, or a filthy back yard. The\ncause is inadequate to ihe effect. If so small a cause could\nproduce such general effects it would be an anomaly in nature'.\nBesides, it would be strange beyond comprehension if a\npeculiar miasm, could be generated from a hundred different\nsources, nnd under as many different circumstances: for the\ncauses and circumstances necessary for the production of yellow fever, as generally maintained by the advocates of vegetable or animal putrefaction, are almost innumerable. In\nmedical investigations ns well ns in some othcis, we arc too\nipt lo direel our attention exclusively to a few apparently\nprominent circumstances, which strike some of our senses,\n'\u25a0\u25a0\u2022\u25a0\u25a0Ait\n[A. ;wm\nV;!'iT:\nm\n;\u25a0\nm\nm\nI\n\u25a0\ni\nvh\n\u2022 Vide Coxc's Medical Museum, vol. I, p. 83\u20144.\nK","fullrs":{},"find":"475.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"474","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1759667","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
