<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/612</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>612</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/612/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 23","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH W E S T E K N   J 0 U RN A 1,\n210\n1\nheave in surveying the last moments of Epaminondas, the\nlisliious Theban General, who, in the battle of Mantinia was\nwounded, and while the javelin was still remaining in his\nbreast, enquired the fate of his country, and being told that\nall was well, exclaimed,  \"I have lived long enough,\"    But\nwc need not go back to ancient Greece and Rome for examples\nof truo patriotism.    In our own history and in our limes, we\nhave tho examples of such men as a Wolfe, who, when mortally wounded on the field of battle, and learning that the en\nciny fled, exclaimed, \"I die happy,\" and of a Washington\nwho sacrificed his own ease and comfort for tho good of his\ncountry.    These arc sublime spectacles of patriotism, and\nworthy tho admiration and imitation of all who would be\nstyled the. lovers of their country, and the benefactors of mankind.    Such feelings should animate the breasts of every one\nwho has such an inheritance left him as our fathers left to us\n\u2014free, republican institutions\u2014and to preserve and defend\nthese, tho patriot must show his own right arm.    No govern\nmeiit under heaven, especially a democracy, can long exist\nimcorrupted, unless the people have a love to their country\nand a regard to her institutions, superior to all private and\npersonal considerations.    They must let the glow of patriotism kindle lo a flame, and burn and blaze upon their very\ncountenances, with undying  lustre.    The soul, filled with\ntrue patriotism, feels a fire burning within, which the bloody\nwaters of despotism will never be able to quench, nor the\nsword of the tyrant to subdue.    This was the patriotism that\nbinned in tho bosoms ofthe patriots ofthe revolution.    Yes,\nthey loved their country indeed.    In that little band, the descendants of an oppressed and despised ancestry, driven by\nintolerance and persecution from their homes and their native soil, to seek an asylum in tho forests of a newly discovered world, we behold the consummation and concentration of\nall  human virtues\u2014all that is great in intellect, lofty in\nthought, elevated in sentiment, generous in purpose, or decisive in action.    Their love of truth and justice was ever unwavering; their regard for religion and morality unfaltering;\nand their sincerity, candor, magnanimity, gentleness, and forgiveness of injuries without a parallel.    Reared and educated in the severe school of adversity, there wero no difficulties\nthey could not surmount, no privations they could not submit\nto, no hardships they could not endure, nor any sacrifice they\nwero not ready to make.    Their lives, their fortunes, their\nhonor, and all they held near and dear, were devoted to their\ncountry's cause.    Nor did their patriotism spring from ambition or vain glory.    Many who acted a conspicuous part in\nthe great drama, and staked their all upon tho issue, had already passed the meridian of life, and some wore even veterans of half a century, whoso heads wero silvered o'er with\nage, and who were fast tottering down the declivities of time.\nNeither did it arise from interest or avarice: all forsook their\navocations of gain, their homes, their fire-sides, and their\nfriends, and enlisted in the same common cause.   And whether in the battle field, in the cabinet, or in the desk; whether\nwielding the glittering sword, or flourishing the pen, that\nmighty instrument of little men; or whether with the sword\nof the spirit, directed by an eye of faith; all, with a firm reliance on the justice of their cause and the protection of the\nGod of heaven, aimed at the same great end, the freedom of\ntheir country and the amelioration of the condition of man.\nSuch were the characters and such the patriotism of those\nwhom a world delights to honor ; whoso names, inscribed on\nfreedom's banner, waving at mast head, will live when all\nthe monuments of Egyptian and Roman greatness shall havo\ncrumbled into dust. Never did the moral and intellectual firmament glow with brighter constellations; never was\ntbe historian's page decked with brighter gems. Ancient\nGreece once boasted of a Themistocleg, of a Demosthenes,\nand of Socrates; Rome, too, delighted to tell the story of a\nCicero, a Caisar, and a Constantino; but it was reserved for\nus to boast of such men as a Washington, and a Warren, an\nOtis, and a Jefferson\u2014the former unrivalled in the. field, tho\nlatter unsurpassed in the cabinet. To such pilots, was freedom's\nbark, with her little crow, intrusted in that perilous hour, when\ntho darkness of the firmament and the commotion ofthe eh:-\nments, seemed to threaten destruction and extinguish hope.\nYes I then it was that this little chosen band, borne forward\nin the ark of liberty, remained steadfast in their purpose, till\nthe dove of peace sent forth, having found whereon lo rest her\nfoot, returned bearing the olive leaf, which was hailed with\nacclamations, which echoed and re-echoed through the length\nand breadth of our happy land; which acclamations havo\nbeen annually reiterated on the day of our national jubilee,\nuntil the sound, wafted on the gentle breeze, has been borne\nto distant climes, proclaiming man's \"inalienable right to life,\nliberty, and the pursuit of happiness.\" Let but such patriotism fire the bosom of Americans, and a literary and mural\nreformation would commence, which would enlighten and\nchristianize the world.\nEditorial Correspondence. A gentleman in Boston, no less distinguished for mercantile ability and honor,\nlhan for his persevering habits of mental improvement, which\nhe declares shall continue \"as long as there is any thing to\nlearn,\" thus writes the editor of this Journal, under date of\nJune 12th, and embodies a historical account of tho Boston\nLyceum:\u2014\" I see by the pamphlets sent, that tho word 1 ,y-\nceum is still a favorite with you. I am glad you are. introducing it, and making it familiar at tho South. It has wrought\nwonders here; no class of associations in New England\nhas excited so general an interest and been so successful as\nLyceums. ' Could you have entered one of our weekly meetings at the Odeon last winter, and seen Governor Everett,\nour President, in the chair, and an audience of two thousand\npersons, with interested and smiling countenances, wedged in\nthe centre, and ranged round the four extensive galleries, one\nabove another, from the bottom to the top of the building, you\nwould involuntarily, I think, have been carried back to the;\nprimary meeting, at ' Old Hanover,' where it devolved on\nyou, in a speech, to explain tho meaning of tho word Lyceum !\nYou cannot, I think, havo forgotten it.\n\"While on this subject, considering the interest you took in\ntho formation of the Boston Lyceum, a brief account of its\nrise and progress' may not bo uninteresting to you.   I copy\nit just as it was written for one of our papers, a few weeks\nsince, at the close of our course of lectures.\nvol. i.\u2014xvt.*","fullrs":{},"find":"613.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"612","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1710125","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.63 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
