<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 35</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2260</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2260</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2260/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 35","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":",       on the ridge northerly to the head-waters of the Loutre, near El Dorado,\n\u00ae Akansas, and then turn to the west on the old trail of the Quapaw Indians.\nTh country beyond the Loutre was more populous; the roads in better order;\nlies more easily obtained, and information more reliable and abundant.\nU was decided to cross the Loutre, which we did at Brown's Ferry. The\nntrv between the Washita and this point is rolling, but favorable for constrnc-\nn There is rock in the hills, which became visible at Dr. Collier's spring,\na ' [jjg Washita, but not elsewhere. The soil is good for bricks, and many are\n!Lde near our line. The Loutre will be crossed by abridge of 150 feet span\n\"nd 25 feet high, which i3 sufficient to pass the highest water. The western\nbore of the river is low, however, for a distance of three-fourths of a mile, and\nL much iike the Mississippi Swamp: it will require a bank from ten to eighteen\nr t [jjo-h to bring the road above high water. The line is continued eastward to\nthe D'Arbonne side ol the ridge, towards Farmersville, thb county-seat of Union\nParish, which place we leave one mile and a half to the left by the actual line,\nand three and a half by the projected line, and continuing on the D'Arbonne\nade of the ridge, pass near a place called Speursville, six miles beyond which\nwe cross the state line into Arkansas, 42i miles from the Washita ; aud thence\ncontinue twenty miles further, in a general northwest course, to Darden's, on the\nroad from Kl Dorado to Springhill, and near the dividing ridge between the\nSmacovert and D'Arbonne before described. If, instead of crossing the Loutre,\nwe had continued up the ridge between that stream and the Washita to El Dorado, and thence turned westward, the two lines would have joined at Darden's,\nthe distance being about the same.\nWe found the country, after crossing the Loutre, very hilly, with abundance of\nreck, until after passing Farmersville. Beyond Farmersville it has still a very\nirregular surface, and we lose sight of the rock until we approach Spearsville.\nNear the Arkansas line there is much sand, the roads in some places being deep\nwith it. It is not, however, difficult to accommodate a good line to the country\nwith reasonable curvature and grades of fifty feet to the mile.\nFrom Darden's we continue westward, on the ridge before mentioned, (said\nto be the Quapaw trail,) to Col. Bucknor's, at Beechland Post-Office. Here another choice of routes presents itself, and we may incline northerly towards\nSpringhill, lying ten miles east of Fulton, and, crossing the Bois d'Arc, Bodcom,\nand Dorcheat rivers, near their sources, reach Fulton by that route in a distance of\n58 miles, or we may continue westward on the same ridge ten miles further;\nandthence, inclining to tbe south, pass into the valley of the Dorcheat, and following down the slope of one of its branches, called Big Creek, cross the Dorcheat just below the junction, 2*&gt;J miles from Beechland; thence, following up\nthe opposite: slope of the Dorcheat, and the ridge between it and tbe Bodcom,\ndescend obliquely the Bodcom slope, aud cross that stream three miles south of\nLouisville, the county-seat of Lafayette county ; thence, following up the slope of\nits valley and that of the Little Bodcom, its tributary, to the source of the latter,\n'assiato the valley of the Bois d'Arc, and, crossing that stream, reach the table\n'ordering the Red River, on which we keep to its edge back of Fullon ; then,\nsscending, reach the Red River at Fulton, with a distance from the  Dorcheat\n-\u25a0\"6 ot 403 miles, and from Beechland of 67 miles, or nine miles further than\nbLl ot'ier route. The line, however, was run over the latter route, as it ena-\nRiv UV\u00b0 exam'ne the ground with reference to a nearer terminus on the Red\n[, , r llan Fulton. The country, from Darden's towards Fulton, on the ridge\nobstaT\" D'Arbonne and Smacovert, is high and undulating, but presenting no\nwe h 8 *\u00b0 c^'eaP ai1^ 8afe construction. To pass into tbe valley ofthe Dorcheat,\nthirie^6 t0 s'\"'moiint a summit requiring 20 feet cutting, from which there is no-\n&gt;pan \"V',ls\"al to the place of crossing. \" This will require a bridge of 100 feet\nand ab abutments 25 feet high, and beyond it a bank a mile and a half long,\nB0(ico011* 12ineIeet high. From this we attain the ridge between Dorcheat and\n\"^Ddim, K^ s'\u00b0t,e9&gt; a\u00bbd, while on the ridge, have a level plain; thence, de-\ntttreg &lt;L;\u00b0 the Bodcom, along the slope, we find sinuosities requiring curva-\nvated* h S\u00b0'' between the two streams is sand, clay and gravel, easily exca-\negg8.' Uj n\" r\u00b0ck. I saw gravel here in which the pebbles were as large as\nCr\u00b0ssed h many \u00b0f the streams ran over fine white sand. The Bodcom must be\nb^a bridge of 100 feet span, with abutments 35 feet high, and there will","fullrs":{},"find":"2261.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2260","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"570350","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
