<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 22</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/578</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>578</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/578/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 22","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":";   \u25a0\u25a0t\u00bbi?7\nJH\nSOUTH-WESTERN J O RU N A L.\nIf \u25a0\u25a0'\u25a0\nKm \u25a0 \u25a0\nli \u25a0\nIff:;;\nw \u25a0\u25a0\u2022\n#\u25a0\u25a0\"\nM.-\nii\n#\u25a0\ni'\nii\nety winning example, as well ns the honied precepts of affection, of his duty to God, and his native reverence will spontaneously mount upward. You plant a sheet anchor in his\nsoul, through the power of which he shall be able lo ride out\nthe future storms of passion, and achieve the final moral conquest over the original obliquity of his nature.\nThere is not a ricfi, glad,.innocent, or brave feeling of the\nheart, but may bo appreciated and enjoyed almost by the\nyoungest child.\nA little boy near Hagarstown, in Maryland, was one day\npointing out to me a copse ol trees as the place where Washington, at the head of the Virginia rangers, fought a bailie\nlong before the war of the revolution with some Indians headed by French from Fort Duquesne, now Pittsburgh. The\nlittle fellow had seen some balls of lead that had been fired\nin that battle, chopped from ihe centres ofthe now massive and\naged oaks. I saw that the sunbeam of some sublime moral\nemotion was in his eyes, and I asked him further of Wash.\ning:on, the brave youth who led the Virginians into that\nthicket when the war whoop shook its boughs, and the rifle\nrung in its gloom.\nHis mind seemed to glance like lightning through the illustrious deeds of arms in which Washington had been engaged, and settled down at the closing scene of Yorktown.\nHe told me of one circumstance only. Said he, \"when the\nBritish troops were marched out of their entrenchments to\nlay down their arms, Washington told the American army,\n1 My boys, let there be no insults over a conquered foe ! when\nthey lay down their arms, don't huzza; posterity will huzza\nfor you.'\"\nI could have hugged the little hoy 10 my bosom. Although\nhe had not probably been able to rend more than four years,\nyet his mind hud drunk in the moral greatness of the act of\nsparing the feelings of a fallen foe. I asked him what it was\nthat Washington said, that posterity would do? he quickly\nanswered, hurra. Hurra! then, said I; and he sent his\nclear, wild shout inlo the battle wood, and 1 shouted with him\nHurra for Washington!\nAn important part of my subject is the Union that may\nand should exist between intellectual anel moral education.\nLike that holiest of earthly lies, what God hath so joined\ntogether, let not man put asunder. If in the ninety-seven\ncolleges in the United States and in the almost countless-High\nSchools and Academies which adorn, nnd fill iho count\nwore educated lo the noblest principles and emotions of our\nnature, as well as their heads stored with the treasures of the\nntellect. The ono course of education dooming its subject\no a fiery, erratic path, often eclipsed in tho gloom of infa-\nmy; the other so balancing the powers of the combined\nnan, as to secure him from the probabilities of uncertain\nate\u2014making him invulnerable to disgrace\u2014always superior\nto fortune\u2014as far above her sinilo as her frown\u2014like some\ntall mountain summit that hath grown up in altitude so neat\nthe stars that the thunder cloud forms far below its peak,\nwhere the calm sunbeams sleep, while all is tempest and\ngloom beneath. The union of the two powers forms Ihe\nperfect education,\nAn Education of terrific and destructive energy may be\nobtained by cultivating the Intellect alone. Such were the\neducations of Alexander, of Hannibal, and of Caesar, the Napoleon of Rome. An Education of great excellence (nay\nbe gained by an effort of the moral power only; a man may\nbe very pious, and yet have much ignorance; but the perfection of the power of Education is found in the trinity of its\ndevelopments\u2014physical, intellectual, moral!\nIntellectual Education, in its antithesis to Moral Education, is as the miner to the smeller of the ores; the one seeks\nthe quarry, rends ils strata, and finds the coarse gray metal\nthat has slumbered for thousands of years in the embraces of\nthe stone; the other causes the pure gold to flow out in a\nductile mass of richness and splendor, disconnected from ils\ndross, and fit for the crown of an empire;\u2014the one is the\npioneer that explores and runs the boundaries of a country,\nfixing upon the sites of its cities, and stretching ils map across\nrivers and mountains; the other is the husbandman, who caliches the soil with the waving harvests of plenty; the one\nis the advance guard, commencing and bringing on the skirmish\u2014then perhaps retreating; the other is the heavy column of battle that shall not waver under its heaviest thunders, or break into confusion before ils most fearful avalanches; the one is the white-capped surge, running broken and\nconfusedly before the chariots of tho storm; the oilier is tbe\nmountain wave, which pulsates from tho groaning bottom ol\ntho sea, rolling onward and stronger until it becomes a wall\nof power, that the dyke of God's invention, the sand beach,\nalone can withstand.\nThe one is tho (lash, the smoke, and the voice of the can\nnon; the other its noiseless messenger, that bears more lhan\nwo could feel assured that Moral and Intellectual Education\nwas plurning both its wings at the same moment in every\nbosom and in every brain, well might we rejoice and say of\nour beloved land, ihat its glory should be as perpetual as the\neverlasting hills.\nThere are in American Annuls, sad instances of tho education and power of the intellect, to the neglect of that of\nthe heart. Of these beacons of warning, the case of the\ntraitor Arnold Was one; the histories of Pierpont Edwards\nand Aaron Burr furnish others, while, on the other hand,\nthe shades of Washington, and Franklin, and Marshall, and\nWirt, with a countless multitude that come rushing on the\nmemory, furnish tho cheering contrast\u2014men whose hearts\nr.v', tho wrath of the thunderbolt on its wing; the one is the chill\nwinter, with its lustred snow-wreaths, its icicles pendent in\nOdin's halls in his northern palaces, its flashing keen-eyed\nstars\u2014but with its desolation and its chill; the other is tho\nverdant spring, with the breath of flowers and the song ol\nbirds, bearing on its green bosom tho hope of the year and\nthe promise of plenty. The one is thcoarth: tho other .3\nllic heaven of the soul!\nBiitTiu'LAOE of Columbus,\u2014The following is from a\nGenoa letter of recent date:\u2014\"Tho real locality of th\"\nbirthplace of Christopher Columbus has not been hitherto\nknown. The biographers of this illustrious navigator\u2014who\nall agree that he was born in the state of Genoa\u2014differ as","fullrs":{},"find":"579.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"578","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1777481","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
