<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 9</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2206</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2206</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2206/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 6, Page 9","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[9]\n\/ Ways and Means.\u2014-Peter Conrey, J. W. Stanton, B. S. Slatter.\nCo**tlt'* i{lirwell of Virginia, presented the following:\nMr.vV- M',T (\u2022 play and J. R. Anderson be substituted on the Standing Com-\nThat(-;e'i77il.sence of others from Virginia,\nmiitce. indw^wit      and liesoiations presented by Mr. H. W. Walter, of Mis-\nOn \"r*JSaSh instant, were adopted.\ni    vler of Arkansas, offered the following resolutions, which, on his mo-\n&gt;Ir* .^referred to the Committee on Routes.\ntion. were i       ^ this Convention approve of the line designated in the charter\n\u00a3fi Arkansas Central Rail-road Company\" as an important link in the general\nal system of the Southwestern states and of the Union.\na    Z ed  That this Convention recommend tbe several delegations in Congress\ntoe states represented here, to lend their countenance and aid in furthering\n{\"\"\"objects 0r tj]e accompanying memorial, and in consummating the grant of\nlands therein prayed for.\nResolved, That in the opinion of this Convention, it is not only proper but ne-\nJsary, in carrying out theprimary objects ofthe Convention, and in advancing the\nMwpenty ofthe States of Missouri, Arkansas. Texas and Louisiana, that said line\nof rail-road, from some poiut east of Little Rock, be extended to St. Louis, and\nfrom its southern terminus by one line through the State of Texas, and another to\nHaw-Orleans.    Referred.\nThe following resolutions, presented by Mr. John Ray, of ^Louisiana, were referred to the Committee on Routes.\nResolved, That the Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United\nStates, representing the states represented in this Convention, be requested to\nuse their exertions and influence to obtain from the United States a survey of the\nproposed railroad route from the Mississippi River via Shreveport, west, with a\nview to the relative advantage and practicability of this route as the eastern terminus ofthe contemplated Pacific Rail-road..\nResolved, That said Senators and Representatives be also requested to use their\nexertions and influence in obtaining the repeal of the duty on rail-road iron imported into the United States.\nA report relative to rail-roads in progress of construction and projected in Missouri, was presented by Mr. H. Chouteau, and on his motion referred to the same\ncommittee.    [Will be published in another place.]\nThe following, presented by Mr. John T. Mills, of Texas, was, on his motion,\nreferred to the same committee.\nleeohed. That the Committee on Routes be instructed to inquire into the\nt p\/act'?a^e. route, by rail-road, of connecting the northeast portion of Texas\nwith the Mississippi River, at some point below the city of Memphis, and report\nthereon.   Referred.\nThe following preamble and resolution, offered   by   Mr.  B.  B.  Simmes,  nf\nLouisiana, were, on his motion, referred to tbe same committee :\nconnt     u9 the'e exists iQ tllis Convention conflicting views as to that portion ot\nAnd7 \u00a3roa8ll.which tlie principal rail-road line westward should run\u2014\nhastily       r?as lt wou'd be imprudent in a matter of such magnitude to decide\ntherefor\u00b0P W''Il0Ut a ^ examination arjd survey of the different routes proposed ;\nofmemo'r'l' ?hiUna committee of five be appointed by the Chair for the purpose\nshall bet la,lzmo Congress to have appointed a board of engineers, whose duty it\nto the S\u00b0&gt; \u25a0 ermme ^e most practicable route for a rail-road from the Mississippi\nthrou-h T C' t0 imeet -tlle Great Western and Pa\u00b0ifio Kail road, as projected\nfl\u00bb the roi t^' tbat \" be ma(Ie tlie ^llty of 8\u00a3lid board of engineers to exam-\nf'ver-   ne\u00a3re\u00a7r\u00b0P0Sed throuSh Loilisiaiia at, and south of, the mouth of Red\nkis motion t'v. S' of\" Louisiana, presented the following resolutions, and, on\nfato!  j Wei'e reterred t0 the Committee on Routes.\nAbility and        l vS ^omm*tlee \u00b0n Routes be instructed to report upon the prac-\n*^ Parish i?p6i1ieilCy ofconnecting any rail-road from Texas with Shreveport,\n4v\u00b0yellea tn    baddo ; thence through the parishes of Nachitoches, Rapides and\n' w connect with the Opelousas Road at Washington.","fullrs":{},"find":"2207.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2206","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"539285","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
