<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/595</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>595</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/595/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:56">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"v? . ,,\n\u25a0if\n||\nA ft ' c'j\nlife\nfa\u00ab\u00bb': :\\-l\nIffi  \u25a0'\nfc'i\nI\nIS '     !\n|.\n\u25a0%    \u25a0\nw\n230\nSOUTH-WESTERN JORUNAL.\ni\ns\nW\ni\n1$\nI\nI\nii'i' -\nnia and New Mexico to this day, there are large villages of\nIndians surrounded by mud-built walls, as described by Lieutenant L. M. Pike, in his passage from Santa Fe to the\nUnited States. Those which have been forts or fortified\nplaces for troops in war, are comparatively lew in the south ;\nand when found, they arc generally in positions not easily\naccessible; or situated at some convenient point of communication. One of each kind we will briefly describe. The\nfirst is situated upon the plantation of Walter Irvin, Esq.,\nabout ten miles north-east from Natchez, and about seven\nmill s in a direct line from the Mississippi river. This is\nprobably one of the most remarkable works of tho kind to\nbe found in the south-west. It is situated upon an elevated\nsummit of ground, in the centre of an amphitheatre of hills,\nof the same elevation on all sides. From the base of the\nsummit upon which the works are situated, the ground has a\ngradual, but irregular and uneven descent for six or eight\nhundred yards, except on the cast, a narrow ridge extends\nfrom the base of the works to the hills at tho distance of half\na mile. This whole region is constituted of yellow clay, or\nloam; sand, gravel, or rock are not found near. The mound\nis very large, erected upon the summit by excavating around\nthe base, and carrying upon top: the excavation has been\nmuch more extensive at the west and east ends than at the\nsides, which face tho north and south. The extent of tho\nbase of the main mound is two hundred yards by one hundred and twenty yards, with an elevation of the main terrace\nof twenty-five or thirty-five feet, with an irregular outline,\nsomewhat similar to the salient angles of modern fortifications; these angles or projections are much larger on the\nsouth-west and north-west corners than elsewhere. The\narea upon the top, including the base of a super-tumulus upon Ihe west end, as well as one on the east end, is about three\nacres, while the area of the main mound around the base is\nlive acres. The greatest length of the base is two hundred\nyards, and of the top about one hundred and twenty yards.\nThe sides of the main mound are quite steep, being not more\nthan thirty-five or forty degrees from a perpendicular. Upon iho top of the main mound are six other mounds; ono\nlarge one on the west end, and another smaller on the east\nend; two smaller ones are situated upon the north side and\ntwo upon the south. The largest at its base covers an area\nof one fourth of an acre, while its level surface on top ofthe\nterrace is about one-third as much. This supertumulus has\nits western side or slope continuous with tho main mound,\nabove which it rises about forty or forty-five feet. From its\ntop down to the bottom of tho excavation at the west end, is\neighty feet. The mound upon the east end is similar to the\nwestern, but not one-fourth as large, having its eastern slope\ncontinuous with the side of tho main mound fifty feet to the\nexcavation below. Tho others are quite small, beinn- not\nmore than fifteen or twenty feet in diameter across the base,\nand not more than three or four feet high, although they have\nbeen much higher. Those on the north side are largest, and\nare not more than twenty feet apart, being situated on each\nside of a ravine from the terrace down to the base, which appears to be the remains of a covert way or entrance. Those\non tho south are more remote, but appear on each side of a\nsmaller ravine towards tho west of the south side, which also\nappears to have been likewise a covert way. The larger of\nthese covert ways appears to have entered near ihe centre of\nthe great terrace, through the body of the work; the other\nappears to have entered nearer the circumlerence, about two\nthirds of the distance towards the west end. On the north\nside, about fifty or sixty feet from the base of the mound\nthere appears to have been a large bastion to defend the entrance; a similar, but smaller one appears to have defended\nthe other entrance on the south-east. Close around the base\nof the mound, on all sides, there are the remains of a deep\nand wide ditch or fosse, part of which, fifteen years ago, contained water: but of late has become nearly level.\nThis has been a vast work, and probably combined in itself at the same time a fortress and a temple for tho worship of\nsome divinity, probably of the sun. The smaller supertumulus on the east end may have typified the rising sun; and the\nlarger one on the west may have typified the intensei light\nbefore he sank to rest behind the western hills. On these, as\naltars and high places, may have burned the sacred fire,\nwhich they worshipped as emanations from their divinity.\nHere too may have been the residence and the tombs of a\nlong line of kings, who once held dominion here; and here\ntoo may have been the seat of their power and the great\nsource of their religious rites and ceremonies. And, finally,\nthe whole may havo fallen in some desperate assault, and left\nits surface and out-works strewed with the bodies of its defenders, and with the implements of warfare, and the sacred\nemblems of their religion.\nWhatever may have been the use for which it was i: tended\nby tho original builders, it has evidently been a placeof grcat\nstrength against all kinds of military machinations, unaided\nby gunpowder and artillery. From either supertumulus ihe\neye could take in every object round for a mile', and surprise\nof course was impossible; the ascent on all sides made assault\nalmost impracticable, and exceedingly hazardous. Slill it\nmust have fallen by assault or strategem. Ils surface has\nbeen and even ye: is thickly strewn with human bones, and\nthe relics of implements of warfare and of art; which have\nbecome covered in part by the earthy detritus and rubbish.\nAbout this mound various remains of earthenware, and of\nimplements of warfare have been found, besides numerous\nskeletons. Some years since, the skeleton of an individual\nwho would have measured seven or eight feet high and large\nin proportion, was found here, upon the main mound. A\nmore recent examination resulted in the discovery of several\nskeletons of common size lying promiscuously on the top ol\nthe main mound near the western base of the eastern supertumulus. These were found within a few inches of the surface, where doubtless they had been covered by the detritus\nupon them. These skeletons exhibited such evidences of\ngreat antiquity, that they soon fell to pieces when exposed to\nthe air. One skull only with grcat care was preserved sufficiently entire to admit of a true drawing for an engraving.\nThis skull was decidedly of the \"flat-head,\" or compressed\nkind; the occiput being greatly compressed or elevated,\nwhile the parietal bones were proportionally full and elevated.\nBesides these, on the top of the eastern supertumulus, were","fullrs":{},"find":"596.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"595","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1794641","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.71 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
