<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/518</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>518</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/518/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\nThe posterity of men who had thus signalized and ado\n| their age, did them no disgrace.   Magellan, a Portuguese,\n157\nnspir\nthan\nships &lt;\nrincr to the fame of Columbus, sailed through the straits\niat still bear his name : nnd Europe saw wilh astonishment\nwhich had circumnavigated the world.    The telescope\n,.,-U produced\u2014watches were first made\u2014the variation of the\ncompass assigned\u2014and improvement extended even to the\nminor arts; skewers, which had been used by ladies, were\nbanished, and the common brass pin substituted in their stead.\nIt is a truth, that whatever improvements take place in the con\nditioaof men, originate with themselves; and all governments\nhave been found either to oppose, or only to yield slowly to\nthem. For teaching the true system ofthe world\u2014for the discovery of the secondary planets, the moons of Jupiter\u2014for\n-hoiving spots on the sun, the holy inquisition laid violent\nhands on Galileo, an immortal man ; and Ihe same government, that was forced by the times to establish in England, by\nact of Parliament, the book of common prayer, caused to be\nburned by the common hangman, tho books of astronomy and\ngeography, because they were infected with magic.    But the\npersecutions which were endured by philosophers from the\niiialice of princes, could neither rein nor stop the progress of\nknowledge.    Decimal arithmetic, with all ils advantages,\nwas promulgated, and soon after a Scotch Baron invented\nlogarithms; the thermometer made its appearance in Holland; and that maritime spirit which had doubled the Capes\nof South Africa and South America, already sought a northwest passage lo India, and projected a visit lo the north pole.\nHarvey discovered the circulation of the blood\u2014a discovery\nthai lias done more for the advancement of medical science\nthan almost all that prcdeded it.    Torricelli invented the\nbarometer, and proved that air possessed weight.   Huygens\ninvented the pendulum clock; Otto Guerick constructed the\nlirsl air pump, and exposed bodies to a vacuum.    The current of discovery was now fairly in motion\u2014scientific asso\nnations were springing up in every country; and had things\n\u2022till gone on in their usual  channel, the accumulation of\nknowledge would  have been great; but a propitious event\noccurred\u2014for at the close of 1642, Isaac Newton was born ;\n\" man whom God made, to comprehend his works.\nI might here expatiate at length on the consequent development of all parts of natural science, not only those cultivated by this groat man, but those too surveyed by his disciples. I might point your attention to the discovery they\nmade, of the system of the universe, how they weighed\nworlds, and told their distances and magnitudes. I might\n'\u2022escribe bow they effected the analysis of light, and gave us\n'be reflecting and achromatic telescopes; but time would fail\nme. I come, therefore, to confine myself more strictly to the\nbinits I have proposed, to examine whether the legacy of\nknowledge handed down has been improved. Science should\n\"cither stand still nor be on the decline, but progress forward,\n\"\"d push her conquests into the unexplored region of know-\n'edge. Hovy much greater are our inducements than those\n\u00b0f earlier philosophers ! Wc havo learned from their experience how vast a treasure we arc the guardians of\u2014a\ntreasure obtained by years of anxiety, thought and pain. Let\nw recollect how short the span  of life, and let us gather,\n i - -\u2014\nfrom what we i\nnow to consider, a fresh de\nforward on the stage of life, and has\ntermination to\nn but lo die; be comes\nis his day. Every moment the elements that are around him, contend with him for\nmastery, and solicit his destruction. Should he escape Ihe\nrepealed irruptions of disease, the years that pass slowly over\nhim wear him away; one by one, all his faculties leave him :\nbis animal life decays, and at last becomes extinct; his remaining functions are slowly and imperfectly performed.\nNature, always provident, takes from him the knowledge of\nhis end, or even makes that end desirable. I'he ties of his\nyouth are broken, the endearments of other times havo\nceased to exist, nnd the terrors that youth and health have\nplanted over the tomb, nre forgotten; the tranquil slumber\nof death comes calmly to close the troubles of life, and the\nold man sinks down in the lap of his mother earth, and quietly sleeps in her bosom. Then, seeing these things arc so,\net us resolve to discharge our duty to the future\u2014to transmit\nwhat we haverecived, not only unimpaired, but with an honorable increase.\u2014Southern Literary Messenger.\nVOYAGING ON THE MISSISSIPPI.\nThis morning we seemed lo bo lost among islands in a\nwaste of waters. The vastness of the river now began to\nbear upon our'imnginnlions. The flatboats we met seemed\nto be at the mercy of the floods, their long oars bending like\nstraws in the current. They are so picturesque, however,\nand there is something so fanciful in the canopy ol green\nboughs under which the floating voyagers repose during the\nheat of the day, that some of US proposed building a flat-boat\non the Ohio, and floating down to New Orleans at our U. i-\nsure.\nAdams fort, in the state of Mississippi, afforded the most\nbeautiful view wo had yet seen on the river. The swelling,\nhills, dropped with wood, closed in a reach ofthe waters, and\ngave them the appearance of a lake. White houses nestled\nin the clumps; goats, black and white, browsed on the points\nof the many hills ; nnd a perfect harmony of coloring dissolved the whole into something like a dream. This last\ncharm is as striking to us as any in the vast wilderness through\nwhich the \"Father of Waters\" takes his way. Even turbid floods, varying their hues with the changes of light and\nshadow, are a fit clement of the picture, and no one wishes;\nthem other than they are.\nI was on the lookout for alligators all the way up the river,\nbut could never see one. A deck passenger declared that a\nsmall specimen slipped offa log into tho water one day, when\nnobody else was looking; but his companions supposed that\nhe might be mistaken, as alligators are now rarely seen in\nthis region. Terrapins were very numerous, sometimes\nsunningthcmsclves on floatinglogs, and sometimesswiniming,\nwith only their pert little heads visible above water. Wood\npigeons might bo seen flitting in tho forest, when we were so\nclose under the- banks as to pry into the shades, and the beautiful blue-jay often gleamed before our eyes. No object was\nmore striking than the canoes which wo frequently saw, looking fearfully light and frail amid the strong current. The\nrower used a spoon-shaped paddle, nnd advanced with amassing\n\t\nm\n\u25a0'Mi\n\u25a0 *, H\nm\n-.1 \u2022-\u25a0\u2022:\u25a0\u25a0('\n-\u2022it t-\n\u25a0: V","fullrs":{},"find":"519.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"518","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1672928","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.60 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
