<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/386</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>386</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/386/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"j I\nSB\nS 0 U T II - W F, S T E UN JO U It N A L.\nKaM\nbut some years previous to this, in 170-1, the first American jStokes, and he commenced in Natchez, and continued for som\nnewspaper was established in Boston, called the \"Boston News time, the Mississippi Gazette on a fools cap sheet.   Thiswa\nLetter,\" which had an existence of 70 years, up to the dnwnin.\nof the American revolution, and was interrupted only by the\nclangor of arms and ihe rude British bayonet, then whetted\nfor the sanguinary charge upon Hunker's Hill.      Fifteen\nsometime in the summer of 17110 ; but he soon failed,\nAbout March or April 1803, a Mr. Green, from Baltimore\nbrought a press to Natchez. I do not recollect the title o\nhis paper; it ceased while I was at the north,  and the pres\nyears later than the origin ofthe \" News Letter,\" the Boston ft,)] into the hands of James Ferrall, who, with one Mofiatl\n(fazettomado ils appearance.    This was in 171!', and one day published a paper for n short time.\nlater, tho third American newspaper was printed in Philadel- I arrived from Philadelphia the lest of July 1802, nni\nphia, called the \"American Weekly Mercury.\" Six years commenced the Mississippi Herald, I think on the 20th Jul;\nafter, in 172.1, ihe firstpnper in New York city wascotnmen- 0f |]K. same year. I cannot conveniently lay my hand oi\nced, ami eleven years after that, the first papi r in Virginia.\u2014 the 1st volume; but send you, ns a specimen of the poverty o\nDuring tho succeeding fifty years, the newspapers in the colo- thoso days, a small file of 1803 and 1. 1 commenced on mc\nnies had increased to thirty five in number, and thus they met dimn, but was reduced, for want of paper, to cap.\nthe storm of ihe revolution, alter having been highly instru\nmental in arousing iho people of the colonies to the duty of\nasserting their rights and resorting lo the lost appeal.\n1 am yours, &amp;C,\nA ndiikw Maksciiai.k.\nI have not time, in a brief essay, to investigate the history o|\nBefore the revolution there had been sryn\\ Magazines or the newspaper end periodical press in the United Stales from\nPeriodicals in Philadelphia, and oncorlwo in New York.\u2014 yenrto pcar.since ihe period ofthe revolution; letmo rather\nIn mnking the distinction between periodicals and newspapers, touch upon the state of these branches of American literature\nI follow tho received practico of calling all thoso periodicals\nwhich arc issued in tho pamphlet or bonk form.ul regular intervals of time, generally exceeding n week. But it is n fact\nthat American periodicals nro the growth of,he Republic.\u2014\nThey cannot be traced to any perfection in the colonial days\nofthe country. With regard to ni wspnpers, it may be well li\nat the pit sent lime. The printed documents, to which I have\naccess for the statistics of my subject, wero compiled in 1834,\nthree years ago, and show the state of iho press at or near\nthat time.\nIn 1831 tin re were published in the State of Maine, 51 newspapers, including 2 daily, .besides 2 periodicals; in   New\nto notico our indebtedness to the Franklin family. The third Hampshire, 27 newspapers, 2 periodicals; in Vermont, 20\nBoston newspaper, \" The Ni w England &lt; lourant\" was edited newspapers, 1 periodical: in M:,.:s:i\"hiis'-tts, 108 newspapers,\nami printed by James Franklin, an older brother of I Ir, Frank- including 11 daily, besides 38 periodicals; in If bode Island, 10\nlin'.s. in whoso oflico tho Doctor learned ihe mystery of Faust, newspapers, 5 periodicals; in Connecticut, 38 newspapers,\nand in whoso columns ho plumed his youthful pen ns an un-8 periodicals; in New York, 240 newspapers, inch,-\nknown correspondent.    Tho Doctor was, afterwards, sole pro-ding 21 daily, besides 21 periodicals; in New Jersey, 35\nprietor and editor ofthe sei I newspaper published in Phil- newspapers, including2daily, besides2 periodicals ; in Pcnn-\niiilelphia, '\u2022 Tin- Pennsylvania (lazi lie,\" established by Sniii'l. sylvnnia, 185 newspapers, including 8 daily, besides 20 peri-\nKeimcr, The first daily newspaper in ihe United States oelicals; in Delaware, 4 newspapers; in Maryland, 35 news-\nwas printed in 1784, two years iiiii-r tho closo nl' the rcvo- papers, including 5daily, besides 8 periodicals; in Virginia,\nlutionary war. at Philadelphia; it was \"The American 11 newspapers, including 4 daily, besides 4 periodicals; in\nDaily Advertiser.\" The first newspaper published in the North Carolina, 22newspapers; in South Carolina,21 news-\nvalley of the .Mississippi was four years after tho revolutionn- papers, including 3 daily, besides il periodicals; in Georgia,\nry war, at Pittsburg, in 178G, called tho \"Pittsburg Gazette.\" 29 newspapers, 1 daily: in Alabama, 20 newspapers; in\nI'll-- following letter, received from the venerable Col. An- Mississippi, 7 newspapers, (at present time 20, including 4\ndrew Marstbalk, nl' Washington, in this c ity, who is the\nlather nl the typographical art in Mississippi, gives a succinct\nhistory of tin- earh press in ibis State:\u2014\nWashington, Sept. 2, 1837.\nI,. A. Besanoox, Esq.:\nI Ieab Sib;\u2014The first press in Mississippi was a smal\ndailies, besides 3 periodicals); in Louisiana, 15 newspapers,\nincluding G daily; in Tennessee, 20 newspapers, including\nI daily, besides 3 periodicals; in Kentucky, 25 newspapers,\nincluding2daily, besides 1 periodical; in Ohio, 140 newspapers.\nincluding 3 daily, besides 1 periodicals; in Indiana, 33 newspapers; Illinois, lo newspapers; in Missouri, 15 newspapers;\nmahogany en.-, brought by me from J ,ondon, in September, in I listrict of Columbia, 0 newspapers, including 2 daily, be-\n1,'ui    It was nut ,,1 my possession foi si, y,,n-s.    when skies 5 periodicals; in Michigan, 8 newspapers'; in Arkan-\ni..  ,I,..- i, 1,. ,.\\ , :  \/i  _  ns        \u2022 T-  ,. ' . '    '\ns, -I newspapers; in Florida, 5 nowspapers,\nordered in this (then) territory (1 was an officer iii the U, S,\nArmy) in ihe year '07, 08. J regained possession ni' it and\nobtained a small font of typ&lt;\u2014say 30 lbs.\u2014and whilo at the\nWalnut Hills, printed a ballad (tho Galley Slave.) Great\nexcitement was caused in Natchez by the knowledge nl a\npress being in iho country, nnd strong inducements wero held\nnut for me in remove lo thut place. Finally, 1 constructed a\nlarge press, capable of printing a fools cup sheet, and printed\nlb- territorial laws.    This press was sold by mc lo Ben. M.\nMaking u total in tho year 1831, of 1232 newspapers, of\nwhich 7-1 nrodaily papers, and 139 periodicals, Such has been\nrapid increase of newspapers during ihe threo years past,\nthai they may safely be rated at one hundred establishments\nevery year, making out a total which exceeds fifteen hundred\nin the United States at the present time.\nIt would be impossible to calculate, with certainty, the number of newspaper sheets printed in ti year in tho  United\n.X*~\u00bb'-'l\\J*?","fullrs":{},"find":"387.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"386","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1874569","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
