<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/403</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>403</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/403/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"\u2022 ' '\u2022\u25a0!\nijg\n't\nt\n|\n' ':'\n!R\n\/\nS o U T H-WESTERN J OURNAL.\ni    \u25a0\nYet smiles and tears and death make up the Past;\nIf not, the Present would forever last,\nStretch far along on Being's boundless plain,\nAnd nil would be Eternity again.\nThen let me, reverent, with uncovered head,\nUnrol the cerements that enshroud the dead,\nTo question voiceless tongues, now stiff and chill,\nAnd make the Past responsive lo my will,\nWill Science from her sacred altar here,\nWill cold philosophy, with smile severe,\nrjepulse a Lecture woven into verse ?\nIndued, a curtain lecture might be worse !\nBut, be not rash\u2014for verse is often prose,\nAnd poor at that, as every school-boy knows.\nIf sterner man shall turn in scorn away\nFrom fancy's sketch and pool's artless lay,\nStill there's a court of high and last appeal\u2014\nThe female heart has not forget to feel;\nThere, still has Poetry a queenly throne,\nAnd deems ihat blessed region\u2014all its own.\nFrom (he wide bosom ofthe shoreless Past\nDim shadows, from old mounds and temples cast,\nLoom into sight and vainly strive lo tell\nHow once they lived, and how, at last, they fell;\nAnd could not history one word inscribe\nOn the lone tomb-stone of a mighty tribe 1\nAnd were there leaves in Nature's volume none\nTo register the Children of the Sun,\nWhose thousands trod our ancient woodlands o'er.\nAnd reared their domes on Mississippi's shore?\nThey lived\u2014they loved! the warrior's mighty voice\n.Made the wild echoes of these woods rejoice,\nAnd song of virgin innocence uprose,\nSoft as Zophyrus in the evening blowi,\nAnd tunes teolian minstrelsy to sound,\nTill music quivers in the air around.\nThey worshipped, loo, in solemn temple's shude\ni Iroad with the shrines their own slrong hands had made\nHigh o'er the graven altar proudly shone\nThe Sun God flaming on his earthly thrpno ;\nWild was ihat worship, veiled in Persian riles,\nSuch fire as Zoroaster's pupil lights,\nAnd human sacrifice, as Baal demands,\nWas oft times offered up with bjoody hands;\nBut when the Song of Sacrifice rose clear\nAn angel harper might have paused lo hear\u2014\nSo soft\u2014yet loud\u2014a thousand tongues repeat\nTho Incas' litany, so wildly sweet:\n And this the Chaunt:\nTho Night hath charms,\nBut the day hath fire,\nAnd even at night,\nThe flame shoots higher!\nThe Moon is soft,\nBut the Sun is strong;\nIt rolls in power\nlis glory along.\nIt lights to war,\nIt blazes in battle,\nIt strengthens the brave,\nWhen arrows rattle.\nTo the Fire God, then,\nLift tho thunder roar,\u2014\nThe multitude voice\nOf Seas on the shore I\nLong years have passed, since first to yonder shore\nThe gallant ships of France her soldiers bore,\u2014\nSince Rosalie's stern frowning ramparts stood\nIn pride above the Mississippi's flood.\nTho lily banner threw ils virgin sheet\nOn gentle winds, with spicy fragrance sweet,\nAnd the deep cannon thundered the delight,\nOf warlike chevalier and courtly knight,\nTo see this glorious land\u2014ils Eden flowers\u2014\nIts olden forests\u2014its romantic bowers,\nAnd feel, with each successive brcalh they drew,\nSensations strange, unutterably now.\nA world so bright\u2014so lovely to the eye\u2014\nA balm upon ihe air like Italy\u2014\nA sky that deepened far and soft above,\nThe ocean element of Nature's love!\nOh, 'twas a splendid scene at night to view\nThe stars gaze elown the labyrinth ol'bluej\nLike eyes celestial, deep entranced to see\nSuch beauty thrown o'er hill and vole ami tree!\nBui hark! how solemn roars ihat nightly \"'in\nProclaiming weary day and duly done\u2014\nThen beats along the lines the reveille\u2014\nBtrange'Sounds were these to Indian chivalry!\nThe Children of the Sun drew near to scan\nThis proud and strange variety of man,\nMuch wondering, thinking that they came\nStrait from the Sun,\u2014inheritors of flame.\nBut Gallia's gallant sons, soon understood\nBy the fair moons, made ancient habit good,\nAnd breathed soft sighs in Indian maiden's ears,\nSmiled when she smiled, and gave her beads for tears,\nAnd swore, with many sacres, uttered well;\nHow passing fair was every Natchez belle !\nThin Natchez belles were beautiful, and spreael\nThe boars' oil unction thick from foot to head ;\nAnd then, to give the finish to their grace-,\nLaid gouts of paint upon tho glistening face ;\nOn ono cheek black\u2014upon the other green\u2014\nThe forehead red\u2014was e'er such beauty seen I\nRings in the cars and pendants in the nose,\n1\n\u00ab","fullrs":{},"find":"404.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"403","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1680797","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.60 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
