<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 20</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/576</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>576</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/576/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 20","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I--\n&amp;\n\u2122\"\nr\ntea,;\nSI\nIf,\ni\n.1;'''\nI\nM \u25a0\nI\nHI\nI'!\n\u25a0 :'\nH ,'i\n21:\nSOUT II -W E B T E R N   J 0 LI R N A L\ntual and moral power of education, Oo the studies of lan-l Once gazing upon a mound the dull outline fell thought\nguages and of the mathematics furnish the intellect with her lessly upon his eye; now he links its history lo Hie pyramid's\n-   do they lend a wide-felt power lo moral lo other years, anil lo mighty nations, that left these memori\nuls as land-marks on the shores of time to indicate that once\nbrightest arm\ninfluence, an I enter broadly into its constituents. Tho\ngrowlh of ihe heart, under such stirring sentiments, keeps\npace with the growth of thought.\nHut the power of intellectual education, may, perhaps, be\ncontemplated in its general effects on human character.\nTake the rude-shupcti, ungainly boy, from one of the mountain cottages of our laud\u2014a mere follower of the herd or\nIho plough -and lei but a spark of intellectual ambition fire\ntho magazine ol his coarse-clad bosom, and ho wends his\nway to some c ; , the bashful, sheepish, unmannered hoy\nofthe mountains; wi'h coat ofthe cut of his grandfather, and\nhair cut to th prim fashion of the round heads, or floating\nlong, lank and negligee' in a March wind. Every waggish\neye is turned upon him and kindled into mischief by his ex.\neeeding greenness, But, tread lightly, yo wags, upon his\nin may yet\u2014even in the shoit space\nus of power\u2014and ihat now\ntoes!\nof four\nunstead\nlellect,\nlege with an\nany, mc 0 Ihe\nlo peTsiiad -\nmental wen;\nthat have be\ni ies &lt;.',' long\nmiirhtV dead\nwith all that flashes from in\nai the matriculation and tin\nEntering col\n\u25a0)'\u2022   it wilh a tongue as i\n. .bo harp of Orpheus, and with\ne ireer of influence and fame,\nhis  iron grasp from tho anno-\nI lo may have talked with ihe\ntome imbued with their immor-\nhi :ii r his manners be polished\ntalsentimenl .    No , tal\nby inl i oi i\"   - ...       \u2022'\nof the gentility, ay \u2022. the  i\nhave undergonon wondorful change. Every line of his\ncountenance How expresses the action of mind. Lights and\nshades of thought, the \"gloom and the-glory\" of limey, the\nsolemn picturing ol imagination, and the thick coming visions of poetry come and go ovei th - expressive face that, but\nfour years since, was as passionless in its expression as the\ninert bayous whose currents have, not had time since the creation lo learn in what direction to flow.\nThis comparatively brief space of intellectual culture bus\nmade ono man to become a hundred in capacity of fooling,\nin knowledge and intellectual enjoyment. Every object that\nnow meets his eyes, once incapable of suggesting splendid\nstrains of association, i- now linked to something noble anel\nspirit-stirring in the past, iho present, or the future.\nSwimming across a frith or estuary, in the days of his unlettered boyhood, would not have been considered a matter of\nhigh achievement, nor would his soul have wanned'into.\nsome poetic frenzy, as ho dragged his chilled limbs, like a\nwc dog, up tho opposite bank: but now, doubtless, he would,\nunder similar circumstances, think at least of Jonah anel the\nwhnle, if not of the swimming race, the two water-snakes\nthat coiled round Laocoon and his two boys, had from Ti ne-\ndos to the plain before Troy, and to the passage of Leander\nacross the Hellespont, borne up by a lover's hope anel a lover's ardor.\nthey too lived and panted for immortality.\nThe action of his intellect is now like that of a powerful\nanel well-fiitiil mass of machinery\u2014with judgment ns a bub\nlance wheel, and radiant fancy ns the fly wheels, all set in\nharmonious motion by the propulsion of burning thought.\nPope's stanza may will be adapted (o the action of a cultivated intellect: \"Lives through all life and operates unspent.\" The engine thus set in motion, and thus endowed\nwith super-human power, must roll on in ceaseless action\nthrough the term of human life\u2014and onward still until tin,\nsoul, that cannot grow old, shall wax mighty in the immortality of its energies, and tho perfection of ils developments.\nLike a ship of wonder, borne over the \"sea of gla:-s,\" ihat\nwells out from tho foot of that throne where sils llie TIncre.\nated Thought, so shall this revolving intellect sail in the rye\nof heaven, approaching nearer and nearer to ihe Unapproachable, and burning brighter and brighter with the fires of tbe\nUnconsumable, until lhc eestacy of earth shall be forgotten.\n amidst tho intellectual profusions of heaven\u2014-or remembered\ninly to, and never tried upon only as the starling point of being\u2014the twilight of eternity\nisieal dimly resting on the bosom of the thick darkness thai preceded the birth of the soul.\nNol only every hour of life, but even tho dreary hour ol\ndeath, has a strange and high excitement to the cultivated in-\ntcllect, The poet's thought, \"thou shalt lie down with patriarchs and kings,\" comes rolling upon his intellect, which\ncalmly contemplates tho ruin of tho body, and philosophizes\nr not, ho is now possessed on each new and strange sensation which invades the ciladel\ny of intellect. His features of his being,' as the outwork*, ono by one, are taken by the\nlast enemy. What hurried thoughts then range through all\ntime, striving from the past to forestall the future, and anticipate doom !    .\nIt is said of one who fell from a height with the full expectation of being dashed into eternity on his reaching the\nearth, but who was providentially saved, that, during bis\nfoil\u2014the brief second of time in which he passed from the\nsummit of a steeple to tho ground\u2014he found time to review\nevery principal event of his life, lo sigh out his farewells to\nouch dear friend of his heart, to calculate his prospects for\neither heaven or hell, anel to throw himself with an inexpressible energy upon the merits of the Great Sacrifice. From\nthe long and dreamless sleep of insensibility, ho awoke\u2014\nnot in either of the two worlds whose dreadful shadows\nstretched, like dragon wings, over this eclipse of bis being\u2014\nbut in this world, nnd lived to tell the Inst thoughts of earth,\nas his soul was on wing for the shores of immortality.\nIntellect is an Enchanter. Long years after loved friends\nare entombed, the wand of memory waves over the'chill\nvaults of the sepulchre, and tho dead start into life I Pn'e,\npurified, spiritual, passionless as the seraphs, their sweet\nfaces beam again upon us. Tho fragrance of their spirit-\nbreath, stirs in our time-bleached locks. Their thrilliaj\nkisses are again on our lips. With their spirits, our spin's\nagain mingle in a better fraternity of feeling   than ever","fullrs":{},"find":"577.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"576","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1825229","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
