<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 18</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2243</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2243</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2243/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 18","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[18]\nAdmitted upon the Amazon with their boats, our people wo Li\ndesire to participate there in what is called with us \" the river trada!*\nfor considering that the habits ofthe Amazonians are not at all aqnaf'\nit is not by any means probable, that Brazilian enterprise would r*\nsufficient to supply the boats and boatmen requisite for this jjv\"'\ntrade.   She cannot do it now.\nBut are we prepared to let Brazilian capital, and Brazilian subjects\ncompete with our own people for the business\u2014the river trade\u20140(\nour own Mississippi waters % We should ask nothing of Brazil which\nwe are not willing to render to Brazil. Are we prepared, therefore,\nto offer to admit Brazilian subjects to an equal participation with our\nown citizens, ofthe trade ofthe Mississippi River, -on condition that\nshe will admit our citizens to an equal participation with her own\nsubjects in the river-trade ofthe Amazon and its tributaries?\nThat is the question as to which I desire to draw an expression of\nopinion from the Convention, because I believe that that opinion,\nbeing regarded as the opinion of the people of the Mississippi valley,\nwould have a bearing upon the subject, as one of a practical nature,\nand of paramount importance.\nSuppose that the XJnited States should declare, that the citizens\nand subjects of all nations should have the same rights to build and\nlaunch boats on the Mississippi River that our people have; that the\nright to take freight from one landing or town to another, and to\ntrade up and down the river, should be as perfect and as complete te\nthe foreigner of whatever nation, as it is to the American citizen\u2014\n\u25a0what would be the effect %\nSuch a surrendering of the \" coasting trade,\" as the river-trade\nmay be properly called, might possibly induce a few foreigners to\nsend over their capital and build boats. But these boats, to compete with our own boats, would have to be manned by our own\nwatermen\u2014officered by our own people. And such a law, therefore,\nmight interfere with American owners.\nBut, instead of such a privilege being offered to all nations, suppose it were offered only to Brazil, in exchange for like privileges to\nour own citizens upon her rivers\u2014what would be the result then?\nWhy, this: Brazil has not even the energy among her own subjects\nto put boats upon her own rivers, where they have the monopoly o\ntrade and navigation ; much less would her subjects have the enterprise to come here and put boats upon the Mississippi, to run\ncompetition with our own.    On the  other hand, we, who have JJ|\nenterprise, the energy, the  skill in  boat-building, would, with\nknowledge, over all the world, which we have  in steamboat rrv\nnavigation, go  to   the  Amazon, and  enjoy there something hW\npractical monopoly.    For it is not to be supposed that, if wc &lt;*'\ndivide our Mississippi River trade with her subjects, on con*\nthat she will make a like division to us of her Amazonian trade\u2014'\nnot, such being the conditions, to be supposed, I say, that any \u00b0\nnation would  on  either  side  be admitted  into   the arranger^\nThere is  but  one Mississippi River, and but one Amazon, &gt;n","fullrs":{},"find":"2244.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2243","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"571732","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
