<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/554</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>554</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/554/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 15","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\n191\nmounds and of this skull are in preparation, and will bo in-\n,,rtC[l iu some future number of the South-Western Journal,\nwilh the scientific measurements, taken by Professor Fofshey,\nifcompanied by notes anel explanations.\nThe skeletons, seen in position, were thoso of common\nline, one or two exhibiting a length of bone that may have\nbelonged to a person six feet in height,\nNear the centre of the parallelogram of tho foundation\nmound, there is an appearance of what has been supposed to\nhave been a covered way from the base of the mound (perhaps from the fosse) nearly to the centre. It is now grown\nup with tiees, and has the appearance of a deep gulf worn\nby the water. Gentlemen who examined this chasm, fifteen\nor twenty years since, were firm in the belief that it had\nbeen a subterranean passage. The longer chasm from the\nnorth side of the mound is approached by a similar one, although shorter, from the southern side.\nIt was most pleasing to an investigating mind, to witness\nthe deep interest exhibited by the gentlemen who composed\nthe party of exploration to tho mound. The subject of In\ndian antiquities is one connected with important results, and\nnone are so capable of giving duo attention to the subject, as\nthose who reside in the vicinity of such remains of by-gone\nyears. These explorations should ever be made a matter ol\nrecord, and be conducted aseorollaries to, anel in the full light\nof, the modern discoveries of the stupendous remains ofanti\nnuity in South America. As the antiquities of Palenquc arc\nbut the presumptive radiations of art from the southern shores\nof the Mediterranean, bearing affinity to Carthaginian architecture; as Carthage was built by the colonies that emigrated\nfrom Phoenicia, at the eastern end of the Mediterranean, that\nfavored spot where both human .nature and science were\nnursed in the infancy of the world;\u2014as Mexico, with her\nstill remarkable antiquities, may be but a radiation from Pa-\nlenque in Central America; and as the vale of the Mississippi may have been colonized by the Incas and C'nziques of\nMexico,\u2014the results of antiquarian researches may connect\nthe old world to the new in the history of antiquity, and\nmake the discovery of our continent, three centuries ago, only a return to shores on which the ancestors of Hannibal, and\nthe gold merchants ol Solomon might have often met in traffic\nTHE CANNIBAL'S RETURN.\nMr. Woodworth, who sailed to the South Seas, with the\ncelebrated Captain Morrell, in his late unfortunate expedition,\nhas furnished tho Sunday Morning News, with an extract\nfrom his journal, describing tho return of Sunday, one of\nthe cannibals brought home in the Antarctic, some years\nsince. Wo extract the narrative, as disclosing many traits of\nnative, unsophisticated character.\n\"After keeping Sunday in his family for more than two\nyears, teaching him to speak and read English, Captain Mor-\nrel caused him to embark with him in tho Margaret Oakley.\non the Oth day of March, 1834, with the intention of restoring him to his home and his country, of which he was a chief\nof some note, at the time of his captivity. After touching nt\ntho Capede Vcrd Islands and the Isle of France, the Margaret Oakley made Sunday's Island on the 20th of November,\nin sight of which tho brig became sudib nly becalmed.\nCORRESPONDENCE.\nLBTrrn from Uio Librarian of llic American  Antiquarian Society, In Massachusetts, to tliej Kelilur of (lie Soulh-Western Journal.\n, , Worcester, Mass., May 10, 1838.\nG- V. H, Fohdes, Esa.\nBear Sir,\u2014In behalf of the American Antiquarian Society, I\nwould acknowledge; their obligations to you for the gift of nine\nnumbers of the South-Western Journal. Tho progress of\nscience and literature at the West, is a subject of peculiar\ninterest, and it is gratifying to receive such favorable speci-\nm''iis of the public spirit and talent which will ensure its rapid advancement. It is to be hoped that Southern and Wes-\n'c\"i Antiquities will have a fair share of consideration in\nyour Journal, as much that is important and interesting might\nundoubtedly be developed by the attention of persons so well\nsituated and qualified for a scientific investigation of them.\nVery respectfully, your obedient servant,\nSam'l F. Haven., Librarian Am. Ant. Sociely,\nK X T 11 A O T F HOI \"THE JOURNAL.\"\n\"As we approached the latitude of Sunday's island, the\npoor fellow's anxiety anel impatience became painfully intense. During the ten days we were cruising in ils neighborhood, he could scarcely cat or sleep, and while it was daylight, was continually aloft, looking out for land\u2014most generally in the slings of the fore topsail yard, leaning with his\nback-against the topmast crosstrecs, in which position 1 have\nknown him to sit for four hours, steadily gazing on the horizon ahead, and apparently absorbed in deep mi dilation ;\u2014\nand he would announce \" a sail,\" \" land,\" \" green water,\" or\na \"canoe coming oft]\" long before we could see the same objects from deck, with our best glasses. We finally made his\nisland early in the morning, before he had yet left his berth ;\nand when Captain Morrell told him that his island was in\nsight, he started from his bunk\u2014which was the top out of\nthree in the cabin\u2014and fell prostrate on the floor, being in u\nsound sleep, having turned in but one hour previous. After\nrecovering himself in some measure from the sudden surprise, and rubbing his eyes, he exclaimed, in his broken English\u2014\"What for you loo much afoul, Captain. Morrell?\nYou. no see my island! and suppose me. no see my island, me\nno like you too much I\" With this speech, he instantly came\nupon deck. It was a beautiful morning, and almost a perfect\ncalm. The smooth sea shone like a polished mirror, and\nthe sun was just peeping above the horizon. I think it was\none of the finest mornings that I had ever seen, which is saying much, after a cruise in the Indian Ocean, in the month\nof Octob 'i-, a vernal season in this latitude. A ruin squall\nhad just subsided, leaving the decks wet, and the morning air\ncool and refreshing. The rigging was studded with sparkling drops of dew and rain, which shone like pearls and diamonds in the light of the rising sun, and gave the shrouds\nmdslaysa most imposing appearance; and, as that splendid\nluminary attained a greater elevation, the atmosphere in the\nvicinity of land,became thick and cloudy, with the evaporation from the recent shower, and the heavy dews which invariably prevail in these latitudes. But the morning mists\nwere soon dispersed by agendo breeze, and unveiled to our\nview tho beauties of this \"land of promise\"\u2014the goal for\nwhich we had so long toiled was now in sight, and tho mo-\n\u25a0\u2022\u25a0 ;\u25a0' i\n\/\nA","fullrs":{},"find":"555.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"554","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1694858","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.62 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
