<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/548</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>548</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/548/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nCharlotte left the room, her feet were in tho warm bath, anel\n\u2022bain tears; but gave Mother no satisfaction when she re-\npeatedly asked of her tho cause.\"\nAlary had scarcely finished speaking, when, in the most\nmelancholy strain of voice, the following stanzas reached our\ncats:\n\" I-, there some spirit sighing,\nWilli sorrow in ihe air,\nCan weary hearts be dying,\nVain love repining there 1\nIf nol, then how can that wild wall,\nOsad jEuli.ui lyr :l\nHe drawn forth by ihe wand'rlng gale.\nBy thy deep-thrilling wire?\n\" No, no! thou dost not narrow\nThat sadness from the wind,\nKor arc those tones of sorrow\nIn thee, O harp, enshrined!\nBut in our own hearts deeply sei,\nLies llic true quivering lyre,\nWhence love, and memory, and regret.\nWake answers from thy wire.\"\n\" Good Heavens I \" cried Mary, \" 'lis Clara I Doctor Melmoth, can ibis bo the premonition of returning sense, or is\nihat doleful melody but another maniacal ebullition from my\npoor sister?\" The affectionate girl burst into tears, as I\nell her \"it was one of the singular phenomena that attended\nHysteria.\" \" Your sister's mind and feelings,\" I continued,\n'have received a severe and unexpected shock-; her whole\nnervous system is disordered, anel being of a full habit and\ntanguine tempi rament, this singular affection is the result. 1\nwish, however, the united efforts of you all, to aid me in re\nSoring Clara's health nnd intellect, and as soon as I attend to\nher immediate want of medical assistance, I hope you will\ncorrectly observe the line of conduct I shall lay down, to be:\nexercised towards Clara, and very soon, perhaps, we may\nwitness ils salutary eflect.\" I left the sitting room and crossing the hall, entered the apartment of my patient, finding her\nin tears, and sobbing most pitifully, whilst the alleviating cf-\nfals of her kind mother were being exercised to assuage her\ndiseased grii f. She was in a silting posture upon the bedside; herleet were immersed in a vase of warm water, and,\n'villi her fnce buried in her hands, she wept, without noticing\nmy approach.\nI bowed to the mother, and asked Clara how she was. She\nstarted upon hearing my voice-, and seemed astonished that I\nMd found my way to her bjd-sidc unobserved. \" 1 am very\n\"ell,\" she replied, \" but why make the enquiry? I have but\na slight head-achol \" Without answering, I fell her pulse,\n\"10, finding it somewhat quick and irritable, I asked her if\n'no would allow mo to take some blood from her arm; adding\n'hit il would relieve her head.\n\" \u00a5es I yes! \" she quickly replied; \" but\u2014b\u2014bul you must\nwt take too much!\"\n\"I will do as you wish,\" I rejoined, and having bound up\n''\u00ab arm, I let about eight ounce's of blood, with the injunction\n185\nand, immediately after ii, to administer a moderate dose of\ncamphor. She appeared quite rational after blood-letting,\nand satisfied that nothing more was needed nt the time, I was\nabout to leave tho room, when Clara observed enquiringly,\n\u2014\"You will return to the Lodge to-morrow morning?\"\n\"At ten o'clock I will be here,\" I replied, and bid her \"gocel\nevening.\" I found i|\u201e- re mninder of th, family in the sitting\nroom, anxious to know my opinion of Clara's illness, and\nhaving \"told a flattering tale,\" requested \"that she should\nnol be bit alone; that c.he orfulness and a li, Iy t mo el' conversation must be observed by every one ol the familyin her\npresence, and that occasion-illy readingaloud to h 'r something\nlight and amusing would hive a very beneficial tendency!\nIndeed, every thing calculated to di.vert her mind from the\npainful cause of her uni ashen . was, in her present nervous\ncondition, necessary to prevent a return of paroxvsms.\" I\nagain left the Lodge, pleas .1 with the prospect of affording\nimmediate relief to my patient.\nI  returned next day at the appointed  hour, found Clara\n\u25a0.- cnair\n, np]  ar III\nPerryan i'&gt;\ncomfortably ensconced in\nversation with the family ra\ni lurking melancholy, un ; i\nthrough the efforts she mad\ninduced me to advise Colon\nlo the South, as business colled him\nthat novelty and change of sci n wei\nrevolution in her pi- -, nt train of ti\nthat she should accompi ny him ; and\nbeing necessary to corn cl ne] rous il i\nfortnight I had ceased visiting Clan\nafternoon, shortly afterwards at I\ncd a nolo upon the table (-&gt; my addre\nthe seal, read as follows:\n[coul\n111.I pi\nI ne\nDu. Melmoth:\ni in d. This\nher wiib him\nLouisiana, urging,\nleci ssary to produce\nrhts. Itwasagrced\noccasional visit only\nility, at the enil of a\n!'\"!;. ther, when ono\n,- y office, tperceiv-\nand having broken\n, Monday.\nwith etiquette for a young lady\n'. in: i; upon a subject so delicate\npini ss w \u25a0-\u25a0 involved ami an apol*\nYou will excuse me, however,\nircumstances\nained (luring\nid\n\"Hit she must remain quietly in bed till morning. Upon en\nm\"ry, I found her digestive organs much impaired, and having prescribed a corrective, I ordered pediluvium at bed-time,\nIt is not in accordance\nlo address a  nolo to a gel\nas ihe one in which my ha\nogy is therefore due you.\nwhen I inform you, that your knowled\nrelating to a subject of importance ti mc\nmy illness, has induced me to request the pleasure of your\nompany this evening nt  ihe Lodge, that 1 may have some\nconversation with you, relative t-.i the matter.\nWith considerations of esteem,\nYours respectfully,\nCi.aha Pkuiiyan.\nTo Dr. Melmoth.\nThis unexpected summons surprised mo; and being then\n3 o'clock, P. M., I jumped into a cab, and drove to tho\nLodge, unable lo divine the result of this interview. My\narrival was anticipati d, us i one of ihe family seemed surprised at my visit, but, on tho contrary, Mary, as if by previous\nunderstanding, showed ino directly in ('lira's apartment.\nAs Madam Perryan and myself entered alone, 1 was met by\nmy interesting patient, wilh a smile and u cordial shake ol tho\nhand, when, after some commonplace remarks, her mother\nleft tho room.    I noticed that Clara had siiiforcel much from\nt V\nr.","fullrs":{},"find":"549.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"548","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1908301","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.82 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
