<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 18</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2215</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2215</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2215/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 18","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[18]\nroad should be built on tressel-work, through the Lafourche swamp, through Bayoj\nMacon and Tensas swamps, a distance which I cannot venture to name without an actual\nsurvey.\n'* But this necessity results from the direction of the route, which is at right angles to\nthe trend of the alluvial planes, and hence across the drainage. Continuous embankment*\ncannot be constructed without manifest injury to the drainage of the country.\n\"Tressel-work, for elevations of 3 to 6 feet, would increase the minimum cost of th,\nroad about 20 per cent, per mile, for the number of miles so constructed. It is a vague\nestimate, but I suppose that S50,000 would be a sufficient sum to meet this contingency.\n\"According to this estimate, it may be assumed in general terms, that\n180 miles, rail-road track, culverts and stations     1,800,000\n8 bridges, first and second class       350,000\n20 miles tressel-work, &amp;c         50,000\nTotal probable cost of tbe road \u00a92,200,000\n\" I must beg, my dear sir, that you will take these as crude opinions, based upon a very\ngood knowledge ofthe country, true, but without any surveys upon the route you designate; and I would not be willing to have these opinions arrayed against any others\nresulting from careful surveys in the future, made by myself or other competent\nengineers.\n\" Very faithfully your obedient servant,\n\u2022   \u2022 \" Caleb G. Forshet,\n\"Civil Engineer.\"\nThe government of the United States is interested in a most direct and unmistakable\nmanner in the construction of this road.    Its treaty stipulations with Mexico, and its obit\nf;ations to protect its own citizens, require a line of military posts to be kept up on llie\nrentiers of Texas and Mexico. Five regiments of soldiers are now stationed upon these\nlines, and the number will probably be increased this winter to eight. The transportation\nof supplies to these stations will make a heavy drain upon the treasury of the United\nStates, and rentier indispensable a considerable increase in the appropriations for the\narmy. From data furnished the undersigned from reliable sources, they have been\nenabled to form such estimates as to place it beyond doubt, that the mere freight and\ntransportation of supplies to these stations will cost the government more than a million ol\ndollars annually. We are aware that this statement will startle persons unacquainted\nwith the difficulties of the country. But the estimate is below the actual cost. The\nSecretary of War mentions that more than forty dollars has been paid on the transportation of a barrel of flour. In one instance the government engaged a man to haul supplies\nfrom St. Antonio to El Pa30. at \u00a31G 50, who threw up the contract as a bad bargain.\nThere are other ways in which the federal government will be profited.   With the\nfacilities which the road would afford for concentrating her forces, the country may giTe\nits citizens a far more efficient protection with a reduced number of soldiers.    Indeed,*\"\nrail-road would develop a population which, in a few year3,would supersede the necessity\nof keeping up these stations at all.    This was the effect in our own state of opening w\nnavigation of Red River.    More than this, the same population would become consumers\nof imported goods, paying duty, aud thus the road will augment the revenue of ihe g\u00b0?el*\nment, at the same time that it lessens its expenditures.    The people along this r\u00b0\u2122 *v\nalive to the subject.    Enthusiastic meetings have been held in many of the parislie\nnorthern Louisiana, and the counties mentioned in Texas, in all of which the people\npassed resolutions in favor of its immediate construction.    In addition, large convent-\nhave been held in Shreveport, Monroe, Marshall, and Palestine, in which delegates\npresenting quite a number of parishes and counties have conferred, and united in 6\"'\nexpression to the public sentiment.    Such is the state of feeling upon tbe subject,   ^^\nprivate citizens have offered to donate a portion of their land to secure the building0   .\nroad.    In submitting this report, the undersigned would conclude, it by recommend''1?\nconstruction of this road, as important to a numerous people, inhabiting a large and e* ^\nsive region of country, prolific in sources of wealth, situated in northern \u25a0^?u's,)^gW.\nmiddle, western, northern, and eastern Texas.    That it is important to tbe city of -\nOrleans, as opening a channel through which she may secure to herself almost the ci   ^\ntrade of the country in question\u2014a trade which  at present amounts to severa1 m\u00bb \"Jj\nand which is susceptible of au indefinite increase.    The interest which the uniler.-\u2122^\nfeels upon this subject induces a pause here\u2014to observe that the position w''     ..^risl\nOrleans  now occupies, in regard to this  trade, is one of peril.    Unless some m^.\nmeans be devised to facilitate and cheapen transportation to and from that portion  ^et\ncountry lying  west of Shreveport,  its  entire trade will  soon  be  diverted into\nchannels.","fullrs":{},"find":"2216.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2215","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"651847","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.62 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
