<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/402</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>402</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/402/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n37\ns they\nce to\nopin-\nprrs-\n'nt or-\nmpar-\nose of\nt then\nal ev-\nrhtus\nresort\nency.\n\u25a0eflcc-\nlinate\nts for\ncason\nappli-\nmost\ni, by\nthat\ner of\nf the\ngreat\ne de.\nlatch\n-rup-\nion u\n:pen-\n.e ef\nitilit\nUnit.\nafter\nthe\nmay\n\u25a0ated\nmay\nents\nalso\ni, on\nlory\nrem\n&gt;mi-\nnol\nrusher\nrely\n\u25a0 re-\nREPORT\nlip tub Doaiid selected and Invited liy (lie Faculty to attend tho-anmial examination of ,leflernon College, on tho 7th and 8th of August, 1837.\nTo -run Ficl-i.tv, the President and Processors:\nGentlemen:\u2014Agreeably to the invitation so politely extended to us, the undersigned were in attendance, more or\nless, during the days'of College Examination, designated in\nthe official notice, and by comparing and collating the obser-\n\" -. vations which we individually made, are happy to present the\nfollowing report as tho result:\u2014\nDividing the studies embraced in the examination, into the\n\u00bb    Preparatory, Classical and  Mathematical Departments, we\n\u25a0 shall proceed to notice them in course:   The examination of\n.   students in the primary studies under the charge of Professor\n\u25a0    Van Hoesen, although a brief and limited one, exhibited a\n\u2022 *\u25a0   close and critical attention on the part of their teacher (and a\n\"    corresponding improvement on the part of the students) in\ngrounding them in the earliest and elementary principles of\nI:     education.    Of a course so important to the welfare of every\n\\ literary institution, this gentleman seemed fully aware, and\nr\"  the success of his exertions appeared, to the Board, to be fully\nproved by the proficiency of his pupils, the evident result of\nI   \u25a0    the united energies and perseverance of both the teacher and\ntho taught.\nr-' Tho Latin Classes, under the charge of Professor Wyche\nwere examined in Ctesar's Commentaries, in the Bucolics and\njEneid of Virgil, and in tho Odes and Satires of Horace,\nThese several exercises wore strict and searching, as the portions selected for examination were generally the more diffi-\n\u2022 cult passages and calculated to test the improvement of the\nstudents. We take pleasure in expressing our unanimous\nopinion, that tho Latin classes exhibited a proficiency highly\ncreditable to themselves and to tho critical method of instruction pursued in tho College. The younger class in Cesser's\nCommentaries went through their examination with entire\nsatisfaction to the Board. The translations from Virgil and\nHorace evinced a clear conception of the meaning ofthe au\nthors, expressed with ease and fluency, and with a due regard\nto the idioms of ihe original language. If there were any\ndeficiency, it was in a knowledge of syntax. In their examination on the hexameter verse of Virgil and Horace the slu-\n\u00bb ' dents exhibited a good knowledge of the rules of prosody\nand scanning\u2014belter, perhaps, than in the irregular verse of\nihe Odes of Horace, the latter being more difficult of mastery than the former. Their pronunciation of the Latin was\nparticularly pleasing and correct.\nTho Greek Class, under Professor Wyche, was examined\nfrom Gracca Majora, in selections from Herodotus, and acquitted themselves respectably in tho translation, with some\ndefect of fluency in reading; but, as a whole, the Greek\n\u2022 examination was creditable to all concerned. The class had\nbut recently taken up Graeca Majora, and were consequently\nnot so familiar with the reading (we do not now refer to trans \u2022\nlaticn) of tho eleler Greek authors: Indeed, it requires con.\nsiderablo practice in reading the Greek to attain an easy,\n\u2022   rapid, flowing enunciation of that rich and sonorous language.\n\"'   In taking leave of the classical department, the Bonrd of Ex.\namination cannot but recommend a constant recurrence to the\n; -'  grammar and tho elementary principles of bolh ihe Latin and\n-.\nGreek languages by the student, even after he shall have commenced the reading of the higher authors, as the only sure\nbasis for a deep and enduring knowledge ofthe learned languages. The memory cannot be too frequently tasked with\ntheir rules, exceptions, the variations and elementnry idioms.\nThe examination of the students in the Mathematical Department, in charge of Professor Forshey, reflected much\ncredit on that gentleman's capability and method of instruction. They were examined in algebra, geometry, trigonometry, nnd surveying, and exhibited, in a good degree of perfection, the power of retaining in mind and connecting the various\nsteps in any given problem, while conducting them, consecutively, to the final demonstralion. The Board of Examination\nfeel fully satisfied that the instructions in this department have\nbeen close, searching, deeply scientific, as well as practical.\nAlthough the mode of tuition is similar to that pursued by\nthe mathematical classes in the celebrated West Point Institution, yet the Board feel a pleasure in saying, that its best\nrecommenelation, in their opinion, stands in the improvement\nof the students who have had the advantage of Professor For-\nshey's accurate and skilful instructions.\nIn conclusion, the Board of Examinatibn congratulate the\nFaculty of Jefferson College on the successful progress of\ntheir experiment in favor of southern collegiate education\u2014a\nsubject as dear to State pride and patriotism as to science and\nliterature.\nThe Committee feel the more confident that the institution\nwill hereafter justify the anticipations of its friends, inasmuch\nas President Dubuisson has now returned and will be able to\nexert an active supervision over the different classes in college\nfrom which ho was prevented, during the most part of las,\nsession, by his absence and the illness of his family-\nRespectfully, your ob't serv'ts,\nTuos. Akmat,\nJno. M. Hubbaro,\nWm. P. Mellen,\nG. V. H. FonBEs,\nS. S. FABnieitiE,\nSam'l C. Mekwin.\nH, L. Conjioii.\nWashington, August 9, 1817.\nA POETIC FRAGMENT.\nEntitled Iho \"Past and Present,\" read hyMr. C. V. II. Forbes, before tuo, J\u00abf\nfcrson College and Washington Lyceum, on fcalurdny Jan, 0,1838.\nThe Past! where arc its voices\u2014where its halls\u2014\nWhere all that hath been in its storied walls\u2014\nWhere all its forms of beauty passing fair %\nLone echo wakes, and only answers\u2014Where !\nYet man felt then as every man feels now,\nSuch joys lit up, such sorrows gloomed his brow,\nAnd every heart, now frosted in the tomb,\nFelt, as we feel, the dread of coming doom ;\nIt was to them a bitter thing to die,\nTo take a long farewell of earth and sky,\nSend from this world the darkened thoughts away\nThrough sunless dungeons, shorn of life's sweet ray,\nAnd feel the shadows ofthe world unknown\nFall on the soul, and freeze tho heartto stone","fullrs":{},"find":"403.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"402","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1692005","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.61 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
