<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
      <title>Donn Young Photographs</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate"
        authority="naf"
        authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
        valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
        displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
     <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
     <role>
        <roleTerm type="text"
                  authority="marcrelator"
                  authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                  valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
     </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">&lt;p&gt;Donn Young began his professional photographer's life over 30 years ago. His work has appeared in Time, Newsweek, the New York Times, and many other publications. In addition to his studio and commercial work, he became the official photographer of the Port of New Orleans in 1996.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Donn's entire life's work was in his Lakeview studio and home when the flood waters of Hurricane Katrina rose in 2005. Unreachable for weeks, his home and studio were submerged, drained, and submerged again, with the collection left to mold and ruin in a witches' brew of brackish water, sewage, petroleum products, and other compounds while efforts to drain the city got underway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The LSU Libraries Special Collections managed to salvage 32,645 images portraying a wide range of images from New Orleans, Louisiana, and beyond. Images include people, art, music, theater, plants, food, buildings, views, manners and customs, religion and culture, education, medicine, business, industry and transportation, Associations and Institutions, Publications, sports, and portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">&lt;p&gt;Photographs by New Orleans photographer, Donn Young, salvaged from his Lakeview home after Hurricane Katrina.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-sc-dyp</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Search)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/search/collection/LSU_DYP</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Landing Page)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/LSU_DYP</identifier>
</mods>
