<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 24</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2221</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2221</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2221/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 24","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[24]\n7th. That passing through the populous, fertile, and productive parishes of Enst R ^\nRouge, aud East Feliciana, in Louisiana, and the county of Amite, Mississippi, each m*i\u00b0\nof the road would produce revenue as soon as it is constructed.\n8th. That the inhabitants ofthe parishes of East Baton Rouge and East Feliciana will\npromptly and cheerfully contribute a sum sufficient to construct such road fj\"\u2122\u00ab \u25a0\nborders, the evidence of which is the fact that, after the adjournment of the Convenri\nheld in April last, near one hundrbd thousand dollars was subscribed by the inhabit^\nof Baton Rouge and its vicinity in three days, and no doubt thrice that amount can readib\nbe obtained, should the road take the course indicated.\n9th. That there being no obstruction to navigation between the cities of New-0r]eu,\nand Baton Rouge at any season ofthe year, the passengers and the produce of die conn,\nties through which a road is proposed to pass, would at all times reach the great\u2122\nmercial metropolis of tbe South-west without detention, and without any additionaJer.\npeuse.\n10th. That the difference in distance between the route passing to the west of bait\nMaurepas and that passing by the city of Baton Rouge, will not exceed twenty rai!ea,and\nthe expense of construction will not exceed that of the shorter lines.\nOne other view, we conceive, may with propriety be presented to your consideration.\nBy taking the route wc propose, the road will reach a point on the River Mississippioppo.\nsite the Bayou LaFourche, and from thence may be constructed the great road leading\nthrough the parishes situate on that Bayou, and thence through the counties of Attakapu\nand Opelousas to the Sabine River, at such point as may meet the desires of Texas. By\nso doing we will avoid the interruptions that may occur by breaches in the levee on the\nwest bank of the river below the Lafourche, and save the expense of constructing many\nmiles of road. If to this it is objected, that all passengers and freights must be transported\nacross the river at Don aid son ville, the reply is, that if the road is continued on the west\nbank of the river to Algiers, still you must cross it to reach New-Orleans, and the expense\nand delay of crossing at tbe one point cannot be greater than at the other. W e all concede that New-Orleans is, and of necessity must be, the great commercial mart ofilu\nSouth-west and West. We do not, therefore, seek to supplant her\u2014we seek to enter into\nno invidious rivalry with her, but we do seek to conduce as much as possible to her\nadvancement, considering that by so doing we advocate our own best interests.\nTherefore be it resolved,\n1st. That the Committee on Routes be instructed to take the said route into consideration,\nand report thereon.\n2d. That in the opinion of this Convention it is of vital importance to construct nroadlij\nwhich the River Mississippi can be reached at a point, between which and the city \u00ab\nNew-Orleans there are no obstructions to navigation, and which would insure a safe,\nspeedy, and cheap transportation of passengers and products to the city of New-OrlesM\nat all seasons ofthe year, and without danger of delay from inundations of the alarm\ncountry, by tbe breaking of levees, or the opening ofthe Bayou Mancbac.\n3d. That it will be tbe true policy ofthe state of Louisiana and of the city of Ne*-\nOrleans to construct the proposed rail-road through a country, practicable, populous, fertile, and wealthy, rather than through a difficult, sparsely-populated, and unprodocO'\npart of the country, even although the  distance and   expense may  be somewhat in-\neased.\nRespectfully submitted on behalf of the delegation from East Baton Rouge, by\nThomas GiuiiEs Morga*-\nMISSISSIPPI ROUTES.\nThe undersigned begs leave to submit to the General Committee on Rou&amp;\nlowing report in support ofthe resolutions offered by him to the Convention in r';'y7--\na system of railway running from the city of New-Orleans through  the State of sa\nsippi.\u2014It  cannot  be doubted,   that   the   system  proposed  bv   the   resohii-io\ncompleted,   would not only   be   of incalculable  benefit  to   the   citizens  of M&gt;-3* ^\nand   Louisiana,   but would  also   afford   to the   city   of New-Orleans  a full\nplete communication with all the rail-roads east ofthe Mississippi River., *.ral unsigned believes that he cannot do greater justice to the present condition and gen     ^\nportance of the Brandon and Montgomery Rail-road, than was done it in a rep\u00b0    pg,\nupon the subject, by a delegation of the citizens of Vicksburg, at tbe ii. R      , ^jfifl*\nheld in this city in April last.    That delegation stated,  '-that this road i* t0Ae,XifuBa\u00abw\nJackson, Mississippi, to Montgomery, and will connect at  Selma with the A    ''tempi*]\nTennessee River Rail-road, by which, and the roads now under coutract, and m c\u00b0 ^.i*\"\"\ntion, a continuous railway communication will be opened through Tennessee, Ken &lt;  Q$sP\nOhio, with the lakes ; and through Tennessee and Virginia, with tbe Atlantic an","fullrs":{},"find":"2222.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2221","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"550483","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.52 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
