<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/471</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>471</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/471/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\n08\nSOUT II - W E S T E B N JOU R N A L.\n\u25a0\\'W\n','$'\u25a0'\n\u25a0 ' e     i\nflVf\n'&lt;&lt;   ii'\nr\nll'llifej\ni' ,.\nm\npasses off rapidly into vapor; and a much lower temperature\nis retpiired to condense this vapor again into water. To eflect\nihis, it must be reduced ton temperature but littieaboveonelhird\nof that which has been nccessary.to convert it into steam; and\nby reducing the temperature to one-half of the last, it becomes\nsolid. Somewhat similar may it not be with the miasm of\nyellow fever? It seems to require a temperature of 120\u00b0 in\nihe sun, or 88\u00b0 or 90\u00b0 in the shade, to generate it; although\nit is destroyed by a temperature as low as 50\u00b0.\nWe suppose this miasm innocuous, when uncombintd, because we find during the hotti st weather in cities, when the\nthermometer at mid-day ranges between 90\u00b0 and 95\" in the\nshade, there will be no yellow fever, while the air is sufficiently agitated with winds to carry off the air which has been\nfreely respired, and is freely charged with exhalations from\nliving bodies: for, although the miasm may be generating\nrapidly at such times, there is no tendency towards yellow\nlever, until the air becomes stagnant, and often respired, and\ncharged with animal exhalations: when it seems to acquire\nnew properties and new virulence. We know that but a\na short time In fore nn epidemic begins to prevail, the most\nperfect health often prevails among those who become the\nfust victims; although, at other times, cases of common bilious\nremittents are the harbingers of the epidemic. The hitter,\nwc believe, occurs only after much hot, damp weather, and\ntic former after hot and dry weather.\nWe suppose that this miasm is not morbific per sc; that it\nseparates itself from pure, free air, nnd settles to tho lowest\nplaces; but that it combines actively with impure air, especially such as has been frequently respired; and thus it becomes a more active cause of disease. When thus combined,\nwe call it malaria or infectious air; and in this Mate it is a\npredisposing cause of disease, as well as a suitable nidus for\ninfection, In this infectious air, infection will spread, and\nyellow fever may be disseminated among the people, by exciting causes of a mild kind, or without any. Winn thus combined with contaminated air, it becomes more volatile than\nbefore, and diffuses itself more generally in the atmosphere,\nalthough it is still heavier than common air, and remains\nabout those places which collect and retain the miasm.\nII. Infectious Ant or Malaria. This combination,\nwhen not concentrated, or v. hen n.oeh rait Iy diluted with free\nair, conveysa very slight predisposition to yellow fever: but\nwhen concentrated by close, sultry weather, in a dense population, ihe predisposition will bo so strong that sporadic cases,\nunder highly exciting causes, will occur; especially among\nstrangers, and those who are unaccliinated. Those who are\nacclimated escape. If many sporadic cases occur, wo may\ninfertile existence of malaria or infectious air, and without a\nchange in tho weather, such^as a reduction of temperature',\nwinds, or a rain-storm, we may expect yellow fever to become\nepidemic. Each case appeals to haste n on the e pidi mic, as if\nit wero by imparting some deleterious property to the impure\nair at different points, and thus forming finally a fermentative\ncoalescence. If several of tin se sporadic cases occur in the\nsame vicinity, as it will do if there he many unacclimuted\nforeigners together, tin; disease will begin to spread from thai\npoint.    Others who are unacclimateel, will be attacked without\nany highly exciting cause, and finally without any excitino\ncause except the infectious air about them, which has gradually become infected. When the air becomes highly inficteei,\nit appeals to be more volatile and in some manner diffusej\nItself more readily than when in the form of miasm alonf|\nor even of malaria, and it doubtless does possess the power of\nextending or reproducing itself.\nTho impure air, which unites with miasm, and forms the\ninfectious air, which is the proper basis for receiving and t\\.\ntending the infection, is dependent, we think, chiefly upon the\neffects produced upon common air at a high temperature, by\nrespiration and animal exhalations, especially from human\nbodies. This prepares it for the union with miasm. Thus\nfrom miasm the first degree of contamination is effected In\nexhalations from healthy bodies in a high temperature; tha\nsecond by the accumulated exhalations from bodies laboriiif\nunder high grades of yellow fever; or, by a much greater\nconcentration ofthe morbific properties, which appears to lake\nplace after, but not before the sporadic cases occur.\nOur reasons for believing that respiration and cutaneous\nexhalations effect the morbid change in the air, to form malaria, are principally as follows:\n1. Thnt sultry weather is always necessary lo produce\nmalaria, and to cause yellow fever to spread when infected air\nhas been introduced, I have in no case found yellow fever\nto become epidemic at any place shortly after it had been thoroughly swept out by a storm, unless in cases whore infected\nuir had been previously generated and retained in the houses.\nStagnant air, when exhausted by men and animals, is as destructive to health and life in them, as stagnant water is lo\nfish, when overstocked. Running water always affords a\nchange for fish; and in the large masses of water, they\nchange their places in it. So with air, where from the confined situation of a city or district, or from the nature of ihe\nbuildings and enclosures, or from a general and protracted\nstagnation of the atmosphere, the air is not sufficiently renewed, it becomes more or less morbific, by being breathed\nrepeatedly and charged with animal exhalations.\n2. When there are sufficient winds to sweep out the avenues and streets of cities frequently during summer, there ii\nmi yellow fever generated as an epidemic, although the actual heat, as indicated by the thermometer, may beat least three\nor four degrees higher, than it is in sultry weather, when\nyellow fever begins. This is confirmed by the history of\nevery epidemic yellow fever which we have been able to \u00ab\u25a0\namine, either in the United States or the West Indies.\n3. We know that yellow fever, during our epidemics, prevails especially along the margins of the large and deep ravines or bayoux, which originate around the city, and spread;\nmostly in the space embraced in the declivities towards the.\"'\nravines. The miasm sctth s in them at till times; and the ait\ncontaminated by exhalations and respirations of the contiguous population, in sultry, calm weather, settles in these declivities, and the infectious air becomes more concentrated neat\nthe margins of the ravines, and especially in their channels.\nGentle breezes, after a long, sultry, calm spell, will sweep\nover the tups of ihe houses and points of ihe hills, but will\nnot sweep out these bayoux; at most they will agitate str1","fullrs":{},"find":"472.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"471","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1805679","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
