<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 01</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/540</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>540</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/540/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 01","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n,.,,,\u201e,. \u00bb.\u00abi. \u00bb^i\u00bb... .nit. D-\".m^v^nn^j^T^rn;. .\u201e, \u00bb.\u00ab\u201e.\u201e.\u201e \u201e\u201e\u201e,\nI N T 11 II   9 V I. V A S\nsvAn i: m i o u a: r i; h k\nNATCHEZ, MAY 30, 1838.\nNO.  18.\nEXTIIAOTS   FROM   A   I.EOTUUE   ON   THE\nPHILOSOPHY  OF  THE LAW,\n(.,.I before Iho Washington Lyceum, Dee. 2d, 1837, by J. S. n. Tiucunn, Esq.\nIt is hazarding a charge of rashness, and, perhaps, of presumption, to attempt to treat, within tho limits of a lecture, a\nlabject ihat might well store and enrieha volume, and to bring\nto tho task inferior abilities, which should fully engage the\nbest efforts of minds of the first class. There are, then, two\nprominent reasons for a want of confidence, which, with the\ncharily of a liberal audience, must serve ns an apology for\n1   in?, anil my treatment of the subject.\nA popular prejudice has over existed against the science of\nthe law, and its professors have freely shared in the unfavorable prepossession.    At best, many view it and them, only as\nnecessary evils.    Nor is the world wholly without excuse.\nAntiquity, though it lends a sanctity, has added a degree of\nmystery to some ofthe early principles of the art, which,\nivbile it augments the toil of the sincere student, offers to the\nill-designing a medium of mischievous misconstruction.    It\nis one feature of total ignorance seldom to doubt or hesitate,\nand as accident sometimes guides it right, it has, at. least, the\nmerit of promptness; but uncertainty, and even error, on ac-\nf.iiint of the unfortunate conflict of learned opinions, are as\nfrequently found in the companionship of knowledge as of\nignorance.   Thus credulity is many times more philosophical than skepticism.    -'A little   knowledge,\"   it has been\nsail, \"is a dangerous thing.\"   Dangerous to a well-balanced\nmind,because it produces ambiguity;\u2014to ono imperfectly\ncultivated, because it renders it presumptuous.    All those extremes are so many pitfalls in which many lawyers find a\ngrave betimes, while the unprofessional man of plain, com\nmon sense looks carelessly ai tin' mole-hill which tho micro\n\u2022topic eyo of the jurist magnifies into a mountain,\nMi,1 science of the law is compelled to combat more physical obstacles.    The obscurity, which envelops many of its\nprimitive elements, is mainly caused by tho use of an antique\n\u2022''\"l peculiar phraseology in treatises on ihe subject.    The\nWcient writers sought more to be practically understood than\n'' be praised   for the elegance of  their style nnd diction,\n\u00abud, therefore, used tho most familiar words, at the period, in\nWgue, many 0f which, at this day, are obsolete, or their interpretation changed,    Hero is, then, a mass of mechanical labor nnd confusion productive of much  loss of time upon\nmatters merely technical.    A more modern, and a still more\nfist objection arises from the multiplicity of books which fills\nH\" library ,.f the lawyer, and draws largely on his industry.\n\"he ingenuity of litigation has surrounded him with innumerable treatises and voluminous \"reports of cases\" from\nwhose \"distinctions without differences\" have grown the\nrn:lny subleties which are the parents of the delay and uncer-\nlainlyof the Law.\nh will be pardoned, 1 trust, if before pursuing the main ob\nject of this lecture, your attention is called to a few observations upon some of these objections, which, it must be confessed, have nn unfavorable nspecl, nnd if I essay lo rescue my\nprofession from an unmerited reproach arising more from misapprehension than fact.\nA prime fault with many is the procrastination, or as it has\nbeen bitterly called, \"the glorious uncertainty of the law.\"\nThe impediments in the way of a satisfactory conclusion in\na subject almost wholly speculative in its character, originate\nIrom the natural distrust that must accompany the examination,\nthat, in its elucidation, has no help fiom matters of fact.    So\nmuch are we governed by palpable evidences, that a demonstrated theory, although tolhe full as triie.neverobtninsthe confidence that is derived from a practical exemplification.   The\nlaw's delay, therefore, is a corollary of its uncertainly. There\nis a conflict of mind, and the demonstration, like a principle\nin religion or morals, is a matter of intellectual strife.    And\nhere a chief obstruction occurs in the imperfection and barrenness of language.    Men's thoughts do not differ so much\nas their words, and most honest men, when they come to understand each other, and rightly to  interpret each other's\nviews, are of one mind.    Most differences are only verbal.\nClod formed our minds, but he suffered us to construct our\nlanguage.    All   languages, in common with  human inventions, are defective, and ihe more modern, they are the less\npure, borrowing sometimes from all which have preceded, until, like our own, they become a motley of the rest.    Again,\na fancy for a now-mid unauthorized coinage of words, peculiar to the literary character of our times, nnd especially of\nour country, is fast accumulating intellectual confusion for\niterary posterity.    Purity of style may abandon hope, when\neach one, at will, can usurp the prerogative of Adam in Paradise, and give a new name lo every thing \"in the Heaven's\nabove, the earth beneath, and  the waters under the earth.\"\nThis is the reason why, for so long a period, all legal knowledge was couched in the Latin tongue : This is a language of\nchaste, classic difiniteness, and great comprehensiveness, and\nfrom being exclusively the property of the learned, less exposed to the foislerings of vulgar ignoiancc.    Nor  is the\nancient English less deserving of commendation.    There are\nmany rich old words and phrases, which can bo lound preserved only in a dusty wink on law or philosophy, that are\nworth all the new-fangled terms that over fashion had the impudence lo impose upon a civilized literature.    They are the\nbone and muscle of a healthy language, and unlike their eha-\nmelion successors, they have bul ono interpretation, which,\nat once, is particular and universal.    Who docs not venerate\nthe noble phraseology of tho Bible,\u2014the very majesty  of\nanguage !    Independent of other claims to his respect, tho\nscholar owes it much for having preserved a purity of mcan-\nincr to many terms of natural objects, without which ihe anchor\nf literature, language, would longago havo drifted into moro\n&lt;i *?$\ni\"    I .\n\/\\","fullrs":{},"find":"541.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"540","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1820500","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
