<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/395</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>395</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/395/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:55">{"title":"Page 17","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S O U T 11 - VV E S T E It N .1 0 tl R N A I\n31\n,S   Yes:   it is also employed ill eilttinglimber ililo lengths?\nP. N it lengths A thing cannot be said to have been cut\ninto lengths.\nS. Into shortnesses.\nP, Very right: what are the mechanical laws of ihe\nhammer?\nGovernor. We have just received intelligence that dinner\nis nearly readyjand as tho medical class is yet lobe examined,\nlet the medical gentlemen therefore come forward.\nANATOMV.\n\/'.   What is a s;.lt-bo\\ &gt;\n,'v   It is a body composed of wood, glue, nails, and hinges.\n\/'.  How is this body divided.\nS.  Into external and internal,\n\/&gt;   Vcrygood: external and internal; very proper: and\nwhat are the external parts of a sal,-box?\n,','. One fun lamental, four literals, and one superlateral.\nP. An! hv.vdo you find the internal parts of a salt-box?\ns Divided by a vertical membrane or partition into two\nlarge cavities or sinuses,\nP. A re- these cavities always equal ?\nS. Tln-y used to be so formerly; but modern joiners have\nfound it best to have them unequal, for the more convenieii\naccommodation of the viscera, or contents: tho larger cavity\nfor the reception of the coarser viscera, and the smaller for\ntlie line.\nP. Vory true, sir: thus have modern joiners, by their\nimprovements, excelled tho first makers of salt-boxes.\u2014Tell\nm \u25a0 iniw, what peculiarity do you observe in the superlateral\nmember of (he salt-box ?\nS. Whereas nil the oilier members are fixed and stationary\nwith respect to each other, the superlateral is moveable on a\npair of hinges.\n\/'. To what purpose is it so constructed ?\nS. For the admission, retention, anil emission of the saline\nparticles.\nGovernor. This is sufficient.     Let us proceed to\nSUROERV   AND   Till:   PRACTICE OF   PHYSIC.\n\/'. Mention a few of the disorders to which a salt-box is\nliable.\nS. A cracked and leaky fundamental; gaping of the joints\nin the lateral; taxation of the hinges; and an accession and\nconcretion of filth and foulness, external nnd internal.\n\/'. Very well. How would you treat these disorders 1\u2014\nBegin with the first.\nS. I would caulk the leaky fundamental wilh pledgets of\nlow, which 1 would secure in the fissuro by a strip of linen\nor paper pasted over. For tho starting lateral points, 1 would\nadminister powerful astringents, such nstho gluten comuosa,\nnnd would bind lb\" parts together by triple bandages, until\nthe joints should knit.\n\/'.   Would you nol assist with chalybeate.*?\nS. I would all tcA'th \u25a0 disease with prepared iron, in doses\nproportioned to the strength of the parts.\n\/'.  How would you manage ihe luxation of ihe hinges?\nS. 1 would first ovnnine whether it was occasion, d by the\nstarting ofthe points which annex the processes to the superolateral or ils antagonist; or by a loss of tho fulcrum ; or by an\nabsolute fracture of ihe sutures. In the first case, 1 would su'\ncure the process by a screw; in the second, I would bring the\nsutures together, nnd introduce die fulcrum ; and in the last, I\nwould entirely remove the fractured hinge.and supply its place,\npro tempore, with one of leather.\n\/'. Very well, sir; very well. Now for your treatment\nin case of accumulated foulness, external and internal.\u2014But\nfirst tell me how ibis foulness is contracted,\n8. Externally, by ihe greasy hands of the cook ; and internally, by the solutions nnd adhesion of the saline particles,\n\/'. Very true; and now for the cure.\nS. I would first evacuate the abdominal vessel, through\niho prima via. I would then exhibit detergents and diluents;\nsuch us the saponacious preparation, with plenty of aqua\nfonlana.\nP.  Would not at\/un cmlestis answer better?\nS. Yes: plenty of aqua ea\/estiswilh the marine sand. I\nwould also apply ihe friction brush, with a brisk and strong\nhand, until the excrcmentitious concreto should be totally dissolved and removed,\n\/'. Very proper.   What next?\nS. I won hi use the cold bath by means of a common pump.\nI would then apply lintal absorbents; and, finally, exsiccate\nthe body by exposition , either in the sun, or before the culinary or kitchen lire.\n\/'. In what situation would you leave the superlateral valve\nduring the exsiccating operation ?\nS. I would leave it opm to the extent, in order that the ra-\nrilieil humidities might escape from the abdominal cavities or\nsinuses.\n( IIYMISTin.\nP. You have mentioned the saponaceous preparation : how\nis that prociii't .1 I\nS. By the action of a vegetable alkaline salt upon a pin-\nguidinous or unctuous substance.\n\/'.  What is salt?\n,S. It is u substanco sui generis, pungent to the taste, of an\nantiseptic quality ; and is produci tl by crystallization, or the\nevaporation ofthe fluid in which it is suspended.\n\/'.  How many kinds of sail occur in a salt-box ?\nS. Two: coarse nnd line.\nP. You have said that the saponaceous preparation is pro-\ncurcd by the action of an alkaline sail upon a pinguidinous or\nunctuous substance.    Describe (he process.\nS. I f u ''-rent quantity of strong ley ho. procured by passing\nwater throne ii tho wood-nshes, and if a very large body of a\npinguidinous habit should be immersed in this ley, and exposed lo a considerable heat, ihe action ofthe ley, or rather of\nthe salts with which it abounds, upon the pinguidinous body,\nwould cause tho mixture to coagulate into soap.\nNotice was given ut this instant that the dinner was on the\ntable: the examination was concluded, and the parties separated; the examiners rejoicing in the anticipation of a feast, and\nthe examined happy in finding the fiery trial over.\nSeize the opportunity.\u2014A man has as much time al-\nowed him in this life lo do good, as a pearl-diver to seize his\npearls.\naues\nnasB","fullrs":{},"find":"396.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"395","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1836018","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
