<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/572</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>572</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/572/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"IS\nmy\n:\u25a0 i\n\u2022\u25a0:\nKfii\n\"'\/.v\nis\nm\n\u25a0\n\u25a0\n\u2022\u25a0\u25a0ei\n203\nSOUTH -WE S T E R N   J 0 U R N A L .\nfour men, two women and five children; at Wniolama and\nIlaima, a woman and child were drowned ; nl K'nuwale one\nwoman lost her life. 'The amount of eb.n.uge done has nol\nyet been ascertained, nor is it l.nown how many limes the\nsea rose and fell. There was no shock of an earthquake\nfelt at Hilo, or elsewhere, although it is ascertained that the\nvalcanoof Kilauea was unusually distuibed the previous\nevening, the fires were suddenly quenched, and yawning\nchasms bins: open in previously tranquil places, accompnnii d\nwith violent explosions. Inquiries have been made of masters of vessels who were to the rtottll and to the east of the\nislands on ihe 7th, at various distencts Lut-ncne el them noticed any thing unusual in the sea orntmospllt le.    'J bat this\ncommit this audacious plagiarism, his feelings were touched\nhis In art relented, his anger melted away like wax, Ho\nwent to him ngain, and said, 'Sir, you did very wrong, and\nyou know it, to appropriate to your own use and benefit thn\nfruit of my labors. But 1 understand you arc poor, and\nhave a family to suppott. 1 feel for yon, and will help yon\nThat plan is unfinished, and contains errors ihat would have\ndisgraced you nnd me had it been published in the statu in\nwhich you found il. I'll tell you what I will do, I will fur-\nnish ihe plan; I will correct the errors; and then you shall\npublish it lor your own benefit, and I will head the subscription list with my name.\"\n\" What a sublime, noble, Christian spirit was theremoni\napparent submarine volcanic action has taken place at some festcd !    'This was really overcoming evil wilh good, and\npouring coals of fire upon the poor man's head. The natural leeling ol resentment, which God has implanted within\nall bosoms for our protection against sudden essanlt ondinjti.\ndistance from ihe islands is proved by ihe wave stiiking the\ndifferent islands simultaneously and apparently in lhc same\ndirection; but at what distance we have no means at present\nof determining.    Perhaps tho internal fires have- found anew I ry, was overruled and conquered by the higher, ihe sovereign\nvent, which may be laying the foundation of a new group of principles of conscience.\"\nislands in our neighborhood.    Il is now nineteen years and\na half since a similar phenomenon occurred here, but not so\nviolently as the last, nor was it alt, nded with anv loss of life.\nOn the second .lav after, an affecting seine was witnessed \u2122s praiseworthy Society has been organized, and the in-\nat Wailuku, (.Maui.) The bodies that bad been recovered cl&gt;ent stePs tnl{en for ,ts immediate commencement and per-\nfrom the sea were conveved together to the church, followed ma\u00bb[''\" continuance; and we cannot I ut congratulate the cili-\n\u25a0    COLUMBUS SOCIETY\nroit tiii: acquisition aso diffusion of knowledge,\nby a great multitude; a funeral sermon was preached en the\noccasion; this solemn warning made a deep, nnd it is to be\nhoped, a lasting impression en these who witnessed it, of the\nuncertain tenure by which we hold our lives.\nHawaiian Spectator.\nDr. Bowditch.\u2014We have before us a discourse on the\nlife and character of Or. Bowditch, by tho Rev. Alexander\nyoung, of Boston. We had thought that the wo,Id had\nnothing to learn of the intelh dual greatness of this eminent\nmathematician, but this discourse heightens our respect for\nhis talents, by showing us with what little aid, and in the face\nof what difli.'ultios his large attainments were made.     Ol\nthe moral excellence of his character, a variety of delightful taste for knowledge, may, in its pursuit, shun the thousand\nzens of Columbus, in view of the beneficial effects it will\ncertainly exert upon our moral, social nnci intellectual culture. It is not expected of the members of the members of\nthe society to become teachers of the public; but, 1 y on interchange of sentiment on the subjects of Science, Literature,\nEducation, and Morality, they may learn of each oilier, imbibe n taste for study and reflection, and diffuse their concentrated knowledge lo all;\u2014and, more then nil that,\u2014to cultivate social feeling and to acquire a lasle for the more refined\nanel virtuous enjoyments of life. 'The Society is not exclusive- ; old and young, male and female, are invited to pnitici-\npate in ils benefits, to tile end that the present generation\njinny become better, and the rising generation, by ncquhinga\ntraits nre related in this discourse-, which ^c cemmond to our\nreaders as one of the most interesting anif instructive compositions ofthe kind that we renumber to nave reed. We give\nthe following sample:\ntemptations which beset their path on every side, and loin-\nfuse into all that spirit of noble emulation. Similar institutions are springing up i.i various pails of ihe Union, bavin\"\nfor their object the elevation of the standard of morality, and\n\"Dr. Bowditch had born preparing a plan of the town of!cl'l'at'n= a distaste for the thousand vicious enjoyments, which\nSalem, which he intended soon to publish.    It had been the lum' l0 debase and destroy every vestige of morality and virtue\n'Tiie Columbus Society, having purely in view the good of\nfruit of much labor and care. By some means or other, an\nindividual in the town had surreptitiously got possession of\nit, and had the audacity to issue pioposals lo publish it as his\nown. This was too much for Dr. Bowditch to bear, llein-\nStanlly went to the prison, and hurst out in the following\nstrain: 'Yon villain I how dare you do this? What do von\nmean by it? If you presume lo proceed any farther in this\nbusiness, I will prosecute you lo tho utmost extent ofthe law.'\nThe poor fellow cowered before the storm of his indignation,\nand was silent; for his wrath was terrible. Or. Bowditch\nwent home and slept on it; and ihe next day, hearing from\nsome authentic source, that the man was extremely poor, and\nhad probably been driven by the necessities of his family to\nthe public, by providing the. means and place where ruticnal\namusement and useful knowledge may be obtained and imparted, cannot, we think-, but receive tho hearty support of\nour citizens; and we soon hope to see the Society so fiouri.-h-\ning as to bo enabled to erect a building of its own, in which\nits library, chemical and philosophical apparatus, and its illustrations of Natural History maybe deposited.\niolu,i.hi..s &lt;Mi.) ScUlHern Areti\u00bb-\nGenerous Feelings.\u2014Generosity is the wealthiest feeling of the heart. Feel as if you would aid suffering if J'ou\ncould, und you will have nearly all the self-satisfeclieli thai\nyou would have had, if you really had relieved distress.","fullrs":{},"find":"573.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"572","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1756610","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
