<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/417</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>417</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/417/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUT H - WEST ERN JOURNA 1,\n51\nmatical science 1 Nor does it require so limited an amount of\nthe knowledge of calculation, as is sometimes asserted. It\nhas required men ofthe best and quickest mathematical talent,\nto avoid the most disastrous confusion in the books of great\nbusiness establishments. As nn instance: Sir Wm. Pitt, lord\nChancellor of the British exchequer, employed George At-\nwood, ono of the most distinguished mathematicians of his\nday, and conferred upon him an office, otherwise sinecure, to\nmake his yearly financial calculation?. Dr. Franklin say\narithmetic is the \"primum mobile, (principal mover,) of all\nmundane aflairs, in general, nnd is useful for all sorts and de\ngrees of men, from the highest to the lowest.\" Argument\naside, every one knows that an acquaintance with arithmetic,\nis absolutely necessary to carry on ones ordinary dealings\nwith society.\nSurveying is the science from which geometry takes its\nname, (&gt;--, the earth, and e-Tt'-\", to measure,) because it was\nfirst applied to the measurement of lands. Claims to certain\nportions of the earth have obtained, from the earliest ages,\namong nearly all nations. To ascertain ihe precise boundaries ol thes3 claims, and the exact quantities contained, are\nnecessary to the order and peace of society. Now the assumption that this science may be learned from a few plain\nrules, without understanding their reasons, is entirely gratui\ntons, as the attempt is mischievous. Having had oecasion to\nexamine some of these surveys, which have produced half a\ncentury's litigation, we have found them but strong instances\nof what may and dors occur, in almost every instance, where\nmen attempt lo work by principles they do not understand-\n'Tis true that if ns much time be spent in committing rules,\nas would master the principles, it will enable some men lo perform the simplest jobs in surveying. Bui lit the slightest difficulty, or even doubt occur, and your men; practical man\nmust halt at once, or blunder on, lo the loss or ruin of his\nemployer, and the disgrace of the noble science he professes.\nNo, it requires all intimate knowledge of both trigonometry\nand geometry, and even of the higher branches r,f algebraic\nanalysis, to examine the correctness of his logarithmic la Mis\nand mike an expeditious and accurate surveyor. And to these\nmust b? ad led some knowledge of Astronomy, before he can\nscientifically take the variations of the needle,\nBut in the mechanic arts, where shall we look for the part\nnot dependant upon mathematics? In all the gradations of\nbuilding, from the cabin or lint to the stately dome of a capitol,\nthe tribute of praise is due to ibis one prolific source. 'Tis\ntrue that some degree of proficiency may bo attained by patient application, without understanding the scientific principles of a mechanical branch. But how have those principles\noriginally been applied, and the particular art brought lo its\npresent perfection ? How, for instance, has a watery element\nbeen compelled to render that very service, which now overcomes the resistance of its wave, and almost annihilates difficulty and distance. The records of time present not half\nso magnificent a triumph of art over nature, by the applications of her own principles to herself, as is daily witnessed,\nin the proud monument to the memory of Fulton. And the\nanalysis will sustain the position, that the glory is due to the\nmathematics.    Steam is the great moving cause, nnd is refer\nable at once lo that branch of mechanical philosophy called\nhydrostatics. All the machinery set in motion is but combinations, permutations, and arrangements of the lever, tho\nwheel and axl.\\ and the pulley, all discussed in mathematical\nphilosophy. In building, too, every leading triumph of\nStrength or permanence, has been the result of vigorous calculation. The brace, the column, tho spire, the arch, the\ndome, with all their precise, symmetrical proportions, acknowledged same origin. Now, wliat.thougb theblunderingcopy-\nist may construct an edifice of beauty nfter years of slavish aiid\nblind imitation I if a change is to be made, or a new beauly\nadded, you must go to the man of science. So your mere\npractical nrchitect is deprived of nil the mental gratification\nof understanding the principles by which he labors; he must\nsuffer the immense loss of time and material which could be\nsaved by science. He is shut out from the great world of\nimprovement, he is debarred from invention, that most gratifying nnd triumphant of human gifts. So, if mental gratification is the object of the mechanist, it is only to be found, in\nthe scientific application of principles to practice; for there\nis certainly something of humiliating degradation in copying\nfor a lifetime, the workmanship of another.\nBut the mathematics are not confined lo mechanic arts, in\ntheir application to the useful business of life. All the intercommunication between different pails of our country, and\nbetween different and distant lands, bring ihese laws into essential requisition. To run the line of the most common\nroad, the surveyor must be called lo tin' undertaking. To\nlocate such road upon the most eligible grounds,\u2014such as\nshall cost ihe least possible amount, approach nearest to n\nlevel, and take the shortest accessible route;\u2014and where all\nthese are not possible, lo balance judiciously, cost, level, and\ndistance'\u2014all require the most intricate and perplexing calculations, Indeed, none bul an Engineer possessingn thorough\nknowledge of mathematics, is competenl to the undertaking.\nAnd in the construction of a road, his knowledge must still\ndirect every movement, whilst laborers perform but the manual\npar,. Upon the vast ocean, ho-^jwa-, tho triumph of calculation is most magnificent, most iboundless in utility. \"That\na man by merely measuring the moon's distance, from a fixed\nstar, with a little sextant, should tell, within five miles, of his' v\nposition, upon a boundless water, cannot but appear to np-C\nproach the miraculous.\" A trembling bark, lost in the infinity \u2022*\nof its littleness, compared with the clement, uponwhich it ventured, trusted itself to a boisterous Pacific, at San Bias, in Mexico,\nto seek a port 80(111 miles distant. A fow bounds of ihe gallant traveller, and the last land-mark sank behind the wave;\nyet onward, and still onward she bore, with hula canopy and\nits gems or its thunders above; and, ns if in mockery, thesame\ndeep mirrored canopy beneath.    Upon the bow,\n\"If pans so small a lltiiier can have,\"\nthere might be seen the pigmy man, who, with bis sextant,\nlances at the moon, gives a command, retreats within his little world, and all is safe. Tempests swept and billows dashed,\nand the reeling bark sank and rose, and drove at random on\ntho wave. Thesky at last appeared, the Utile lord was at his\npost with his wand, and again his realm leapt over the sea, In\nghty-nine long days and nights, no land was seen, to cheer or\n$\u25a0;\u25a0,.\nh\nj-', -   !\nIjt\nIt\nil","fullrs":{},"find":"418.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"417","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1849946","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
