<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 32</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2139</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2139</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2139/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Section 3, Page 32","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"32 ADDRESS.\nOrleans to Jackson; by the other, a mil-road from Madisonvillc to Jackson, and\nthence to a connection with New-Orleans, by steam-ferry boats being used j-\nbringing the trains of rail-road cars down the Cbcfuncte river, and acroai\nLake Pontchartraiu to the landing of the Pontchartrain Rail-road.\nThe distance from New-Orleans to Jackson, via Pontchartrain Rail-road, Lake\nPontchartrain and Madisonville, is 173 miles, of which distance about 30 milei\nwill be steam-ferry. By the located line ofthe old Nashville Rail-road the dig.\ntance is 192 miles. By a route recently surveyed by Mr. Phelps, passing above\nLake Mauripas, the distance will be about 200 miles ; and by a proposed lint,\nup the river, to the vicinity of Baton Rouge, the distance from New-Orleans to\nJackson will be about 213 miles.\nThe latter route avoids difficult swamps, expensive drawbridges across navi-\ngable rivers, and passes through a fertile and well improved country.\nEstimating 30 miles per hour for passenger trains, on a level and strait\nrail-road, the time of passing over each of the routes will be as follows:\n1st. By the Pontchartrain Rail-road, steam-ferry and Madisonville route\u20148\nhours 15 minutes.\n2d. By the old Nashville Rail-road\u20146 h. 24 minutes.\n3d. By the line above Lake Mauripas\u20146 h. 40 m. ; and by the route near\nBaton Rouge\u20147 h. 5m.\nThe majority ofthe committee are of the opinion that the road via Baton Rouge\nmay be constructed in the most substantial manner from New-Orleans to\nJackson for two millions of dollars, and that the shorter lines would not cost\nmaterially less. The cost of the road from the state line of Louisiana to the\ntown of Jackson, will be the same on either route, and may be estimated separately at one million of dollars.\nThe majority of the committee are strenuously opposed to any interruption\nof a continuous rail-road communication between New-Orleans and neighboring states. The time allotted to the committee will not permit a report ia detail, but the majority feel well assured that, on a simple statement of the case,\nthe Convention will not hesitate in adopting an unbroken line of rail-road communication.    On behalf of the majority,\nGlendy Burke,  CJiairman.'\"\n11. The New-Orleans and Opelousas Mail-road.\u2014The proceedings!\nofthe Convention on this road, and which gave rise to the present\ncommittee, will be found reported in detail in the number oi'Dt\nBow's Review for August, 1851, as the proceedings of the other con* (\nventions are published in previous numbers. The number of delegates was large, comprising the wealth of the state, and the enthusiasm throughout the country is beyond all precedent.*\nThe construction of these two roads is, then, the first great matter\nupon which the people of Louisiana and of New-Orleans must be engaged to regain their lost position, aud acquire that rank in \"*\naffairs of the nation which nature seems to have marked out fo-\"\nthem.\nBy the one our city will be connected with that great and groWjtf\nregion of Texas, which is destined to be the empire State of the\nSouth, and the trade of which will compensate for many losses incurred by us in other quarters. In the progress of population the\nroad will be extended further, and still further to the westward, un1\"'\nin less than a generation, it is no chimera to suppose it with *\nterminus upon the Pacific, and conducting the commerce of the tffC\n* For other information upon this ioad, see Appendix at end.   Also De Bow's i^*1\nVol. X.","fullrs":{},"find":"2140.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2139","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"550453","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.52 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
