<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 3</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2200</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2200</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2200/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 6, Page 3","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"L3]\nn-.~nf Jefferson.\u2014John M. Bach, J. Calhoun, C. Besbee, Samuel Ricker, C. Brown\nVVh' H Williams, Thomas May, W. P- Coleman.\nU^',' f i\\'m-Orleans.\u2014L.J. Harris, Hon. J. E. Morse, W. Elmore, L.Sur&lt;n,Dr.F\n,,i T G. Collins, J. Genois, JE. Solomon, D. Cronan, George Allan, W. C. Tomo-\nA 9 rM Waterman, J. Leeds, J. S. Holden, G. May, J. H. Caldwell, B. H. Payne, J. M.\n\"il', T T Lu\u00abhenbulil, G. De Fenet, P. Seuzeneau, George Clark, J. C. Prenderoast\n\u00a3U r Piere A- Derbes, J. A. Bonneval, A. Fisk, L. Heyleger, G. A. Holt, J. L. McLean'\ni'in Y..eennes, P. A- Degelos, A.Fernandez, N. C. Folger, W. T. Hepp.C. De Blanc,\nni Taiiata A. Dupre, J. Cassard, R W. Montgomery, H. C. Cammack, M. Blasoo, A.\nMiiUbereer, J. W. 2acharie, L. E. Forstall, F. Correjolles, J. M. Lepeyre, John Pem-\nbllwn, M. Bamett, Sr., H. Legendre, F. Buisson, W. Vogel, N. Richards, R. D. Sheppard,\nV Wiltz,\" J- Viosca, F. Marguez, R. M. McAlpin, J. D. Denegre, G. B. Duncan, B.Aveg-\n' r- fj' F Maxent, P. Desverges, W. E. Wilson, G. Bieneau, G. Burke, James Robb,\nT Mathews W. H. Garland, P. Conrev, Jr., W. S. Campbell, J. Baldwin, H.&lt;J. Ranney,\nj P.Harrison. John G. Cocks, A. J. Wedderburn, E. Rawle, G. M. Pinkard, H. W. Palfrey' John R. Shaw, H, G- Stetson, J. O. Nixon, H. M. Summers, A. P. Simpson, J. N.\nHawthorne, Thomas Curry, D. Conyngham, M. M. Cohen, N. R. Jennings, W. p. Aiwood,\n[ N Marks, B.W.Powell, A. Harris, J. H. Maddox, P. Irwin, Colonel Seymour, S.W.\n(laliey, Alex. Walker, J. W. Stanton, J. D. B. De Bow, A. M. Holbrook, Logan McNight,\nS.Turner, J. G. Gribble, S. Story, S. S. Harby, H. Kennedy, A. Montanye, J. A. Beard,\nW P Converse, E. Mcpherson, T. B. Winston, S. J. Peters, H. Florance, R. Hunt, W.\nCriW,L. Hunton.J.G. Dunlap, J. Crickard, J. E. Caldwell, C. C. Lathrop, C. J.Leeds,\nJ. W.Price, A.Lanfear, S. Smith, I. D. Marsh, Janus Bonner, W. G. Kendall, E. E.\nCity of Lafayette.\u2014John M. Burke,B. Florance, H. S. Buckner, A. D. Kelly, L. De\nSanies, Logan McKnight, J. H. Donegan, C. T. Buddecke, R. N. Ogden, D, S. Dewees,\nJames Norment, S. H. Peck, L. R. Kenny, H. J. Hart, N. Commander, M, M. Dowler,\nJohn Turpin, T. C. Jenkins, T. G. Mackay,D. Hadden, S. S. Burdette, R. W. Milbank,\nS-S. Green, John A. Watkins, H.E.Lawrence.\nVirginia.\u2014William M. Burwell, James McDowell.\nKentucky.\u2014William Soery, J. N. Beadles, W. Thornsbury, H. M. McCarty, T. Davis,\nJ. W. Jones, J. Campble.\nTennessee.\u2014Col. A. Herman, and James A. Porter, Nashville; Right. Rev. J. H. 0tey,\nCol George W.Polk, and Gen. L.J. Polk, Maury county ; T. Trezevant, R. C. Brinkley,\nJ. R. McClemiahan, D. M. Leatherman. W. Armour, J. T. Leath.\nAlabama.\u2014T. B. Goldsby, P. J. Weaver, J. W. Lansley, George P. Blevina, W. S.\nBnrr,J.P. Perham.\nFlorida.\u2014J. M. Landrum, William D. Keyser, and John Forsyth, St. Rosa county.\nMissouri.\u2014(Appointed by the St. Louis Chamber of Commerce.)\u2014P. R. McCreery,\nr'J\\' *\"-V'W* ^' Bennett, B- -A. Burnes, R. J- Lockwood, R. N. Rennick, and Franklin\nChilds, absent; Henry Chouteau, and William Wade, present.\nMississippi\u2014C. S- Tarpley, Hinds county; Gen. E. L-Acee, Yallabusha county; Rev-\nft- S- Gladney, Aberdeen; Rev. J. Sidney Hays, Louisville ; Col- John Duncan, Grenada;\nMajor A. M. Route, Jackson ; Z. Rector, French Camp ; Major Samuel White, Pearling-\nton; Col H. G- Street, Liberty; R- A. Johnson, Princeton; R. H- Crump, J. W. Vick,\n\u00a3 &lt;-*- Noland, Shepherd Brown, N- G- Watts, J. D- Cobb, and J. Willis, Vicksburg; W-\nV-Lane.Warrenton; J. S- Yerger, Greenville; J. S. McCall, H-W.Walter, Richard\nH. Stokes, S.W. Land.\nI AllK*NfiAs\u2014Capt. Albert Pike, Col. A. Fowler, R. C- Farrelly, Little Rock; Colonel\nJobn Martin, St. Helena; Rev- Leonard Fletcher, J. C Palmer, R. F- Sutton, S. C\nFaulkner, Luther Chase, W. D. Ferguson-\n.J txi.S\";rTravis G.;Wright, Amos Morrill, J. T- Mills, Red River county; C- C Alex-\n\"Oer, B. B. Allen, Lamar county.\nIORgia\u2014Peter Conrev, and others, citizens of New-Orleans, appointed to represent\nT!'\"\\Prae\u201eted their credentials.\n. ilobb, Irom tho ronnnittee on officers, reported the following, and the nominations\nWere \"\"Wimously approved :\nVi\u00ab p    -j Ex-Gov. Alex. Mouton, of La., President.\nC PM,^^Xdents.\u2014C. S. Tai-plev, Mississippi; Joseph Forsyth, Florida; Gen. Lucius\nMisaoi' Ie\"nH,ssee; William N. Burwell, Virginia; Amos Morrill, Texas; H. Chouteau,\nLo\u201e;.i    '    .,    Parham, Alabama : J. N. Beadles, Kentucky; Judge James Campbell,\n\u25a0Sa;-Absalom F\u00b0^r, Arkansas.\nDum-\u2122 iv^~~Jl&gt;,m Calhoun, Victor Wiltz, Louisiana ; R. C. Farreley, Arkansas ; John\n\"\u25a0\"-an, -Mississippi.\n\" Gettib ^0^\u00b0n'on laking the Chair, addressed the Convention as follows:\nfcnder J mn \\tlte Vonvcntion:\u2014For the unexpected honor you have conferred on me, I\n\u25a0^\"etiuieart?^! nks\" r am f'ully aware of the difficulties that surround my position, and\nWe; but f r - * am hardly equal to the discharge of the duties you have imposed upon\n'Wlliu-,. ook\"\\g at the character of the gentlemen assembled here, and appreciating their\ne and Patriotism, and the motives that actuate them. I tb-.- \u25a0\u25a0*\u25a0 siy*elf unhesita-","fullrs":{},"find":"2201.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2200","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"515866","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
