<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/473</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>473</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/473/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":".'\n1':\nm\n\u25a0 \u25a0. -.\ni :^\u00a5\ni\nj\n100\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL\n7\nThere appears a striking analogy between the common\nprocess of carbonic acid gas fermentation and this gaseous\nferment, viz: in the former it is requisite to have a suitable\nvegetable basis, of a certain consistence, at a certain temper\nature, for a longer or shorter time, to produce the effect. This\neflect will be greatly expedited by introducing into tho basis\nso prepared a portion of ferment or leaven; although the\nsame effect would be produced without it after a longer time.\nWhen the fermentative process is complete a portion of the\nfermentated basis introduced into another basis in a suitable\ntemperature, will excite tho same action ; and so on ad infinitum. This ferment, although it require a temperature\nfrom 70\u00b0 to 80\u00b0 for its production, is not destroyed when\nonce produced, by any moderate change of temperature'. II\na portion of this leaven be introduced inlo an unsuitnbL\nbasis, at an improper temperature, it will bo neutralized and\nlost.\nSo il appears to us is the gaseous ferment of yellow fever.    It requires a basis of impure air, exhausted by respiration, and charged with human effluvia, at a regular temperature for a certain time, to produce it in the first place:\nbut when a portion of the infection already formed in another place is   introduced, the   assimilating   process   takes\nplace much sooner, and probably without the same degree\nof heat or contamination that would be necessary to generate it ah initio.    This \"leaven\" of infection when introduced into several points ol a malarious district, will much more\ncertainly institute the assimilating  process, than if it were\nintroduced at one or two points only, and in small quantities.\nIf introduced into pure air it becomes neutralized and lost.\nUpon this principle we may explain why it is so necessary to desert an infected district, to check the spread of th\ndisease; for thereby, wo  not only prevent the formation  ofj\nthe malaria, or basis, but likewise remove the sources of in\nfection or \" leaven.\"    The air becomes more pure by removing those who contaminate it, and new cases of fever in\nthe contaminated air, or malaria, are prevented.    If this precaution is taken soon after the first few cases, before the gen\neral air of a district becomes infected, the spread of the dis\ncase may be arrested : for in ten or twelve days where res\npiration has been suspended or intermitted, the air loses its\npeculiar adaptation for supporting the assimilating proces:\nThe fermentative process ceases for want of a suitable basis;\nand the miasm settles down near the ground in ils simple\nharmless state, or is waited off by winds.    But if the popu\nlation remain contaminating the air at such time, until it be\ncomes infected, rains may wash portions of it inlo bayoux,\nnnd winds may sweep all infected air from the streets, bul\nthere will remain sufficient of the infected air in the houses\nand  enclosures to institute the fermentative process a\"ain\nfrom a hundred sources.\nThe properties of infection, or infected air, so far as can\nbe ascertained are as follows, viz :\n1. It is a gaseous poison which is diffused in the air at\ncertain times, or mny bo contained in confined air of houses,\nships, and even in bales of goods. It is more volatile than\nsimple miasm or infectious air; and diffuses itself further and\ninsinuates itself more intimately and extensively in the at\nmosphere of a city; and when concentrated produces yellow\nfever in its most malignant forms, in from three to five days\nfrom the exposure, without any exciting cause. To bring\nthe system under its influence, it is neccssan only to breathe\nit for a few minutes, or an hour or two, according to tlle\ndegree of concentration. It so acts through the nervous system, upon the whole of the vital functions, as to produce a\nmalignant fever, which mostly terminates indeath, alter from\none to five days.\n2. When a suitable quantity of it is introduced into the\nproper kind of air, at a suitable temperature, without the free\nadmission of pure air, it acts as a ferment, and re-proelures\na larger amount of infection, equally efficient with that first\nintroduced. In this way it will assimilate the contiguous air\nand diffuse itself as extensively as the malaria. A large\namount of it introduced, will bo diffused in an atmosphere\nless contaminated than actual malaria, and assimilate, or render infected a much greater amount of air. Although a\nsmall quantity diffused in a pure atmosphere so as to become\nmuch diluted, loses its fermentative properties, as wellasiis\nmorbific.\nThese properties we find indicated by the infection having\nbecome as virulent as ever in a few days after a severe gale\nor storm must necessarily have swept off all the loose infection from the open air. The infected air in each house is a\nsource for re-infecting the general air of the city or infected\ndistrict.\n3. When air is moderately infected, so ns not lo produce\nactive disease, by being closely confined, tit a temperature between 85\" and 05\" it becomes more virulent in a few days.\nThis is confirmed (luring every epieh mic, in this known\nfact, viz: that a house may be deserted early in the epidemic, when the infection in the general air is weal; so as\nnot to have excited disease in any of its occupants: yet when\nthey have fled, and the house has been closed for a month\nor longer, if any of those same members, or others from the\ncountry return to that house, occupy it, nnd sleep in it without proper ventilation and exposure to cold or frost, they trill\ncontract yellow fever of a high grade and probably die. The\nair contained in In ils h ft in such houses has bcin more closely confined than the free air ofthe room, and nta more regular temperature, and of cntiise is more virulent.\nIt is upon this principle as well as that of section 2nd, thai\ncleanliness and ventilation are so essentially neeessaiy ntent\npatients laboring under yellow fever, list it may accumulate\nin a stagnant air and become a new source of infection. Fofi\nas Dr. Paloni, of Naples, observes, of the yellow fever ol\nLeghorn, which swept of!'seven hundred souls in thnt city in\nthe autumn of 1804 : \" The infi ction of this fever is of such\na constitution, thnt pure and renewed air decomposes its \/(WW\nit a small distance from the sick: on the other hand, air that\nstagnates and is replete with animal exhalations, easily '\"\"\ncomes a vehicle for it. Hence it happens thnt as soon ns lb\ndisorder broke out, wc saw it rage most fierci ly in the ine-'!\nfilthy nnd least ventilated pails of the city. Pvre.freslh'1'\nncwed air destroys its infection.\" Med. Repository, vol. &amp;\np. 426\u20147, &amp;c.\nIn this case the Doctor's views are correct, and unusual'?","fullrs":{},"find":"474.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"473","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1833961","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
