<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/466</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>466</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/466/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"kk\n11\/:\niifii-\n91\nS 0 U T H - W F S T E R N J 0 U R N A 1.\nBefienth a cluster of tall beeches, near the sea shore, tit\none end of the royal gardens, sat \"the loved and the lover.\"\nTradition has talked much about the remarkable beauty of\nPhaon, nnd its equally remarkable effects, making all hearts\nyield in adoration and love. He was formerly a ferryman\nbetween the isle of Lesbos and the shore of Asia. One morning, as his little bark lay moored in the harbor of Mitylene,\nnn old woman applied to him for a speedy passage over lo\nAsia. He readily complied, and hythe aid of oars and sail,\nsoon crossed the narrow strip of sen, that separated the island\nfrom the continent. Upon landing, the old woman produced\na small box, and, delivering it to him, said, \"Be this ihy ferriage: anoint thyself with the ointment, and then gaze upon\none of the clear springs of thy native isle, (for thou art, from\nthy looks, too poor to possess a mirror,) and thou wilt toil no\nmore.\" The old woman quickly vanished to her heavenly\nhome, for it was the goddess of beauty in disguise.\nThe rough and awkward ferryman did as Venus commanded, and the ointment transformed his coarse proportions\nto the most symmetrical figure. The world ne'er gazed upon a handsomer man than Phaon, and with his person also\nchanged his fortunes.\nBook-worms and dreamers tell us, in strains almost ol\nrhapsody, of the unequalled dominion of the intellect over\nthe affections. A high-soulccf, imaginative being, we believe,\nwould willingly lay the heart's rich treasures at the shrine ol\ngenius, but only such. Beauty's dominion is the most extensive and the most powerful. The heart, almost at its first\nbeat, feels the lively sensations of that power, and cherishes\nthem fondly, until its last pulsation. Wilh men like Phaon\nwhoso all is in their appearance, what can genius do? It\ncan command admiration, nnd even tears, but it cannot entwine itself around the affections of the heart. It is the soft\ngaze of a lustrous eye; the low, sweet tone of voice, and the\nlittle trickeries of attention, that fascinate and allure.\nThere was a softness in Rhodophe's voice, and a mildness\nin her heavenly eyes, that few could withstand, and we need\nnot wonder that Phaon loved, even to the most desperate adoration. Perhaps the knowledge of his dominion over the affections of Sappho nnd her own power, prompted her to increase, by a thousand little attentions, the flame that was consuming him,\nAt first, the pride of being the lord of the affections of ihe\npoetess, almost mastered him. He was always at her side,\nheard with admiration the recital of her own sweet poetry,\nnnd poured into her ears the sweetest strains of adulation and\nof love. Rhodophe saw that vanityalone prompted him to pursue such a course, and succeeded, at length, in weaning entirely his heart and attention, and binding him irrevocably to her.\nRhodophe's hand was warmly clasped in his, and he was\ndrinking from her gaze the draught that gave life and buoyancy to his soul.\n\" I would talk to thee of our love, Rhodophe.\"\n\" Nay, do not, hut tell me of- Sappho.\"\n\"1 have not seen her for many days.\"\n\" I saw her last evening, in the garden, gazing upon the\nsilver moon.    As I approached her, I heard her sigh, and\nnn thought she whispered, ' Phaon.'     1 placed my hand upon\nher shoulder, and gazed full upon her face; but yet she Bmiled\nnot, as she was wont. A deep melancholy has shaded a]|\nher feelings. Ah ! Phaon, 'tis you who have made her mjj.\nerable. 1 would that she was loved as thou lovest me. Sh,,\nwould be happy.\"\n\"I cannot love her as I love thee, yet'tis misery to tl;,,];\nof the intenseness of her love. Oh Rhodophe, hadst thou\nbeen there when she told me the story of her love, thou\nwouldst have wept nt the strange eloquence she used. She\ntold mi', while the tears trickled down her cheeks, and her\nfull heart seemed bursting with the effort, that when she saw\nme, I appeared, (but only to her bright fancy, Rhodophe,) at\none equal to the gods; that when she heard me speak, hei\nheart trembled in her bosom, she lost the power of speech, anil\nher tongue was broken,\u2014and, immediately, ihe gnnwings of\nan inward fire consumed her. She saw nothing with y,\neyes,\u2014a cold sweat remained upon her body, anil trenblio'i\nseized her own frame. And, at length, she burst forth in a\nflood of tears, and said, 'I am paler than the grass, and nol far\ndistant from the grave. My life seems leaving me; but, oh'\nit must be borne, since I am miserable and poor.\" * Teats\ncame to my eyes, in spite of my manliness, and I u-Jshe.\nthat I could have loved her. But 1 told her that I loved\nthee, and thee alone. She started, but she spoke not. Het\neyes seemed suddenly kindled, with an unearthly fire, am\nmelhought, that I would wither beneath its interiseness,-\nTwas not, Rhodophe, the fire of anger, but it seemed of mail\nnnd hopeless despair.\nThe sun was going down behind Leitcate. Upon thelal\nwhite cliff's, that reared themselves proudly from the sea, was\nseen the solitary form of a human being. Her white drapcrr\nwas beautifully relieved, by the brilliant sky of the eveninr.\nShe held in her hand a lyre, and its jewels caught the lustre\nof the sun's last beams.\nThe stillness of the gtave was around that promontory\nThe sen bird had hushed its shrill cry, and the waves of ike\nbillowy Ionian seemed to sleep. Hark! a strain of the\nsweetest music floated upon the evening zephyr. 'Twnsso::.\nand would have reminded you of some buried affection,*\nmelancholy was the air. The sun went down, and the raiisi:\ncensed. With her long hair, streaming in the evening zephyr\nand her hands uplifted towards heaven, she prayed to the\ngods to look in mercy upon the sacrifice she was about to mate\nand then she turned, and took a farewell look upon the beautiful Leucnelia, and then gazed upon the \"deep, blue sen,\" bf-\nfore, around, beneath her. For a moment, she stood with il\nfirmness of a statue, anil then gave one fearful spring,\u2014cm\nsullen plunge was heard,\u2014and the waters of the Ionian\nclosed forever over the ill-fated and unhappy Sappho.\n  PAi.AimjiB^\n1 Tho classical scholar, In rending this sketch, must not fin-net iho n'cssrt\nnuance, and excuse our having thus used tlio Idensof ono of the'mosiltSi1**\nlonccl and beautiful framents, that arc left usof iho lioctryof Boppho^beti\nciioluf horlove,\nReligious Consolation.\u2014He whose abode is onto\nlofty heights of religious feeling, will have his hours of dart\nness like others, but they will be short; as the nights ai\nongcr in valloysthan on mountains.\u2014Paul Jean.\nCc\nto I\nme\ndcr\nint\nas\\\nnrn\nthe\ni\nand\n","fullrs":{},"find":"467.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2016-06-22","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"466","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1842824","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
