<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/384</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>384</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/384/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"li\nV\n:   i\n20\nS 0 U T II - W E S T E R N J 0 U TL N A L\nof bis audience ;  he should know all the springs and avenues!first cause\u2014flic source \" from whence Cometh every good i\nto the human heart, that he may convince by his reasoning, perfect gift.\"    He who has never known adversity, who I\nand persuade by his eloquence.    Thus he may be able to win 'never had losses, crosses nnd  disappointments, and who I\nmany souls to Christ, as seah of his ministry.    He, loo, is never buffeted ihe adverse waves, has never known himself,\nthe best General, who loves Ins country more than he fears Misfortunes and disappointments, though ihey seem grievm\ndangor; who, stimulated by the righteousness of his cause, are, by a wise dispensation of Providence, calculated for r\nand trusting in the God of battles, rides foremost in the mar good.   Adversity has not tinfrequently called forth mas\ntial band, and, by his precept and example, encourages to ac- spirits, aroused the latent energies, which otherwise inig\ntion.   And, lo the Student, who is toiling up the hill of sci- have remained dormant, and struck forth a spark flint lias e\nence, what can be more essential than ibis self-command!\u2014 lightened ihe world.   We must always grapple with an onon\nIt enables him lo concentrate his energies so as to grapple before we can learn his weakness or our own strength; at\nwith every difficulty and overcome every obstacle in his way.i the victory once obtained, every afler conquest will he easie\nIt leaches\" him his own strength, and how to apply it lo the 'I'm the well disciplined soldier we are to look for aid  in il\nlies! advantage.    It is a key  by  which we may unlock the lime of trouble ;  and  lie, who would  be proud It)  have h\nstorehouse of knowledge, or it is a kind of moral goniometer, name registered as a benefactor lo mankind, must be willin\nby which we may measure our own menial elevaiion.    It is to endure hardship as a good soldier i he must be willing!\nthe balance wheel by which all die parts of a well regulated forego many present pleasures as a sacrifice lo those more en\nhuman machine are moved and governed.    It is a mysterious,(luring pleasures that are to come.    Show me a man who ha,\nlogic which unravels the most abstruse points in metaphysics;always  indulged  in  ease, who has never denied himself ain\nand ethics, and makes the rugged paths of science smooth audi present gratification, and I will show you a man win will ne\neasy.    Ii tempers the judgment, purifies the thoughts, curbs ver astonish the world by bis eloquence, or rule il by his wis\nthe imagination, invigorates the mind, quickens the moral sen- dom.    Where is tho scholar or ihe philosopher that has no\nsibility, and strengthens the body by teaching it to observe burned tho midnight oil ?    Where is the astronomer that hai\nthose laws of our being  which  cannot be transgressed with, not passed many a sleepless night wandering among the stars!\nimpunity.   To him, who can govern himself, nothing is loo And where the chemist and botanist that have not wandered\nhard to accomplish; he penetrates the arcana of nature, and lover hill nnd through dell for many a weary hour I    Their\nbrings to light her hidden stores;   he dives into tho ocean, language is to us, \" go and tin likewise';\"   -t well vour\nperforates the earth, wings his way into the sky ! Nothing parts, there all the honor lies.\" We are die artificers of our\ni-i too high for his reach, nothing ton deep for his grasp, nor own fortunes, Our improvement in knowledge and virtue,\ntoo extended for his embrace. Who would not possess this our influence, our interest, :::i I oar happiness depend upon\npower and this knowledge .' It is an anchor lo the soul, both ourselves. It is for us lo sav what we shall be, or, at leas,,\nsure and steadfast j ami when once obtained, il will accompa- to sav what wo will not be. Let us be determined ihat we\nnv us through life. Ii is perennial in duration, ecstatic In will no longer be slaves to iho appetites and passions, bill thai\nenjoyment, our guide and support in youth, our consolation we will govern ourselves according to the principles of rea-\nand solace in age, a friend in adversity, and a passport to a son, justice and humanity; and a moral, civil, political and\nblessed and happy immortality. Again, self-control lends no1 religious revolution will have commenced which shall regene-\nmore lo our moral and mutual improvement than to our inter- rate the world. And what lover of his country dnc* not re-\nest and happiness. To bo happy, nol for the present fleeting joice at the interest thai is beginning lo be fell on tin's impor-\nmoment only, but through every part of our existence, we|tant subject, Already religious, social, scientific and literary\nmust know how to use ibc powers, faculties and gifts, thai societies have been formed in every pari of our world, based\nGod has given us, without abusing them. Things which, on the principles of self-government. And, under ihe influ-\nwhen rightly used, lend to our comfort and happiness-, may. ences of these societies, a brighter day seems lo be dawning ;\nwhen used n, excess, tend to our ruin. Tho laws of our ihe clouds of ignorance and superstition are fast flying away,\nbeing are such ihat, so fat as we understand and obey litem,' To these societies we are to look for improvement in the\nwe shall be happy, and the reverse as we disobey llietn.\u2014 arts and sciences, ami for iho amelioration of the condition of\nAnd these laws may be under-,nod by all. They are written man; and may we no, hope ihat the JelTcrson College and\nby the linger of ihe Almighty upon Hie tablet of the heart\u2014 Washington Lyceum will contribute her mile in this work;\nTo this self control and self-denial we one our Independence ilia, she may aid in raising hi-Ji die floodgates of knowledge,\nas a nation. To transmit lo us this ri,-li inheritance, our I':- thai ils pure waters may fertilize all our land, Then shall\nIhers pledged their all\u2014their lives, their fortunes and Iheirsa- we be free, morally, civilly, and religiously; thru will the\nere.l   honor.    They left all the endearments  of life,  their day of millennial glory, foretold by the sacred\nfriends, iheir firesides and their homes, to bailie Ibr \" freedom,\nin freedom's holy laud.\" To enjoy life, we must he able to\nhear misfortune's frowns as well as her smiles. The\nelews of Heaven arc dispensed upon die just and upon the\nunjust. When adversity comes, we must consider the source\nfrom whence it comes.    We must go from the eflect lo ihe\npenmen, have\narrived : then may we proclaim aloud a new day of Jubilee,\nuntil the sound shall be caught by every breeze, and wafted to\nearth's remotest bounds.\nScrap ft,,in il,,- Rerinnn of Jenn Paul.\nThe rain-drop sinks liquid into the rock-cleft, but soon grows\n , \u201e\u201e,   ,,   ,    ., .    .  , ...aid and piercing.  Not so with the tear of man.   It blisters the\nause-noi merely  to the eihcent or final, but to Iho great] eye ihat sfieels it, but then becomes soft, and warm, and melting.","fullrs":{},"find":"385.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"384","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1878199","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
