<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2242</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2242</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2242/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 17","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"17]\n\u201e impulse is given to their commerce and their industrial pur-\nI\"v we shall find there at our doors, instead of away on the other\na of the world, all the productions of \" the East.\" In short, \" the\nSt\" &gt;u one sense' w!\" *&gt;e brought within eight or ten days' sail of\nNv Orleans, instead of being removed to the distance of four or\nfi\u00ab months off, as it now is.\nSeveral nations, as Bolivia, Peru, Ecuador, and Brazil, are the\nuers of the Amazon and its navigable tributaries.\n\u00b0 Brazil is the principal owner.    All the lower Amazon is hers ; and\nshe has given none of the upper countries as yet the right of way\nthrough it to and from the sea.\nThe question then is, do the people who are represented in this\nConvention set any value upon the right to steam and trade up and\ndown the navigable streams of that magnificent water-shed % At\npresent the country is for the most part a wilderness of howling\nmonkeys and noisy parrots ; its boundaries are fringed with settlements ; but only here and there, when you leave the outskirts of the\nvalley and begin to penetrate into the interior, are the traces of civilized man to be found.\nTo obtain this right is the work of diplomacy. But the states and\npeople who have been invited to this Convention, may, by their\naction, influence that diplomacy.\nBrazil may be invited to give the free navigation of this river\naway as a boon to civilization, and make it common to the world.\nBut it is not to be supposed that Brazil will part with such a jewel\nwithout a consideration.\nShall it be bought with a sum of money % Or shall the free navigation of the Mississippi be offered to Brazil in exchange for the free\nnavigation of the Amazon %\nBy our own laws, an English vessel, or the vessel of any other\nnation at peace with us, is as free to sail up the Mississippi River,\nland and take in a cargo at St. Louis, and to come down again, as\n\u00bb is to go up the Chesapeake Bay to Baltimore, or the Delaware\nto Philadelphia.\nBut do such foreign vessels go up to St. Louis 1 No. Why %\nBecause, when they arrive at New-Orleans with their cargoes of\noreign merchandise, which they have brought across the seas, they\nd *l cheaper to send it up in one of our river-boats, than to take it\n\u25a0 P themselves; and, therefore, though foreign vessels, by our own\nW8_, may go up and come down, yet the free navigation ofthe Missis-\nrfP1''\u00b0 'his extent, has proved of no practical value to any of them.\nst ltey-g0 up farther if theycould 1\nWas *'me was' w'len 'he f''ee navigation of the Mississippi River\njj, a,1uestion of deep and absorbing political interest to us; and we\n\u00bbhe h, therefore, that the diplomatist of the country would act,\nto B -i Pr0Per t'me comes, with more confidence touching the offer\nKn r?' \u00b0f the free navigation of the Mississippi for that of the Ama-\nthe'tf i \"a\u2122g learned the opinion and wishes upon the subject, of\nPeople ofthe Mississippi valley.","fullrs":{},"find":"2243.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2242","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"555588","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.53 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
