<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2075</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2075</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2075/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:43">{"title":"Section 2, Page 11","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"11\njs( I will leave that to abler and more eloquent gentlemen.\n2nd\u2014The weather is too warm.\n3d I think it more modest in lawyers (who have so many\nopportunities of exhibiting their immense genius) to permit\nthose who are not of our profession to avail themselves of\noccasions like the present, to present their practical in.\nformation and local knowledge, which the planters have Ihe\nbest means of acquiring.\n4th I have ever held it good policy in lawyers to pretermit some chances of spilling their overflowing eloquence on\ntheir friends and neighbors, and to let their clients speechify\noccasionally, so that, when they come to try their hands at\nit. not finding it the funny and facile thing they look it to be,\nbut, on the contray, a very sweating undertaking, ihey may\nllicnce come to appreciate, more highly, the labor of\nthose who speak for them by proxy or power of attorney. All,\ntherefore, that I now propose to do is, briefly to state the\nreasons that impel me to submit these resolutions to your\nmore enlightened consideration.\nAnd lirst, as to the first resolution, \"that a railroad shall\nbe built from New Orleans to Washington, in the parish of\nSi. Landry\u2014\"\nI take it, that the fust part of this resolution, viz : that a\nrailroad shall be built, is already predetermined ; that it is\nimplied in the fact of our convening now and here. But it\nappeared, to my humble judgment, meet and proper that\nthis, our determination, should be distinctly announced to all\nwhom it may concern. I might have worded it in a more\ncourtly and milk and water phraseology, and could have\nsaid, \"Resolved, that in the opinion of this convention, it is\nexpedient that a Railroad should be built,\" &amp;e. But you\ncannot build a road with milk, any more than you can make\na revolution with rose-water.","fullrs":{},"find":"2076.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2075","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"492597","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.47 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
