<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/422</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>422</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/422/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":".10\nS 0 U T II - W E S T E R N J O U B N A L\nfoundation\nperficial, are, as we before observed, the only sun\nof the sciences, ns well ns the fine arts.\nIt were superfluous lo dwell on the improvement of all ihe\nmental faculties, except perhaps those of mere calculation,\u2014\nof the memory, taste, imagination, judgment, discrimination,\nthe development and expansion, in fine, of all the intellectual\npowers, consequent on the study of the classics, commenced\nin early life, and continued through many successive years.\nThe study of Latin and Greek would constitute a valuable\npart of education, though they were applied to no practical\nuse whatever, hut were viewed merely as a means of mental\ndiscipline.    The close attention and constant effort, required\nin parsing and construing a diflicull author, is an exercise, like\nihat of mathematical studies, well calculated to strengthen\nthe mind, and lo impart an exact and correct mode of reasoning.    The mind, accustomed to the study of grammar, to the\naccurate analysis of single  words, and of words in connexion, acquires habits of order and systematic arrangement, and\nlearns to regard every subject with clearness and discrimination. Were only English authors read,the very facility of the\nlesson, would cause it to be carelessly studied, would lead to\nhabits of indolence and inattention, and ultimately to intellectual sloth and imbecility.    Those who have observed, in a\nlarge school, the comparative progress of Students engaged in\nprosecuting the ancient languages, and those who  were con-\nlined to mathematical and English studies, will be prepared\nfully to appreciate tho force of this argument.    Experience\nhas incontestibly demonstrated, that classical students make\nmore rapid and thorough proficiency ill every branch of learning.    The great abundance of trash, in the shape of newspapers, magazines, novels, doggerel rhymes, etc., which issue\nfrom the press, at the present day, seems to require an antidote to prevent an entire depravation of ihe public taste, and,\nit is to be feared also, a corruption of tho public morals. What\nantidote to the grow ing evil, would be so effectual, as the perusal of ancient aulhoi'sof sterling worth and   Indisputable excellence!\nBut Latin and Greek arc worthy of being studied, not\nonly as a means of intellectual disciplino, but on account of\ntheir intrinsic excellence. These languages, strange as it\nmay seem, far surpass, in dignity, harmony, and expressive\nness, all the modern, however they may have been improve,\nby learned academies, and adorned by the genius of illustri\nous writers. Both Latin and Greek are remarkable for ma\njesly and melody. Like the ancient architecture, statuary,\nand painting, they present models of all that is beautiful,\ngraceful and magnificent. That language is expressive of\nnational character, tho faithful minor of a nation's mind, may\nbe seen by a reference lo modern nations. The lively conversational dialect of tho French, the grave and stately Spanish, the soft and voluptuous Italian, the harsh and guttural\nsounds of the north of Europe, of the Russians and Dutch,\naptly reflect the characters of those respective nations. The\nlanguages of tho Greek's and Romans are, truly, like themselves : the Latin, grave and majestic, the Greek, copious and\nnervous, eloquent and commanding, They embody, and, as\nit were, embalm the genius and disposition of those highly\npolished and enlightened nations.    How delightful to con-\nverso with Socrates and Plato, with Cicero and Seneca, with\nthe good and the wise of ancient days, in their own languages-\nto walk wilh Plato in the grove of Academus, or amid the\nshades of the Lyceum, to listen to the voice of Aristotle, (hat\nmasterspirit, whose philosophy so long held undisputed swav\nover the minds of men ! The Latin writers, says an eloquent\nauthor, display a happy selection of words, a beautiful struc.\nture of phrase, a transparency of style, a precision by which\nthey communicate the strongest sentiment in the directed\nform : indeed, every thing that appertains to the most finished\nstyle of composition. It is the appropriate praise of the best\nRoman writers, that they scarcely present one idle, or exerts-\ncent sound ; that they continually convey their meaning in\nthe choicest words. Their lines dwell upon our memory;\ntheir sentences have the force of maxims; every part vigorous,\nand seldom any thing that can be altered but for the worse.\nThe Roman historians are the best that ever existed. The\ndramatic merit and eloquence of Livy, the rich and sombre\npencil of Tacitus, all ages of the world admire, but no historian of any other country has been able to rival.\nWhat is here asserted of the Roman language, may, wilh\nmore justice, be applied lo the Greek, which was indeed the\narchetype of the Latin, and comformable to the transcendent\nnd universal genius of tho people who spoke it, being from\nits flexibility and expressiveness adopted lo every subject nnd\nevery form of writing. It is at once copious and exact, harmonious and maji stic, elegant and commanding, Who would\nnot desire to become acquainted with tho language in which\nHomer's nnd Pindar's fancy soared, Euclid reasoned, and Demosthenes poured forth that lone nl of \"resistless eloquence\nwhich wielded at will the fierce democracy\" of Athens, \"shook\nthe arsenal ami fulmined over Greece to Mncedon and Ar-\nlaxerxes' throne?'' It is unnecessary to dilate on the beauties ,\nof the Greek poets. What can equal the tenderness of Euripides, the faultless elegance of Sophocles, the, wild grandeur\nand unearthly sublimity of iEschylus, the comic humor and\nnaivclte of Aristophanes, the unaffected moral simplicity of\nTheocritus, Bion anil Moschus? In historic composition,\nHerodotus, Thucydides and Xenophon havo been the mode-Is\nof all succeeding historians. What shall wo say of Longiniis.\nwho is himself \"ihe great sublime he draws;\" of the divine\nPlato, and his disciple the learned Stagyrite, the father of\nrhetoric? To the Greek and Latin writers, collectively, wo\nmay apply the remark of \\)r. Leallie, \"They relish them\nmost, who understand them best, and none affect to despise\nthem but suchasure ignorant of their value.\"\nDuring tho dark ages, that twilight of the world, a glimmering light, in striking contrast wilh the surrounding darkness, was still reflected from the monasteries, nt that lime tlio\nsole depositories of ancient learning, and tended to preserve\nscience and literature from utter extinction. To the zeal ami\nindefatigable industry of the revivers of learning, we arc indebted for rescuing from comparative oblivion, and rendering\naccessible to all, the most valuable remains of antiquity, th\"\nGrecian and Roman authors. In the fifteenth century, tlio\nmind awoke from ils slumber of ages, and threw off tho\nshackles of ignorance nnd superstition, by which it had been\nso long fettered.    The principal cause of this  auspicious","fullrs":{},"find":"423.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"422","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1873231","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
