<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/573</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>573</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/573/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 17","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"\u25a0 ADAMS COUNTY EDUCATION ASSOCIATION.\nI Citv IIai.i., Natchez, June 10, 18.18.\n1      This being the time, according to tho Constitution, for the\nI   First Quarterly Meeting, the Association convened and pro-\nI   Ccedeel to business.    The Secretary read the minutes of the\nI   last meeting, which were adopted.\n1      On motion, it was\nI Resolved, That three delegates bo appointed from this As-\nI sociation, to attend the Western College of Teachers, to he\nI convened at Cincinnati, on the first Monday in October next.\nI Messrs. Brunei-, Forshcy and Black wero appointed on\nI aid delegation.\nI       On motion, it was\nI Resolved, That six delegates from this Association be ap-\nI ]iointed toattend the Mississippi State Convention of Teachers\nI    at Jackson.\nI       Messrs. Black, Besancon, Forshcy, Hodgman, Van Hoe-\nI    sen and Forbes wore appointed delegates to that body.\n\u25a0       A Committee was appointed to prepare a regular Report\n1    for the next Quarterly Meeting, consisting of Messrs. Black,\n1    Forshey and   Oubuisson.    The subject   assigned them is,\nI    \" What are the difficulties that exist in the way of the estah-\nI    lishment of permanent  literary institutions  in the  Soulh-\nI     West, and how they may best bo obviated ? \"\nI       The question assigned for discussion at that meeting is,\nI    \"Should Young L-idies in acquiring an Education study the\nj    dead languages; and if so, to what extent?\"    The debat\nto be opened by Mr. Bruner, in the affirmative.\nA second committee was appointed to report on the follow\nI    ing subject:\u2014\"Should Novel Reading be permitted in Literary Institutions ? \"    This report was assigned lo Messrs.\nForshey. Bruner and Van Hoesen.\nThe following additional committees wero appointed by\nthe choir, to whom themes will be assigned hereafter :\nThird Committee, Messrs. Galpin and Besancon.\nFourth Committee, Messrs. Patridge and Johnson.\nFifth Committee, Messrs. Forbes and Hodgman.\nSixth Committee, Messrs. Merwin anel Eaton.\nSeventh Committee, Messrs. T'ooley and Blake.\nOn nomination, the Rev. John N. Maflitt was duly elected\nnn honorary member of the Association.\nOn nomination, Mr. James Edwards was duly elected as\na regular attending member.\nOn motion, it was\nResolved, That this Association -do now adjourn to meet\nagain in the Methodist Episcopal Church at 8 o'clock, this\nevening, for the purpose of hearing the first Quarterly Ad-\ndress, to bo delivered by Rev. Mr. Maflitt, on \" ihe Moral and\nIntellectual power of Education.\"    Adjourned.\nMethodist Church, Saturday Evening,)\nJune lli, 1838.    J\nThe Association convened, pursuant to adjournment. The\nconstitution and the minutes of the preceding meetings were\n\u25a0oad, after which the Association and audience were favored\nwilh an eloquent and able lecture, by the Rev. Mr. Maflitt,\n\u00b0'i the previously announced theme.\nAfter the close of the lecture, it was, on motion\nResolved,  1st. That the thanks of this Association be ten-\nS.OUTH-WESTE_R_N JOURNAL\ndored to the Rev. Mr. Mafli\n200\nilt, for the very able and intereslinfl\nlecture which he has just delivered, and that a copy thereof\nbe. requested for publication.\n2d. That a Committee bo appointed by the chair to carry\nthe above resolution into effect.\nOn nomination, Messrs. Lawrence ami Latham were elected members of the Association.\nOn motion, it was\nResolved, That ihe minutes of this Association this day,\nhe published.\nI'he chair, on the Committee ordered lo tender the thanks\nof the, Association' to Rev: Mr. Maffitt, appointed Messrs.\nVan Hoesen, Black and Forbes.\nOn motion, adjourned.\nC. L, DUBUISSON, President.\nS. II. ll. Black, Secretary,\nCOHHESPOiVDEN'CE.\nNatchez,\nJune 1^, 18.18.\nTo Ihe Rev. J. A7.  Maffitt,\nDesk Sin: We have llic pleasure of tendering yen the thanks\nof Ihe \" Adams County Association of Teachers und th\" Friends\nof Education,\" for lhc very able and Interesting lecture which you\nread before the Association on the night ofthe leiih instant j and\nwe are further authorized, in behalf of the Association, tu solicit a\ncopy for publication.\nWo cannot but Hatter ourselves Ileal a production will :h we- believe calculated to do so much good in the cau.,e of eiliicalion, will\nbe readily offered to the public.\nWe have the honor lo be, Sir,\nVour obedient servants,\nJ. A. VAX HOESEN,)\nS. If. II. BLACK,       }Committee.\nG. V. II. FORBES,     )\nNatchez, June 21, 1838,\nGr.NTi.r.MEN : I received your llattcnngconiitiimicaiion, dated the\n18tli instant, anil surrender my manuscript in you with all its Imperfections, relying more on your judgment than my own in supposing it possible thai its publication Is calculated to do \"good ill\nthe cause of education,\"\nWishing you, gentlemen, every success in your noble enterprises\nof intellectual and moral improvement,\n1 remain your obedient servant,\nAnd fellow-laborer in the greui cause\nTo which your talents afe devoted,\nJ   N, MAFFITT.\nMessrs. J. A. Van Hoesen, S. II. B. Black, and O. V. II. Forbes.\nTHE INTELLECTUAL AND MORAL POWElt OF EDUCATION.\nAn Address delivered in Natchez on Hi\" evenlm \"i u.\" 16th .In'm, i-s. be,\nfore iho Adonis Onunly Association of Teachers i\nnl their first (lusrterljl niecllng, hy K\u00bbV.\nCalled by tho flattering suffrages of the Adams County\nAssociation of Teachers and Friends of Education, to address its first quarterly meeting, what better or more filling\ntheme can I select, lhan \"the Intellectual and Moral Bower\nof Education?\"\nThe American community is eminently utilitarian. The\nquestion ever is prone to come up respecting any theory or\nproject, what is it good for I What can it effect towards\npromoting the happiness of human life 1 To this test every\nmoral theory that gains admission on American ground must\nbe brought, and tho answer which either scrutiny or expen-\n\u00b0 , VOL. I.\u2014XIV.\ni.l Frio\n, N. MAvFrrr.\n\\h","fullrs":{},"find":"574.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"573","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1738671","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
