<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/516</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>516</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/516/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"30UTH-WE8TERN   J O U R M A L .\n\u201e,- woodland, which afford white and black oak, yellow poplar, hickory, chesnut, curlod maple, &amp;c. It is watered by uii--\nraerous and constant streams, affording a good supply of water power, and the wells, which are from thirty to fifty feet\ndeep, yield water of great purity, thereby contributing largely\nto the health und comfort of the inhabitants.\nThe basin of Rock Creek consists in a succession of subordinate hills between the more elevated ridges, supporting a\nsoil that varies according to tho nature of the subjacent strata.\nThey 'eirm what were formerly considered among the best\nhods in the country, but have been exhausted by repeated\ncrops of tobacco and corn, without any rest or return of vegc-\nlable nutriments, Hence a large portion of the county pre-\nisnts a barren aspect, with the exception of some few fields,\nwhich, by good management, have yielded profitable crops.\nTin's division embraces some fine tracts of woodland, consisting of oaks, hickory, sycamore, poplar and walnuts in the\nricher bottoms. It is well watered. The valleys ofthe several streams afford valuable meadow lands, and pure water\ncan be obtained in abundance.\nThe basin of the Seneca is well watered for agricultural,\nas well as manufacturing and economical purposes. In this\nregion occurs that valuable mineral, ore chrome. Serpentine\nis die prevailing rock, and where this occurs, the soil is poor\nand ill adapted to cultivation, but the mineral beneath makes\namends for this deficiency. In this division, also, the lands\nuro very generally waste and unimproved, though there are\nsome good farms. It is well watered, elevated and healthy.\nThe sugar lands are so called, from having been originally covered by tho sugar maple. Some of the most valuable\nestates of tho county arc located in this region, which presents ihe usual agricultural advantages, and by its proximity\ntu the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, enjoys great facilities for\nllic transportation of its products; which are principally tobacco, corn, oats, rye and wheat. The remainder of the report is taken up with remarks upon the agricultural condition\nof Montgomery county, its mineral resources, on the occurrence of coal in Frederic county, and some general observations.\n1C5\nFor the Hnntii.We-ntwni Journal,\nTHE STARS.\nBehind the hill-tops, in the distant west,\nThe sun lias sunk to sleep.   Now high above\nThe crowning circlet of thedark'ning woods\nThe merry stars are dancing,\u2014and ibc moon\nPeeps from ihe bound, with friendly lightsome smile,\nTo bid the weary traveler on his way, God speed!\nAnd tilings of busy day, arc seeking fast repose.\n'Tis night 1   Tlio epiiel night that seals our cares\nAnd bids us touch ihe cup that drowns our woes\nIn sweel, though Heeling memories of dreams.\nOh, what an hour for thoughts that higher fly!\nLook lo Iho studded sky 1   The jeweled stars,\nSet in the Ethiopian brow of night,\nArc food for musing.    On their glowing plains,\nCan there be aught of mundane likeness 1\nDoes Zephyr there unfold his silken wings,\nAnd nestle in llic bosom of the flowers'!\nDo they rejoice beneath a brighter skyl\nDo genial showers refresh the parched soil,\nAnd rushing rivers wake the forest life\nWith sounds of majesty 1   Do yellow fields\nThere wave with ripened grain\u2014Ihe glad reward\nOf honest toil 1   Do forms of fairy mould,\nBrighter than molhcr carlh can boast below\u2014\nforms that incite to love-lh' enthusiast's dream-\nForms that his wildesl dreams could scarce conceive,\nThere move in radiance!   What and whence arc ye-\nCan the musing sage point out 1   Sprite-like\nYe wand'rer through the fields of air, while sleep\nO'crpowcrs one half the world.   When morning dawns,\nWhere are ye 1   A mystery at most\nKnown butlo him that made ye.\nJ. P. Shannon.\nFor the Smith Wcntern Joitnul\nTUB   GIUL   OF   OTAHEITE\nFrom the; French of Victor Hiiro.\n\"And thou art benl lo leave me! to-night, with heavy heart,\nI heard thy sailors' joyous cry, \" to-morrow wc depart;\"\nThy snowy sails will bear thee, full swiftly o'er Ihe deep,\nAnd leave me sad and lonely, my billcr tears to weep.\n\" Why epiittcst thou our lovely isle 1   In thy strange home afar,\nThy skies are they more beautiful!   Are there no sorrows there 1\nThy friends there, when thou leaves! them, will they all mourn for\nthee 1\nAnd scatter o'er thy funeral bier, flowers of the plantain tree 1\n'Dost thou recal the hour, when first the western breeze\nDid waft thee to our smiling land, its hills and waving trees 1\nWhen thou calleel.st me in Ihe greenwood, tho' before to mc unknown,\nMy hean at once responded, to thy voice's magic tone.\n'Ah haply I was lovely then, for I bad felt nol sorrow's blight.\nWhich o'er my once bright sunny soul, halli cast the gloom of night.\nOh rest with us, young stranger, and sing me once again\nThe sung.s of thy own distant land, far o'er the dark blue main.\n\" Of thy mother I will talk to thee, and thou shall leach mo how,\nTo worship thy own people's God, to him my knee shall bow,\nAnd I'll call thee by Ihe name thou'sl borne in thy young childhood's\nhome,\nIf thou will rest thee always hero, nor seek again to roam.\nPerchance in thy own mountain land, e'en now sonic genlle maid\nIs looking out for thy return, beneath Ihe leafy shade)\nPerchance thou lov'st that gentle maid\u2014yet lake me home wilh\nthee,\nAnd I her duteous, humble slave, through all my life will bo.\n\"All wo is me ! if I should leave my hills and unlive groves,\nI'd wither like a bruised flower, torn from the soil il lovrs.\nYet belter thus lhan here to stay, heart-broken anel alone,\nAnd find this place (an Eden erst) a desert when thou'rt gone.\"\nNext morn the sun rose brightly, Ihe less'ning sail looked white,\nAs wing of snowy sea gull, that's glancing in the light;\nBul Ihe gentle girl of Olalieite, was never heard of more:\nShe was not on ihe gallant ship, nor on llic Greenwood shore.\nERNEar.\nThose things are to be cherished which tend to elevate us\nabove our ordinary sphere, and lo abstract us from our common and everyday concerns. The affectionate recollection\nand admiration of the dead will act gently upon our spirits,\nand fill us with a composed seriousness, favorable to tho best\nand most honorable contemplations.\nii','\n\u25a0' -Ca- \u25a0\nifi\n\u25a0J. :\u00bbf I\ni\nm\n\u25a0 ii\n_\n^^1","fullrs":{},"find":"517.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"516","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1616015","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
