<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/455</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>455</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/455/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"v\\,\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n85\nshore, and contracting the disease there, or by the introduction of infected air, &amp;c. Many other cases might be cited, in\nwhich infection has been generated and carried in ships into\nports, and there produced yellow fever in those from shore\nwho entered on board, although the crew of the vessel, being\nacclimated, remained free from disease.\nThe only point remaining, to establish the importability of\nepidemic yellow fever in ports, is whether the dissemination\nof the infected air of the ship in the vicinity of the wharf,\namong the crowds that frequent them, and reside near them,\ntogether with ten, twenty, thirty, or more cases, which were\ncontracted by going on board such vessels, be capable of\ncausing the disease to spread, among those contiguous, who\ndo not go on board, and this when the temperature of the\nsenson, and the sultry, and if desired, the miasmatic state of\nthe air. is in the most favorable condition for disseminating the\ndisease. Of this, we think there can be no reasonable doubt.\nDr. Rush, and his coadjutors in favor of the domestic origin\nof yellow fever, admitted that(it might, and had occasionally,\nspread from ships in an impure air.\nDr. Mitchell,* one of the most able advocates of the local\nor domestic origin of yellow fever, in a report made to Con\ngress, February 25th, 1803, admits, and even contends that\nvessels often become highly infected, while at sea; that an impure air is generated in the holds during hot, sultry weather\nin tropical climates: that this infection may be communicated,\nnot only to those who go on board, but that the infected air\nmay be diffused in the atmosphere about the wharves and\nshipping, and thus excite the disease more generally. He\ncontends, very properly, against useless and idle detention al\nquarantine, when no disease or infection has been on board\nthe vessel; but he urges the necessity of detention, and thorough ventilation and cleansing, in case of infection, until the\ninfection is destroyed. In all this he denies the foreign origin\nof infection. But is it not immaterial to those in sea port\ntowns, whether the infection be generated on board, or contracted in a foreign port? If it can spread among those\nwhere the. ship arrives, it is as important to guard against it,\nas if it were of foreign origin. Dr. Rush unequivocally\nadmits that there is much danger to bo apprehended from\n\"the foul air of ships,\" where cases of yellow fever have occurred. He also admonishes us, \"to prevent the landing of\npersons affected with the ship fever, in our cities, and the more\n\u2022longerons practice of ships pouring streams of pestilential\nair from, their holds upon Ihe citizens, who lire near the docks\nand wharves.\"    Med. Rep. vol. 6, p. 166.\nAgain, in a communication from Dr. Rush and others to\nGov. Mifflin, in relation to the yellow fever of 1797, in Philadelphia and Kensington, it is maintained, \" that, in addition\n'\"the filth and puirefaction about the city, the foul air issuing\nfrom the holds of two ships, (designated,) produced the. yellow\nfever, independently of foreign contagion.\" Again, the authors declare, that \"the close, unvcntilated holds of ships,\nafter long voyages in hot climates, with perishable matters\non board, thrown open in a heated, sultry atmosphere, arc a\nfruitful source of miasm: although they infer, that \" yellow\n' See Med. Repos. vol. 0, p. 400, 4c.\nfever has not been so often, propagated by contagion, as has\nbeen supposed.\"    See Med. Repos. vol. 2, p. 95, 96.\nWithout multiplying authority, we will cite one case which\nis full of instruction to those who preside over the port police\nof our cities. We mean the \" Yellow Fever \" of New York\nin the summer and fall of 1822. This epidemic, if it could\nbe so called, commenced by scattering cases from the 15th to\nthe 20th of July, and cases multiplied gradually until the\n15th of August, when it was considered epidemic. The\nwhole number of yellow fever cases, from the I5th of July\nuntil the 1st of November, when it ceased, was about four\nhundred and thirty, of whom about two hundred and fifty\ndied. It began in Rector street, near the wharf, where four\nships' cargoes had been discharged from infected vessels, a\nfew days before. From this point, it spread very slowly over\nseveral squares in the vicinity, having extended only a few\nsquares in thirty days: while the remainder of the city was\nunusually healthy. The squares over which it prevailed\nmost fatally, were bounded by wide, clean, and airy streets,\nand the most substantial buildings in the city: no filth could\nbe found in the vicinity; the infected air from the original infected point having been wafted thither by the winds.\nThese are the facts without speculation; viz : the first cases\nbegan between the I5th, and 20th of July. Between th\u00ab\n1st and the 9th of July, the cargoes of four infected vessels\nfrom Havana, were discharged at tho wharf nt the foot of\nRector street, and stored in warehouses. Two of these vessels had lost some of their crews by yellow fever, on the voyage; the crews of the other two were Spaniards and acclimated sailors. During tho first two weeks of July, the weather was very warm, the sun cloudless, nnd the air \"very\ncalm and sultry.\" During the months of July nnd August,\nthere were almost daily arrivals of other vessels from Havana, and other ports where yellow fever was known to be\nprevailing. During this period, the number of vessels from\nWest India ports was unusual; because, on account of the\nterror of pirates, they came in companies, under the convoy\nof battle ships. The following are the arrivals at the quarantine ground, between tho 11th of June, and the 17th of October ; viz: From Havana, eleven vessels, having, or having\nhad on board, forty-four cases of yellow fever and twenty-one\ndeaths; from Matanzas, one vessel, wilh three cases of yellow\nfever; from St. Jago, two vessels, having had three deaths\nfrom yellow fever; from Port au Prince, St. Domingo, four\nvessels, with six deaths from yellow fever : from Vera Cruz,\nbetween July 17th and 28th, three vessels, with nineteen\ncases and two deaths from yellow fever, before arrival. Besides these, there were, during that time, about forty other\nvessels from southern and West India ports, whose crews, being Spaniards or acclimated seamen, had no cases during their\nvoyage, although the air in some of the vessels proved infectious to those who wero unacclimaled.\nIf any ono will take the pains to examine the accounts of\nthis epidemic, as detailed by Dr. Townsend,* Dr. Bayley, and\nDr. Walters, and after making every allowance, especially\nto Dr. Townsend for his views of contagion, of that charity\nwhich the advocates of tho exclusive local origin of yellow\nit\nI\n\u2022 ,\u25a0:\u2666.\u2022!.-\";,\niMi\/ifoH\nII\n:\",\nin\n\u25a0 TV'l\n'1J\n\u2022 \u25a0 I\nr\nI\nS\n: i\n\u2022 Sco Townsend on Yellow Fever of New York, in 1822.","fullrs":{},"find":"456.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"455","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1802876","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
