<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 4, Page 5</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2152</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2152</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2152/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Section 4, Page 5","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"nothing to do, for several months, which both good policy\nand the economy required by the small amount of money to\nbe placed at tho disposal of the committee, forbade.\nThe executive committee, however, took early measures\nto secure the services of an able and experienced engineer,\nwhen he should be required,\u2014such a one as would meet the\nwishes and views expressed by members of the Convention,\nduring its session in June.\nWhen the time arrived to set the surveyor at work, the\nmoney to meet the expense to be incurred, was not ready,\nthrough no fault however, of this committee, as has been\nshown.\nThe active steps now being taken, will, it is confidently believed, secure the completion of the requisite surveys and\nestimates before the assembling of the Convention.\nThus much, as to the performance ofthe specific duties imposed upon the executive committee. Its members\nhave individually endeavored to promote the interests ofthe\nenterprise.\nMessrs. Lanfear and Stanton while at the north, during\nthe Summer, devoted much time and attention to the examination of railroads, They travelled over most ofthe northern\nand eastern roads, making attentive observations and careful\ninquiries in regard to their construction, cost, management,\nbusiness, profits, the employment of engineers, &amp;c, and\nobtained a great amount of valuable information for the be\u00ab\nBefit of this enterprise in which their confidence is confirmed, and to the completion of which they are now more thSn\never devoted.\nIt has been asked, why the executive committee do not\nbring the subject of this rail-road before the people in the\nPublic prints.\nThey have done so when they had any important information to communicate, and at no other time","fullrs":{},"find":"2153.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2152","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"544755","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.52 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
