<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/457</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>457</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/457/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"7\nS O U TII - W B S T E R N J 0 U II N A\n87\nharbor, and thus does not lack for infected air from ships, and\ncrowds of strangers upon whom it operates.    These, when\nattacked, contribute to the infection, which is like \" leaven\nin the contaminated ntmosphcrr, and assists in producing the\nepidemics.    Ibid, p. 78.\nAlthough the yellow fever is endemial all the year in Cuba, it is almost exclusively confined to the commercial ports.\nThe elevated savannas of the interior are as much a stranger\nto it, as our own interior towns. In the ports, it attacks principally Strangers, and prevails mostly from the beginning of\nJuly to the middle of November. When there is a great in-\nlluxof strangers, it becomes more malignant, and finally attacks many of the acclimated inhabitants, especially such as\nare exposed to the ordinary exciting causes of fevers. It is\nbelieved,among the people of Cuba, that the influx of stran-j\nr\/ers, and their numerous attacks from yellow fever, contaminates the air, or infects it, and causes it sometimes to become\nepidemic, when otherwise it would not have prevailed.\nTo produce yellow fever as nn epidemic in our cities, we\ntonceive three grades or stages of action in the production\nof tho infection:\u2014first, the miasm, or simple basis, which\nalone is innocent. 2d. Its combination with impure, or exhausted air, or with air deprived of its healthy, respiratory\nproperties, and charged with animal exhalations:\u2014in this\nstate, we call it infections air, or malaria. In this state, it is\na strong predisposing cause of disease, and a suitable \"nidus\"\nfor the reception and extension of personal infection. 3d.\nInfection, or the union of personal infection with infectious!\nair, or malaria. In this state, it is an aerial ferment: and,i\nwhen respired; becomes the active, predisposing, and exciting\ncauseof yellow fever.   These views we will further illustrate.\nFor Hie Bouth.Wcstern JoumA).\nOUR NATIONAL BANNER.\n1 iraee, in song, Ihe flight of Liberty;\nHei wanderings o'er the world.   When she was driven\nFrom Greece, where erst she had her residence,\nWhile equal laws prevailed, and Justice reigned,\nIn days when glory rested on her arms,\nHer name emblazoned on her shields alar ;\u2014\nWhen she was driven thence, I say,'lis said,\nShe wandered long lo find another home,\nAnd tipped her wearied wing, to light, at last,\nWhere Italy's fair clime of sunny hills,\nOf vineyards, groves, and flowery, fruitful plains.\nBreathe grateful incense to the balmy skies;\nAnd there she fixed her sign, and Rome arose,\nThe great, imperial Rome, that reigned so long,\nUnrivalled mistress of a conquered world.\nJoyful tiny bailed the Goddess Liberty,\nAnd bad..' her welcome to their skyey land.\nShe, too, rejoicing in the prospect fair,\nAm! smiling o'er her new adopted sons,\nSpread out her bannerol of equal rights,\nAnd o'er llicm reigned propitious.    While she reigned,\nRome sent her legions, conquering, and to conquer.\nThe Eagle, on her sign, displayed its wings,\nO'er cities, fromth' Atlantic's restless waves,\nTo where Ihe sun first gilds the coral strand\nOf India, with rays of morning light:\nFrom Nubia's desert, burning waves of sand,\nTo bleak Siberia's wilds of trackless snow;\nO'er them displayed its wings, in matchless pride,\nAnd tokenof dominion Absolute.\nThen, loo, the wisdom of her Senate shone,\nHer Cicero and Cineinnatus ruled.\nBut whither tied Ihe glory of those days '!\nAh ! vanished in the common wreck and ruin\nOf Ambition I   Contending heroes rose,\nWho strove for might; their common country rent,\nIts citizens involved in deadly strife,\nBy mutual hands, in impious conflict slain;\nThe eagle perched on high, their country's eagle.\nFrom his lofty ovry foully struck,\nAnd. on the altar of their madness.made\nA sacrifice, with all that once was thought\nThe pride of Rone\n~-: \"r-c. :.---:\u25a0- ;.w the change;\nH-:: :-.\".\u2022..:\u25a0\u25a0 \u25a0.1.-11 \u25a0_ -..-_. -::., : jir.s lie;\nH:.- -r\\.\\.:.-.:' &gt;z: : \u25a0:\nSi-s-.yrsi-.! ::-\u25a0\u2022:- a    -.--. -.- , of men once free:\nTree .. \u25a0-        .*      - -\u25a0--\u2022?: *.-\u2022: dropped a tear;\nAnd     .\u25a0   : -     P :-\u25a0--:;. Rome, thy sun is set,\"\nForsooi ihe \u00abnnny clime, and fled for aye\nWhere dwelt she then 1\nOr did \u00abhe seek again,\nHer native land, the classic soil of Greece,\ni Ir visit fair Hispanla's fields of gold,\nTo gain a glitteringwreath. or golden fane 1\nOr wander forth, to ancient Gallic shores,\nThe land of armies, chronicled of old,\nFor numbers and Ibr deeds on record high,\nTo seek a lasting home, and empire there;\nAnd league those armies in her own bright cause,\nTo spread the victories of Peace around,\nAnd Europe's legions bind, in freedom's chains'.'\nI 'r sought she Albion's lonely sea-girt isle,\nTo dwell retired, and far from din of arms,\nAnd. e'er a few. hold mild and gentle sway'!\nAit. no I    The tyrants of the Eastern world\nHad, in a mad conspiracy, combined\nTo blot her name, and drive her from the earth\nShe lived a wanderer in banishment,\nBeholding from afar, the train of woes\nWhich then betel the hapless race of men.\nShe saw Oppression's iron rod of death\nIndict its bloody stripes on Innocence!\nShe heard the threatening voice of despots, bid\nThe dungeon, rack, and guillotine prepare,\nFor victims doomed to gratify the thirst\nOt cursed cruelty with Innocent blood!\nThe ponderous wheel of death, reeking wilh gore,\nHeard crush the martyr for the truih of God,\nDying to stamp the seal of its divinity;\nAll saw and heard, and wept the Folly,\nOnly eau.se of all, but only wept:\nShe lived in exile still!\nAt length il dawned,\nHer rising slar, long set in deepest night,\nAnd shone, in brilliancy', o'er western skies.\nThe moment, signalled from eternity,\nArrived, when,tired of a world of bonds,\nOf stripes and tears, for ages felt and poured,\nShe spread her pinions for her destined clime.\nA new empire was rising to the view,\u2014\nAnd there wero those, who, having lied like her,\nFor refuge, to Columbia's distant wilds,\nBeyond oppression's reach, (thus fondly hoped,\nBut followed thence,) again, in holy strife,\nTo blood, were vindicating human rights.\ni'l'i\nm\nm\n-.' .\u2022&gt;\nIt.'A\n:  I\n'Ml\n\u25a0: m\n-Ml: .\nifi\n\u25a0 \u2022'. oil\ni'i\n.v.'\nI   M\n,1     \u2022!\n.'\u00bb\u2022\n'il\n.,.--:\n9.\nK\n:A\nil\n1\ni\nt'!\na\nn","fullrs":{},"find":"458.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"457","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1631604","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
