<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 38</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2102</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2102</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2102/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 38","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"38\nMr. Glendy Burke, moved the following prcam\nand resolutions :\nWhereas, There are evidences throughout the Souti\nStates of an awaking spirit of enterprise in the construe\nof railroads; and whereas, New Orleans, from her posj\nand connections, is deeply interested in the promotio\nthese roads, and their concentration upon points whichj\nintersect with the roads now in projection from our ij\nit is\nResolved, That a committee of five be appointed bjj\nPresident of this convention, whose duty it shall be to]\npare an address to the people of the southern and wej\nstates, setting out with all the facts and statistics they\ngather, the various railroad projections in which these si\nhave a direct and immediate interest, and the hearty co-\nration which New Orleans and Louisiana is prepared fl\ntend to them all, and inviting the people of these state\nmeet us in convention, in the city of New Orleans\nfirst Monday in January next, [in the resolution, as presd\nby Mr. Burke, it was December, but changed subsequerJ\nin order to an exchange of views and opinions, and, iu\nsible, a concentration of unity of effort in the extensl\nour railroad system.\nResolved, That the committee have authority, during\nensuing summer and fall, to represent the views of Newi\nleans in these matters, in any of the states it may be in!\npower to visit, and that the agencies of the press, in\nof the convenntph, be respectfully solicited.\nMr. Burke accompanied the resolutions with i\npertinent and able remarks.    He said that foi\npurpose of keeping the prosperity  of the   Sa\nsome great system of railway enterprise slmulAf\nadopted, and he moved these resolutions that soj\nthing should be done, during the next sitting \u00b0'","fullrs":{},"find":"2103.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2102","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"501271","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.48 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
