<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 24</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/580</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>580</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/580/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 24","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"Erf!!\nIB* p.?\nII; v\u25a0\nit'i,'.-1 '\u25a0\n#.l.;ie\n\u00a7fri.\nIP\"\nII; \u25a0;\ni \u25a0 \u25a0\n210\nSOU T H - W E S '1' E B N   J 0 U R N A L.\n\u2022hr\n\u2022'e&gt;\n$5\nI\niff\n:;\ni i \u25a0'\nii.- j\nJ Jit\n\\! 'if\n. .',\n!\n'\u25a0\ning people had conquered Mexico, as Rome had been vanquished by the Goths, and China by the Tartars. The existing people were called the Azteques, the vanquished were\nthe Tnltequcs: as in other instances, (he former preserved\nmany of the monuments and customs, and acquired some ol\nthe knowledge of the latter. This they acknowledged ; and\nis recorded. The Mexicans asserted that they had come\nfrom tho hyperborean regions of America; and had taken\nthe country they possessed from a different tribe. They further stated that their country had originally been peopled by\n\" wandering builders or masons.\" This is proved not only\nby their tradition nnd assertion, but by their hieroglyphical\nor picture writings, which record their feats or transactions.\nBut both the Azteques and Tulteques wero red and beardless\nmen, ns represented on nil their hieroglyphics.\nNow history records the country and vicissitudes of an\nextinct race of red men; not only whoso appearance, but\nwhoso customs, language nnd religion are identified with\nthose that existed or had existed, in Mexico particularly, and\nAmerica generally, when discovered during the 15th century. The primitive race was variously designated. Sometimes tho people were termed 'shepherds' or 'shepherd\nkings,'as in the Pentateuch; ' wanderers,' 'wandering masons,' 'giants,' ' Cyclopcans,' 'Pelasgians' or 'Peleginns,'\ni. e. of the race of Peleg mentioned in Genesis, und afterwards Phoenicians, etc., according to the country which they\ninhabited. They were the great Cyclopean family, commonly called 'Titans,' in mythology, from their various architectural foals in building temples or towers und pyramids,\nwhose summits reached the clouds or heavens.    This hnbi-\nof Tyro, and of Carthage, forms u prominent part of ihe\ntransactions of those reel men.\nIt is recorded that they were the first lo invent signs or let-\nlers for sounds, if not the first to invent symbols for transactions and idens: they invented the phonetic language or hieroglyphics, and they improved at least the symbolical. To\nCadmus, one of their race, Greece acknowledges to havo\nowed ils language of letters or writings; and his arrival in\nthat country is generally held synonymous with the flight of\nIsrael from Egypt, or 1491 before Christ. The characters\nhe brought were essentially Phenician or Pelasgian; and\nhad been previously introduced into Egypt. They were\nknown to Moses; nnd it may bo supposed he used them in\nwriting the second edition of his decalogue, And it is not\nunreasonable to infer that they hail been used previously in\nwriting the book of Job. At least history sanctions lhc\nidea that they had been used by the various nations of Canaan\u2014who were of the Cyclopean, Anakim or Pelegian\nrace, and had been expelled by Joshua. The temples, lab-\nlets nnd inscriptions of those Ciinaanites tally accurately\nwilh those of the Phenieians and with those formerly and\nstill extant in Mexico. The ruins of Taehnor in the wilderness, are akin to those of Paleiiijiio in Mexico.\nTo those Phenieians or Ciinaanites may fairly be attributed the primitive or original colonization of. America, both\neastwaidly and westwardly. That the Phenieians visited all\npails, and discovered many portions of the old world, is a\nfact well authenticated, and that they had ships capable of\nnavigating the ocean, as well as inland seas, is equally irdtl-\nbilable.    Their passage from Spain and Africa to the British\ntude of masonry, or free-masonry, to congregate and fortify Isles, is fully attested, end thai they had discovered an ultimo\nthemselves wherever they dispersed, was their prominent\n.characteristic, while pastoral Iribes or nations; although Subsequently, when they engaged in commerce nlso, as in Tyre\nand Carthage, Egypt and Greece, lliey became as celebrated\nfor other arts as for architecture, They invented the various\nphonetic und symbolic, characters; and have left vestiges of\ntheir monuments and acts, wherever they visited or settled.\nAnd those vestiges are alike in the new world as in the old,\nThey may be traced from Babel to Syria, Egypt, Greece,\nCarthage, anil various parts of northern Africa, to Spain, and\niho British Isles, on one side of the early colonization of the\nearth\u2014and to Persia, Ophir, India, China, and Japan, on the\neastern side from where ihe Noachidie resided. Existing\nmonuments, tablets, nnd inscriptions interspersed in various\ncountries, of precisely the same tenor and characters, attest their peregrinations as plainly as history itself could;\nand are as strong sources of testimony, when united with\ntradition, as any human record could be.\nHistory records the expulsion of a race of red men from\nEgypt, by one of its most celebrated kings, prior to the exit\nof the Israelites; (and not at all identified with them,) and\nthat to those red men or shepheid kings, did Egypt chiefly\nowe her northern pyramids, hor hieroglyphics and her religion. Doubtless ihi'se were subsequently imitated and amplified by their conquerors; but sufficient vestiges of the\noriginals still remain, to justify an identity wilh like movements, wherever they exist.    The history ofthe Phenieians,\nihule, distinct from the obi world, is more than a subject ol\nmere tradition': for it is positively recorded in the history of\nCarthage, thai the discovery and possession of such a country formed a slate secret with the Carthaginian government\nand that both Tyre'and Cartilage had acquired much of llieir\npeculiar wealth from that country. Those who are versed\nin ancient history will understand and admit this j and those\nthoroughly conversant, may admit also the singular account\nof the Phenieians traversing oven llic Cape of Good Hope.\nTo others the proofs would be too tedious, and probably useless.\nThe etymology of spoken languages is seldom a safe\nguide to the derivation of nations.: lor vowels are nothing,\nand consonants next to nothing, even in the etymon of languages themselves. But symbolical or written language\nmay approximate safely in nn identification, Hence it is\nthat the original colonists of Spain nnd Ireland have been\ntraced to Rhcnicia; and by a very similar proce-ss, the primitive seniors of America may be also triced to the same people or country, Not only that Phenician inscriptions, etc\nhave been -discovered in Massachusetts and other northern\nparts; and that the Mohawk or Iroquois language, with that\nof various Indian tribes, is u counterpart of ihe Phenician\u2014\nml Phenician monuments or memorials of various kinds, so\nabound even slill in Mexico (as they did also partially in\nPeru,) as to leave litlle doubt in the mind of any candid person of an original identity between the Phenieians or Oa-\nnaanites and the aboriginal Americans.","fullrs":{},"find":"581.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"580","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1782881","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
