<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 6</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2115</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2115</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2115/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 6","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"1825, though in January, 1829, says the Rail-Road Journal, there\nwas not a road in operation on which locomotive engines were successfully used as the propelling power ! In 1832, there were ninety-\ntwo miles in operation, and the utmost that \"was claimed for them\nwas, that they would answer for light parcels and passengers. In\nthe 20 years that followed, there have been constructed 7,000 miles\nof rail-roads in the United States.*\nUp to 1845, there had been expended in the United States 110\nmillions of dollars upon rail-roads, which were yielding at that time \u25a0\nan average interest of five per cent.; whilst in the same period 150\nmillions had been squandered on banks, which had r^-ried ruin before them.\nLet us briefly consider some of the effects of rail-roads as they\nmanifest themselves upon population, industry, wealth and society.\n1. Upon Population.\u2014It will not be denied that very much of\nthe settlement of a country depends upon the capacities afforded of\ncommunication and transport. Even inferior lands will be cultivated,\nif within reach of a market, whilst the most productive will remain\nin a state of nature, or with the most limited population. The arguments which apply to common roads are strengthened in the case of\nturnpikes; still more on plank roads and canals, and in the highest\ndegree on rail-roads, which introduce the potent element of steam.\nIt is common experience that settlements and large towns will spring\nup on the route of a rail-road, where hitherto nothing but farmhouses were to be seen, except at its termini. The traveler at the\nNorth will be struck with this every hour. These villages and towns\nbecome themselves the centres of a back population, and give rise\nto the opening of new lands, and thus the area continually widens.\nThe history of the West is strongly in point. When she was shut\noff from the Atlantic by a road of 60 days, or a flat boat navigation\nquite as long, the progress of population and products was slow, revolutions were openly discussed, and a separate government adequate to her necessities, proposed. The power of rail-roads and\nsteam has changed the whole aspect of things, and the West, which\nhad but 300,000 at the close of the last century, contained, in 1820,\n2,207,463; in 1830, 3,672,569; in 1840, 5,302,91\u00a7, and reaches\nnearly 10,000,000 at the present time. How much larger might have\nbeen the population, had facilities like those of New-York and Massachusetts been enjoyed, may be readily imagined. It will not do to\nargue that population must come before rail-roads. It is possible\nto stimulate and excite it! If the natural facilities of rivers and navigable streams exercise great influence on the growth of population,\nas in the history of settlement none can deny, will not other facilities\nof a like, or even a different character, have the same effect ? Population follows the rivers, and not rivers the population, and so is it of\nrail-roads.\n2. Upon Industry.\u2014A people dependent upon mere production,\nand incapable of exchanging, can only remain in savage barbarism.\n* See Appendix for Extract, from De Bow's Review, in farther illustration.","fullrs":{},"find":"2116.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2115","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"584943","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
