<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/399</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>399</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/399/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"34\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n,'\nWas there any indication of public approbation, or any demonstration, but those ofthe most apathetic indifference7\nFor i;\"arly ten years from this period, the Trustees, altho'\nstruggling under embarrassments of iho most perplexing\nkind, maintained, for tlic greater portion of the time, such a\n.school ns (lie neighborhood Seemed to require, frequently subjecting themselves; thereby, to pecuniary liability in their private capacities The incofisidejable sums which were recovered from escheats, nlwny.-1 uiTlirm-d by costs, were insufficient to pay the demands against the institution for carrying\nmi tlm s'nil with the city of Natchez; and, on account of the\ndebts referred to, the trustees were frequently haVrrassed by\nexecutions levied upon the college edifice and other properly.\nA large portion of these debts wore assumed anil paid by\nsome of the persons co'rilposingihe Board nt that time, and a\nlew of their friends; some id whom, after an interval of\ntwelve or fifteen years, have not yi 1 been reimbursed. So far\nfrom deriving any rcveriue from public pntroiaagf?, during\nthis period, some of those debts were c online ted on account\nof Instructors; the tuition received In ing insufficient to discharge their salaries!\nTo pursue these reminiscences to a more recent poribd,-we\ncomonexl to that only bright era in its history, when the In-\nstittition was organized on the military plan, and placed in the\nrim;.. 'of Messrs. Willistonnnd Holbrook. Then we hadn\ndistiiiBl manifestation of public approbation mid favor. Wiih-\noii, tie' expenditure of a dollar for salaries or any guarantee\ni-i losses, the Institution assumi d at mice ihe most (lour-\nAtnid the sneers and sarcasms of i,s enroll of thoso perpetual cavillers who can\nr, i, imparted a degreo of improvement and\nan !!\u2022 ilul in the State.\nPC\nishing condition,\nmies, \"I flie derii\napprove of nothii\npublic benefit, un;\nTo this period woshnll have occasion again, to refer; suffice ii. for the present, to say, that tin's prosperous career was\nto elTecl ii rniinnti d, by the lamented death of Mnj. Holbrook.\n'I'll is I'vrii: occurred hear the most important crisis in the forum- o, the Institution. Relief from debt and pecuniary cm-\nbaii'.is oii'iil, and a permanent nnd ample revt'iiiie, were then\nIn ci tain prospect. An act pf imparallelled liberality, ob-\ntnim I :'. ... Congress nt n most important juncture, was in\nprogress i execution, and gave assurance, that the Trustees\nneed nevi r again lie' dependent upon tlio capricious favor of\nthe public, for the means of conducting ihe institution; and\nii is from this period, about thirtyyears after i, i 'as chartered,\nthat its i rustenct i hould properly be d -led. Perha] 9 the sud-\nden transition, from poverty to nflluencc, gave rise to extravagant views nn.l expectations. It led to a recurrence to old\nestablished systems, based upon a preference for the cultivation of the ancient languages, rather than tin; acquisition of\nmore practical mid scientific knowledge; and inspired something, not unlilcecontcmpt, for the adventitious aids of modern\ninnovations.\nli dissipated the lessons, and lost us, for n time, the advantages of past experience. Eager to anticipate the expectations\nof ihe public, before a dollar was available from ihe proceeds\nof the college lands, some of the Trustees raised a loan, subsequently discharged, which was so invested as to afford some\nincome until the resources of tho Institution should be real\nized.    Professors were employed, their numbers increased,\nnnd salaries enlarged, from time to time.    For this the whole ft\nincome of the college has not sufficed, but considerable in. I\nroads have been made upon its capital.    The proportion existing between the expenditures for professors, and the receipts\nfor tuition, during this period, show plainly with what eflect \u00a3\nthis lias been done.    The proportion, for the past session, he-  ^\ntween those items being more lhan seven to one ngainst the\nInstitution.  For that period, we have been paying, at the rate\nof more than seven thousand dollars per annum, for educating  '\ness lhan fifty students.\nSuch, in part, have been the fortunes of Jefferson College\nThey bear a striking similitude lo the numerous struggles\nwhich have attended the oldest and best institutions of leant- *.\/.\ning in ihe Union, and form the ordeal, it would seem, through\nwhich all must pass to arrive at a tolerable 'degree of ma-     '.\nturily.\nFrom this review, and all ihe information we have ac- I\nquired, (ho conclusion, to our minds, is irresistible, that the   :'.-.\ncommunity is greatly in default to this Institution.    How- mF]\never   humble  may havo  been   its   pretensions \u2014 however I\nimited its means, it has never, during its whole career, re-   '\u25a0'\nceived that degree of patronage to which it was entitled ; we \u25a0   \u00bb\nexcept, of course, the period of ils military organization, \u25a0\nWe say that this Institution has not received that support\nfrom the public to which it was entitled and had a right to\nclaim, if the policy and necessity of clearing institutions of\nlearning at home be admitted.    But this is a conclusion \u2022*\u25a0_\"'\nwhich we believe the people of our State are far from having I\narrived at; at least they do not act upon that principle:\nThe general diffusion of wealth in our country enables\nalmost every ono to send their sons abroad for education, t\n.\u2022onrse lo which a variety of circumstances impels them:\u2014\nimong these arc the gratification of the pupil,\u2014the advantages of travel in enlarging Iho mind, maturing tho understanding, and in imparting in early life a knowledge of the\nworld, and keeping up an intercourse with and an attachment for friends, relatives, or institutions, which the parent\nhas cherished and desires to perpetuate.\nNol iho least of these, perhaps, is the rational nmbitioa,\nshall we nol say, of deriving their collegiate honors from the .'\nilma mater of some of that multitude of worthies, whose high\nnames and bright destinies have conferred a lustre upon our\ncountry. True, ihero arc some fearful hazards of moral\ncontamination in this removal from paternal restraint; but '\nhave the numerous instances of ruined hopes and blasted expectations rendered these risks less frequent?\nIndeed, it must be admitted, that in the state of tho morals .\nof our own country, and the force of example, by which I\nyouth is encompassed, wo cannot feel assured of security in I\nthis respect in our own public institutions.    The strictly pru-1\ndent, therefore, seek safety for their offspring in solilary in-1\nstruction; and, in consigning their sons to private tutors, arc .      |\ncontent lo sacrifice something in the variety and profundity \u25a0 '\nf their knowledge, to preserve their minds pure and their . \u2022\u00a3 (\nmorals unblemished.\nThese considerations have operated, and must necessarily \u2122    |\ncontinue  long to operate.    Few will enter our own public   \u25a0\nii:\nB9\n-I-","fullrs":{},"find":"400.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"399","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1891782","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.80 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
