<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/400</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>400</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/400/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n88\ninsitutions, for the purpose of pursuing, to its completion, a\ncourse of liberal and 'classical education) nor, indeed, wi\nthey bo generally resorted to ns n preparation for the more\nvenerated northern universities. The difficulty, then, of\nraising olir domestic institutions of learning to even an ap-\n. proneh to eminent distinction, exists in the condition and feelings of society, Under this state of things, colleges may be\nendowed, and professorships crealed, but it will only ho to real,\nize the sarcasm, of \"the empty dome and pensioned preceptors.\"\nUntil tho feelings, views and interests of the communily\nin which we live, are brought to co-operato in giving support\nand celebrity to our institutions, they must, notwithstanding\ntheir revenues and endowments, wither in comparative obscurity.\nThis adaptation of tho public sentiment to such ends, seems\never to have been, in all communities, a tardy process. How\n, long since Virginia herself, \"the Ancient Dominion,\" or her\nsister States, ceased to bo tributary to Harvard, to Yale, or to\nPrinceton ; and, in turn, through what neglect and adversity\ndid they pass to their present proud rank and enviable pre-eminence. However it may- be desired, it is not to be expected,\nthat they, with their amassed stores of learning, their ac-\n&amp; cumulated honors and reputation will have less hold on the\nregard of the people of Mississippi than of other States, or\nthat the vast improvements of the ago, and the imparallelled\nfacilities of traversing the remotest corners of our extended\ncountry, will fail to allure votaries fiom every quarter to their\nvenerated shrines.\nSuch, in our belief, are the primary\u2014the essential causes\nthat  havo restricted   the usifuhicss of Jefferson College.-\nMinor difficulties, however, exist, of sufficient moment to r\nquire some notice at our hands.    The most erroneous notions\nseem lo prevail   in  relation to this institution, even ainom\n(hose who might easily have been bettor informed, particular\nly as regards its resources and income.    It is generally understood to be richly endowed.    What aro tho facts?    Until\nthe sale of its lands, in 1833, it had no fixed income.    The\nfirst payment, under those sales, became duo  about  March,\n183-1.    Of iho instalments falling due at that lime, and those\nof 1835, '3G and '37, a considerable portion has not been paid.\nSojn'e of the purchasers have not yol paid one cent.    The\nperiods for the final payments do not arrive until  the year\n18311, from Marchto August,\u2014until when, tho Trustees can- ,u   ^^j,,,,,\nnot effectually  coerce payment from the defaulters,    The jjfcjjtenctl de\nmortgages then render the debts secure.    Nearly the only*\nincome, (that accruing from tuition being very incoiisjjjprn\nbid,) arises from tho investment of tho moneys rcceijfM fo;\ncollege lands.    The whole amount  of tho interest  on the\nmoneys invested as a permanent fund, and the tuition received\nhas (iccn expended in ihe employment of a President nnd\nProfessors, and other considerable expenditures which have\nbeen incurred on account of purchases for the library and apparatus, and in otherwise preparing the Institution for tho reception and education of students.\nMuch of this information is to bo found in the  reports on\ndie finances of March and August last.    For convenience,\nhowever, we subjoin a summary statement of the fiscal condition of the Institution to the period of the latest disbursement.\nThe institution possesses\nReal Estate, valued at        -        .        -        $43,150 00\nRank Stock, amounting to -        - 01,500 00\nBills receivable, - 77,142 O'.l\nSuspended debt, .... 57,313 80\nLibrary and apparatus,       -       -       . 3,000 00\nSpecial Deposito in off. P. Bank, Columbus,    1,772 90\nCash, 3,148 70\nThe debts ofthe Institution; due principally to the Stale\nand the city of Natchez,Will, in 1339, amount to about\n827,000.\nThis statement will show that tho Trustees are expending\non instructors all they have properly a right to touch for that\npurpose. The salaries, if not satisfactory to the recipients,\nare certainly such as lo command the most respectable grade\nof talents, and are far greater, we fear, than the amount. I\nbenefit conferred on tho community would authorize, if we\nrefer to our catalogue of students. Of salaries, we believe\nthey should not be subject to increase or diminution during\nthe incumbency of any officer. This would save\" the board\nmany harrassing iinpoiluin'ties, and rid it of one cause of dissatisfaction and murmuring.\nThe destruction of the .Steward's house, and the dispersion\nof the students in private fnnilies, have doubtless, in some degree, been prejudicial\u2014principally so as regards the enforce- .\nmcnt of discipline. r\nOilier schools have flourished, however, urieler siuiilttwlfs-\nldvnntagcs; and it is known to us that some have href! conducted with great success without a Slcwmd's department.\nIndeed the disadvantages could not have proven very -g^eat,\nwhen we recollect that parents have generally considered it n\nvaluable privilege to be suffered to board tboir children in\nprivate families, rather than in commons. Although few, il.-'\nany private families were anxious to have the hoarding ol\nstudents, still five.tin,isns many as applied last session could\nhave been very comfortably provided ibr. A building, how-\never, fdr Ihe accommodation of the Steward's department;\nbavin\" bee'n contracted for since ibis committee was raised\naffords an opportunity of removing this difficulty.\nVery much liqs been said of the religious churncter oftli\nIiisUWtieilij'i^ruiiliivoralde comparisons have been recently\ndrawn btjf&amp;ccn this and a flourishing institution in pur vic-iii-\n\u2022ftfiiliicted  Under the  auspices of an  influential and t u-\nnomination of christians. :iss\u00ab3*\nSectarian institutions are necessarily well patronized\u2014all\nof tho denomination to which they belong are prompted by\nevery impulse lo cherish nnd support them; and in this instance, that support, derived from a numerous class asdistin\ngushed for great wealth as unbounded liberal;; v, lias ';\u2022-u.\nxtended, we understand, with no stinted hand. Oilier denominations rear their institutions in different quarters, pi i\nhaps with similar advantages; each look within themselves\nchiefly for support. There is-no interference with each (\u2022!,\ner's rights or privileges. They exist in their own pecnllai\nlimits, promote- their own legitimate interests, upon which\nnone desire to encroach.    This is all right and  laudable;\nx*\"*.","fullrs":{},"find":"401.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"400","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1676273","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.60 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
