<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/563</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>563</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/563/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"la myself, sought me on the afterguard, where 1 hod stohi,\nuaobs-irvcd to brood over my own thoughts. With an en\nibtislasm well enacted, he told me to listen to the grateful\nttwihe had to communicate and \"congratulate him on tin\nprospect of endless bliss. Now,Clara I \" he exclaimed, \" ii is\nfjt you to say, when that happiness shall be secured to me\nbeyond the reach of fate ; your father has left you to be the\narbiter of my future destiny.\"\n\"Three days hence,\" I replied, \"we will reach New Orleans; I should wish\u2014I wont time for\u2014the truth is\u2014pshaw!\nI dont know what I want.\"\n\"Say at once, my dear Clara, that on the expiration of a\nwe.de from next Monday,   you  will accompany me to the\naltar?\"\n\"twill, but if I am to be married, it must be in the church.\"\n\"As you desire! \"\n\"Of this, then, we speak no more, it being a settled mat-\nler; and now let us to the cabin, for I perceive we are observed.\"\nSOUTH-WESf ERN JOURNAL.\nnd arranging themselves on either side in\n100\n, ,       . \u2014 marnage array,\nconscious that the eyes of hundreds were upon us\" and rev\nsou being wrought up for any event, I should not have cow\nered\/al that moment beneath the goze of all ihe marshalled\nhosts ol Louisiana. He proceeded in the ceremeny, till r.t\nlength he arrived at the solemn question, upon the faithful adherence to the answer of which, depends the happiness of millions,    Addressing himself to Herbert he continued\u2014\n\" George Herbert, will ihou have this woman to thy wed-\nded wife, to live together after God's ordinance, etc\u2014to\nwhich Herbert made the required answer\u2014\"1 will.\" Turning to myself, \" Clara Perryan,\" said he\u2014\"wilt thou have\nthis man to thy wedJed husband, to live together after Gcd's\nordinance, in ihe holy estate of matrimony ? Wilt thou obey\nhim, and serve him, love, honor and l.eep him, in sickness\nand in health : nnd forsaking all others, keep thee only unto\nhim, so long as ye both shall live?\" \"Neter'l\" I almost\nshouted, and spinning from me the thunderstruck Heibeit, I\nexclaimed\u2014\"I did not inter this sacred temple to profene its\nThat night I caught a bad cold, from Dame Policy, and lloi.V \"seby leaguing myself with the devil in human shape!\ntook my mess in our own cabin until we reached Orleans, \"e lnal w'\" tlarnj.le upon the holiest ties that bind man to\nwhen Herbeit and my father accomrankd me to my uncle's\nresilience, where, as each hour rolled by, I thought I was an\nhour nearer the fateful moment whet] 1 should bicome either\nihe victim or the victor.    Herbert visited me daily until the\nwoman, and can insult the Most High by prostituting e.ne cf\nhis divine oidinar.ccs to the base purpose of giatii'ying a lust\nfor gold, shall never Ic husband of mine! I came hereto\nhold up to public scorn this perjured pattern of infamy, and\nportentous Monday arrived, and having received many callf,'TeF\u00b0\"tne wrongs dene my sex by the hollow-hearted wretch-\n'twas soon rumored after the usual manner, that \"thchand-l\u2122 who apostatize from their plighted faith, made doubly bind-\n\u00bbmi George Herbert would lead the accomplished Miss Pcr-'.\u21228 by an appeal to the Deity to witness the sincerity of their\nnjMio the altar.\" Melmoth, I cannot tiuly dcsciibe my'professions. To accomplish this, 1 depait from modesty,\nfadings en this occasion, but they were not in keeping with;hrave public opinion, and run the risk of tarnishing the lus-\nray sex. Thoroughly convinced that I had been the dupe cf ire of a name I esteem somewhat revere rely, but an innate\nstudied vindictive nets, and then was about to escape by acci.lmc-nitor tells me that my motives are as pure as the law it-\ndent the sacrifice of my affections to cne whose soid'id pas- self whose penalty is death to a villain that robs a-neighbor\nshins were to have been gratified at the expense of my happiness, I could scarcely await the hour of departure for the\nchurch. At length it arrived; attired cap-a pie in white,\nwith simply a white fillet of silken plush bound about my\nof his life I anel is not he equally a murderer, who joiscr.s\nthe fount whence flows all that renders life dear lo our sex?\nTo you, most reverend sir, and to this respectable assembly, I\nknow not how to make reparation for having ihns publicly\nhead, I almost leaped into the carriage, accompanied by my travelled out of my sphere, and con only hope my motives\nfather, my cousins Isabel and Eugene, who w&lt; re lo wait up- will plead an excuse.\" Tinning to the pei.ified Heibeit,\non lis, and the devoted George Heibeit, 'J he horses dashed whose eyes darted curses at me so soon as mine wcie fixed\non, the wheels of the caniage rattled over the stones, and op- \u00abP\u00b0n him, I continued, \" fox you, sir, I have a parting word :\norated on my feelings like ihe shrill horn upon the soldier's go hide that fair tenement of thy pigmysoul in some secluded\nh\u00abrt on the eve of battle.    T..e horses were soon reined up cave, and never again enter the pale of civilization till ycu\nIn front of the church ; Herbert handed me out of ihe carriage,\nand we entered the sacred fane together, my father leadin;\nthe way, whilst my cousins brought up the rear. Th.\nhouse, was crowded; and flushed with excitement, I felt a:\nthough the blood of all my insulted family galloped through\nmy veins, as with a measured step I proceeded down ihe\noisle with a man whose touch was pollution to my very\nthoughts, and seemed to feed my passion for revenge. We\ntook our seats with my uncle's family, listened to the beautiful service so well calculated to inspire us with feelings o,\nawe, after which an impressive lecture was delivered by the\ndivine upon the duties of man and wife, when wc were ordered to approach the altar for marriage.    Upon tho arm ol\nhave made peace with your God!    Sooner than devote your\nlife to destroying the peace of domestic circles, 'twere better\nyou should die by your own hand,\" and drawing from my,\ntirdle a small poniard I had concealed there before I left\nmy uncle's, I added, hurling it at Herbert's feet, \"here is a\ntrusty blade\u2014I bequeathe it to you as a legacy!\"    The\nscorn which my feelings must have sent to my fe alurcs at this\nmoment, was returned by a scowl from Heibeit, end I had no\nsooner finished speaking, than he snatched up, tho dagger,\nushed at me with the weapon raised above his head, and\nwould have taken my life, had not my enraged father caught\nthe desperado's arm, and with a herculean effort dashed him\nover the balustrade.    Recovering himself and stung almost\nI\nT\ni;ft \\ .\n:   t\nm\n:;...;\nHerbert I advanced to the vestal shrine, my cousins dividing |t0 madness, be again raised the poniard, plunged it to .he hilt","fullrs":{},"find":"564.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"563","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1872063","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
