<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Duplantier Letters Transcripts</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Special Collections Online</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-sce:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <note type="preferred citation" displayLabel="Cite As">LSU Special Collections Online, Louisiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.</note>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/LSU_SCE/id/258</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2007-02-16</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-11-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>LSU_SCE</alias>
         <pointer>258</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/LSU_SCE/258/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-02 09:47:14">{"title":"Duplantier Letters Transcripts","creato":{},"date":{},"dates":{},"publis":{},"contri":{},"subjec":{},"descri":{},"notes":{},"langua":{},"transc":"LSU Libraries Special Collections\n\nArmand Duplantier Letters January 10, 1796 [Duplicate] Finally, my good friend, they have just published La Paix for us here on the first day of the year, which we were awaiting with much impatience. I hope, dear brother, that now I will receive your dear news a little more often. For more than three years, I have not received a single word from any of my relatives. I do not know what has become of you during all that trouble. I am undergoing the greatest impatience to receive some word and fear at the same time learning anything that will perhaps be too troublesome for me. Write me, then, by all routes. That of Spain will be, I think, the most prompt. I sent you this by the American route. I hope also that French ships will come to us and that they will bring me your news. I have written to you and to my father every year by the American route, asking you to give me your news by that route, but I have not received any. I hope that you have received some of mine. I was giving you all the details on what I had done with my uncle's succession. I believe that this year the greatest portion of the funds will be returned, that I will have ready first orders that I will receive from my relatives. The plantation is not sold. The times have been so critical and so unfavorable that I have not aimed to sell it. I have successfully made the sale of slaves. Otherwise, there would have surely been a great deal of compromise due to an insurrection of Negroes that almost occurred last spring in this colony and that had to start at Pointe Coupe. Happily, the thing was discovered in time. They sentenced fifty of them and some leaders, who were all Creoles or Negroes of talent, which stopped their scheme. Despite that, we were not at ease until the moment when they informed us through La Paix. The example of St. Domingue still troubles us. I have much regret over having bought a number of them. If they regain a little value, I would not delay in ridding myself of them. I wait for your news to know the part I must take. Indigo, despite La Paix, is not worth much here. They tell us that it is the same in Europe. Mark exactly from me what it is. My intention being to send some, inform yourself of the prices of different qualities at Bordeaux and Le Havre de Grace if one can hope that it will be worth something. Having no or very little resource here for the education of my children, I was\n1\n\nLSU Libraries Special Collections\n\ndetermined to send my two oldest ones to North America, where there are good colleges, but today, being able to send them to France, I am just waiting to receive your news. I have the greatest regret over seeing these dear children losing their time. They are vigorous and well constituted. They learn with ease everything that people want to teach them. My dear wife is now in a little better health than she has been for the last few years. Despite that, we have not had a child in four years. I still have my three sons, who are well. The last one caused us much anxiety in the first two years of his life when he fell ill to cruel diseases. Presently, he is well! How happy I would be, my dear friend, to learn that you all also are enjoying good health. How much satisfaction I would have in learning that you have passed this storm without accident! Embrace my father and my mother most tenderly for us. Tell them the most respectful and tender things, to think sometimes of their children here, who love them with all their hearts, to maintain their affection. We never cease praying for their preservation. We speak of them continually, and of all of you others. You are the subject of our most tender and pleasant conversations. My wife and I embrace you and our dear sister with our whole heart. Your little nephews do as much and ask for your affection. Remember me to all our relatives and friends. Tell them the most honorable and amicable things for me. I would like sometimes to imagine that maybe I will see you here, but I see that that is impossible. The great age of my father and my mother does not permit that you leave them for an instant. I rejoice sometimes that the will of my uncle that you must have found (as I mentioned it to you all) in the clerk's office of the late public notary is in favor of my mother and that you could well come yourself to look for her benefit. How much pleasure I would have, my good friend, to see you here! I think that you would bring your sister and your little nephews, and I would not delay in following you after having collected my little fortune, whatever it would be. Do not neglect to send some procurations or someone as soon as possible. Goodbye, my good friend. Love a brother who will love you all the days of his life, and believe me your sincere friend. Duplantier When you write me by the way of Spain, do not speak to me of politics or the revolution if you want your letters to arrive.\n\n2\n\nLSU Libraries Special Collections\n\nAs surely some French ships will come to us, address your letters to Messieurs Merci at Bordeaux and put them under the envelope of Mr. Sarpy, merchant, New Orleans, who is in correspondence with that house, an old friend of my uncle and mine. My mother must have received a letter from my wife that she wrote her a little while after my uncle's death, having found one from her to my wife in the papers that he had guarded for her. If the French ships come to us, send me some garden seeds, above all some white beets and beets of all types, cabbage, carrots, yellow turnips, and others in quantity, plain celery, lettuce, and some flower bulbs and seeds. Note from the curator: Transcription reflects spelling as it appears in the original.\n\n3","digitb":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections","source":{},"collec":{},"sourca":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections ( http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special )","type":{},"format":{},"imagb":{},"file":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. copyright laws.","cite":"Special Delivery: A Showcase of LSU Libraries Special Collections, LOUISiana Digital Library, Baton Rouge, La.","to":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","relati":"http:\/\/louisdl.louislibraries.org\/cdm4\/index_LSU_SCE.php?CISOROOT=%2FLSU_SCE","typea":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"259.pdf","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2007-02-16","dmmodified":"2016-06-06","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"258","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"14935","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.01 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
      <transcript displayLabel="Transcript">LSU Libraries Special Collections

Armand Duplantier Letters January 10, 1796 [Duplicate] Finally, my good friend, they have just published La Paix for us here on the first day of the year, which we were awaiting with much impatience. I hope, dear brother, that now I will receive your dear news a little more often. For more than three years, I have not received a single word from any of my relatives. I do not know what has become of you during all that trouble. I am undergoing the greatest impatience to receive some word and fear at the same time learning anything that will perhaps be too troublesome for me. Write me, then, by all routes. That of Spain will be, I think, the most prompt. I sent you this by the American route. I hope also that French ships will come to us and that they will bring me your news. I have written to you and to my father every year by the American route, asking you to give me your news by that route, but I have not received any. I hope that you have received some of mine. I was giving you all the details on what I had done with my uncle's succession. I believe that this year the greatest portion of the funds will be returned, that I will have ready first orders that I will receive from my relatives. The plantation is not sold. The times have been so critical and so unfavorable that I have not aimed to sell it. I have successfully made the sale of slaves. Otherwise, there would have surely been a great deal of compromise due to an insurrection of Negroes that almost occurred last spring in this colony and that had to start at Pointe Coupe. Happily, the thing was discovered in time. They sentenced fifty of them and some leaders, who were all Creoles or Negroes of talent, which stopped their scheme. Despite that, we were not at ease until the moment when they informed us through La Paix. The example of St. Domingue still troubles us. I have much regret over having bought a number of them. If they regain a little value, I would not delay in ridding myself of them. I wait for your news to know the part I must take. Indigo, despite La Paix, is not worth much here. They tell us that it is the same in Europe. Mark exactly from me what it is. My intention being to send some, inform yourself of the prices of different qualities at Bordeaux and Le Havre de Grace if one can hope that it will be worth something. Having no or very little resource here for the education of my children, I was
1

LSU Libraries Special Collections

determined to send my two oldest ones to North America, where there are good colleges, but today, being able to send them to France, I am just waiting to receive your news. I have the greatest regret over seeing these dear children losing their time. They are vigorous and well constituted. They learn with ease everything that people want to teach them. My dear wife is now in a little better health than she has been for the last few years. Despite that, we have not had a child in four years. I still have my three sons, who are well. The last one caused us much anxiety in the first two years of his life when he fell ill to cruel diseases. Presently, he is well! How happy I would be, my dear friend, to learn that you all also are enjoying good health. How much satisfaction I would have in learning that you have passed this storm without accident! Embrace my father and my mother most tenderly for us. Tell them the most respectful and tender things, to think sometimes of their children here, who love them with all their hearts, to maintain their affection. We never cease praying for their preservation. We speak of them continually, and of all of you others. You are the subject of our most tender and pleasant conversations. My wife and I embrace you and our dear sister with our whole heart. Your little nephews do as much and ask for your affection. Remember me to all our relatives and friends. Tell them the most honorable and amicable things for me. I would like sometimes to imagine that maybe I will see you here, but I see that that is impossible. The great age of my father and my mother does not permit that you leave them for an instant. I rejoice sometimes that the will of my uncle that you must have found (as I mentioned it to you all) in the clerk's office of the late public notary is in favor of my mother and that you could well come yourself to look for her benefit. How much pleasure I would have, my good friend, to see you here! I think that you would bring your sister and your little nephews, and I would not delay in following you after having collected my little fortune, whatever it would be. Do not neglect to send some procurations or someone as soon as possible. Goodbye, my good friend. Love a brother who will love you all the days of his life, and believe me your sincere friend. Duplantier When you write me by the way of Spain, do not speak to me of politics or the revolution if you want your letters to arrive.

2

LSU Libraries Special Collections

As surely some French ships will come to us, address your letters to Messieurs Merci at Bordeaux and put them under the envelope of Mr. Sarpy, merchant, New Orleans, who is in correspondence with that house, an old friend of my uncle and mine. My mother must have received a letter from my wife that she wrote her a little while after my uncle's death, having found one from her to my wife in the papers that he had guarded for her. If the French ships come to us, send me some garden seeds, above all some white beets and beets of all types, cabbage, carrots, yellow turnips, and others in quantity, plain celery, lettuce, and some flower bulbs and seeds. Note from the curator: Transcription reflects spelling as it appears in the original.

3</transcript>
  </extension>
</mods>
