<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/405</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>405</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/405/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"41)\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nIS\n1\nI\n\/\nSwift as an arrow o'er the plain she flew,\nWith tiny foot that scarce disturbed the dew,\nAnd, ns the sun upon the tree tops played,\nHither had come this anxious Indian maid.\nIn yonder fountain, gushing from the bank,\nShe bathed her forehead\u2014then its waters drank\u2014\nNor tarried here, but flew along the road\nThat led her to her lover's stern abode I\nHeavens I what a sight is there to greet her eyes I\nEngulph it earth, and shroud it o'er ye skies!\nLost Rosalie! ils chivalry no more\nShall sternly through its high portcullis pour;\nIts smoking palisades are tottering down,\nIts soldiers sleep in death along the ground;\nAnd the fierce Natchez warriors grimly dance\nAbove tho slaughtered sons of vine-clad France I\nAnd when her lover 'midst the dead, she saw,\nWhat pen can picture out tho maniac squaw!\nNot when the tidings o'er the ocean went,\nAnd raised through France the long and loud lament,\nWas there one heart more broken than Annette's\u2014\nHer star went down as time's last planet sets.\nThe Past hath pictures! I could summon one\nOn which once shown a high unclouded sun\u2014\nThat mom when shrill and loud the drum nnd fife\nFirst waked these halls to sounds of martial life.\nI might recall the banner\u2014the long line\nOf boyish soldiers with their battle sign ;\nI might\u2014the dim roll call have loudly read\nTo summon Holbrook from his soldier's bed,\nIn that untented field, all bleak and bare,\nWithout a shade his lowly couch to spare ;\n8c I' edunl arma togae !\u2014other days\nAnd other memories claim my closing lays!\nThe Present! can I find it on the earth ?\nTime rushes onward from its earliest birth,\nAnd all is Past or Future! as a spot\n'      In the wide ocean, or a single dot\nOn thebroad mirror of eternity,\nIs all of lime that is for you and mel\nI grasp the Present\u2014lo, it is the Past I\nSo hurries time on eagle pinions fast!\nThe flight is dread fill, leading to the grave,\nAnd only One hath mighty power to save;\nHe gives us dealh ihat he may give iti life,\nThen comes a rest beyond this warring strife,\nAnd songs of joy and shouts of thrilling bliss\nIn a far belter\u2014dearer world than this!\nNOTES.\n'\u25a0 Dim shadows from old mounds and temples cast\"\nIt is a fact, well known to every antiquarian, that the entire\nVale of the Mississippi abounds with the remains of mounds\nand Indian fortifications. From the stylo of these remains a\nfar higher degree of civilization is indicated than has been found\namong any ofthe North American Indians, now in existence.\nIt is not improbable that emigrations from Mexico, long before\ntheSpanish conquest, might have been effected, peoplingTcxos\nand the banks of tho Mississippi with small colonies of the\nhighly cultivated Atzecs, and monumental Indians.\n\" The Children of the Sun,\" a\/c.        '\nTradition relates that the Natchez Indians were So especially sun-worshippers or \"children of the sun,\" that the warriors\nwere called \" Suns,\" and the wives of the warriors or chiefs\nwere called \" Moons.\"    This was truly oriental and poetic.\n\" They worshipped, loo, in solemn temple's shade.\"\nThere was a tradition extant within the memory of some of\nthe oldest inhabitants of Natchez that the Natchez Indians had\na temple for the worship ofthe sun, within the present, limits of\nthe city.    It was said that the foundation ofthe ancient Catholic church covered, or was near, the site of the temple of the\nsun.    Col. Anthony Campbell, lately deceased, had acquired\nconsiderable evidence on this subject; which was entirely satisfactory to his mind.\n\" High o'er the graven altar proudly shone\nThe Sun God, flaming on his earthly throne,\nSuch fires as Zoroaster,\" tf-c.\nThe ceremonials of the Sun worship; as practised by the\nPeruvian Incas, and by the more civilized tribes of South\nAmerica, were splendid nnd imposing. There is no more difficulty in ascribing the origin ofthe aboriginal American San\nor fire worship to Phoenicia, than there is in ascribing the\norigin ofthe highly civilized tribes that overspread continent\nat the time of its discovery, to Phoemicia, through the Phoenician colony that founded Carthage. The stupendous remain;\nof Palenque, tho long forgotten city of South America, arc indisputably ofthe Phoenician or Carthagenian style of architecture.\n\" The Incas' litany so wildly sweet. \"\nThe music of the natives of Mexico, in their public worship, was astonishingly wild, yet harmonious. In the- worship\nof the god of war, it was, says Bernal Diaz, the Spanish historian of the invasion of Cortez, terrible beyond \"descriptioni\nIn the sun worship, it was of a more pleasing character.\n\" Since Rosalie's stem frowning ramparts stood.\"\nIt is not entirely certain that the first French fort in this\nvicinity was called Rosalie, or that it stood on the site of\nthe ruins of the old fortification that is now gradually\nwasting from the summit of the bluff, and washing into the\nriver, by every powerful rain. The name, Rosalie, is romantic enough to have originated with M. Robert Cavelier de U\nSalle, who left France in 1G84, with a squadron of four ship-\nommanded by Capt. Beaujeu, for ihe purpose of foundinga\nnew settlement on the bonks of the Mississippi.\n\" To sec this glorious land\u2014its Eden flowers. \"\nThe poetic Chateaubriand, the French refugee and traveller, who fled to this country, and travelled through the vale\nof the Mississippi, in the early part ofthe French revolution\nthus describes the scenery on the easlem bank of the Missis\nsippi, in his Alalia :\u2014\n\" But how enchanting is the contrast on the eastern side-\nSuspended on tho floods, grouped on rocks and mountains, dis\npersed in vallies, trees of every odour, every shape, every\nhue, entwine their variegated heads, and ascend to an fmme\u00bb\nurable height; bignoias, vines, colocinthis, wind their slendf\nMM","fullrs":{},"find":"406.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"405","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1867068","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.78 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
