<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>page 71</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2600</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2600</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2600/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:23:44">{"title":"page 71","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"Wells, the proprietor of the hotel went to the above-mentioned\nplace, and purchased twenty mattresses, which were shipped immediately to this place. I mention this fact, because it has been frequently remarked and reported through the country that the mattresses were ordered from New Orleans. About the middle of\nAugust, two suspicious cases occurred, winch created considerable\nalarm among the visitors, but not regarded as yellow fever by the\n-ban. both of which died on the fourth or fifth day,\nwith symptoms of fever, but no black Vomit. Each of these cases\ncame from a fever district a few days before they were taken sick.\nFor a week or ten days there was no sickness of any description.\nOn the 23d of August, a lady from Louisiana was attacked with\nfever; came through Vicksburg a short time before. On the 26th\nof August Dr. Pugh was attacked (the Doctor attended the eases\nabove spoken of). Both of these oases died with black vomit on\nthe fifth day. The prominent symptoms in these, as well as many\nother eases, were severe pain in the head, back, and calves of the\ninicohni. skin yellow, often hot and dry, and frequently a profuse\nstances, be kept up; tympanites and suppression of urine, coma and\nblack vomit, would generally end the same on the fourth or fifth,\nand sometimes on the third day.   During the week that the two\nof well-marked intermittent and remittent forms of fever, all of\nwhom got well, under a mild course of medication for those diseases. The fever then assumed a different type; the change was\ngradual, a running into yellow fever as it were, and spread ra] .idly,\nprincipally among the blacks.\nAt the commencement of the epidemic, dating from the 23d of\nAugust, there were about four hundred persons a: .be Wells, white\nand black, exposed up to the 31st of August, when the first death\ntook place. Yet, I only heard of two cases of fever occurring out\nof this large number after they left Cooper's Wells. All who\nremained were connected with the establishment, numbering fifty,\nwhite and black. Of these, four had had the fever previously, and\none escaped an attack. There were forty-five attacks and nine\ndeaths\u2014six whites and three blacks.\nof Drs. Hubbard, Buckner, and Bricked, of Vicksburg, and Dr.\nCabaniss, of Jackson.   And if a competency of good nurses could","fullrs":{},"find":"2601.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2600","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"470832","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.45 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
