<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/391</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>391</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/391/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:55">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH- W E S T E 1! N J 0 U It N A I,.\ntauts may abridge the time to about 100\"; for both may be\nset very nearly at the proper point, by the observer being at his\npost n few minutes before the time of observation, Bodies\nwithin HI\" of the zenith cannot be conveniently subjected to\nthis method, us the position of tho observer obstructs the\nrays of incidence.\n(i.) This simple stratagem, which, of course, applies to\nthe quadrant as well as tho sextant, will furnish to every observer, who can command either instrument nnd an almanac,\ntho nieiiiis of determining tho tlcclinaiion of nil tho principal\nstars; for by ihe sun's meridian altitude, he may find his lnti-\ntude, and from this, and the stars' altitudes, he will deduce their\ndeclination,\nJefferson College, December Wd, 1837.\nFor the South-Weilcrn Journal.\nFRAGMENT.\nTranslated from the French of \" George Snnds.\"\nHymn ti) the Guardian Angel.\u2014-The monkschaunted\n\" Angel of the Lord, spread over us thy prolccling wings:\nShelter us under them and console us with thy pity.    Thou\nwort created the gentles' and tho most indulgent among all tho\nvirtues and the powers of Heaven, for thou wert destined to\nsuccour and console man, to gnthi r together the it ars he sheds\nand present them as an expiation before eternal justice.\"\u2014\nAnd thochildren answered, \" Hope in the Lord.nll you who\nmourn, for tho guardian nngel spreads his broad wing between man's weakness and his maker's wrath.'1    Then the\nmonks chaunted again, \" 0 youngcsl mid most lovely of i!\nangels, last created, for thou wert creeled nfler man, and\nplaced in Eden to be his companion nnd frien 1\u2014but woman\ncame, and was more powerful tie a thou over the mind nl\nman.\u2014The Angel of Wrnth descended to punish tin in, bnl\nthou didst follow them forth into th ir exile and watched ovi r\nthe children that were born unt i them.\"    And ihe children\nanswered again:  \" &lt; I you ihat love God, thank iho (! nurd inn\nAngel, wlio, on his rapid wing, incessantly mounts from Enrtl\nId Heaven, to bear the prayers of nun, and descends to bring\nthem  blessings.\"    And then the sweet voice of a young\nmonk chaunted, \" It is thou that wilh warm breath revivifies\nin the morning, the plants frozen by the cold of night; i1 i.-\nthou, who, with protecting hand, sustainest at the cabin of tin\nfisherman, when the furious winds coino raging from tho sen;\nit is thou, who awakest sleeping mothers, and callestthcm with\na sweet voice, in the midst of the dreams of the night, to rise\n\u2022hul give suck to their now born; it is thou, who watchest\nover ihe modesty of young virgins, mid turnest aside from\ntheir couch, bid thoughts nnd impure dreams; it is thou, who\nsoatest, hyself at noon day by the cradle of the reaper's child,\n-mil gunrdest it from the scorpion and the viper; and it is thou\nwho, when we seek for consolation in distress, dost turn for us\nthe leaves ofthe blessed Bible, and guides! us lo the text of\ncomfort.\" ERNEST.\nMETEOIHC SHOWER,\nTim appearance of an extraordinary number of meteors,\non the morning of the Kith of November, every year, for six-\nyears in succession, is certainly a very roiniirkabh: phenomenon, and would be scarcely credible, unless attested by iiielu.\nbilnblo evidence. I, is one of those facts which philosophy\nhas failed to account for. The periodical shower that waste\noccur last month, being anticipated by Professor Olmsted, of\nV ah- College, lio sit up in order lo witness il, mid bus published his observations in the Now Haven Herald. Ilesiys\nthe magnitude of the phenomenon was inferior in those of\nsome other years, but it was marked with distinctive peculiarities, which left no doubt of its identity. On other occasions,\nthe hour when the greatest number was visible, w:v.&lt; 1 o'clock'\nmi ,l,e hi.-t occasion, the number rapidly increasi d a,;) o'clock,\nami remained uniform for nearly three hours, nnd thonvcrage\nnumber was one for every minute.\n'1'be professor observes thnt the spots on the sun were very\nremarkable for some days before.    On the l:;,b. theday preceding the appearance of the meteors, these spots were distri-\nbuted in eight groups, distinguished by ihe smallest telescopes,\nand could he resolved into more than sixty spots, by means of\nlarger telescopes.    Tho wonder of this, phenomenon would\nlie nothing in itself but consists in the regularity of its np-\npearanco on the same day of the same month, for six years in\nsuccession, always between midnight and sunrise, and the\ngreatest number and brilliancy between three and 1 o'clock.\nA large meteoric stone is said  lo have fallen on tho earth\nabout tho same lime, in tho neighborhood of Lako Georjre\nweighing 42 pounds.    Could thero be any com tion between ibis meteoric stone mil the shooting stars that were observed nt  New Haven mid elsewhere?    The true origin of\nihe nne nr the other is not   known or lies not been disclosed\nSome have supposed that the meteoric stoni s come from volcanoes in the moon, and npp larances in that plan it, ns indicated by powerful telescope.-:, exhibit tho resemblance of volcanic eruptions.   It is supposi d thai a projectile hurled from\nthe moon, nl Ihe rate of Slll'l) feet   per second, or four time's\nthe velocity of a cannon ball, would overcome the power of\nihe moon's attraction, and arrive in the sphere of thnt of our\nplanet in three days,    Whi ther or not this lie the true source\nof these phenomena, wenrc noi well t nough versed in natural\nphilosophy lo eh lerinine.\nFrom the Satm-Un; Courier,\nUNIVERSAL LYCEUM.\nThe object of this Society is the diffusion of useful know!\nedge over the globe, with the promotion of family education\nand individual improvement.     It is composed of tho friends\nand patrons of .science in different nations of the earth, who\nare to institute a general systi in of exchanges in works of\nnature and art, Ibr the benefit of themselves, of schools, ly-\nceuins, nnd other  literary institutions, and for enlightening\nand redeeming Ihe world from ignorance and vice.\nAny person may be a corresponding- member of the Universal Lyt'-eum, by tho annual payment of one dollar; minors for half that Slim. Five dollars paid at any ono time,\nand two dollars annually afterwards, will constitute an individual a lifu member; nnd fifty dollars paid at one lime,\nwill constitute a person a patron without any additional payment.\nEvery patron, every lift.', honorary anil senior corresponding member, and every three junior members, will bu enti-\nm","fullrs":{},"find":"392.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"391","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1841014","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
