<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/533</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>533</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/533/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:05">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WE STERN  JOURNAL.\nnounds and fortifications found in the great val\n171\nBncie\u201e, mounos aim -\u00bb\u00bb\u2122 \u2014 \u2022\u00bb \u2022- *\"\u00bb valley oft    The most important of these animals in size, are the Ela-\nth, Mississippi were carefully examined they would afford phants and Mastodons, upon whose histor '\nm\u201ech very interesting phenomenon.\nWe here insert a part of tho Professor's Lecture:\nIn my lecture to you on the causes which have acted to\nproduce the present condition  of organized beings, your attention was called to the stale of the earth's surface, when it\nlirjl emerged from the bosom of the ocean ; we saw that it\niras covered for a long time, by lakes, marshes, and savannas,\nand that creatures of peculiar types were produced by these\npeculiarities of condition.    While  the  earth's surface was\ncrradually becoming dryer,  there arrived a lime when  its\nmarshes and wet places were clothed by an exuberant vegetation, of a type peculiar to the localities and temperature\nthen prevailing; they would   then  resemble the jungles of\nSouth Africa and India, and the savannas of South America\nAmong the fossils found in the strata which were formed\nafter this lime, wo perceive the remains of a typo of crea\nmrcs, which we would expect a priori, to arise from the circumstances which seem to have existed at that epoch ; it is\nthat type of quadrupeds, among which arc ihe  Hippopotamus, &amp;C, which are all amphibious.    When the surface be-\ncame dryer, we find other modifications of this type appearing fitted for other modes of life ; among them we perceive\nthe remains ofthe elephant, the mastodon, the rhinoceros, the\nelastnotherium, the anoplothcrium, and palcothcrium.   Many\nof these genera have   become   extinct, as  the   mastodon,\nelasmolbcriuin, &amp;c; others have living representatives,though\nthe species now living, are all different from the fossil ones.\nWhen wo unite the fossil species of this type, lo the living\nones, we form a very natural order, the individuals belonging\n10 which, are allied to each other by many and important relations; the most important of which, is the thickness of the\nskin, to which the order owes the name of Pachydermata,\nwhich has been given to it.    This peculiar thickness of the\ninteguments originated primarily from elevated temperature,\nwhich increased tho flow of the blood to it; while the cutaneous transpiration and exhalation   was prevented by the\n;rcat humidity of the atmosphere, and amphibious habits.\nNow the dimensions of any organ, will be in proportion to\nthe comparative quantity of blood employed in its nutrition ;\nand ns we havo said that a great deal of blood was sent to\nthe integuments of these creatures, and none expended in the\nway of evaporation, it must have been employed in the nutrition of those parts, and produced in them the unusual thickness of skin.    The great heat of climate, together with ranging amidst the coarse vegetation of the jungles, prevented the\ngrowth of hair.    The animals of this type, which still inhabit localities, and live under circumstances similar to those\nthat gave rise to it, retain their thickness and nakedness ofthe\n'l&lt;in, as is the case with the Hippopotamus, Rhinoceros, and\nElephant ofthe tropics; but when a species inhabits high and\ndry regions, or cold latitudes, we find these peculiarities disappearing; we see the horse and hog approaching in external characters to other orders, with thinner skins and hairy\ncoverings; and the elephants found fossil, in Siberia were\n'lad as became inhabitants of the frigid regions of the north.\nlo enter.\nary it is our intention\nOf the elephants, there are two living species; first, the\nelephas Africanus, or African elephant, which is distinguished by having a rounded cranium, very large ears, and molar\nteeth or grinders, marked upon their surface in festoons by\nthe layers of enamel, which are elevated above the bony pun\nof the tooth.    The second, is the elephas Indicus, or Indian\nelephant, which has the cranium elongated, forehead concave,\nears small, crown of the molars marked in undulating lines'\nby the enamel.    These, as their names indicate, are peculiar\nthe one to Africa, and the other to India.    There is, however,\na third species found fossil in various parts of the world; it\nis characterized by an elongated cranium; concave forehead,\nsockets' of the tusks very long, lower jaw obtuse in front, molars parallel, very large, and marked by the enamel, in serrated lines.    Bones of this elephant have been found in great\nabundance, in every part of Europe; they have also been\nfound in many places in America; and the Prairie Mainmouth,\nncarOpelousas, took its name from the bones of an elephant\nof this species being found there in 180-1, and considered as\nthe bones of the mastodon, until desciibed by Dr. Mitchell of\nNew York.    It is,  however, in Siberia, that the greatest\nnumber of these remains have been found ; they are so common in that country, that the inhabitants have forged a story\nto account for it.    They suppose these bones and tusks to belong to a subterranean animal, whose mode of life is similar\nto that of the moles, but which cannot bear with impunity the\nlight  of day.    They call  this animal Mammont or Main-\nmouth, which according to some is taken from the word Mamma, which in some Tartar idiom signifies the earth; and .according to some, it is taken from the Arab word behemoth,\nwhich is used to designate some large unknown animal; or\nfrom mchemoth, a word which the Arabs usually prefix to\nthe name of the elephant (fihl) when it is very large.    It is\nunder the name of Mammunt horns (Mammontovakost) that\nthe Siberians designate the fossil tusks, which are so numerous, and in so perfect a state of preservation, in the northern\nparts of ihat country, as to bo employed for the same purposes\nas the fresh ivory, and they make so important an article of\ncommerce, that the Czars of Russia have reserved the monopoly of the trade.\nThe fable of a subterranean animal is nol unknown to the\nChinese, who call the tusks, tien-schu-yn (teeth of the lien-\nschu,) and have in their works on natural history, descriptions\nwhich they consider as very accurate of a creature of whose\nreal nature ihey have no idea.\nIn 1709, aTongouse fisherman remarked, upon the shores\nof the frozen ocean, near tho mouth of the Lena, a large\nmass in the midst of the ice, whose nature he could not determine. The next year ho perceived that it was more disengaged, but could not yet tell what it was; near the end of\nthe next summer, the whole flank projected from the ice, as\nlid also one of the tusks of some animal. At the end of the\nfifth year, the ice having melted rapidly, the whole of the\nenormous mass fell upon a sand beach beneath.    Two years\n1 '\u25a0\u2022\u25a0'.\n. m\n\u2022&gt; -&gt;&gt;?\u25a0]\n':\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0 11\n\u2022\n:","fullrs":{},"find":"534.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"533","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1764644","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
