<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/349</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>349</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/349/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"aOUTH-W ESTER N JOURNAL.\nisr&lt;\nbegan to demand some other scenes\n..ntiety began \u201e \u00bb;\u2014 .u..,\u201e -,, \u00ab,llea and objects pleasingto the eyc.aftorthedullconfinementof afourmon.hs'\nhy which the mind might be refreshed: when one soft morn- voyage.    They are constructed with flat roofs, and ,\nintf crothe jocund sun hail lilted up his ruddy face to light    ' \"\nihc day, the announcement of a sail ahead broke short the\n\u25a0bread of our indifferent dreams, and, among the rest, we has-\ntrued to the deck, and, with eager eyes, peered through the\nmists of the receding night, to catch n glimpse of the imperfect object. Perhaps it is an island, perhaps a phantom, or\nthe Flying Dutchman, of wizzard memory, who comes to\nask, what news from Holland, and honor us with letters to\nhis consigners ; were speculations uttered by the yawning\ncrowd, as they leaned wondering over the rail. But no: it\nproved to be a ship\u2014an English ship\u2014bound to the Indies,\nand carrying human beings like ourselves. Our swifter ves-\nF,.| socn brought US under the stranger's lfp, where we exchanged the usual salutations of Ship ahoy ! What is your\nname! Where arc you hound? &amp;c. These courtesies\nperformed, our jolly-boat was lowered, and, half prepared,\nsome ol'us jumped into the leaky craft, and pushed off fir\nthe English ship, unmindful of our danger, determined, at all\nhazards, to view once, more the human face divine in woman's\ngarb; for we had not omitted to observe, that our more favored friend could boast of softer forms and brighter countenances, than the rough specimens of the human race by\nwhich we were surrounded.\nOur hasty \\isit was soon paid, and we returned, well satisfied lo bear the remnant or our lengthened voyage, without a\nmurmur, and everyday we thanked our propitious stars for\nsi tilling us an incident for such pleasing reminiscence.\nA lew short weeks or prosperous winds wafted  us across\nthe southern ocean, and brought us off the island of Ceylon,\nwith its spicy groves, and ever-living verdure, that garden-\nspot in which some  eastern  sages have located the  place\nwhere our first parents learned the punishment of their disobedience; and, as we approached, the land breeze sent sweet\nodors from the aromatic herbage forth to meet us\u2014a fitting\nwelcome to a land made sacred by its fairy fable, its genii, its\nnecromancy, and enchantments,    My imperfect pen cannot\ndescribe the beauty of the scenery that gradually opened to\nour view, as we sailed pleasantly along the Coromandel\ncoast.     The gorgeous brilliancy of an eastern clime, mad,\nmore impressive by its novelty ; the sanded beach here and\nthere studded with a tall cocoa-nut or lalipat, lifting their lofty\nsummits to the clouds; the distant foaming surf reflecting\nhack the vivid lustre or a tropical sun, glimpses of swarthy\nforms afar, dressed in the peculiar attire of the country, conspired to fill the mii-.d with a thousand pleasing emotions, pe\nculiar to one about to visit a remote country,  and, in this\neasc.a land made mcmoiublo by its antiquity, memorable by\nits connection with history during its romantic ages, renowned as the land of the Brahmin polytheism, with its temples\nand altars, and sacred  Oanges, renowned for its  moslem\nmosques, and as the favored country of the song-honored\nbulbul.\nWe came to anchor off Madras, a beautiful city situated\ndirectly upon the coast, and, as seen fioin the offing, exhibiting\na very striking appearance. The houses are large, and have\nabout them an air of elegance and comfort, that is extremely\n. , ,  surround\ned by verandahs, with large columns,  covered with a hard\nplastering, called chunam, or great smoothness and beautiful.\nly white.    These, seen against the background oU brilliant\nsky, exhibit a tableau of uncommon and  pleasing beauty-\nNo sooner were we moored, than we descried a small black\nspeck moving towards us from the shore, resembling somewhat a porpoise swimming along the surface of the water,\nwith a chaplet of grey moss fastened to his head, hut as the\nobject approached, we discerned that the subject of our curiosity was a small raft, constructed of two imperfectly hewn\nlogs fastened together, and denominated a caiamarcn.    On\nthis were seated two delicately formed men, or diminutive\ntaturc.    They came along-side, and actively mounted to the\ndeck, calling out in broken English for \" de capum,\" to whom\nthey presented a message from the  Custom House.    The\ncatamaren boatmen live half of their time in the water, and\non their apology for a boat, trust themselves three or four\nmiles from the shore, at times when the terrific surf forbids\nall other communication between the vessels and the shore. At\nsuch times, these little creatures will venture out, and brave,\nthe fury of the breakers, when they seem to threaten with\ndestruction every object that dares encounter their violence.\nThey seem to lie a kind of amphibii well calculated to form\nthe connecting link between the human species and the residents of the deep.    The morning after our arrival off Madras,\nwe prepared to go on shore, and entered a boat  constructed\nespecially lor riding the surf, made or flexible materials, arid\nloosely put together, the joints of which are united by twine\nmade of a tough sea grass, the fissures between the planks\nbeing stuffed with the same material\u2014though so imperfectly\nis this part or their construction accomplished, that innumerable chinks are left, through which the water and day-light^\nthat enter on one side, may find egress on the other.    This\nboat was managed by eleven mer, the whole equal  in force\nlo two or three stout-bodied Americans.    Having pushed off.\nthey pulled us steadily along, keeping time with their voices,\nn a tone half singing and half grunting, until we reached\nthe breakers.    They then broke forth into a louder and more\nearnest vociferation, at the same lime making a more rapid\nmount with their oars.    Taking advantage of the swell, we\nsoon reached the beach; and while the boat floated in the still\nwater of a broken wave, the boatmen jumped into the water,\nand quickly hauled the boat sidelong upon the beach, rolling\nus all out, like so many fish tumbled from a seine, while the\nwaves, striking the side of the boat, dashed their salt spray entirely over our heads, to the no small discomfiture  of our\ncarefully adjusted garments.    We had not fairly made our\nescape from the spray and the surf, when we were beset by a\ncrowd or clamorous natives, who thronged around us, offering\ntheir services with an importunity that seemed unconscious of\nthe natureof a negative.    Some we pushed aside; others we-\nthreatened to knock down with our umbrellas; but we soon\nfound, like the fox in the ruble, that it would be belter to sub\nmit to the annoyance of one crowd, which would keep off all\nother intruders, than to be tormented by a repetition of new\ncomers, since all the reply they deigned to make to one's men\n\u25a0\u25a03 ,\n\u2022 \u25a0A ij\\ i\n'\u25a0'^4s i\n\u25a0 \u25a0'\u2022 \u2022* ;:i i\n- '\u2022*\u25a0; 1\nSi\n'\u25a0\".'.\n:,\n'\ni\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"350.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"349","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1676924","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.60 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
