<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/543</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>543</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/543/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"f''1 ''(!&lt; i\nil\n1   V\ni .,'\"'\"   ;\n\u25a0J &lt;v\nla;.\n'ill\nU\nft*\nIff\n|'\u00abW\n\u25a0l.tf\n\u00bbi\n180\nSOUTH-WE B T E R N  J 0 11 R N A L.\nlican citizen's interest, as well as his pride, to render himself\nfamiliar with the spirit of his government and laws. The\nEnglishman is very tenacious of his privilege \"to grumble,\"\nand, usually, whatever policy Her Majesty's ministers may\nadopt, he boisterously nsserts that privilege. Yet, alas I his\ninfluence, generally, begins and ends in grumbling. This\nalmost profitless prerogative, however, is more desirable, than\nthe fate of utter political darkness,\u2014to know suffering by\nsight and not byname, to live in such civil ignorance as the\nKussiaii soldier, who, when battling bravely, with the war-\ncry _\u2022\u25a0 Constantino and the Constitution I \"\u2014and beiugasked\nthe meaning of the term \" Consli\/ulion,\" replied, \" Constantino's wife, to be sure;\"\u2014and would that the Constitution had\nhad as much authority over the Autocrat as history seems to\nthink had his wile !\nIn our favored land, whatever each individual approves or\ncondemns, he is fitted in aiding to perpetuate or to eradicate.\nNothing will make the love of country warm, und the res-j\npee\nerful energies of the most potent kingdom of modern tin,\nhave been able to effect.    And what gives this mirnculoi\nagency to lite unaided efforts of one man 1   It js (,.,..\nwherever ignorance can bo found and instructed, or sun.nation enlightened, wherever there is a place to do good, or ro'\nfor the exercise of a kindly benevolence,\u2014ihat spot is th\nhome of the .Missionary.    The conversion of one. sinner on\ntear of repentance; erne smile of a newly awakened hope ate\nassociations that endear to the messenger of Heaven a moral\ndesert, where nought beside idolatry and misery before found\nan asylum. I,ike his Divine Example, the Missionary krioivs\nno country, or rather is a denizen of all; to tho Jew and to tin..\nGentile, to ihe rich and lo the poor, he preaches \"the moV.\nment to come,\" and whether in thepalaced city of Jerusalem\nor ofthe despised Nazareth,  his zeal tires not, nndhislaborj\nfind no rest I\nThis analysis shows how closely government and law are\ninterwoven with the strongest, because tho most inartificial\nct for the laws sacred, but the personal feeling in every in- sensibilities of mankind, traces their co-existenco with llieso-\nhabitant of the soil, and every subject of the government, of a\nreal identification with the ono and a participation in the creation of the other. Compare the progress of knowledge,\nliterature, the arts, and local melioration in Great Britain,\nand in her present foreign possessions, wilh all the- advantages nature has presented the latter, in belter materials to employ the scientific and philanthropic, und the comparison is\nfar in favor of Great Britain.    This is not caused bya con-\neial system, and tin ir intimate relation lo all that renders society a blessing. At the first gathering of men into communities, conventional rules, tacitly agreed upon, sufficed for\ntheir simple transactions. But with the growth of number!\nnot so nearly allied by common interest and affection, with\nthe multiplied intricacies of business, growing- out of the creation of properly and its lights, arose the necessity of some\nestablished rubs fin' tho determination of disputed question*.\ntrncted policy on the part ofthe parent government, but is Tho early laws, contained in the Bible, are plain precepts,\ncaused by a liict as natural as it is injurious. The exiled founded chiefly on the principles of natural justice and llic\nresident of a foreign land feels little sympathy with llic soil obligations of good faith. As these became insufficient for\nor its institutions,\u2014he is a wanderer from choice, or'for the ihe varii d cas s arising under the numerous perplexities in\nacquisition of riches, which, when obtained, he fondly hopes the negotiations an-.l dealings between man and man, others\nto enjoy in the place of his birth, and amidst the circle of his; were established, or grow inlo use from custom.   This was\nancient friends,\u2014his eye and heart are ever turned, though\nt dious years have already enumerated tho many anniversaries of his absence, towards what he still affectionately calls\n\"his home,\" and death would come lo him armed with a new\nterror, did he think his bones must moulder in the bind of his\nenterprise, rather than under the: sod of his nativity. In the\nbeautiful lines of Goldsmith, he exclaims,\n\" la all my wanderings round this world of care;\nIn all toy griefs, anel Cruel has given my share j\nI still have hopes, my long vexations past,\nThere lo retain,and die at borne at last.\"\nAffection alone can form dear and lasting associations, and as\nhe has used the place of his sojourning but as the workshop\nof his industry, and the market of his speculations, hero-\nmembers th-.'in but as localities of toil, and scenes of fevered\nanxiety. Of the hired dwelling, how often can we exclaim,\n\"the stone wall thereof is broken down,\"\u2014but behold the\nmagic effect of a consciousness of a life-long possession !\n\" May you die in the midst of your friends ! \" is an oriental\nsalutation among travellers, and one fitted to strike melody\nfrom the finest chord of the heart,\u2014a wish that you may be\ncheered, as alone you can be by human aid, in the awful hour\nthat heralds the parting of the soul and the body.\nMore has been done for the cause of Christianity, in Asia,\nby the solitary devotion of a single missionary, lhan the pow-\nthe origin of what is called tli\" Common  Law, which isn\nsystem, the result of reason acting on the examples of expc-\nThe philosophy of the law is well exemplified by a comparison between the Common and the Statute Law. The\nCommon Law, being the very essence: of reason, being\nsanctified by the repeated and solemn decisions ofthe Courts,\nstands upon a basis which nothing can remove but a change\nin the habits and natures ofthe people, which alone can idler\nthe meaning or reason of the law. It is remarkable that\nwhere a judicial decision has been interfered wilh once, enactments have been altered many times. A principle of\ncommon law established many hundred years ago, is binding\nto this day, and, while a statute may never show itself, iho\nCommon Law, like the atmosphere, surrounds us on all sides,\nmeets us on every occasion, and is a guide in every doubt. It\nforms the main body, of which the Statute Law is but the advanced guard, and every battle-royal in the law, must be decided by its forces. There is between them, all the difference\nthat exists between special and general application. Mv\nprinciple that is narrow in its operation, that meets but fe',v\ncases, and those in a limited respect, can never obtain general utility or material importance. One, indeed, is like\u2122\nisolated precept of morality; the other embraces the whole","fullrs":{},"find":"544.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"543","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1746540","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
