<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 4</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2201</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2201</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2201/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 6, Page 4","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[4]\ntingly upon tbeir indulgence, and hope, with their assistance, that the results antic\"\nfrom the meeting will be accomplished.   1 congratulate you upon the high motiv1^\nhave engaged you in ibis movement.    We have all in view the common good of uV '\ntry, and in working for this end, we cannot expect that all will agree  exactly as ,!j0lJ\nmeans ; but the spirit in which you have assembled is sufficient: guarantee that what\ndifficulties may arise, they will disappear in the presence of the ambition for the pm??\ngood.    You have honored me by associating with me distinguished gentlemen from\u00abL\nstates, upon whose  assistance I rely,    lhave not for many years participated in \u00bb^j*\nmentary proceedings, but, gentlemen, the   great objects for which we have asscniLl J\npreclude the supposition that we will be impeded by technicalities ; and 1 repeat mvcone\ndent belief, that our deliberations will be harmonious, and will result favorably.\"\nMr. Robb, with a few prefatory remarks, offered a resolution authorizing the Chair h\nappoint three committees,viz.: one on Routes; one on Ways and Means, and one*\u2122\nResolutions. The resolution was adopted without dissent, the Chair to announce ji.\ncommittees at tbe next meeting.\nA gentleman, whose name we did not hear, asked if all tbe routes which were entiiU\nto the friendly regard of the various delegations present, were to be referred lo the Com.\nmittee on Routes.\nMr. Robb explained that tbe object of his resolution, and the appointment of the com-\nmittees referred to, was to prevent that dissipation of influence and power, which vooU\ninevitably result from the open debate of every scheme that might be brought before tie\nConvention, They met not for an idle purpose; not for the mere \"expression of\nopinion, but to accomplish results, and those results should be accomplished. The object\nwas to devise practicable projects ; lo establish a grand system of railroads, which would\nmake New-Orleans and the Southwest what they ought to he, and to devise thewaji\nand means by which this great end might be attained. In the course of his remarks,be\nexpressed his high gratification at the large and influential assemblage he saw before bin,\nand from the spirit which animated it, argued undoubted and early success.\nMr. Hampson, of Louisiana, offered a resolution that in voting, each state should hare\nbut one vote, and the resolution was referred to the Committee on Resolutions,\nTuesday, January 6,1852.\nMORNING SESSION.\nThe Convention metal half past 11 o'clock, a. m.\nThe minutes of yesterday's sittings were read and approved.\nThe following committees were announced by the President:\nCommittee on Routes,\nVirginia.\u2014Wm, M. Burwell, Wyndham Robertson, Dr. .Tames McDowell. Texas.-\nJno. T.Mills, C. C. Alexander, H. G. Catlitt. Mississippi.\u2014It. S. Ghdney, E.L. Am,\nJ.W.Vick. Arkansas.\u2014Albert Pike, John Martin, A-Fowler. Missouri-\u2014Hsit]\nChouteau, P. R. McCreery, Edward J. Gay. Kentucky.\u2014William Soery, J.N. Beadle*.\nAlabama.\u2014P. J- Weaver, T. B. Goldsbv, G. P. Blevins. Temtexse* \u2014Rev. J. H- Oiej,\nL. J. Polk, Jas. A. Porter. Louisiana.\u2014Col. W. S. Campbell, L. G. DcRussey, Buckner\nH. Payne. Florida.\u2014W. J. Keyser, J. M. Landrum, Jos. Forsyth.\nCommittee on Ways and Means.\nVirginia.\u2014W. M. Burwell, Wyndham Robertson, Dr. Jas. McDowell. 3^*\nA. Morrill, S. P. Allen, T. G. Wright. Mississippi\u2014Shepherd Brown, Samuel Wb*.\nH. G. Street. ilr\u00a3aHM:-f.\u2014Luther Chase, Wm. D.Ferguson, C. F. Sutton. Miss\u00b0*\"C\nW. C- Kennett, It. A. Barnes, It. J. Lockwood. Kmtncky.~\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\m Soery, )\u2022*\u2022\nBeadles. Alabama.\u2014P. J. Weaver, J. W. Lapsley, J. B. Farham. Te7ihcssee.-~hm*\nJ.Polk, James A. Porter, A. Heiman. Louisiana.- James Bobb, Henry Phillips\nP. Benjamin.    Florida.\u2014Sos. Forsyth,   W. J. Keyset, J. M. Landrum.\nCommittee on Resolutions.\nMississippi\u2014J. S. Yerger, H. G. Street, It. A, Johnson. Virginia.\u2014W. M-Burf*\nWvndbam Robertson, Dr. Jas. McDowell.    Texas.\u2014Sno. T. Mills, T. G- Wright, \u00bb\u2022\"\nCatlett.      Arkansas\u2014 Albert Pike,   John Martin,   L. C. Faulkner.      Misjown-\u2014 ,\nWade, Franklin Chiles, Dr. J. A. January.    Kentucky.\u2014William Soery, J. N- \u00bbe\u00bbJ *\nAlabama.\u2014i- W. Lapsley.   W. F. Burr,   J. B. Parl'mm.     Tonne.ssee.\u2014Oeo. V-J^\nJ. H. Otey,   A. Heiman.      Louisiana.\u2014M. M. Cohen,   A. Declouet,   J. H- u*\nFlorida.\u2014J. M. Landrum, W. J. Keyser, Jos. Forsyth.\nMr. H. W. Walter, of Mississippi, presented the  following resolut'0\"3'\nmoved to refer them to a special committee of 6ve *. _   .  he,ebf\nResolved, That the Legislature of the State ot Mississippi be, audit \u00ab *&gt;","fullrs":{},"find":"2202.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2201","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"588400","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
