<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 4, Page 9</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2156</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2156</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2156/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:46">{"title":"Section 4, Page 9","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"\u201e 5i Resolved, That a committee be appointed to be call-\n\u25a0 tnj permanent committee of eastern Texas, of the New\nn leans Opelousas and Texas Railroad, to consist of\nV 7 members from each county represented in this conven-\n.',,\u201e with power to appoint a sub-executive committee.\nu o. Resolved, That said committee take the necessary\nsteps to procure such legislation in the State of Texas, as\nmay be required to carry out the object of this Convention.\n'\u25a0 7. Resolved, That said committee procure all the statistical information of each county of Texas that may be in\ntheir power, embracing its population, products, soil, minerals,\nand other objects of value or trade, and transmit the same,\nfrom time to time, to the Chairman of the exeeutive committee, Ambrose Lanfear, Esq., at New Orleans, for publication.\n* 8. Resolved, That said committee be requested to correspond with the executive committee of this road, at New\nOrleans.\"\nThe fruits of that convention have been shown by several\nlarge meetings, since held in different places in Texas, in favor of the extension of the Opelousas railroad through that\nState, and especially by a Convention held in Trinity, on the\n25th of October, by which the substance and spirit of the\nabove resolutions were emphatically and unanimously re-af-\nlirmcd.\nThe executive committee have also printed, in pamphlet,\nan elaborate draft to an Act to provide for the organization\nol corporations, and which was made by the special committee appointed for that duty. This \" Act,\" and a \" Memorial to the Legislature,\" and an \" Act to authorize subscriptions,\" are now in the hands of all the members of said\nspecial committee, for examination and revision, previous to\nadoption, as a final report, to be submitted to the Convention\n\u25a0a January.\nihe executive committee, at their regular meeting, held\nOctober 27th took the responsibility of calling an extra ses-\n,lon of the convention, on the 2d day of January, by the\n\"doption of the Preamble and Resolutions which have been","fullrs":{},"find":"2157.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2156","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"515996","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
