<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/420</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>420</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/420/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"'\"\u2022',1\nmm'\n\u2022*, ll\n;ll'\"\n-V\n(*\ni-l;\".I\u00bb\n'ilk\nW\n' ' 1\n\u00abtV ii\n..(' ;r\ni;\n,11\nSOUTH- W E S T E R N J 0 U R N A L-\n%\nfor moral character. But if classic learning lead not t|le\nmind toward morality or Christianity,\u2014if it have no refer-\nence to a future existence, but n ruincus and almost denning\ninfluence in driving it to a contrary extreme, it has failed lo\nanswer ihe second object of correct education, It hasahecdj\nbeen shown, that it almost entirely failed of the fiist: thcie.\nfore its claims are last and least to attention.\nLet no one inquire, nt this late day, whal shall be the tub.\nstitule for classic learning. The longest life of hcnlih n;d\ncompile nee, with every advantage of genius and instruction,\nis not sufficient to muster half the branches of useful Icamintr,\nThe world of infinite beauty is around us; and the laws by\nwhich all its pulls and appendages, exist and move, and arc\nadapted to the uses of man, furnish a host of sciences, nil\ncontending for the vacancy created by the resignation of su-\nperannuated classics. These sciences, we lave pioved,ate\nadapted to the natural development of mind ; lo the thcrcugh\ndiscipline of the reasoning powers; and ramify into all the\nbusiness of life: hence they best answer the first object of\ncorrect education. They lead the mind from beauty to beauty, from height to height, from magnificence to magnificence;\nfrom stupendous to omnipotent power and grandeur; to see\nthe dimiuutiveness of man, and his utter dependence upon\nand allegiance lo God, They answer, then, to the second\ngreat object of man's existence; therefore, their claims lo attention, acknowledge no parallel,\u2014they should be first, and\nlast, and greatest.\nledge of the English language might have brcn mastered, instantly abandoned; for what shall a man accept in exchange\nwhich is yet to be accomplished by the Latinist; and the\nstudent would thus be prepared to enter upon ihe active du\nties of manhood, at a much earlier period. Let us repeat\nemphatically, thai Ihe correct use of every word in Ihe English language, can be lea rncd without a knowledge of any other\nlanguage; though we confess, that lo trace ihe reasons and\norigin of a particular application,\u2014generally n useless task,\na knowledge of several languages may be requisite. Since,\nthen, a high degree of taste is but ornament, not positive and\nessential utility, let it be preceded by Utility\u2014by the sciences\nwhich apply lo the business of life; and let it be added, if\ntime bo found, for a high degree of ornament.\nThere are higher objections to classic study, when arraigned upon the second great business of education. Taste\u2014\nand sentiment, nnd oven intellectual might, if necessary, must\nbe sacrificed, when they militate against or endanger man's\neternal destiny. Who dares doubt, that three or four years',\nor half a score's training and drilling of ihe mind, to the love\nof pagan literature\u2014lo a taste for the lascivious poetry of an\nabandoned and dissipated Horace; to admire the character of\na brutal Achilles or \"perfidious jEneas\"; who dares deny,\nihat to study and admire the works of those who deify treacherous, bloody mortals, stones, and even shadows, in volumes\nof silly, disgusting absurdity,\u2014will teach man by degrees,\ninsidious and unnoticed, lo degrade\u2014then forget tho God\nwho created him ? to cherish the fiendish passions a debauched poet lias sung? If any one doubts it, he has not watched\nthe morals, and learned the character ofthe thousand subjects\nof college honors, in his own day. Take the opinion ol one\nof the most distinguished scholars, classic and philosophic,\nour country can afford; one who has been half u century\nwatching the signs of the times, mourning over human depravity, and seeking out the strongholds of vice. \" 1 remember,\" says he, -no instance of distinguished moral worth,\nthat owetl not its existence to the domestic influence of parental piety, which had so deeply imbued the mind with moral\nsentiment, or so fully developed the moral powers, as to place\nthe virtuous youth beyond the contaminating influence of ihe\npolluted fountains of Grecian and Roman literature. *    *   *\n\"So commonly have all the rank vices of the age- been found\nmost luxuriant among the educated classes, that philosophers,\nfor the last century, have often been employed in inquiring\ninto the causes of this great discrepancy. They have generally agreed, that it is owing, in a great measure, to the dominion of pagan literature, mythology and morality, necessary\nto college honors. There is so much more of Grecian and\nRoman ambition, cruelty, debauchery, perfidy, rapine, general licentiousness and lewdness, in an academic course, than\nof the Christian virtues and morality, that most theorists on\nthe moral culture of the learned world, ascribe to this the\ndelinquencies of the age.\"\nWe acknowledge that a vast change, to moral advantage,\nmight be made by a judicious substitution of works less exceptionable. But the udvocates of classic literature insist,\nthat Horace and Homer arc the best models of taste, and\ntherefore must be retained, and their influence must follow.\nWe demand, then, that the substitution be made, or the who\n\u2022\u2022(Hire of tli*\nA FORENSIC ESSAY\n',.-  ,':' 0 \u2014'\u2022 Al-C   tilt1   C-lili'llS  Of!\n(1:0   M.'tl.rm-itirs to pre.\nclonilnsnce, in Cleneml Education, greater tlit.it tin- clalii s of the Ancient Cna-\n\u25ba I.-* .'\u25a0\u2022 Head hcibro the J 'ffersou College and Washington Lyceum, 3d Jum-,\n; ::, by.I J. Wrouq, A. M., Professor of Lanjutvfesln Jefferson Colics?.\nWe appear before you, this evening, for the purpose of vin-\nHeating the claims of classical learning, which, assailed\nthough it has been, by some of high name and authority in\nthe literary world, has yet, perhaps, suffered more from the\nneglect and supineness of ils friends, than by ihe open and\nviolent attacks of its opposers. We would solicit your kind\nindulgence, whilst we invite your attention to a few brief and\ndesultory remarks, (thrown together in the intervals of intermission from perplexing and laborious professional engagements,) in behalf of a cause lo do entire justice to whirl,\nwould demand a more labored deft nee, and a much abler\nadvocate. In the short space to which we are necessarily\nrestricted, by the want of time and the fear of taxing too\ngreatly your patience, we can barely glance at the prominent\narguments in favor of the study of the ancient classics, and\nnotice, in a very cursory manner, some of the more common\nand popular objections, which have been urged against then,.\nIn our own country, a Bush and a Grimke, and in England, Lord Bacon, \" magnum el vencrabile iioiurn,\" Locke,\nAddison, and Milton, those giants of literature, whose very ;\nnames, even, would almost give a sanction to any system of\neducation, however chimerical or irrational, have condemned\nhe study ofthe Latin and Greek, at least as usually conducted\n\u2014that study to which they were indebted themselves for what-.\never of elegance, force and eloquence their own writings **","fullrs":{},"find":"421.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"420","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1895771","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.81 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
