<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/439</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>439</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/439/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"f\"\nm\ntSj.l.1\n\"\u2022Si\np'fj;';\n11\ni. if\nmm\nJ :\u2022&gt;,:\n72\nS OUTII- W E S T E R N  .1 0 U II N A L.\n'\nthe infected air more morbific, it lriusl be by some exhalation thrown off from the lungs or skin; for it is hardly possible that the general infection should he rendered more\nactive and morbific by the loss or consumption of those portions of it required to produce the disease in those attacked. The consumption, or taking away a part, certainly\ncannot change the qualities of the remainder; and the\nonly inference remaining is, that each body laboring under\nthe disease, becomes a new source of contamination to the\nlocal atmosphere, however small may be the influence of each.\nThe lungs and the skin are two of the greatest einuiie-\ntories of the human system, and carry off more fluids in a\ngaseous form, than all the other excretories together. The\nllitid which passes off by insensible perspiration from the\nskin alone, in the form of gas or vapor, is equal to about\nfive pounds in twenty-four hours; the same from the lungs,\nin the same time is about seven pounds\u2014besides which\neach respiration deprives the air breathed of u part of its\nogygon, and imparls to it a portion of carbonic acid gas or\nother gaseous compounds. The effluvia thus thrown out\nby a healthy body, or by a number of healthy bodies, are\nmore or less pernicous to those who respire them;\u2014how\nmuch more su then are they from bodies laboring under a\npestilential disease? A portion of these exhalations is diffused in the air nnd wafted and lost by free ventilation in\nthe general atmosphere; another portion is absorbed into\nthe beds and bedding used by the sick, which in close air\nacquires a new degree of virulence. This is evidently admitted by the non-contagionists, when they enjoin free ventilation and cleanliness as a precaution for safety, to those\nwho nurse yellow fever patients. If this effluvium were\nnot thrown olf; or if it were not morbific, why enjoin the necessity of cleanliness and ventilation about the sick chamber 'I\nThis may be infection, or it may not be. But all diseases, and especially epidemics are in some degree infectious, ami require more or less the precaution of cleanliness\nand ventilation, There are two kinds of morbific matter\neliminated from bodies diseased: which is by some called\ncontagion, or infection: the one is a gaseous exhalation,\nand the other a palpable matter of secretion.    Some diseases\nthrow off one kind of infection, and some the other:  I\nsome, such ns small-pox, plague, and malignant erysipelas,\nthrow oil'both kinds of infection. Others, such as vaccine\npock, are communicated only by a palpable virus, (if\nthose infections thrown oil* a gaseous form, some are so mild\nas scarcely to be estimated; others are more active, but\nstill controllable by proper care to bbviate the circumstan\nccs of close air, concentration of the effluvium, by\nmaintaining cleanliness and a proper temperature: others,\nas small pox, throw off a subtle exhalation, which, under\nnearly all circumstances, is infectious to the distance of a few-\nfeet, in all suites of temperature. The same may be said of\ntyphus and jail fever, which requires a cool or cold damp air\nfor its dissemination. The matter of contagion is originally\nmorbific per se: other diseases give off an effluvium which\nbecomes morbific, or infectious, under certain circumstances:\nthus of yellow fever.\nIn relation to yellow fever, tho great error of both tbecon-\ntagionists and tho non-contagionists, is altruism. Thenon\ncontagieuiist, because be, believes that personal contagion ha.\nno agency in the extrication ofthe miasm in tho first instance\nseems to think he would bo inconsistent if he admitted person,\nal infection possible in any case. The contugioiiist, because he\nbelieves the disease capable of reproducing itself by an infec.\nlions exhalation, thinks ho would be inconsistent, were he u\nadmit the possibility of the disease being produced otherwise\nIn this, as in many other disputed questions, we believe out\nmotto indicates the correct course, \" In medio est lulissimui\u25a0\"\nfor a disease may certn inly be epidemic, and in some detrre\ninfectious also : and a disease may sometimes originate from\nsome peculiar exciting circumstances, and yet, when produced, possess properties slightly infectious. For llie first\ncase of the most infectious disease, must have originated without personal contagion. If a disease be capable of reproducing itself once in a hundred limes, under the most favorable circumstances, it is certainly infectious. The infection is\nspecific, because in all eases it produces the same disease as\nihat from which the infection was produced. A disease which\nspreads alone by personal infection or contagion, makes but\nslow advances from one individual to another; while epidemic I\ninfectious diseases, attack a number of individuals in close\nsuccession. If yellow fever possess no infectious qualities,\nin impart none to the air, or clothing, to beds, blankets, &amp;c.\nwhy use the precaution of cleanliness and ventilation?\nI Ir.  Hush is the author of the most enlightened views on\nthe subject of yellow liver ; and when he wrote, a very gen\noral belief was, that it spread by contagion alone; or by llic\nexhalations from one person to another, exclusively of nn infected atmosphere.    Under this state of things, ihe sick were\noften deserted to their fate, by those who believed in the doctrine of specific contagion.    They believed thnt it was pro I\nduced .solely by communication with those sick of yclkm !\niiver, and from their infected clothes, &amp;c.    Hence it wash,- l\nlieved, that the great precaution for safety, consisted in keep \\\ning as remote as possible from the sick ; and where this beliel j\nolitaine-d  generally, the sick wero neglected and abandoned |\nby those who entertained such views.    Dr. Rush, in his zealous and philanthropic labors to remove this error, frequently\ncarried his arguments even beyond the point ut which he\nwould have rested, had such prejudico not obtained so generally.    He Strove to convince the people, that the disease nil\ntho result of local causes and circumstances; and not pro- .\nduced solely by the emanation from a diseased body, or from .\na secret contagion brought from the West Indies; by which\none  man was  infected; to whom all other cases were to 1\u00bb'\ntraced,    In his  eflbrls to disabuse the public mind on this'\npoint, it was not necessary to stop and discuss tho exceptions\nto the general rule; it was politic  in him to pass them by, I\nand direct all his efforts to establish the great fundamental!\ntruths which he was inculcating. Hence, nearly all his writ-\nings go to show, that it was of domestic origin,and spread '\nfrom an infected atmosphere, more or less local.    It was his\nbusiness to break down the general prejudice, and preparf\ntho way for calm and impartial reasoning : this bo did: and\nleft it to his successors, and to other times, when public sentiment  should he  prepared, lo define the precise nature nnd","fullrs":{},"find":"440.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"439","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1862693","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.78 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
