<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/538</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>538</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/538/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:05">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"We1'.-\n&lt;P .:\u2022;\u2022\nlb I  '\nI &gt;\u20ac\u25a0\u25a0'(: \u25a0&lt;\n: \u25a0,*\u25a0'\u2022 v. \u25a0 - :\n1? ..:ii--t\n-If*\niiMfi;;\n\u25a0nTSf\n\u25a0tl''}'.\n(#\n&gt;\u25a0\u2022'\nW\n17(5\nSOUTHWESTERN JOURNAL.\nNATCHEZ FEMALE ACADEMY.\nThe examination of the students in this institution, under\nthe charge of the Rev, E. II.Brunei- and Lady, has just closed.\nThough we were not present, we have learned from the committee of examination, that the young ladies acquitted themselves\nwith honor and credit. We understand that this examination\npassed off in such a manner as to convince every one present\nof Mr. and Mrs. Brunei's skill and qualifications in teaching,\nand to persuade the most incredulous that Female Education\nis no \"experiment.\"\nWe have the names of a number of the young ladies who\nwere said to manifest an uncommon degree of intellect\u2014\" But\nwhy praise one whore all are brave\" ?\nAs we expect soon to sec a full report from the committee,\nwe. shall say no more at present\nREGISTER OF METEOROLOGY.\nWashington, Mississippi.\u2014Latitude 31' 3G' 48\",   Longitude 9f. ja\nArntt. IITHErMOMETErII\nDuces.\nS.\nM.\nT.\nW.   4\nFrom Mitchell'* Geography.\nNatchez, the largest and most important town in the State,\nis situated on the east bank of the Mississippi, 300 miles above\nNew Orleans. It consists of two distinct parts; the lower\ntown, called Natchez under the Hill, or the Landing, is built\non a dead level on the margin of the river, about half a mile\nin length, and from 100 to 200 yards in breadth, and is occupied by ware-houses, tippling-shops, boarding-houses for the\nboatmen, &amp;c.; the upper town stands on a lofty bank or bltifii\nrising abruptly to the height of 300 feet, and is the residence\nof the better class of citizens. The streets are wide, regularly disposed, and adorned with fine shade trees, while many\nof the houses are embosomed in groves of the orange, palmetto, and other trees, and ornamental shrubs. This place\nhas been occasionally visited by tlie yellow fever and other diseases, but is during the greater part of the year an agreeable and healthful residence, and seems of late years to have\nlost its character for insalubrity. Natchez is 300 miles above\nNew Orleans, yet it carries on a considerable direct trade with\nforeign countries, and large ships come up to the town. Its\nriver and inland trade is, however, more extensive. In 1835,\n35,000 bales of cotton were shipped from the port. Its population in 1830 was 2790, but at present is probably .1500.\nVicksburg, 103 miles above Natchez, and about 12 miles\nbelow the mouth of the Yazoo River, stands in a picturesque\nsituation, on the declivity of several considerable eminences,\ncalled the Walnut Hills, rising abruptly from tho river. Il\nis surrounded by numerous large and rich plantations, and is\nthe depot of a large tract of newly settled country, which a\nfew years since was owned and occupied solely by Indians. In\n1835 it shipped off 55,000 bales of cotton, and contains at present probably 3500 inhabitants, having doubled ils numbers\nwithin the last two years. The merchants have commenced\na direct intercourse by sea with the Atlantic ports, and are\nmaking exertions to have it declared a port of entry. All the\ntrade of the Yazoo country centres in this place. Vicksburg is upwards of 500 miles from the Gulf of Mexico, by\ntho Mississippi River\nT.\nP.\nS.\ns.\nM,\nT.   10\nErrata.\u2014167th page, second column, twelfth line from\nthe bottom, for in sight, read in situ.\nF.   13\nS. 11\nS. 15\nM. 1C\nT.   1\nw. is\nT. Ill\nF. 20\nS. 21\nS. 22\nM. 23\nT. 21\nW. 25\nT. 2(i\nP.\nS. 28\nS. 29\nM.  30\n80 88\n70 78\nI\n75 70\n19,7380\n027072\n7871\nI\n7S80\n78 80\n00 83,81\n59\n7-1 75\n78,7\nIT\n59 7983\n0083 85\n7283 81\n7283 85\n5863.65\n02,05 00\ni    I\n507175\n08,77,80\nC4j79.'SS\n078183\n00,80 81\n6884 83\nI\n00 78 85\n72 80 85\n70 78\n71:73\n75 7!i\n76 80\n80,75\n\u2022200\n0801\n0900\n07:01\n07j08\n7-170\n7002\n7364\n75 65\n08 a:\n6865\n09 65\nT\nI\n7875\n66 65\n00 54\n6466\n717(1\n757.\n77(75\n78 72\nT\n78 71\nT\n83 81\nI\n08 61\nI\n110 01\nI\n70 71\n-Mean\nMonthly Mean   71 J.\nBAROMETEH.\nj i\nU 111 M\n' 39,64\n29.05\n29,01 ' 80,64\n29,67 j 29,09\n29,08 ; 29,08,5\n29,08 j 29,70\n29,01 i 29.G4\n29,19 29,52\n29,71 ; 29,7-1\n29,80 ' 29,81\n29,70 | 29,72 29,00\n29,85\n29,58\n29,00\n29,62\n29,6.1\n29,61\n29,50\n29,54\n29,74\n29,70\n29,70 | 29,83\n\u00a39,90 I 30,97\n29,90\n29,91\n29,75\n29,90\n29,88\n29,71\n29,02 ! 29,01\n29,05 ! 29,01\n29,80 : 30,83\n30,01 j 29,99\n30,03\n29,98\n29,91\n29,81\n29,05\n29,51\n29,57\n29,00\n29,03\n29,73\n29,70\n29,99\n29,98\n29,92\n29,74\n29,01\n29,50\n29,00\n29,01\n29,71\n29.7G\n29.71\n29,87\n29,88\n29,79\n29,03\n29,00\n29,07\n29,85\n29,97\n29,92\n29,93\n29,81\n29,09\n29,51\n29,51\n29,58\n29,58\n29,70\n29,78\n29,08\n2 07 29,71,-1 29,71,l] 39,70,1\nVinci,*' di\ni-'icticnucdf,\nsw2i 'J\nn 2 I\ne 1 n 3 e\ne2 1\ne 2s c 2\nseSs3seSti4 i\u00bb\ns s w 3 w 3 3\nn 2 n w- 9\nneSmhij\nw 2 s w 3 2\nn e 1 3 n 3\nn e 2 n 3 1\ne 1 sw 2 w 1\nsw23\nsi 234\ns34\ns3sc4n56\nn 34\nw 2 n w 3\ns 2 3 s w I\ns w 1 3 s 2\ns w 1 2s 1\nsi 3\nsl23\ns34ne3swl\ns 2 s w 3 2\ns23\ns3sw2n 5ne3ear\nIi24e5ne4\ne2sc24\nMISCELLANEOUS   REMARKS. \u201e\nApim, 1\u2014A scorching day i smoke returned atSP.'M.I lunar halo fetal -\nNona ensi wind brought dense amoks,drooping burnt leaves   a-'*\u2122'\u2122,\";\nitraliia.   4-Sunlosi In smoke.   6-I.lglit showoral noon.  O-Sbowers \u00ab'\"Kg\nIhe day.   AtSI\\ M. avion urrlcono squalli Innim. lowest at sji ro\u00bb[jJ\"\n\u25a0-'tv 89.60 in 10 mica : a constant blase of lightning, with Itulo !\"!\u00bb'','\nwinds S l-:. s, clouds s. w.i rain commenced oner wind abated; some nail \u00bb',\n9-Clrroatroi. 10-Olrrus. 11\u2014Light Ulrrum lunar Inlo. K-u\"\"r\u201eZ\ncirro-strat. I3-dn. H-do. 10-I.owatratus, cirro-strat. oumulu;; \"\u25a0-;\",,\ncum., Blritue. Sunset halo. ir-WInd and clouds S. eill 5 V. M-. ft\"*\"*\nchanged to N', withe violent Blorm of wind, followed by raln-Bll IU\u00ab{\ncorresponding lo Mr. Bspy'stl rv of storms    IS\u2014fine weather nil 0\",.  .,;\ndark threatening clrro-cum.   SO\u2014Tli ler s w. m dark; wind N. B. &lt;\"'-.'\n-Overcast, anel thon clear.   B7-Urge cumulus and rapid cirrus. \u00ab-*&lt;\u00bb \u201e'\ninn resiin... siorin, g rated apparently over Natcho*,, w -c Iho upward\n\u00bbl&gt; bly I'\" I. mak ng dread commotion among the clouda, and ewelie \u00abJ*J\nejery atnallor one.   Hull stones I'. Inches In diameter foil.   Very few feU*\u2122\nehosi inn in r. miles dlsin i em each s ihev were vory abundant.  -'-'r\nwilh heavy thunder., 30-Olrro cum, thundoi and rain i scarce a meteor *\u25a0' ;\nin \u25a0 month ; a few about tho 93d; lodlacal light still in thewest, till\u00bb\u00bb'\n, moonlight,\nRECAPITULATION-? clear clavs; 19 cloudy , 0 smoky I 4 rainy.","fullrs":{},"find":"539.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"538","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1834877","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
