<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Louisiana Railroad Depot Photograph Collection</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate"
      authority="naf"
      authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
      valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
      displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
   <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
   <role>
      <roleTerm type="text"
                authority="marcrelator"
                authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
   </role>
</name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">&lt;p&gt;The scene of comings and goings in small towns and large across Louisiana and a hub for their commerce, train stations and railroad depots were at the crossroads of community social and economic life. This collection is comprised of images of 129 stations in the state from Houma to Bastrop and points in between, and dates from 1905 to 1984, reflecting the heyday of rail travel to its decline. Railroads represented in the collection include the Illinois Central, Kansas City Southern, Louisiana and Arkansas, Missouri Pacific, Santa Fe, Southern Pacific, Texas and New Orleans, and Texas and Pacific, among others.&lt;/p&gt;</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">&lt;p&gt;This collection is comprised of images of 129 stations in the state from Houma to Bastrop and points in between, and dates from 1905 to 1984, reflecting the heyday of rail travel to its decline. Railroads represented in the collection include the Illinois Central, Kansas City Southern, Louisiana and Arkansas, Missouri Pacific, Santa Fe, Southern Pacific, Texas and New Orleans, and Texas and Pacific, among others.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-sc-p16313coll79</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Search)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/search/collection/p16313coll79</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Landing Page)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p16313coll79</identifier>
</mods>
