<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 30</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/586</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>586</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/586/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 30","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":".I!' V\"',\ntl'' -ft I\n*! M.\nI -M\n\u00ab\u25a0;:\u25a0\u25a0\nin\n1\n'':p -\n: ?\u25a0\u25a0.,. '\nI\ni\nS OUTH-W E S T E R N   J 0 U R N A L.\n'I\" \"I\"\n1\nWe remark that the map is particularly correct in the orthography of the Indian names, in which the Stale of Mississippi is rich above all other States in the Union\nFor Hie- SMiilli-WiiMi-ru .Iciurnii\nTHE  SEASONS. \u2014No. II.\nnv joiin v. shannon, nsa.\nSUMMER.\nSpring, \u00abiib a sigh, lurns from the verdant plain,\nAmi from lhc far-off hills llic summer's song\nWinds o'er the broad expanse of air and earth,\ntint still reluctantly the maiden yields\nJlur ilirone, and in th'embowerlng shade of woods,\nLingers awhile'to foster many a flow'r,\nThat, fearful of the sudden wintry blasts\nThat sometimes mark her ever fickle reign,\nWere half afraid lo blow; but now that spring,\nWith more of fostering care, protects her charge,\nAnd like a mother whom stern death has lobbed\nOf all but one, hangs on that single one\nWilli more than double love, till her young charge\nGrows in its beauty and ils strength\u2014so too\nThe timid flower peeps out and buds, then blossoms !\nHark ! the last strain of spring's fast dying song\nIs sinking on Ihe ear in cadence low,\nVet slill il lingers like lhc long-loved tones\nOf some departed spirit which nt night\nWake In Ihe cells of memory, or like\nThe sigh of some fond heart that's breaking.\nSee! from the hills, in robes of living light,\nThe summer comes\u2014and from the orient bound\nThe glowing sun with chariot wheels of fire\nBursts on the shrinking gaze,   Now parched plains\n&lt; Jasp for the welcome showers.   Now scarce a leaf.\nNot e'en Ihe aspen, quivers on the -spray.\nWhich pendant.shades the liny Streamlet's bank.\n'Tisnoon-day, and the sunbeams seem to dance\nAnd tremble on the bosom of tbe air,\nIf airlhere be.   So hushed ir lies\u2014'twould seem\nIl followed in ihe wake of flying spring.\nThe panting herd are gathered in Ihe shade\nAnd silence reigns around, save where the bay\nOf deep-mouthed hound, or chirp of lonely bird\nFalls lazily upon the quiet ear.\nA dreamy languor hangs on bill and dell.\nTbe very things of summer birth now sleep,\nThe breeze thai woke the morning nestles close\nin tiee-top high, or breathes so softly low,\nIt bul provokes to rest.   The eye-lid closes.\nSleep'\t\nWake! for the southern breeze, in sportive play,\nIs chequering heav'n with clouds; wake! wake I the storm\nComes riding onward.   On ils hurtling from.\nThe lightning Hashes, nnd from out iisbreasl,\nThe thuuder murmurs to Ihe dark'ning plain ;\nWake ! for the sounding hail descends amain,\nBorne on the bosom of the wind; up! up I\nThe storm-fiend lightens in the rushing blast.\nTispasi! the storm is o'er! the brlght'ning bow\nThat arches half the east, proclaims that peace\nAgain is o'er us.   How the meadow sparkles!\nAnd the rushing streams that late half feared lo flow.\nCome thundering onwards.\nThe summer is our manhood.    Yonih, like spring,\nRetires apace,and nobler spheres now claim,\nThe. hopes, lhc fears, the love, the hale that burn ;\nAmbition's fire,\u2014like to Ihe noon-day sun,\nWithers each flower\u2014consigns our fears lo sleep \u2022\nllul when lhc storm of misery clouds Ihe scene\nAh! then they waken to another light;\nHappy are wcif then affection's bow\nLightens our lonely hours, and soothes our grief\nWith promise of a brighter day.\nHebrkw Poktry. Considerable obscurity often rests\nupon the moaning of the sacred poetry of the Scriptures\nfrom not knowing who the speaker is. The Knickerbocker\ncontains the following from a well known chapter, as an ib\nlustration:\u2014\n\"A choral company is introduced, addressing the Messiah,\nafter some glorious victory over his enemies:\nChorus,   Who is this that comelh from Edom 1\nWilli garments deeply dyed from Botsra 7\nThis that is magnificent in bis apparel,\nMarching on in ihe greatness of his strength 1\nMessiah. I, who publish righteousness, and am mighty lo save\nChoiii'-i-   Wherefore is thine apparel red 1\nAnd thy garments as of one that Ireadeth the win.' ral'\nMessiah. I have trodden Iho vat alone ;\nAnd of lhc peoples Ihere was nol a man with me.\nAnd I irod theni in mine anger,\nAnd I trampled them in mine indignation ;\nAnel their life-blood was sprinkled upon my garments;\nAnd I have stained all mine apparel.\nFor the day of vengeance was in mine hearl;\nAnd the year of my redeemed was come.\nAnd I lordeed and there was no one to help;\nAnd I was astonished, thai there was no one to uphold,\u2014\nTherefore mine own arm wrought salvation for me;\nAnd mine indignation itself sustained me ;\nAnel I trod down Ihe peoples in mine anger;\nAnd I crushed Ihem in mine indignation;\nAnd I spilled their life-blood on the ground.\"\nTRANSCRIPT OF THE MINUTES OF THE LYCEUM\nMay 86, 183s.\nThe Society met in Natchez, according to adjournment,\nand elected the following gentlemen as officers for the ensuing year, viz:\nOn. J. W. MoNETTK, President.\nC. O. Forshey, Vice President.\nS. C. Merwin, Secretary.\nJ. A. Van Hoesen, Treasurer.\nC. L. Dubuisson, ) \u201e\nr Curators,\nE. II. Bruner,     j\nSome resolutions were then offered to umend the Constitution, which were laid over, lo be taken up at the nextregubn\nmonthly meeting.\nOn motion, the Society adjourned, to meet in Washington\non the first Saturday in June.\nJune 2, 1838.\nThe Society met in the Methodist Church in Washington.\nAfter the reading of tho minutes of the last meeting, '\"r\nDubuisson addressed the Society in a short and appropriate\nvaledictory, and then invited the President elect, with the oilier officers of the Society, to take their seats. Previous t\"\nthe resumption of ihe. regular business, Dr. Monette delivered an inaugural well suited to the occasion.    On motion of","fullrs":{},"find":"587.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"586","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1732410","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.65 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
