<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 28</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/617</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>617</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/617/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 28","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"251\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n*!v'\nl^'k\nm\nm\n4-'\nP\n\u25a0.*\u00ab.\nI\ni\ni *\ntfti\nIf\n1\nIf\ni'|\n1*\n'\nsword for my native land.' If Europe is to be revolutionized it must be by such men as these, and such influences as\nthey exert. Willi such a battle cry it is not likely that Poland,\ntho land of chivalry and romance, will rest forever in her\npresent abject situation. The Pole may be wary, but he will\nnot be timid; and when tho time is ripe he will be at his\npost. Though the minion of a tyrant sit in the halls of her\nprinces\u2014though the iron car of the proud Ammon of the\nNorth, grind in tho dust the unprotected and defenceless\u2014\nthough the ploughshare sink deep in the foundation of her\nancient capital\u2014though the frozen plains of Siberia receive\nihe noblest spirits she can boast\u2014Poland will arise from\nthe ashes of her desolation, fling her broad banner to the\nbreeze, and in the palace of St. Petersburg, '\u201e' sound tbe\ntrump of freedom in the despot's ear.\" Years may pass,\nperhaps an age, but the time will come. The severe measures against the Poles show that with all his power, the\nEmperor is not without a wholesome fear of the consequences of the late Polish insurrection. And these very measures will eventually bring about the very things he would\navoid. Every exile becomes at once a missionary in the\ncause for which he fought nnd suffered. The Emperor well\nknows that the progress of liberal principle is rapid towards\nhis dominions, and that Poland is a dangerous neighbor.\nPoland did not bleed in vain; she contended for proper principles, and but for the jealousies of some of her nobles, with\nthe proper spirit. Present sufferings will chasten and puri\nfy from selfishness, without crushing her spirit.\n\" To the man of science and thought, no country on earth\npresents so interesting a field for contemplation as Germany\nFrom the time when Luther, with an arm of omnipotence,\nswept away the night of ages, and freed tho intellect, which\nhad grovelled in darkness and despair, from tho shackles of\nsuperstition; since Guttenberg put the press into successful\noperation and poured into the soul an inexhaustible flood of\nlight, Germany has been the land of thought. In philology and tho abstruse studies of mental philosophy, and the\nhigher walks of poetry, the Germans have left all others far\nbehind\u2014while in the science of government and practical\nimprovement, they have been culpably negligent. Recently,\nhowever, there seems to have taken place a favorable change.\nAfter the return of Bonaparte from Elba, and when all Europe was trembling before his gigantic power, the princes of\nGermany, to save themselves from impending danger, made\na voluntary promise that their subjects should have a share\nin the government by representation. This promise was afterwards approved and confirmed by a federal act of Vienna,\nviz: there should be a separate legislative constitution.\nThough these promises were never performed, and were nol\nmade for thai purpose, they have made a deep impression\non the minds of the people. They have shown them that\nprinces must sometimes play the suppliant; that the real\nsource of power is the people, and that the will to exercise\nit makes them invincible, for without their enthusiasm and\ncourage Bonaparte could not have been crushed; that no\nreliance could be placed on men, who, through cowardice or\ntreachery, would make any promise to delude their credulous subjects.    The hope of possessing a positive interest in\nthe government, directed their thoughts and feelings in a new\nchannel. Still the Germans are a slow people, nnd cannot\nbo moved by sudden impulses. They regard, with apparent\nindifference, but in reality with deep interest, the progress of\nliberal principles among their neighbors. The emotions of\nsuch a poople lie too deep to be observed by a passinn\nglance. They gather facts and principles, and retiring into\nthe 'fortress of their thoughts,' ponder deeply on them.\nThey have not forgotten the deceitful promise of their princes\nnor havo they forgotten that vengeance is due for the treachery. Reform may precede revolution, nnd fortunate will it\nbo for the people and the world, if that order of things be\ncarried out. Should the powers that be, yield to tho tide of\npopular feeling, the revolution will be silent and gradual.\nbut if they are so infatuated as to attempt to suppress it, no\none can foresee where it will end. The principles which\nare beginning to shew themselves are our principles, and\nthe spirit that moves upon and troubles the waters, is the\nspirit of practical freedom which sprung up with our revolution, and no human power can quell them. Opposition\nmay restrain for a time, but the longer the restraint continues\nthe more sensible will be the explosion : As the mountain\nstream, whose course tbe falling avalnnche has stopped, rises\nslowly and gently until it reaches the sumr.it of the obstacle, then bursts away with a force that rocks and mountains\ncannot resist.\n\"A late German writer who is enthusiastic in tho anticipation of a revolution, says: 'Thought precedes actions, as\nlightning precedes thunder. Thunder, in Germany, truly\ndeserves the name of German; it does not come on in successive cli-.ps, but rolls on slowly and gradually; but when you\nhear a peal louder than any yet heard since the commencement of the world, then rest assured that German thunder\nhas struck its mark. Then shall eagles fall dead from tho\nair, and lions, in the remotest desert, crawl into their royal\ndens. Germany will witness tho performance of a drama,\nto which the revolution of France will be but a mere idyll.\nEvery thing is at present calm, it is true ; and if you see a\nfew men here and there gesticulating violently, do not suppose that these are to bo tho actors of the great drama. They\nare merely the curs that go biting about the arena, previous\nto the arrival of the gladiators, who arc to figure in tho deadly combat. When the clock strikes, nations will crowd\niround Germany, as on tho stands of n great amphitheatre,\nto witness vast and fearful games.'\n\"On the movements of Germany, depends the destiny of\na large portion of continental Europe. The influence which\nthe Germans possess over all minds, is very great. When\nsuch men become excited, on such a subject, their enthusiasm must bo deep and steady. When such intellect and\nlearning take hold of the philosophy of utility, we may\nlook for results worthy of their source,\n\" Nor is this spirit confined to Europe alone\u2014it has been\nseen in every quarter of tho globe\u2014in every island of the\nsea. From the insular empire of Japan to the Red Sea\u2014\nfrom tho coral capes of Ceylon to the icy rivers of Siberia,\noccasional scintillations of tbe celestial fire are stricken out","fullrs":{},"find":"618.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"617","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1739587","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
