<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 7</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2232</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2232</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2232/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 7","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"m\n6th\u2014The opening of commercial highways across the Isthmus.\n7th\u2014The establishment, in the Mississippi valley, of a navy-yard,\na not and work-shops, which in war shall have strength, capacity,\nd resources enough to give us command of the Gulf of Mexico, and\nSntrol ofthe commerce passing through it.\ngt[j The free navigation ofthe Amazon River, and the building up\nthere of those business relations and friendly ties, which hold nations\ntogether in the bonds of peace and friendship.\nThese are the measures\u2014the means are simple : they consist in a\nfirm reliance upon our own abilities, with a determination to perform\n0Ur part in the matter, and to require the government to do its part\nas well.\nSuch are the questions which I propose to consider, except in so\nfar as the proposed rail-roads may be involved in the case. That, as\nalready remarked, I leave to wiser heads.'\nIf the people of the South and West will be but true to them-\nse}ves\u2014if they will put their shoulders to the wheel, and, as one\nman, appear, in the persons of their representatives here, in the halls\nof Congress, and insist upon fair, even-handed justice in the appropriations for public works, that course of legislation will follow, which\nlong ago ought to have been adopted with regard to the Mississippi\nRiver, and kindred subjects.\nI do not present these measures, or any of them, as substitutes or\nrivals to the proposed system of railways ; nor do I hold them up as\nmeasures which will, ought, or should divert attention from the railways. There will be ability enough in the Convention to treat all of\nthese measures, and to present each one to the public in its true bearings upon the common weal; and there is energy with enterprise\nenough in that region to carry them all on together.\nII. The drowned lands in the Mississippi valley have been ceded\nto the states in which they lie, upon condition that those states, in\nreclaiming them, will confine the river within its banks.\nThe reclamation of these lands would improve the climate of a\nvast region of country, and make it much more salubrious : it would\nadd vastly to the wealth of those states by giving value to the lands,\nand greatly increase their commercial resources by bringing immense\nregions ot these vacant lands under cultivation *, and it would also\nvastly improve the navigation of the river.\n-An object of so much importance to the health and, prosperity of\nso many people, in so many states, is certainly worth looking after ;\naad the work, when done, should be done in the most thorough and\nj manner.\n, herefore ^et us P^y Congress for the appointment of an engineer\nho shall plan the work; and for the enactment of a statute, requir-\n8 jhe states to have the work done according to that plan.\n-Lhis work is to last for all time.   Suppose, therefore, merely for\ne sake of illustration, that one of the states above Louisiana should\nrow     tUnate In the adoPtion of a Plan &gt; that after haviriS let the\ntk    ' accepted it, and parted with the lands, experience should prove\nplan to be bad or the work to be useless.    Louisiana then is","fullrs":{},"find":"2233.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2232","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"555958","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.53 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
