<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/475</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>475</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/475/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"i\nIf\n'?'#\u25a0'&gt;\n. i a.-i;'\n- sc'-. ?\\\n!-:J#\ni ! ?   t* *\n!. i5\n102\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n\u25a0':\nand make all our deductions from them; as if all the operations of nature were known lo us; or as if nothing was carried on in the natural world, except the few comparatively\ngross operations which are cognizable to our few and imperfect senses. Hence it happens, that in attempting to trace\nthe secret cause of yellow fever miasm, as it is called, we\nhave been led so often to thoso things which are offensive to\nour senses; notwithstanding the same exist equally when no\nyellow fever prevails; and notwithstanding the poison of yellow fever cannot bo detected by any of our senses.\nWe doubt not, the precursor most essential to yellow fever\nepidemics, at Natchez, as well as elsewhere, will be found to\nbe hot, calm, sultry weather, for ten or fifteen days in succession, immediately before it breaks forth. If no infected air\nbe introduced, the disease will not manifest itself in so short\na period as otherwise, nor in air as slightly contaminated as\notherwise. We conceive the vicissitudes of weather, whatever they may have been a month or six weeks previously, have\nno immediate effect upon ils production. In all probability,\nthe effects necessary for an epidemic are elaborated principally within twenty days or less, immediately previous to the appearance of the epidemic. Although the miasm is elaborating continually during hot weather, it never accumulates in\nsuch quantities as to produce disease, until after several hot,\ncalm, sultry days, during' which time also, the air, being stagnant, becomes exhausted and charged with exhalations. If\naltera week or ten days of clear, hot, sultry weather, calm,\ncloudy, or foggy weather succeed, nt an extreme temperature\nduring the day, of 85\" to 05\", the miasm Still continues to accumulate, though more slowly, until strong winds or cold\nnights succeed. Upon this principle, do we account for yellow (ever having prevailed in calm, cloudy, or wet weather,\nalthough it did not appear during the previous hot and dry\nweather.\nThe most common appearances observed in the weather,\nimmediately preceding yellow fever, are as follows; viz : the\ntemperature in the shade, from 88\" to 05\" at noon, with warm\nnights, for ten or fifteen days, at least, in succession. During\nthis time, whether the weather be clear or cloudy, or attended\nwith moderatj rains, the air is not agitated by any stronc\nwinds, such as sweep out every part of a city; the air feels\noppressive, and respiration is oppressive. Durinn- such\ntimes, especially in August and September, every precaution\nshould be observed, until a change of weather ensues; a por\ntion of the population should disperse; strangers and unaccli\nmated persons should leave the city, all unusual exposure\nshould be avoided, all fatigue, debauch, or intemperance, or\nirregular hours, shoubl be strictly avoided, nt least until after\nu favorable change of weather. Every precaution necessary\nto keep up a proper equilibrium of tho healthy functions\nshould be punctiliously observed by those who value their\nlives above a few dollars, or above temporary sensual gratifications. This remark is especially applicable to those who\nare properly unaccliinated.\nI shall now proceed to give a sketch of tho history of the\ndifferent yellow fever epidemics of Natchez, with a few remarks relative to each.\n'-. The EnnEMicoF 1817 is considered as the first in the I\nhistory of Natchez; although I have been very credibly in.\nformed,, that individual cases were often seen previously\n:ome of which, I have been informed, appeared to have ori'\nginated in the city; and others derived their infection from\nNew Orleans, or from infected boats. Dr. Tooley informs\nme that occasional cases occurred about the city in 1817, a,\nearly as July and August; it did not become epidemic, how-\never, until the 28th of September. Dr. Perlee* says th,\nstuie ofthe weather had been such as predisposed very strong,\nyto violent disease, even in the early part of September,and\n'required only a small concentration of power to produce i\nsweeping epidemic.\" \"At this lime,\" says he, \" when lb,\npopulation was highly susceptible, the Washington steam.\nboat reached us from New Orleans, with persons on board ill\nof yellow fever; some of whom were landed; and several\nyoung men from town went on board, who were all taken\nsick soon after and died. The disease spread rapidly, am!\nwith most destructive malignity. For some time it hadii!\nsway over the whole city. On the 28th of September, tli,\nphysicians publicly announced the existence of yellow fever.\n:mel a large portion of the population retired to the country.\"\nOn the 1st of October, the President of the Selectmen, EJ\nward Turner, issued a circular, advising the citizens to seel;\nrefuge in the country, and regretting, at the same time, lljl\nthe disease had been in the city several (lays before it wusaii-\nnounced. The disease continued to prevail among those win\nremained until about the 9th of November; nnd severs!\ncases occurred among those who returned us late as '.lie loll\nof that month.\nThe whole number of deaths in the city (lining tliiscpi\ndemic, was one hundred and thirty-four, besides somendio\ncontracted the disease in the city and died in the country. Dr.\nPerlee States that the number was estimated about three hundred : but that is doubtless an exaggerated estimate. The\npopulation of the city at that time was comparatively small.\nThe epidemic commenced late, nnd terminated rather early\nFrom a meteorological table given by Dr. Perlee, it aj-\npears that the mean temperature of July was 80\u00b0, of August\n77\u00b0, of September 73\u00b0. The quantity of rain up to the lint\nof September, was rather more than usual; being in July\n3-95 inches; in August 4-41 inches: in September l-W\ninches. I have not been able to ascertain what was the daily\nextreme temperature of September; although Dr. Pen1\"\ninforms us it was a hot, sultry, an 1 humid month.\nTho \"predisposing causes,\" to which Dr. PerleeascriW\nthis epidemic, are exhalations from city filth ; from ground)\nnewly made in leveling tho streets; from stagnant water in\nthe streets and cellars; from the old grave-yard near the centre of the city. These various exhalations, he supposed\nproduced a high state of \"general predisposition,\" and will\n\"other causes of insalubrity\" prepared the inhabitants fora\u00bb\nepidemic, so soon as any exciting cause should occur, orw\nsoon as any concentration of power should take place in tl&gt;&lt;\npredisposing cause. This ho leaves us to infer, was effect\nby the introduction of infected nir and yellow fever patients ftw1\nthe steamboat Washington :\u2014for besides several yellow few\nj patients landed from her,\u2014the air in her cabin was so bigUf\n' Chapman's fifed, Jou\nr. v.a, p, r,.\nJul\nJul;\nthai\n'I'll.\nin I\nvail,\nthan\nof 1\nhigh\nlen v\nhigh\nDi\ncause\nsujipc\nstroni\n1818\nticula\n1819,\nparto\n'\u25a0pideii","fullrs":{},"find":"476.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"475","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1800307","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
