<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2081</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2081</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2081/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:43">{"title":"Section 2, Page 17","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"17\nresolutions already passed would cover that matter,\nand the motion was lost.\n\\ general call was here made for the Hon. John\nMoore, who delivered a speech of great importance,\nfull of facts and figures, which will be found very-\ninteresting and is as follows :\n\"I respond to your call, fellow-citizens, cheerfully, and must\nsay that I am glad to see the citizens of New Orleans, and\nthe State generally, aroused on the subject of intercommunication by means of railroads. Whilst we have been\nslumbering, our fellow-citizens of the Eastern States have\nbeen constructing canals and railroads to every available\n.oiiit in this great valley to draw off the trade from New\nOrleans; even our Southern neighbors are taking the lead-\narid unless some active measures are taken to counteract the\ntendency of these works, New Orleans must soon feel the\neffects most wofully. I will detain you no longer with these\ngeneralities, but will speak of the subject which brings us\nlogether. The project of a railroad from opposite this city\nto Washington, six miles beyond Opelousas, passing through\nLafourche and Attakapas; giving the road such deviations\nfrom a right line as will give the best route and insure the\ngreatest amount of business. It will make it, according to\nmy estimate, about 172 miles long; and I am of opinion that\nit can be laid down within the estimate made by B. H. Payne,\nEsq., S 1,(500,000.\nThat part of the route with which I am best acquainted,\ntrom Berwick's Bay to Opelousas, presents fewer difficulties,\nami the railroad can be laid down as cheap, if not cheaper,\n'rail any other railroad in Louisiana, or elsewhere\u2014there\nWill be but one stream, worth noticing, to cross, (the Vermil-\nl,\"n) and that presenting no difficulty, being narrow and\nshallow,witbgood firm banks\u2014all others between those points\nMe mere gullies, The entire distance, with little exception.\n3","fullrs":{},"find":"2082.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2081","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"539535","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
