<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/462</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>462</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/462/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"mm\n11*\nI M\ni-'p\noo\nS 0 U 'I'll- W E S T E R N J 0 U B N A L .\ns\n:l M(\n.|J,\n\"\nobjectionable; yet, acknowledging that great. trut-b, the exist\nence of a superior Being, to whom man is accountable, produced a beneficial influence, and this benefit is in proportion\nto the strength or weakness of the conviction.\nFrom all that wo are able to conjecture, guided by the dim\nlights of ancient history, those nations who were mostdevoted\nto religious worship, were the most civilized, enlightened, and\nhappy. This applies especially to Egypt, Greece, and Rome.\nAnd these great nations began to decline in their political,\nmoral, and social relations, when their great men began to\ncontemn and ridicule the worship of the gods, without substituting any purer form of worship.\nThere is still another remark which I wish to make in\nthis place. It is not tho splendor of military achievements,\nw'.iich constitutes the standard of national prosperity. Often,\nwhen a nation's anus are triumphant every where, every political privilege is trampled on, and all the moral and social\nrelations are disregarded. A noble Roman once exclaimed,\nwhen he had achieved a signal victory for his country, \"a\nfew more such victories would ruin Rome.\"\nThere nre many evils which Christianity has not yet been\nnble to extirpate; but, in most, or all instances, it has mitigated them. The horrors of war have been greatly moderated, by entirely exempting women and children from its\nfury, and attending to the safety and comfort of prisoners. By\nthe good fuith with which Christian nations observe solemn\ntreaties, more than half the evils of war are prevented.\nThe good faith observed by the commercial community in\nChristian countries, is a source of many of the comforts in a\ncivilized state of society. Nothing but mutual confidence can\nenable the merchants of distant countries to carry on the extensive business necessary to supply the wants of a populous\nnnl civilized country. This good faith may be attributed to\nChristianity, as it has never existed, to so great an extent,\nwhere this pure form of religion did not prevail. Compare\nthe well-placed confidence of an English or American merchant, with the treachery of a Chinese or East Indian.\nMan, while in tin's world, is liable to misfortune, poverty,\nand sickness. In most Christian countries, provision is made\nfor these unavoidable miseries. Every asylum for taking\ncare of the helpless orphan, every hospital to nurse and cur.\nthe sick, every alms-house to take care of the infirm, tin\naged, or the lunatic, is a triumph of Christianity over heartless atheism, or dark heathenism. Institutions of this char-\nacter have never been known to flourish, save under the benign influence of Christianity.\nBut thelendorest and most important relation in life, is tin\ndomestic circle. And here Christianity has done much for\nman. Polygamy, the fruitful source of family contention\nand heartburning; and divorce at pleasure, the no less fruitful\nsource of injustice and licentiousness, nro indigenous in every\nheathen soil. Had Christianity done no more for man, than\nto regulate the domestic circle, it would have been a boon\nworthy of the interposition of a benevolent God, and laying\nman under boundless obligations to him. And ho who could\ncontemn, or lightly esteem such a boon, would prove himsell\nexceedingly ungrateful, or brutishly sensual.\nBut does Christianity promote literature and the sciences?\n\u25a0LtflCi\nIt would be sufficient, in answering this question, to refer to\ntho present stato of the world. Where are the most enlirrh.\ntened nations to be found? Is it not in Christendom? And\nit is worthy of remark, that, by the influence of Christianity\nthese nations have been elevated from a state of br.barism\nor savngism, to their present state And here I would endi-a-\nvor to correct an error, which appears to be very common.\nIt is believed that the ignorance of the dark ages is the result\nof tho introduction of Christianity in the Roman empire\nNothing can bo more foreign from the truth. The truth is\nthat the military despotism which had prevailed long before\nChristianity had any voice in that government, had checked\nthe genius of that people; and the effeminacy which so gene,\nrally prevailed, prepared the way for the savage invaders ol\nthe fifth find sixth centuries. In these invasions and conquests, we have the real cause of the great decline of learning. The rulers of the various countries of Europe, were\nilliterate savages. The only reason that Asia wus not so\ndeeply involved in the night of, the dark ages, was, ils con-\nquerors, the Saracens, were far more enlightened than the\nonquerors of the west. In some of tho countries of Europe,\ntho ancient inhabitants were either driven out, or almost entirely extirpated. This was especially tho case in Britain.\nBut where tho ancient inhabitants were suffered to live, they\nu-ere enslaved. The haughty master viewed the literature of\nthe slave as the. badge of that effeminacy which had resulted\nin slavery. The wonder is, thai, under these circumstances,\nliterature should have lived at all. It is at tin's period, and\nunder these circumstances, that the monks are upbraided with\nhiding the jcarning of the age from the community. Now\nthis is arrant injustice. They preserved lite inline from tclal\nextinction, And so fat as I am able to-lenrn, tluy wcret-ver\nready to communicate their knowledge to those who were\nwilling to learn ; lot learning was. then a mere monkish accomplishment, and the lords of the land would net stoop to\nacquire it. Now I am no apologist for monastic life; but I\nprotest against abusing tho monks for ihe only good thing\nthey ever did, the preservation of literature.\nThe truth, then, is this: Christianity took the savage hordes\nof the north, and converted them into the present enlightened\nand refined inhabitants of Europe and America. Nor shall\nmodern infidelity share the glory with her. It comes in, indeed, to attempt to share the spoil, when the victory is achieved. It bustles and fumes about founding a few colleges and\nuniversities, as if it had laid the foundations of literature and\nscience; whereas it has only cpmo up in time to mar ihe lop-\nstone. Infidel Fiance is appealed to us the modem light of\nthe world; But her self-styled illuminism set so soon in blood,\nihat the appeal is unfortunate. 1 should not fear to say, that\nnine out of ten of all the literary foundations in the woild,\nhave been created by Christians. Let, then,,','her own works\npraise her in the gates.\"\nWith these remarks, I beg leave to close this essay with the\nsentiments of a highly esteemed member of this Lyceum:\u2014\n\"Liberal government is the centrifugal force, which semis\ncolonies of civilized and enlightened men to people the world;\nwhile religion acts as the centripetal force, to prevent such\nIcolonies from becoming roving savages.\"","fullrs":{},"find":"463.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"462","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1809845","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
