<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/434</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>434</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/434/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":",m\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n67\nistical, and the schools which he instituted were chiefly adapted to teach the military art, gunnery, fortification and tactics.\nHe wanted the refiiiementund humanity which classical studies\nalone impart. \u25a0  The calculating system of politics, considers\nmen commercially and  numerically, not as beings possessed\nof fine sensibilities, ever \" trembling at the touch of joy, or\nwoe,\" but a*s living engines capable of productive labor.    A\npolitical economy founded solely on  calculation, can never\nadvance the happiness of rational  beings, formed to feel as\nwell as to feed, to think as well  as to vegetate, to enjoy as\nwell as to  labor.    A calculating policy, derived probably\nfrom his mathematical education,  rendered  Napoleon careless of the waste of human life', and regardless of the claims\nof humanity.    He sacrificed liberty and religion, as well as\nthe Belles Lcttres, on the altar of a bloody ambition.    Under\nhis auspices, the mathematics were rendered subservient to\nthose gigantic projects of personal aggrandizement, which\naimed at nothing less than the dominion of the world.    In his\nreign, the war-spirit, which it has been said ihe peculiar tendency of the classics is to foster, was manifested by men, who\nhad not the least tincture of classical learning, but were profound mathematicians, engineers,  and tacticians.    Then all\nEurope became  one vast camp.    Every where wero heard\ndie din of arms, and the sound of preparation for deadly con-\nflict.    Oceans of precious blood were poured forth, rivers of\nbriny tears flowed, the groans of the widowed  mother, the\nivild wail of the fatherless children, ascended to Heaven, and\nreached the ear of the God of battles.    The man \" of destiny,\" whose edicts hud appeared like the deeices of omnipotence, rendered  giddy by ihe height to  which  be had been\nson. A dry, jejune, inelegant style, can never become popular. The profoundest books of science, composed in a dull,\nheavy, clumsy maimer, speedily sink into neglect. Soon they\nascend to the upper shelves ol the library, where they arc allowed to remain unmolested, save by the worm and spider.\nMathematics seem lo have a peculiar tendency to clip the\nwings of fancy, and to obtund tho finer sensibilities of the\nheart. Let arithmetic, and the oilier exact sciences, constitute\nthe whole of education, men would have nothing else to do\nbut to measure and calculate. Rhetoric would be proscribed,\nand poetry banished. Every thing would then be reduced\nlo \" mathematic rule,\" and more in obedience to \"mathematic\nlaw.\" Man himself, stript of fancy and feeling, might be\nmade a mere machine, as unimaginative and insensible as an\nautomaton, which moves only by mechanic springs.\nAll nature, it has been remarked, is constructed on mathematical principles. Is this true? On the contrary, are not\nthe grandest, as well as the most beautiful natural objects remarkable for irregularity and variety ? The rugged mountain, the verdant valley, the stream that winds through the enamelled mead, the flower that decks its bunks, the tree that\nlifts its majestic form, laden with fruitage and foliage to the\nbreeze, tho bird that sports through its branches, and fairer\nthan all, \"the human face divine,\" derive not their attractions\nfrom mathematical figures. Whichof the mathematic curves\nis the curve of beauty! How tiresome a uniformity would\npervade the works of nature, were all things reduced to\nubes and cones, to pyramids, spheres and parallellopipeds?\nI is not true, then, of the animal, and vegetable, and only to\na limited extent of the mineral kingdom.\nelevated in the pursuit of false glory, was precipitated from!    We here begJleave to introduce a quotation from Locke,\nlofty eminence. The last act of the great tragedy of\ntwenty years, closed with the fatal scene of Waterloo, which\nmade the haughty monarch a prisoner and an exile from the\nland of his adoption and his glory. Chained to the barren\nrock el St. Helena, like another Prometheus, disappointment,\nchagrin, and remorse preying on his vitals, ho soon fe'll a victim lo the restless activity of his own nature, now turned\nagainst itself He will forever remain a monument of blasted ambition, a beacon in the deep to warn the adventurer who\nrides the waves of a \"sea of glory,\" ofthe hidden rucks\nwhich lurk beneath its deceitful surface. Since the downfal\nel Napoleon, the classics, which by him were proscribed and\nbanished, as uncongenial, doubtless, with the spirit of military\ndespotism, have been restored to their just rank in the system\nol French education. This virtual recantation of their former sentiments in regard to tho classics, does equal honor to\nthe head and hearl, to the good sense, as well as good feel in J\nof that ingenious and highly polished nation.\nNot only do the classics constitute the broad and stable fouii\nelation, the only sure basis on which to erect the beautiful and\nmajestic temple of science J but even science itself, with all\nits celestial nature, its exact symmetry, its graceful proportions, and its lofty sublimity, requires the embellishments of\nrhetoric, the decorations of style, the classical elegance of\ncomposition, to recommend it to the mass of mankind, who,\nin the general, are more sensitive than rational, more under\nfir\npartly wilh a view 10 exhibit his sentiments on the subject of\nclassical education, but more particularly to show the style of\none who condemns the classics, and rejects all tho ornaments\nof rhetorical embellishment, upon which from the proud\nheights of philosophy, he doubtlesss looked down with a degree of contempt. \" The character of a sober man is what\neveryone expects in a tutor. This is generally thought\nenough. But when this sober man has emptied out into his\npupil all the Latin and logic he brought from the university,\nwill that furniture make him a gentleman ? The tutor should\nknow the world, the humors, the cheats, the faults of the age\nhe has fallen into, and particularly the country he lives in.\nThen shall be be able to show them his pupil, and teach him\nskill in men and manners, and pull oil' the masque which\ntheir several callings and pretences cover them with. Learning, 1 put last, though that is almost the only thing thought\non, when people talk of education. \"When 1 ronsitlcr what\nado is made about learning a little Latin and Greek, how many years are spent in it, and what a noise and business it makes\nIn 7io purpose, I can hardly forbear thinking, that the parents\nof the children still live in fear of ihe schoolmaster's rod,\nwhich they look upon as tho only instrument of education, as\na language or two is to be the whole business. How else is\nit possible that a child should be chained to the oar, seven,\neight, or ten of the best years of his life, to get a language or\ntwo?\"    The objections of Locke to an exclusive study of\ne influence of llieir feelings and imagination, than of rea-|Lutin and Greek, however applicable to the English schools\nW',\nI\nf'    'I'\n1\n\u2022ti\n'::\n:\u25a0;\nA\n\u25a0","fullrs":{},"find":"435.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"434","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1764029","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
