<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/542</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>542</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/542/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL.\n170\nal skill, by tho only secret of power\u2014a knowl-\na|| with equ\nflj\u201ec uf man and his natural weakness.\nThere is nothing in the study or tho practice of the law\nwhich must necessarily destroy simplicity or benevolence of\ncharacter. The opposite idea has arisen from the malice of\ndisappointed clients, who, to protect themselves from the ef-\nItctj of their own improper attempts, have endeavored to\natmse the world with the idea that what they have been de-\nlected in or thwarted in, is attributable solely to the wickedness of their own or their opponent's lawyer. The lawyer,\noccasionally, proceeds in an indirect manner. The fictions\nof the law may require it, and the proceedings, as far as he\nis concerned, are compulsory. Let no man suppose that\nProvidence will interfere in a suit-at-law, on the ground of\nhis views of justice, separate from religious considerations.\nProvidence never interrupts the chain of causes, und their\nanalogies, to produce any specific effect or object. This is\nthe true reason, however harsh it may appear, which reconciles i.'ie supposed anomaly that the intrinsic justice of his\nsuit may bo the lawyer's least dependence for success.\nIt is a recklessness and want of charity that would asperse\nthe character ofthe lawyer.    Trace him through long years\nof study, and mental application to a pursuit, in which the\nfascination of ambition, or a zeal for knowledge alone, can\ndiscover a flower\u2014searching, like the entombed miner, in a\nrayless world,  for  gems of learning in a \"black-lettered\"\nfolio, which a poet of our own day so well describes, as\n\" That weight of wood, with leathern coat o'erlaid,\nThose ample clasps of solid metal made,\nThe close-pressed leaves unclos'd for many an a;\nThe dull reel edging of the well filled page,\nOn the broad back the stubborn ridges roll'd\nWhere yet the title stands in tarnished gold ! \"\nBehold his youth and strength poured out like water, on his\ntoil, over which fancy never casts a smile\u2014the best feelings\ncf his manhood jarred by contact with criminals and their\ndreadful disclosures, until he sickens al the dark and joyless\npicture life constantly holds up to him; and well, perhaps,\nmay he sigh with the sad poet:\n\" Now spring returns, but not lo me returns,\nThe vernal joys my better clays have known;\nDim in my breast life's dying taper burns,\nAnd all the joys of life, with health, are flown ! \"\nnut there are moments of his career that would illumine the\ngloom of the grave, and print joy on  the lips of despair\u2014\nmoments, when he  finds himself the successful advocate of\nvirtue and the  triumphant  vindicator  of innocence.    The\nworld presents no nobler spectacle than that of a brilliant in-\nlellect striving in a righteous cause I\nWith this brief and imperfect defence of the lawyer's good\nfame, I commence the main design of the lecture, which is\nto endeavor to show, in unfolding the philosophy ofthe law,\nnow intimately it is connected with human afiairs\u2014with government, religion, morals, business and social life.\nGovernment, logically viewed, is but the mechanism of\nthe law, the development and application of legal principles.\n\" Laws,\" says a learned writer, \" are the very soul of a peo-\nPle; \"ot merely those which are contained in the letter of\n'heir ordinances and statute books, but still more those which\nhave\ngrown up of themselves fr\nom their manners, and reli\ngion and history.\"    It may be definitively proved that legislation is independent of arbitrary caprice, and history is evidence, that if a law is forced against  the general manners\nand common religious views of a people, it must finally vanish or become modified by those irresistible impulses. Hence,\nthe best legislation is made by a representation, not merely\nof the most learned and the most talented, but of those who\nbest know tho wants of the people and the defects of existing\nlaws.    The wild doctrine of unrestrained, natural right, acted upon by the French, during their memorable revolution,\nwas abandoned as chimerical, when reflection had introduced\nreason.    As sympathy of manners and feelings, the influence of similar laws, and, sometimes, particular prejudices,\nform a people peculiar, it is absurd to argue that a form of\ngovernment can be suddenly changed, because such change\nrequires an hasty and complete rupture of fumiliar and long\ncherished ways of thinking nnd  feeling.    Every precipitate\ntitration which has occurred in the government of any\ncountry, has been of short existence.    Oliver Cromwell formed England inlo a republic, but, when the master-spirit of his\nday was taken  from the scene of his singular triumph, the\npeople', as if by common consent, joyfully returned to their\nancient allegiance.    The Republic of France, in the emphatic language of the scriptures, \" was of few days, and full\nof troubles;\"\u2014it had no foundation in the hearts ofthe people\u2014it was a sacrifice to an idol, falsely called the Goddess\nof Liberty I    Yet many believe that the governments of Europe, and especially of Great Britain, are tending to the lc-\npublican form, and some alarmists would have us believe ihat\nour own is verging on a monarchy, if not a despotism.    The\nerror lies in false reasoning and unfair comparison.    The\nmonarchy of to-day is not the monarchy of former times, nor\nis a modern republic to be tested by those of antiquity.    Time\nhas wrought unavoidable changes in the usages and institutions ofthe world; education and the diffusion of knowledge\nave rendered men less dependent and more capable of their\nown government, and with the necessity has passed away the\nactual authority of the one over the many.    The iron of tyranny is found only in the soil of ignorance.    Mind is tho\nonly  real sovereign.    It   is  impossible to dethrone intelligence\u2014it once reigned in the persons of a few; it is now the\ninheritance of all.    Whatever forms old and fond associations may retain\u2014look not to them alone for the spirit of government, for where knowledge is, there is the power.\nGovernment and law are, therefore, the twin-offspring of\nthe character and policy of a people. Their joint association in the government of our own country, establishes this\ntruth. Political knowledge is a republican virtue, and the\nprivilege of freely commenting both on our institutions and\ntheir chosen guardians, forms the most jealously watched\nfeature of our liberty. But tho right to reprove or to find\nfault, without the ability to weigh tho reasons of either,\nwould be useless, as the knowledge of an evil, without the\npower of applying its remedy, is a disheartening destiny;\nthus are found in a republic two powerful auxiliaries of civilization and the advance of intelligence, which exist in far\nless degree in other forms of Government.    It is the repub-\n. s-djrj\n; m\nm\n-\u25a0 :V J-]\ntC?\"Vi\nI   '    if \u25a0    - \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0","fullrs":{},"find":"543.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"542","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1738732","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
