<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 8</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/369</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>369</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/369/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 8","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T H - WES T EIIN JOURNAL.\nwhich we term galvanism, and in fact gravitation; by which\nterrestrial bodies are governed, and by which our planet holds\nits course in the great revolutions of the solar system\u2014a\nlink in the great chain by which the whole universe is bound\ntogether? If ihe puny pile of concentric plates, which one\nman can erect and move at pleasure, can produce an invisible power sufficient lo lift many thousands of pounds, or equal\nti, a steam engine, how amply provided is the earth's great\nlaboratory for performing all the operations and movements\nrequiring this agency ?\nAll human philosophy is subject to continual change: tho\nlast theories und discoveries are generally considered true, or\nmore correct titan tho former, which ore abandoned as exploded errors: notwithstanding men are not now probably as far\nfrom absolute truth, as they were six thousand years ago. To\nthe most perfi-ct approaches to absolute truth there will always be some obstacle, or some apparent error to confute, ow.\ning to the limited nature of our senses ; and theories may appear to us perfect, which new light will show to he absurd:\nundone theory ait ir another will In-exploded, as long us man\nshall he a reasoning being. As has been the case fur six thousand years, so it will contil : and we may say \"in 24,000\nyears, there will arise philosophers, who will boast, that they\nlire destroying tin- errors which have been reigning in tho\nworld, for 30,000 years pas': and there will be people, who\nwill If lievc, that they are then only just begining to open\ntheir eyes.\"\n\"METEORIC SHOWERS.\"\nnv i,iiiii't&gt;-siii; c. (i. ronsiiRV, or jra'FEitsoN cui.i.r.ni:\n'fin- American Journal of Science of Jan. 1837, contains\ntin- following article upon this subject, from the pen of Pro-\nI'.-: sor \u2022 llmsted of Vale ('ollege. The very recent recurrence\nof the anniversary of this splendid phenomenon, with several\n,-:tt&lt; ndanl circumsi\ntheory; and as tin\nleresting, I propoi\n\" For six years\nor about tho I3lh\nexhibition of sh &lt;\nthe \"Meteoric SI\n\"In 1831, tho\nOhio,* an 1 in the\nsei m t\" (li niand a notice of Mr. O's\n\u25a0 alluded to contains much that is in\ninsertion ofit nearly entire\n-,\u25a0\u25a0 ssinn, there has Icon observed, on\nivember, of each year, a remnrkabh\ntars, which has received the name of\nphen imenon was observed in the State of\nMediterranean, off the coast of Spain.f\u2014\nIn 1832, the shower appeared ill a more imposing form, and\nwas seen at Mocha, in Arabia :% in the middle of the Atlantic Ocean:6 near Orenburg, in Russia:|| and at Pornambuco,\nin South America.\"! Tho magnificent Meteoric Shower of\n1833, is too well known to require the recital of any particulars. (Jf the recurrence of the phenomenon at the corresponding period in 1834, and in 1835, evidence has been\npresented to the public in previous numbers of this Journal.\n\" I now feel authorized to assert, that the Meteoric Shower\nit-appeared on the morning of the 13,\/j November, 1S30.\n\" It has been supposed by some, that tho appearance of an\nextraordinary number of shooting stars, at tho several anniversaries since the great phenomenon of November, 1833,\ni\n' Amer. Jour, i,r Bclcneo, xxviU,419.\n.' Airier. Jour. .\\-.\\vt, 130.\n\u00bb Ed. New Phil, Jour, July, 1S3G.\nI BIbllothoquo Unlverselle, Bent. 1835\ni II,. 340.\nn N. Y. American, Nov, IP, 1?,\"C.\ncan be accounted for by the fact, that so general an expectation of such an event has been excited, and that so many persons have been on the watch for it. Having, however, been\nmuch in the habit of observing phenomena of this kind,]\ncan truly say, that those exhibitions of shooting stars which\nhave for several years occurred on the 13th or 14th of November, are characterized by several peculiarities which\nclearly distinguish them from ordinary shooting stars. Such\npeculiarities are the following.\nI. The number of meteors, though exceedingly variable,\nis much greater than usual, especially of the larger and\nbrighter kinds.\nU. An uncommonly large proportion leave luminous\ntrains.\n:!. Tho meteors, with few exceptions, all appear to proceed from a common centre, the position of which lias been\nuniformly in nearly the same point in the heavens, viz. in\nsome part of the constellation Leo.\n-1. 'l'he principal exhibition lias at all times, nnd at all places, occurred between midnight and sunrise, and the maximum from three, to [our o'clock.\n\" In all these particulars, the Meteoric Showers of 1834, 5.\nand li, have resembled that of 1833; while no person, so far\nas I have heard, has observed the same combination of circumstances on any other occasion within the same period.\u2014\nI have not supposed il necessary, in order to establish Ihe\nidentity of these later meteoric showers with that of 1833,\nthat tiny should he of the same magnitude with that. A\nsmall eclipse I have considered a phenomenon of the same\nkind with a large one; and conformably to this analogy, I\nhave regarded an eclipse of the sun, first exhibiting itself as\na slight indentation of the solar limb, but increasing in magnitude at every recurrence, until it becomes total, and afterwards, at each return, but partially covering the solar disk.\nuntil the moon passes quite clear of the sun,\u2014as affording\nno bad illustration of what probably takes place in regard to\nthese meteoric showers. The fiict that the Aurora Borealis\nappears unusually frequent and magnificent for a few successive years, and then for a long time is scarcely seen at all, was\nproved by Mairan, a hundred years ago.** There is much\nreason to suspect a like periodical character in tie- phenomenon in question, which first arrested attention in 1831, became\nmine remarkable in 1832, arrived at its maximum in 1833,\nand has since grown less and less at each annual'return.\u2014\nSome seem to suppose that we are now wan-anted in expecting\na similar exhibition of meteors on the morning of every future\nanniversary; hut this, I think, is not to he expected. It is\nperhaps more probable, that its recurrence, unless in a very\ndiminished degree, will scarcely be witnessed again by the\npresent generation. The shower, however, at its late return,\nwas more striking than I had anticipated; and it must be acknowledged to be adventurous, to enter the region of prediction respecting the future exhibitions of a phenomenon, both\nwhoso origin and whose laws we so imperfectly understand.\"\n(Here follow copies of letters from observers of different\nand distant places in the United States, abundantly proving .\n\"Tralte 1'hys. n iriat. lie L'Aurore Iloreolo.\nthe Royal Academy ol Sciencca fur 1731,\nPar M. de Mairan.\u2014Memoirs ui","fullrs":{},"find":"370.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"369","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1848948","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
