<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/454</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>454</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/454/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\n0\nHi\n\u25a0;tt:4\n\u25a0 \u00ab'.]*'\u25a0\n:.'!n:ii'\nI      .\"    ri\n'      tf '**\n'Ill\n84\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nand situated on a steep declivity, with spacious and airy streets,\nand not crowded with houses. The number of cases that\noccurred at this place was eleven, of whom nine died. Every\ncase was clearly traced to communication with a vessel which\nhad recently ai rived from Havana, on board which one of\nthe sailors had died with yellow fever on the voyage. Th.\nwhole number of cases occurred and terminated in the course\nof a fortnight; for tt'i alarm excited by the appearance of|\na malignant disease among them, caused a complete and\nspeedy desertion of the village, and non-intercourse with the\nship. This village has always maintained the character of!\nuncommon salubrity. Up to the arrival of the infected ship,\nno disease of any kind prevailed; and immediately the ship\nwas abandoned by the inhabitants, the disease ceased. The\ninfection on board this ship was not generated by putrefaction\nof either animal or vegetable matters, as none existed on\nboard; and Dr. Tully declares that she was perfectly clean;\nno such matters were found in the town, or suspected by any\nas the cause of the disease: the ship was the undoubted\nsource, and none were attacked but such as had been on\nboard. In this case had the weather been such as generally\nprecedes epidemic yellow fever: and had the inhabitants not\nfled, but remained, and continued their intercourse with the\ninfected ship, the town would doubtless have been visited with\nepidemic yellow fever.\nDr. Tully informs us, that as many other cases occurred a\nthe different places at which this vessel anchored in ascend\ning the river, and always in those only who had been or\nboard. He also informs us, that, for the last twenty-five\nyears, scarcely a year has passed, in which one or more similar cases have not appeared at different points on the Connecticut river; all of which are clearly attributable solely to intercourse with vessels from the West Indies, or from southern\nports of the United States.\nDr. Bayley,* health officer of the port of New York,\ngives an account of a number of cases of yellow fever which\noccurred, in the autumn of 1821, at the \"quarantine establishment,\" or. Staten Island, six miles below the city. From\nthe 8th of September until the 7th of October, twenty-nine\ncases and twenty-one deaths occurred; of ihe latter, fourteen\nhad black vomit. These cases were clearly traced to intercourse with infected vessels then lying at the wharf, nnd recently from the West Indies and New Orleans. Tho health\nof those about the \" quarantine establishment\" never was\nbetter, both immediately before and after these cases: nothing-\nlike bilious or remittent fever had been seen : neither marshes, nor filth, nor vegetable putrefaction existed any where in\nthe vicinity. The cases were traced clearly to the ships, and\nto them alone : and each case occurred just five days, and\none on the sixth day, after the particular exposure to the infected air of the vessels. A washerwoman and her two\ndaughters, took the disease, without having been on board the\nvessels. They contracted their disease by handling nnd washing the foul clothes and bedding of four men who had died\nof yellow fever about four days previously. The bedding\nand clothes had been thrown aside until taken to her to be\n' New York Med. and Phys, Jour. vol. 1, p. 27,28,dec,\nwashed. She took the disease just five days after she had\nhandled the clothes, and died on the fifth day of her disease;\nher daughters were attacked afterwards. In this case, a favorable condition of the air would, no doubt, have caused it\nto become epidemic.\nDr. Bayley * also gives us the case of the United States'\nbrig Enterprise, infected with yellow fever, at the \"quaran-\ntine ground,\" in 1822. This vessel was perfectly clean, and\nfree from any animal or vegetable putrefaction. She arrived\nfrom Havana with ten cases on board; and immediately the\nsick were removed to the hospital, and the well were quartered on shore, to avoid the infected air of the vessel. She\nwas then thoroughly cleansed, ventilated, washed, and whitewashed with lime, in a tenfold degree; lime was slaked in her\ntimbers in large quantities. Yet, after this purification, she\nretained tho infection, and communicated the yellow fever lo\nthose wlio afterwards went on board; of whom five, out of\neleven, died. The process of purification was again instituted. Artificial ventilation with windsails was constantly\nperformed; water, to the depth of several feet, was daily let\nin, and pumped out: lime was strewed in the hold, and her\ntimbers thoroughly whitewashed, and still the infection was\nnot destroyed, until cold weather. In this case, her own crew\nhaving taken the disease first, the people from shore avoided\nthe vessel, and escaped the disease.\nAnother case is given by Dr. Kollock, and quoted by Dr.\nRush, in which a vessel at sea, in tropical latitudes, engendered on board a malaria which finally produced yellow fever.\nThis is the case of the United States' frigate General Greene,\nwhich became infected while on a cruise in the West India\nsens, and did not become disinfected until she reached the\ncold climate of Rhode Island During the time, she retain\ned the infection, every kind of cleansing, fumigation, and ventilation, were used freely, but ineffectually. In this case, the\nvessel was new, and perfectly clean and healthy, when she\nleft Newport, Rhode Island, on the 3d of June, 1790. She\nhad on board a complement of two hundred and fourteen\nsouls, besides large quantities of provisions for a cruise in the\nWest India seas. Having encountered a storm, soon after\nshe put to sen, the vessel became leaky, and a noxious malaria was generated, during a subsequent period of unusually\nhot weather. At first, and for some days, the disease assumul\nthe symptoms of a violent bilious fever, with no deaths until\nthey arrived in the port of Havana: when immediately sevr-\nral cases began to assume symptoms of yellow fever. \" After\nthis period,\" says Dr. Kollock, \"three, four, and five new-\ncases occurred daily; and the violence of the symptom\nseemed to increase, with the multiplication of cases, during\nle six days she lay in port.\" f Cases and deaths continued\nto multiply daily, until she passed the capes of Virginia, when\nthe disease became gradually milder. The whole number of\nthe cases was forty; and twenty of them died. In this case,\nan infectious air was generated in the ship's hold, by the number on board, during the hot weather and leaky condition of\nthe vessel; and it appears that the\" leaven\" of infection ivu\nsuperadded at the port of Havana, either by persons going on\n\u2022 New York Mod. and Phys. Jour., vol. 1, p. 420-7, &amp;c,\n\\ Med,Rep. vol. 4, p. 3.","fullrs":{},"find":"455.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"454","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1888819","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.80 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
