<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Folder 1a-10, Hermann Moyse, Sr. Letters, 1918 June 29-Aug. 19</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name displayLabel="Author">
      <namePart>Moyse, Hermann, 1891-1985</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">aut</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Author</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name displayLabel="Author">
      <namePart>Sommer, Lydie, 1903-1981</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">aut</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Author</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name displayLabel="Author">
      <namePart>Sommer, Ray, 1906-1995</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">aut</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Author</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name displayLabel="Author">
      <namePart>Kelton, Robert Hall Campbell, 1872-1922</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">aut</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Author</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated keyDate="yes">1918</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>World War, 1914-1918</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh" displayLabel="Location">
      <geographic>France</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh" displayLabel="Location">
      <geographic>Baton Rouge (La.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh" displayLabel="Location">
      <geographic>Blois (France)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <abstract displayLabel="Description">This folder contains ten items from June 29 through August 19, 1918, nine of which are letters and one of which is a general order from the Third Division Headquarters of the American Expeditionary Forces. The general order is dated August 4, 1918, signed 'By command of Major General Dickman: Robert H. C. Kelton, Colonel, General Staff, Chief of Staff,' and commends the troops of the VIth and Xth Divisions on their "remarkable valor."  Seven of the letters are from Hermann Moyse to Rosalie Gottlieb, one of the letters is from Moyse to his parents Simon and Flora Moyse, and the ninth letter is a note from Moyse's nieces Lydie and Ray Sommer, dated August 3, stating that they read in the paper that the 32nd Division, "(Uncle Hermann's division)," is "fighting in the big offensive or that is what we thought.  Grandpa says that it means that hes in active service but is holding a quiet sector at Vosges [.] We see now that Grandpa was wrong."  Moyse writes to Gottlieb on July 7 about having completed his first stint in the trenches, and describes the Fourth of July celebration he attended and how the festivities made the day the most enjoyable one he has experienced thus far in France.  The most "stirring" event of the day occurred when "about fifty little girls, all [] in their native costumes, sang one stanza and the chorus of the 'Star Spangled Banner,' in English, their accent adding considerably to the significance of their expression of the hope that the good old flag may long fly over the 'land of the free and the home of the brave.' [] I tell you; it made a fellow feel good!"  Moyse was shot three times in battle on July 31, 1918, and sent to a hospital in Blois, France, to recuperate.  In a letter to his parents dated August 16, he assures them he is making a speedy recovery.  Describing his injuries, he recognizes "that there are so many others who have so much more serious wounds and pains that it would be wrong for me to complain; please look at it in the same way.  Oh folks, if you could see what the Huns in their rule of terrorism have done to this country you would willingly sacrifice not merely worldly goods but life itself in order that our own America may be forever spared such a visitation, for Germany victorious would have meant an America ruined.  Don't let our own little griefs and pains make us blind to the truth."</abstract>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <physicalDescription>
      <extent>10 letters.</extent>
      <internetMediaType>jp2</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
   <genre>correspondence</genre>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code">en</languageTerm>
  </language>
   <note type="ownership" displayLabel="Source">Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections ( http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special )</note>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo type="alternative" displayLabel="Repository Collection">
         <title>Moyse-Gottlieb-Sommer Family Papers, Mss. 4671, Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections, LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La.</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>Hermann Moyse, Sr. World War I Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Repository Collection Guide">http://www.lib.lsu.edu/sites/default/files/sc/findaid/4671.pdf</url>
      </location>
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://lsu.louisianadigitallibrary.org/lsu-p15140coll18%3Acollection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location">Louisiana State University: LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url displayLabel="Institution Web Site">http://lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library: Special Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>Mss. 4671, Box 1a: 10</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll18/id/663</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordChangeDate>2017-02-06</recordChangeDate>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-11-24</recordCreationDate>
  </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll18</alias>
         <pointer>663</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll18/663/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-06 12:53:17">{"title":"Folder 1a-10, Hermann Moyse, Sr. Letters, 1918 June 29-Aug. 19","creato":"Moyse, Hermann, 1891-1985; Sommer, Lydie, 1903-1981; Sommer, Ray, 1906-1995; Kelton, Robert Hall Campbell, 1872-1922","date":"1918","physic":"10 letters.","langua":"en","type":"correspondence","covera":"France; Baton Rouge (La.); Blois (France)","subjec":"World War, 1914-1918","descri":"This folder contains ten items from June 29 through August 19, 1918, nine of which are letters and one of which is a general order from the Third Division Headquarters of the American Expeditionary Forces. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The general order is dated August 4, 1918, signed 'By command of Major General Dickman: Robert H. C. Kelton, Colonel, General Staff, Chief of Staff,' and commends the troops of the VIth and Xth Divisions on their \"remarkable valor.\"  Seven of the letters are from Hermann Moyse to Rosalie Gottlieb, one of the letters is from Moyse to his parents Simon and Flora Moyse, and the ninth letter is a note from Moyse's nieces Lydie and Ray Sommer, dated August 3, stating that they read in the paper that the 32nd Division, \"(Uncle Hermann's division),\" is \"fighting in the big offensive or that is what we thought.  Grandpa says that it means that hes in active service but is holding a quiet sector at Vosges [.] We see now that Grandpa was wrong.\"  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moyse writes to Gottlieb on July 7 about having completed his first stint in the trenches, and describes the Fourth of July celebration he attended and how the festivities made the day the most enjoyable one he has experienced thus far in France.  The most \"stirring\" event of the day occurred when \"about fifty little girls, all [] in their native costumes, sang one stanza and the chorus of the 'Star Spangled Banner,' in English, their accent adding considerably to the significance of their expression of the hope that the good old flag may long fly over the 'land of the free and the home of the brave.' [] I tell you; it made a fellow feel good!\"  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moyse was shot three times in battle on July 31, 1918, and sent to a hospital in Blois, France, to recuperate.  In a letter to his parents dated August 16, he assures them he is making a speedy recovery.  Describing his injuries, he recognizes \"that there are so many others who have so much more serious wounds and pains that it would be wrong for me to complain; please look at it in the same way.  Oh folks, if you could see what the Huns in their rule of terrorism have done to this country you would willingly sacrifice not merely worldly goods but life itself in order that our own America may be forever spared such a visitation, for Germany victorious would have meant an America ruined.  Don't let our own little griefs and pains make us blind to the truth.\"","locati":"Mss. 4671, Box 1a: 10","source":"Moyse-Gottlieb-Sommer Family Papers, Mss. 4671, Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections, LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La.","reposi":"http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/sites\/default\/files\/sc\/findaid\/4671.pdf","contri":{},"notes":{},"publis":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"rights":{},"contac":{},"catalo":{},"imaga":{},"color":{},"extent":{},"imagb":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"object":{},"fullrs":{},"find":"664.cpd","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-11-24","dmmodified":"2010-11-24","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"663","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"6897","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.01 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"0","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
