<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/599</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>599</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/599/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:56">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"m\nf\u00a7\ni'i&gt;.\na- \u25a0*\"\u25a0\n, \u2022 \u25a0 i\ntSbl'i'fi\nte\n\u25a0 i '\n-Tiv '\u25a0\"-\n234\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\nf','\n\u25a0&gt;\u25a0'\u25a0&gt;\u25a0\nII\ni \u25a0\nH*L'|\nw\nSi!*\nft '\nI\n1\nI:;\n'-' '   \u2022\nI\nI;\nIff\nill\nn\nshould be held in high estimation by that Being, whose nature is Benevolence, whose name is Love.\nThe foregoing principles are applicable, in their full extent, only to the divine laws ; fur they alone are unerring,\nNevertheless they have a modified and very important relation to such laws as are measurably of human origin, and\nof a conventional character. Laws of this sort are all designed to promote the happiness of those for whom they arc\nenacted. To accomplish this object, however, they must be\nin accordance with the nature of man, and with his various\nrelations at the time and place for which they are designed.\nSocial laws, when thus constructed, are obviously neither\nmore nor less than an acknowledgment of tho natural laws,\nand a conventional stipulation to abide by them, under pain\nof a given penalty. In all such cases it is no less manifest,\nthat misery must necessarily result from transgression, than\nthat a heavy body, unsupported, must, by the law of gravitation, fall to the ground.\n\" They despise government,\" is as certain an indication of\ncharacters destined to utter ruin, as any that can be furnished\nin tho whole range of human thought, or human language.\nSince, then, tho lawless are self-doomed to destruction, in all\ntheir relations and interests, human happiness is obviously\nidentified with the cultivation of a law-abiding spirit, and\nwith the extinction of an arbitrary and self-willed temper-\nHence, sound philosophy teaches tbe importance of a cheerful submission to t'.ose laws, under which for the time beiiu\nwo may be placed.\nThis remark is intended to apply, not merely to laws of\nacknowledged utility, but even to such as may be unwise and\ninexpedient. A given law may, it is true, operate injuriously\nupon our interests; yet the injury may be of a subordinate\nand local character, and bear no comparison to lhc much\ngreater amount of injury which a violation of the law in\nquestion wculd necessarily inflict on us and others, by the\ncultivation of a lawless and arbitrary spirit.\nHence, government of some kind necessarily results from\nman's organization and circumstances in the world; and\ntherefore, whatever may bo said relative to its peculiar form,\nas to the thing itself, \"there is no power but of God: the\npowers that be are ordained ol God. Whosoever, therefore,\nrcsisteth the power, resisteth the ordinance of God; and they\nthat resist, shall receive to themselves condemnation.\"\nLet none, however, misapprehend my meaning. When\nen earthly despot, in any relation of life, dares to enjoin\nwhat God forbids, or to forbid what God enjoins, resistance\nbecomes a duty, and obedience a crime.\nBy resistance, in such a case, the rule is exemplified, not\nviolated. \" Let every soul be subject to the higher powers,\"\nis the rule. This is manifestly infringed when wo disobey\nGod, who is the highest power\u2014and himself the fountain of\nall dominion\u2014that we may obey an earthly ruler, who is at\nbest but subordinate, and, in this instance, a despot and a\nusurper.     Disobedience, in such a case, proceeds from, and\ntends to cherish, not a lawless, but a law-abiding spirit a\ndetermination to be subject to the highest powers, at every\nrisk, that may be incurred, through the displeasure of those\nwhose authority is subordinate.\nLaw, then, must be supreme. And the very existence of\nthe world in which we live, is not more undeniable:, than that\nit is utterly impossible, for any society that will not sustain\nthe supremacy of law, to attain to the perfection of human\nlappiness.\nWhen these principles are generally understood and appro,\ndated as they should be, the good order of sociely will nu\nlonger be interrupted by the shameless brawls of drunken\nlawless rowdyism. No longer will brute violence usurp the\nempire of law and reason. Neither will unbridled insolence\nny more, with his hideous, brazen front, intrude upon the\nsanctity anil disturb the peace of the domestic circle. Under\nthe supremacy of omnipotent law, tranquillity and good order will extend their heavenly influence to all the interests,\nand through all the ramifications of society. Violence will\nno more be heard in our land, wasting nor destruction within\nour borders; but, in their stead, tho spontaneous chorus of\nuniversal nature will be\u2014\" Glory to God in the highest heavens, on earth peace, good will to men.\"\nWho, that has a heart warmed by one spark ol generous\nand lofty feeling, is not ready to exclaim\u2014Oh I consummation, devoutly to be wished! Thrice happy he, who shall\nlive to see thoo accomplished I\nEre this state of things, however, can be introduced, it is\nmanifest to the reflecting inind, that a radical change must\ntake place in tho habits of the community, and especially\nwith reference to tho education of youth.\nSolomon once said, that folly was bound up in the heart of\na child, and that the rod and reproof brought wisdom. In\nthis ago of universal improvement, we have discovered that\nSolomon was a fool; that wisdom is bound up in the heart ol'\na child, and thai, in the education of tbe young, the rod and\nreproof do no good, but nnniiiigled mischief. We have discovered, that every little urchin, so soon as he can crawl\u2014so\nsoon as ho can curse and swcai, drink ardent spirits, smoke\nsegars, and chew tobacco\u2014is wiser tl: .;i all his teachers;\nand, consequently, that to him correction and the restraints\nof a wholesome discipline are unnecessary, and a great evil.\nHence, even in the nursery, the little darling must have his\nown way, to the great annoyance of the family, and of all\ntho friends by whom they may be visited. When he is old\nenough to be sent to school, there also, if practicable, lie\nmust be allowed to have his own way. The grand object is\nto limit his teacher as far as possible, and, in every difficulty\nthat occurs, to take the part of the dear oppressed boy, and rail\nout against the teacher as guilty of cruelly, tyranny, and oppression. In such circumstances, his connexion with the institution is worse than unprofitable, both to himself and to all\nconcerned. By and by, he leaves school, about as ignorant\nas when he entered it, but ten times more depraved and incorrigible ; and then he struts forth on the stage of manhood,\nthere to play out a consistent part. Accustomed from his infancy to despise government\u2014to regard no restraint, no rule\nof conduct but his own lawless and arbitrary will\u2014it is not\nto be expected, that he will become a good and sober citizen,\na supporter of tho laws and institutions of his country. As\nreasonably might we expect to see the raven transformed into\na dove, the lion into a lamb.    In consequence of the manner","fullrs":{},"find":"600.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"599","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1874835","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
