<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/464</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>464</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/464/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 14","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"ml\n11-.-\nA'.'.'\n\u25a0k\n92\nSOU T II - W E S T E R N J 0 U It N A L.\n; M\nm\nI\n\u2022 i. '*,\nii ;.v\nI\nIn1:*\n. V i1'\n\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\nthe office that evening. I observed to him, that I was afraid\nhe had got wet. He said, No, his great coat had kept him\ndry. But his neck appeared to be wet, and the snow was\nhanging upon his hair. He came to dinner (which had been\nwaiting lor him) without changing his dress. In the evening, he appeared as well as usual.\nA heavy fall of snow took place on Friday, which prevented the General from riding out as usual. He hud taken\ncold, undoubtedly from being so much exposed the day before,\nnnd complained of a sore throat. He, however, went out in\nthe afternoon, into the ground between the house and the\nriver, to mark some trees, which were to be cut down in the\nimprovement of that spot. He had a hoarseness, which increased in the evening; but he made light of it.\nIn the evening, the papers were brought from the post office, nnd he sat in tho pallor with Mrs. Washington and myself, rending them, till about nine o'clock, when Mrs. Wash-\nington went up into Mrs. Lewis's room, who was confined,\nand left the General and myself rending the papers. He\nwas very cheerful, and when he met with any thing interesting or entertaining, he read it aloud as well as his hoarseness\nwould permit. He requested me to read lo him the Debates\nof the Virginia Assembly, on tho election of a Senator and\nGovernor; nnd, on hearing Mr. Madison's observations respecting Mr, Monroe, he appeared much affected, and spoke\nwith some degree of asperity on the subject, which I endeavored to moderate, as 1 always did on such occasions. On\nhis retiring, I observed to him, that ho had better take something to remove his culd. Ho answered, \"No; you know I\nnever take tiny thing for a cold.    Let it go as it came.\"\nBetween two and three o'clock on Saturday morning, he\nawoke Mrs. Washington, and told her that he was very unwell, and had had an ague. She observed that ho could\nscarcely speak, and breathed with difficulty, and would have\ngot up to call a servant. Hut he would not permit her, lest\nshe should take a cold. As soon as the day appeared, the\nwoman (Caroline) went into the room to make a fire, and\nMrs. Washington sent her immediately lo call me. I got\nup, put on my clothes as quickly ns possible, nnd went to his\nchamber. Mrs. Washington was then up, and related to me\nhis being ill, ns before stated. I found the General breathing\nwith difficulty, nnd hardly able lo inter a word intelligibly.\nHe desired Mr. Rawlins, (one of the overseers,) might be\nsent for to bleed him, before the doctor could arrive. 1 despatched a servant instantly for Rawlins, and another for Dr.\nCraik, and returned again to the General's chamber, where I\nfound him in the same situation as 1 had left him.\nA mixture of molasses, vinegar, and butter was prepared,\nto try its effects in the throat; but he could not swallow a\ndrop. Whenever he attempted it, he appeared to be distressed, convulsed, and almost suffocated. Rawlins came in soon\nafter sunrise, and prepared to bleed him. When the arm\nwas ready, the General, observing that Rawlins appeared to\nbe agitated, said, as well as lie could speak, \" Don't bo afraid.\"\nAnd when the incision was made, ho observed, \"The orifice\nis not large enough.\" However, (he blood ran pretty freely.\nMrs. Washington, not knowing whether bleeding was proper\nor not, in the General's situation, begged that much might not\nbe taken from him, lest it should be injurious, and desired tne\nto stop it; but, when I was about to untie the string, the Gen-\nernl put up his hand to prevent it, and, as soon as he could\nspeak, he said, \" More, more.\" Mrs. Washington being still\nvery uneasy, lest too much blood should be taken, it was\nStopped, after taking about half a pint. Finding that no re.\nlief was obtained from bleeding, nnd that nothing would tro\ndown the throat, I proposed bathing it externally with sal\nvolatile, which was done, and, in the operation, which was\nwith the hand, nnd in the gentlest manner, he observed, \"It\nis very sore.\" A piece of flannel, dipped in sal volatile,\nwas put around his neck, and his feet bathed in warm water,\nbut without affording any relief.\nIn the mean lime, before Dr. Craik arrived, Sirs. Wash,\nington desired me to send for Dr. Brown, of Fort Tobacco,\nwhom Dr. Craik had recommended to be called, if any case\nshould ever occur, that was seriously alarming. I despatched a messenger immediately for Dr. Brown, between eight\nand nine o'clock. Dr. Craik came in soon after, and, urea\nexamining the General, he put a blister of enntharides m\nthe throat, took some more blood from him, and had a gargle\nof vinegar and sage tea prepared) and ordered some vinegar\nand hot water for him to inhale the steam of it, which he\ndid ; but, in attempting to use the gargle-, he was almost suffocated, When the gargle came from the throat, seme phlegm\nfollowed, and he attempted to cough, which the doctor encouraged hlrri to do as much as possible; but he could only at-\ntempt it. About eleven o'clock, Dr. Craik requested thai\nDr. Dick might be sent for, as he feared Dr. Brown would\nnot come in time. A messenger was accordingly despatched\nfor him About this time, the General was bled again. No\neffect, however, was produced by it, and he remained in (he\nsame slate, unable to swallow any thing.\nDr. Dick came about three o'clock, and Br. Brown arrived soon after. Upon Dr. Dick's seeing the '. len ral, and con\nsuiting a few minutes wilh Dr. Craik, he wi s bled again.\nTho blood came very slow, was thick, and did not produce\ntiny symptoms of fainting. Dr. Brown came into the chamber soon after, and upon feeling the General's pulse, the physicians went out together. Dr. Craik returned soon after.\nThe General could now swallow a little. Calomel and tartar emetic were administered, but without any effect.\nAbouf half past four o'clock, he desired me to call Mrs.\nWashington to his bedside, when he requested her to go down\ninto his room, nnd take from his desk two wills, which she\nwould find there, and bring them to him, which she did. Upon looking at them, he gave her one, which he observed was\nuseless, as being superseded by the other, and desired her W\nburn it, which she did, and took the other and put it into her\ncloset.\nAfter this was done, I returned to his bedside, and took hi*\nhand. He said to me, \" I find I am going. My breath cannot Inst long. 1 believed from the first, that the disorder\nwould prove final. Do you arrange and record all my Into\nmilitary letters and papers. Arrange my accounts, and settle\nmy books, as you know more about them than any one else,\nand let Mr. Rawlins finish recording my other letters, which\nhe has begun.\"    I told him this should be done.    He the\"","fullrs":{},"find":"465.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"464","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1860873","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
