<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2126</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2126</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2126/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 17","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"17\n\u2022t\u00ab citizens     Whether the road will have that effect or not, may\nT-t of some question.    It would seem, at the worst, that the road\nff     but tiro choice of markets to the planters of those sections, who\n\u00b0k rwise from the difficulties of reaching the Mississippi River, migl\n:ht\n!!w7take'the cars to Charleston in preference.    It would seem also,\nhe tho policy of New-Orleans, that every rail-road from the Atlantic sea board penetrating tho valley, should find its terminus invariably at the river. ,  , '. . .j.\n3 Arkansas.\u2014This now prosperous and thriving state, with a po-\nDUlation of 209,641, and a crop of 100,000 hales of cotton, has not\nwithin her limits a single mile of rail-road. A citizen of Memphis\nhas proposed two roads for the people of Arkansas, which we have\nunderstood meet with great favor in that state. 1st.\u2014A road from\nopposite Memphis to St. Francis, with two branches from that point,,\none into the heart of Missouri to Erie, on the Osage River, and the\nother to Little Rock, tho capital of the state. 2d.\u2014A road from\nLittle Rock to Lagrange, on the south-western extremity of Arkansas, to connect with a road at that point extending to Natchez,\nMiss. These roads form a system for Arkansas, which must exert\nan extraordinary influence in developing her resources, and putting\nher far in advance of her present position in this era of progress. The\narguments in their favor are thus strongly summed up by Mr.\nHewson:\n\" The road from Memphis to the Osage must form the basin of a\nsystem of roads. Though only some two hundred and fifty miles\nlong, it suggests, indeed will force, junctions, extensions, branches, to\nan extent much greater than its own. The branch from St. Francis\nto Little Rock, the first link in a southern route to tho Pacific, will\nbe 90 miles long. A branch road westward from Elizabeth will open\nup the country to the head waters of White River. A northeasterly\nbranch from Jackson, or Canton in Arkansas, will penetrate the great\nmineral district of Missouri. A connection at Erie, or some other\npoint in the valley of the Osage, will tap the St. Louis \" Pacific\nKail-road\" on its route easterly. This Osage road must, necessarily,\n\u00b0e the parent of all these. It will, therefore, identify New-Orleans\nwith the great future\u2014lying within and without the State of Missouri,\ntraversing ,a country teeming with industrial resources\u2014coal, lead,\n2'nc copper, iron\u2014it will make New-Orleans the market of the\ngreatest manufacturing city in the Mississippi valley, namely, the city\nMcmpms, when acted on by this road. This road may be said to\ne not so much a work of development as of creation\u2014the creation,\nmorolT' an unequa\u00bbed, and still more of an unassailable, eom-\nWMt, T&gt;? ess- But even now the farmers in *e valleys of\nline- .T v and of Arfemsas River are crying, like Sterne's star-\nthriftv flP g0t \u00b0Ut' Gentlem\u2122 \u00b0f New-Orleans, pray help those\nmost like \u00b0T \u00a3 \u2122s grist t0 y\u00b0ur miU- 1.200,000 dollars will,\ndonation f i a rail'road from Memphis to Little Rock.    A land\nmade to v\u00b0n t,hogovemment\u2014obtainable for the asking\u2014may be\nsettlcmor,A   ., (-a\"    the sa,es shouId bo ma&lt;le on tho condition of\n\u25a0matt) at least 500,000 dollars ; Arkansas and Memphis will sub-\n2","fullrs":{},"find":"2127.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2126","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"526900","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
