<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 35</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2194</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2194</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2194/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:48">{"title":"Section 5, Page 35","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"ENGINEER'S   REPORT\nTo Messrs. M. M. Cohen, P. Simihs, M. O. H. Norton, A. Lanfear, Maunsel White, J\nW. Stanton, and B. H. Payne, Executive Committee on New Orleans and Opelousas\nRailroad:\nGentlemen,\u2014Agreeably to your request and instructions, I have, with the assistance of Dr.\nW. S. Smith, surveyed that portion of the route of the contemplated New Orleans and Opelousas Railroad lying between Thibodaux and Berwick's Bay, and submit to you this my\nreport:\nWe first fixed on a point supposed to be the most eligible for crossing Bayou Lafourche,\nabout a quarter of a mile above the corporate limits of the town of Thibodaux, which point is\n15 chains and 70 links below the upper line ofthe plantation of Judge Guion.\nFrom thence, for nearly 5 miles, we directed our course so as to follow a ridge of high land,\nknown as the Point aux Chimes : at this distance the ridge turns so much westward as to be\nno longer available. We then turned the course a few degrees to the right hand, running\nthrough a cypress swamp two miles and a half across, striking the nearest point of high land\non the Chucahoula ridge. This last-mentioned swamp has a fine hard clay bottom, with\ncrevasse water-marks varying from three to four feet, and in a few sloughs five feet watermark. In the summer season this swamp becomes entirely dry, but now has on it water\naveraging one foot in depth. It is my opinion this swamp might be drained and kept most\ngenerally dry, by making a sufficiently large canal across the Chucahoula Ridge into Bayou\nIiger, at a point where the distance would be but about one-half a mile in length.\nIhence our line curves still more to the right hand, running along the Chucahoula Ridge\nour miles, and enters a cypress swamp similar to the one last described. This swamp\np C|\u00b0SseB ln a Stance of g- mile, striking a low and narrow ridge of land on the Bayou Tiger,\nW1**g this ridge, twice crossing the Bayou Tiger, at 13 miles from Lafourche, we arrived\n* a poinl oa l*\u00bbe right bank of Bayou Black, opposite the town of Tigerville.\ni, .' e \u00b0hserved, also, by referring to the annexed sketch, that the line thus far crosses\nref    T\u00b0U C!luca'10llla four times ; but this Bayou, as well as the Bayou L'Ours, hereafte\n\u00b0i is very small and hardly observable, being what is generally termed a dry Bayou.\nland enfCeRfr0Ii:i \u00b0PP\u00b0site Tigerville, crossing a little to the left, the line runs along the high\nhj , . ayou Black two miles and a half, thence curving slightly to the right across the\n\\y    , \"ayou L'Ours one mile and a half, and enters a cypress and tupelo gum swamp.\nTJj etWeen the high Innds of Bayou L'Ours and Bayou Boeuf.\nf*\u00abe th       amP liaS crevasSe water-marks from three to four feet, and is less firm on the sur-\nthe g   ,     \u00b0se PreviousIy crossed on our line.    At a depth of from six to twelve inches below\ngr\u00bbs\"   t&gt;     ^ ground is tolerably firm, being clayey, or what is here generally termed \" terre\n\"riddle       6 across this swamp is a little more than two miles in length, and at near the\nLeav'       e&amp;- a Sma\" draining Bayou, the bottom of which is boggy.\nLif0Ur , s last-mentioned swamp, and passing over cultivated land, at 19$ miles from\n^\"ks 81 *e arrived on the east bank of Bayou Boeuf.    This Bayou is 590 feet in  width,\nr^nce bet ve tide water, and has a gentle current each way according to the tide\u2014diffe-\nWeen ordinary high and low tides, about 18 inches.","fullrs":{},"find":"2195.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2194","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"670701","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.64 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
