<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/437</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>437</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/437/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:58">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"PI\nI'MS\n%\nro\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nfall into a state of rudeness, frivolity, and slavery, if we throw\naway the key that unlocks the stores of manly sentiment, of\nelegance, taste, and all intellectual excellence, that opens lo\nns, in fine, all the treasures of wisdom, both sacred and profane. Banish the classics, and the cause of science itself, of\nliberty and religion, would suffer detriment. A people trained merely to mercantile and military pursuits, actuated solely\nby the desire of gain and the love ol conquest, would be fit\ninstruments for the artful demagogue and aspiring chieftain;\nwould be, as they doubtless would soon become, like the\nFrench, proper subjects for the despotism of a Grand Mon-\narque, a lordly aristocracy, and a corrupt hierarchy. Our\npoliticians, instructed not in the generous learning of Greece\nand Rome, but in the lessons of mere calculation and measurement, instead of possessing liberal and expanded views\nof policy, would be men of narrow, selfish, contracted spirits.\nThe practice of law would be confined to ignorant pettifoggers; of medicine to unprincipled quacks; the lamp of the\nsanctuary itself, which now diffuses ils hallowed influence\nover our land, would grow dim ; the wild spirit of fanaticism\nwould usurp thcplace of rational religion: the reign of ignorance and superstition would be revived, and the light of science be extinguished in the Egyptian gloom of an endless\nnight.\nTHE EPIDEMIC YELLOW FEVERS OP NATCHEZ.\n\" IN   MEDIO VKttl'I'.VS \"\nAn !&gt;say rcml l.eferr the Jeffemon College, tincf Washington Lyceum, Iit-r, S\n1837, I.) .1. W. MoNsn-B, M, li.\nNotwithstanding the great diversity of opinions, entertain\ned by medical men, relative to the nature and production of\nyellow-fever miasm, and its operation upon the human system in producing thai disease epidemically j some points are\nadmitted, on all hands, as facts attending its production, extension, and destruction, in cities, and certain other localities.\nIt is admitted on all sides, that, at certain times, a peculiar not be known\nin the evening dews, and accumulates in low, damp places,\nnear the ground; that it is more rarified by the sun, and oV\nstroyed entirely by cold, or the abstraction of heat down to\n32\" Fall. Then it must be admitted, that if it can be confined\nin a bouse, a ship, or a balloon, it can also be carried from\none place to another, where it will be equally deleterious as.\nbefore it was transported, provided its temperature, be not reduced too near 32\" of Fahrenheit, and provided it be not too\nmuch diluted with pure, common air. If so, then it must be\nadmitted, that it can produce yellow fever in any place to\nwhich it may be carried and breathed in accordance with the\nabove conditions: or, a portion of it maybe introduced into\na hot, confined, and contaminated atmosphere, and produce\nthere the assimilating process; and thus in some degree ex-\ntend itself: and the miasm or infection thus generated, will he\nquully efficient in producing the disease, as the original\nsource from which it was taken. This principle is exemplified in the infected air which is shut up in houses during an\nepidemic, yellow-fever. A storm, or gale of wind, may so\ncompletely carry off the out-door infection, that the epidemic\nwill almost cease: yet so soon as the \"leaven \" of infection\nwhich is retained in the houses and enclosures, can diffuse\nitself, and again effect the assimilating process in (he general\nair, the epidemic will again break forth, with renewed vim-\nlence. The malignity of the disease is in direct proportion\nto tho virulence of the infection; and if, after such a change\nof weather, the disease again becomes equally malignant, the\nnewly generated infection is equally deleterious with the original : and this, wc believe, is the result of an assimilating\nprocess, which the infection can, and doe? eflect, in a suitable\natmosphere.\nIt is admitted that yellow fever is endemic all the year\nwithin the tropics, and in some places more than in others:\nthat, although its habitation is properly intertropical, its great-\nst ravages arc among northern strangers, and that it would\npidemic in the tropics, were it not for\nmiasm is generated, which will excite, in healthy individuals the constant influx of northern strangers, who, when numhws\nwho breathe it and who are not natiiralizi d to it, a peculiar|0f them are attacked, sometimes cause the infection to become\no concentrated that it will produce an epidemic even amort\":\nmalignant fever, or disease termed by common consent, ycllme\nfever: that this miasm, or aerial poison, may he confined in\nbouses, rooms, and other similar places, with all its deleterious\nproperties, even after the surrounding general atmosphere,\nwhich is iincoiifincel and free in ils circulation, has become entirely healthy: that this poisonous malaria, in rooms, ships\n&amp;c, insinuates itself into every opening, recess, or interstice,\ninto which common air can penetrate, especially near the\nsurface ofthe ground: that when diffused in a hot and sultry\natmosphere, ii has a property of extending itself gradually,\nnnd sometimes rapidly, and of imparting to that atmosphere\na deleterious property, which will excite yellow fever: or\nthai it assimilates a sultry, hot atmosphere to its own nature\nor impregnates it with the miasmatic poison, so as to produce\nyellow fever, and in this manlier spreads through a city: that\nthis miasm may become so concentrated, as to produce yellow-\nfever in unaccliinated persons who breathe it, even in very\nsmall quantities: or it may he so far diluted by pure, com-\ninonair, as to produce no sensible effect in those who respire\nit freely: that it is heavier than the common air, and settles\nthe indigenous or acclimated inhabitants. This increase, or\nconcentration of miasm, or infection, is apparently owintr\nsolely to the further vitiation of the local atmosphere, by the\nnumber of bodies laboring under that disease: for, in the\nWest Indies, and other places subject to yellow fever, it is\nknown to prevail generally among unaccliinated persons or\nstrangers, and does not attack the natives, until after a large'\nnumber of strangers have died. Hence, in those countries\nand cities where it is endemic nearly all the year, it is called\nthe \" strangers' fever.\" It is known also, that when the infection (or miasm) is sufficiently concentrated to produce yellow fever, in its most malignant forms, among strangers and\nunaccliinated persons, the natives, or naturalized inhabitants,\nif attacked at all, will be affected with it in a much milder\nform,\nIt is generally admitted by all parties, when a city, or certain district in a city, is attacked wilh yellow fever, that there\nexists in that district the peculiar miasm of yellow fever; and\nthat strangers, or ncn-residents, or a portion of them, who\nSOHB\nEM","fullrs":{},"find":"438.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"437","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1842459","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
