<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 25</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2250</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2250</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2250/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 25","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[25]\nIt is considered that the lake trade alone has made necessary the\n.. roa(j from Buffalo to Albany ; the rail-road from Dunkirk to\n!? ff.York ; the rail-road from Albany to Boston, and the rail-road\nfom Albany to New-York.    The various branches  to these great\nads derive their chief support from the same causes, the vast\n'mount of internal trade and the passenger trade winch it generates.\nThe same reasoning and causes are applicable to the southern railroads. How few of these would exist, if local patronage were their\nsole support.\nWe are indebted to Europe for many of the most useful mechanic\narts \u2022 but Europe is indebted to us for the great moral mechanics\nwhich best develop the energies and resources of a people, and which\nbrin** into profitable activity the industry and capacity of every\nmember of the great body politic.\nReferring effects to adequate and palpable causes, I believe it is to\nbe demonstrated, that this rapid and immense development of internal trade, this better than the mines of California, diffusing employment, wealth and happiness throughout our vastly extended\ncountry, is owing chiefly to the very limited patronage which has, as\nyet, been extended by the general government to our Lake Harbor\nand Western River improvements. This patronage has populated\nthose regions, and has thrown a vast amount of wild land into useful\ncultivation. Because it has furnished the means by which the products of the soil can find a market, exempt from consuming charges\nof transportation, and in return by increasing the means, has increased\nthe wants of the cultivator and his ability to supply them.\nThe propriety of any particular rail-road project is to be decided\nby reference to this great trade, in the benefits of which it will participate ; and there can hardly be a project of a road, which shall form\na link in the connection between the western rivers, or the lake harbors and the Atlantic, which will not partake of these as well as of\nlocal benefits.\nBut it appears to me that this great chain will be incomplete, and\nits benefits be but partially enjoyed, unless the connection be formed\nbetween the Mississippi and the Pacific. Of the rail-road to insure\nthis connection, I have written several letters, but probably the last\nls p that you would desire to read.    I send a copy of this.\n\"appears to me that such a road, connecting with the Mississippi\nsome point so far south as to be exempt from interruption from\n\u25a0ce, would make New-Orleans the  great emporium for. the Pacific\n|he connection between the Mississippi end of* the road and New-\nneans, as well as with other points on that river, would probably\nano      accomplished by steamboat.    And  by means  of  this river\nthe Ohio, there is no town on the shores  of either which would\nand h    6 benefit from the road-   Then hy the lakes' hy rail-roads\u00ab\ntoM. ? Canals, links already exist to complete the connection inland\n** ibe Atlantic. * P\nam     s?bJect is o. vast one-    It fills the imagination; and unless I\nmu&lt;* mistaken, it would also fill the pockets of our people.","fullrs":{},"find":"2251.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2250","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"539742","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
