<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/416</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>416</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/416/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":":iit!\n\u25a0m\nm\nI\/!1\n\u25a0 \u25a0;}.\nI  '?-!\n50\nSOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\n' il\nrefuse ivhat leads lo consequence. The province of Algebra,\nnot less important, is to analyze every proposition, whether\nmoral or mathematical, which solicits credence', by such a\nprocess of scrutiny, as at once and forever lo settle its claims.\nIf any of ils parts be found wauling or fallacious; if their arrangement be found suei) that a sophistical conclusion has been\nplausibly drawn, the analysis will delecl and expose the error.\nIf all iho parts which compose a general truth bo found\npresent, each genuine, and the conclusion correctly drawn,\nand yet the arrangement so confused as to create suspicion,\nanalysis will point out the correction, and present the whole\nIn a clearer and more forcible light. * * * It need nol\nbe further insisted that these influences are the same in moral\nas in mathematical reasoning. Without reducing all propositions to formulas, still they can be subjected to mathematical rigor, in the demonstration or the analysis of truth. And in\nthe admission of truths into the mind, for the formation of principle, the nearer each can be brought to the standard of scrutiny,\npointed out by mathematical logic, the more safely may those\nprinciples be relied upon, and the profound will be all subsequent research. For all other logic is theory without application; such theory \"niayerr, observation may deceive, but\ndemonstration never I\"\nIt has been said that the pure mathematics have their foundation in the nature of things. This position we shall reverse, and say, that lite natures of things have their foundation\nin the pure mathematics.\nThe laws of attraction, an essential properly of material\nexistence,\u2014the cause of all motion,\u2014are demonstrated to be\ndeeply, and rigorously mathematical.    Attraction of gravita-\ning upon its bosom. That wind is moved by the principle (f\ngravitation just shown to be strictly mathematical. Tlle\nlightning obeys the laws of electricity, and the thunder is but\nthe concussion of the lightning with the neighboring atmosphere, causing a vibration, which decreases in the inverse\nratio of the squares of the dislances from ihe point of concussion. Again: The torrents tumble from the mountain\nlop, rush together upon the plain, and in the form of n mighty\nriver, wind their way across a continent, to find a resting\nplace in the ocean. Gravity gives to those waters their original\nimpulse, and ils few simple laws, govern all their meander-\nings, till in the ocean they find their nearest possible approach\nto the center. And again ; observe the trembling leaflet, the\nmorning dew, tho music of an instiument, the symmetry of\nthe human form, the insect sporting in the evening sun: see\nthe canopy that overspreads us, the rainbow that spans it, the\nfalling avalanche, and the awful throes of nature. Now return and analyze each in its order. Tho leaves that quiver\nyield to the impulse of the wind, and in every revolution describe a geometric curve, and the wind is moved by gravitation. The tlew drop forms and falls by gravitation, and music\nbeautifully and deeply mathematical. The bird or the insect upon the air is supported by repulsion, and every stroke\nof a microscopic wing, describes the arc of a circle. The\ncurves that bound the human frame, with the figures described\nby the motion of its limbs, may be separated, classified, and\nsubjected to the most rigid mathematical analysis. The canopy\nabove us is but the boundary of sight, a sphere of which the\neye is tlie center: and the rainbow, itself the arcs of several\nconcentric circles, the line joining their common center and\ntion, the grandest in its effects, of all its class of properties,!the sun, passes through ihe eye of the observer,\u2014is but tho\ncommences by reducing inorganic matter to spherical form\u2014'separation of ihe rays of light by refraction, and referable to\na perfect geometrical figure\u2014produced by the tendency of its the mathematic science of optics. The dread avalanche obeys\nparts to a common center, Thus, from the ::'.'n drop to theithe impulse of gravity; and the direful earthquake finds ils\nocean, from earth to the heavens\u2014the moon, the stars, the governing laws and its final conqueror, in attraction and re-\nsuns of a thousand systems, all have assumed their beaiitcousjsistance. Shall wo forbear to weary the mind, already more\n\u2014mathematic form, froija the action of this law upon its lhan convinced, that the nature of things is based upen the\ngeometric principles.    The same law preserves the regular principles of pure mathematics?\ngrandeur of the planetary motion, us they roll in eternal cir-      But if it be conceded that nature was framed by mathematic\ncles around the sun.    Can wc ask a more triumphant proofl laws, Meirpre-existence is thereby acknowledged,    This truth\nthat mathematics cannot err? A million times a myriad suns,\nforever \"thwarting and convolved, yet never, never know confusion!\" But these are tbelaws of nature, and hence the 1. ws\nof God; and the wonder that they cannot err, finds here its\nmay bo demonstrated a priori, from the following considera-\nlions: Grant that there was a time when the creation occurred. Before that period, space was, in every direction, equally\nextendi (I.    Suppose tj point; and  if from  this point,  space\nonly satisfactory solution,    And m prove the other varieties! was, in every diction, equally extended, space was a snhere\nof attraction, such as electric magnetic,  &amp;c;, obey \u201e,e sanJof which the given point was the center! and th^ZsX\nUnity,    But the sphere involves nearly every geometrical\nunchanging laws, suffice  it to say, that the law of increased\npower, in the  inverse  ratio of the squares of tho dislances,\nhas been rigorously demonstrated, in regard to cac\nBut to change for a few moments, the order of reasoning,\nfrom the inductive lo the analytic  le, let us take the phenomena of nature as they present themselves\u2014trace them to\ntheir causes, nnd examine the laws which govern their operation.     When we look abroad upon the beauteous world, we\nsee nearly all things in living- motion.    \"The wind is on itslmost universal bearing; how shall all the com\nwandering way,\" carrying freshness and life lo every region, business transactions of the enterprising world\nHero ihe pillowing cloud lays leisurely upon its pinions, audi but by an intimate knowledge of arithmetic? How shall dis-\ntherc the tempest, with dread lightning and thunder, is sweep-jtance, time, and number be estimated but by this first mathe-\nproperty; therefore, the principles of geometry were antecedent to creation.\nWo next invite attention lo Ihe connection of mathematics\nwith the business of life. And here we find the variety of\nsubjects so great, each presenting such irresistible claims to\nnotice, that our great difficulty is lo make a selection without\nmanifest injustice to the subject.    But ,0 ,nko a s,;n|ce of th\u201e\nmercial and\njo conducted,","fullrs":{},"find":"417.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"416","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1850263","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
