<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2239</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2239</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2239/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 14","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[14]\npeltries, flax and wool, gums, various ornamental woods, mines nf\nsilver, gold and precious stones, of new varieties, kinds and virtues\nhave been reached, and added to the list of countless treasures, bound\nless commercial capacities, and dazzling resources, of these two m^\"\nnificent water-sheds.\nSave and except tea, which is the only article of commerce that\nis gathered from the field, the forest or the mine, that is not to be\nfound in one or the other of these two river basins, everything that\nis grown or cultivated upon the face of the earth is to be found ia\nequal, if not in greater perfection and abundance, in one or the other\nof these valleys, than in any other part of the world.\nOne of these is in the rear of New-Orleans\u2014the other, in its front.\nIt is for this Convention to say whether these two rivers shall be\nunited in the bonds of commerce or not.\nThe Amazon, with its tributaries, is said to afford an inland navi.\ngation, up and down, of not less than 70.000 miles. The country\ndrained by that river, and the water-courses connected with it, is\nmore than half as large as Europe, and it is thought to contain near-\nly as much arable land within it as is to be found on that continent\nIt has resources enough to maintain a population of hundreds of mil-\nlions of souls.\nThe navigation on that river is at present such, that the people of\nthe upper country can make but one trip in the year. They have\nthere, in their delightful climate of an everlasting spring, the calm\nseason and the trade-wind season. The trade-winds blow up the\nriver. In the calm season, the natives, in their rude bungaloes, loaded with the produce of the upper country, drift down with the cup\nrent. Arrived with their stuff at Para, they sell almost for dollars\nwhat they got for cents at the place of production.\nHaving completed the business of the season, they wait for the\nS. E. trade-winds to set in ; with them they return, and complete the\nbusiness and the trading for the year.\nTo afford the Convention an idea of the business carried on, by sea,\nwith Para, I quote returns of exports for the year ending Dec. 31stj\n1850, which Mr. Noms, the American Consul for that port, has had\nthe kindness to furnish me :\nEXPORTS FROM THE PORT OF PARA FOR THE YEAR ENDING DEC. 31, 1**'\nI\na\n*a\n1\nS\n!\nH\n1\n6\n1\n1\n4\nll\neao\n|\n1\n1\nI\ni\n5\n|\n&lt;\n!\n1\n1\n1\nI\nTo the United States ..\n58\n1638\n3254\n3990\n28,479\n1130\n50,069\n1633\n4558\n6655\n7595\n82,606\n283,753\n1837\n313-3\nT^tf","fullrs":{},"find":"2240.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2239","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"502411","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.48 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
