<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/430</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>430</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/430/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I\nI\n*\u25a0'\n\"\u2022\u25a0'ii\n\u25a0 i \u00a3\nW\n\" a  ?&gt;ri s\nI\",'to\nC4\nS(\nI1TI1- SVF.STE i: N JO U li N A I.\nReft\nNOTHING BEAUTIFUL  BUT MIND,\nthis attribute, tnebrighl earth la\n\u25a0\u2022\u2022I    by the Royal Antiquarian Society of Copenhagen, in which\nextracts from various manuscripts  in  the  Icelandic tongue,\nare given, accompanied with critical and geographical ro\nno charm.- \u2014thelmarks, all tending to substantiate tho belief of an i nrlier dig.\nookt around about him, Uvcry of the continent, than that by Columbus.    It iVstatid\nvilli careless eye and unlimited soul; lie sees no beauty in b)'the compilers-of this rfork, that the coast ol North A.,,,-,.\nlicious inelodv in her ica was thoroughly explored from Newfoundland to New\nmeet i- lost to iiis un- Jersey, and that Massuchiisctts ami Rhode island wt-resettled\nV moves him not. No: by them.    The testimony on the subject is not entirely'cos\nine mcchnnism &lt;\nharmonious am!\nenraptured sight\nlike the unintellectiuil herd that ciop the grass, helms no\nemotions apart from the elemands of his wants. But. give\nhim a mini \u2022 located by cultivation, expanded by knowledge,\nthen he looks proudly upon the works of his Creator. Every\npanicle of matter, lie feels, is filled with the presence ol Deity. 'With 1.iviur eye. lie gazes upon the grandeurs of nature,\nnnd her beauties, until his rapt soul drinks in melody far\nsweeti r lhan the sound of harps, or ihe song of bards. For\nhim there's music in ihe deepened thunder, in the voice of\ntho tempest, and the loud roar of the ocean, lie ,urns bis\neye ,o the bright nrch of heaven; he beholds the glorious\nsun in splendor rolling; fondly he gazes until the last expiring\nbeam has flashed upon the departure of day. Still he up\nturns his di lighted gaze to the concave firmament. Its brilliant azure is I,,, longci illumed by the bright blush of Eve\nfor she, with silent trend, has stolen away into the hushed\ncity id' nighl ' But now, the sweet, smiling eyes of llu: hour\nare gleaming bright upon the soft rest of heaven. Elevated\nby the contemplation divine, his soul whispers him, worship\nthy God I be kneels, and now, beneath the pale moon, and\nbrighter stars, he pours forth the feelings of his soul: his mind,\ndivested of all imholincss,seeks communion with that eternal\n.Mind, ol which his is but an emanation.\nWe consider mind as the light of life, the godlike apprehension, that renders man superior to all creation,\u2014as the only\ntie that links him to his Maker. He it what it may, we believe it divin\" an 1 immortal, destined by the Eternal, in the\nbeginning, ,o be gatht red buck to himself\u2014to be freed from\nall impurity, Superio\nnonentity cannol contain it, the unmeasured void of chaotic\nnothingness has no receptacle for it. No! like the divine\nsource from whence it sprang, it is superior to aught we can\nconceive of it; ii is in itself mighty, great, grand, wonderful, sublime, and little understood. In tho language of the\npoet, we would say '\n'\u2022 Mind, mind alone\u2014bear witness earth and heaven ;\nThe living fountain, in itself contains\nOf beauteous and sublime.\"\nelusive, and further information is yet needed before we ran\njustly rob the great Genoese ofthe glory which for three\ncenturies has remained undisputed, of having first seen mid\ndescribed the American continent.\nCause of Southwestern Education*.\u2014There is no:\nu generous and philanthropic spirit in the Southwest, that\nwill not rejoice nt tho prospects of an increasing zeal in the\ncause of education in this interesting region of country. The\nreport of the Education Convi ntion at Jackson, in the early\npart of this month, will speak a sentiment ihat shall be n~ I\nechoed from plantation to plantation throughout Mississippi I\nWe have before us the official report of a committee of the I\nLegisture of Louisiana, on the state of Jeflerson College,'in I\nthe parish of St. .lames, in that State, ( an institution, which, L\nfrom identity of name, is often mistaken, by people at a (lis- F\ntnncc for Jefferson College in this Slate, the eldest proprietor I\nof the name.)\nThe joint committee of the Louisiana Legislature report'I\none hundred and twenty-seven resident students, most of whom |i\nwere proficients in Latin nnd Greek, and were able to trans-1\nlate French and Spanish into English, and the latter into tli'\nothers, vicissim.    A new edifice, at a cost of twenty thousand\nlollars, has been added to the structures previously erected,\nThe Slate owes the college more than thirty thousand dolhirs.\nas the balance of former appropriations,\nTo Readers.    Some long and interesting articles, in thi\n, \u2022!\u25a0!,\u25a0      .iiti      t        r present number, have excluded the usual editorial wiitinn\nIn niiiniiilaliiiii, ihe dark chambers of '\nDISCOVERY OP AMERICA.\nIn the Boston Advertiser there is an articln on the subject\nof the probable discovery of America, hy some navigator, anterior to the time of Columbus. That Greenland was discovered and peopled long before ihe age of Columbus, is\nmost certain, but ns Greenland is now considered by geographers a vast island, its discovery cannot be regarded as that of\nthe main land. Recent researches, however, go to prove that\nthe continent itself was colonized by the Panes, during some\nThere are several merely literal errors in this number, which'\niart ol the eleventh century,    A volume has hem published|do not include in the ah,,v.\nThe Review of \"Elements of .Moral Philosophy,\" is fro\none of the ablest pens in Massachusetts, to which we hope,i)\nfuture, tube largely indebted, as a contributor to the column\nof the South-Western Journnl,\nJEFFERSON COLLEGE AND WASHINGTON LYCEUM.\nTho Monthly Meeting of the .Lyceum, will be attend'\nin the College Hall, on Saturday next. ( February 3d,) il'l\no'clock, P, M,\nThe exercises are expected to be, a Lecture by Dr. S. C-r\nMl'RWIN, and Essays by Messrs. President C. L. DUBMM\nson and (i. L. Davis,\nLadies and gentlemen are respectfully invited to attend, f\nPago\nSO\n'il\nERRATA.\niiinn   11111-\n1 -J(t      before profound, insert \"more.\"\n(\u2022-', from the bottom,)    fur - lays,\" rend \" lag\n2 (1       for \" vigorous, read \" rigorous.\"\n1      37      for \"moral,\" read \"rural.\"\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"431.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"430","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1936319","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.85 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
