<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/602</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>602</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/602/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n239\nii r\npossessed much of the firmness of purpose, which, being exhibited by men of contracted mind without any discrimination, and as pertinaciously when they arc in the right, lends\nto their character nn appearance of inflexible consistency\nwhich is often mistaken for greatness of mind, anel not seldom\nreceived as a substitute for honesty. In all that related to\nhis kingly office, he was the slave of asdeep-iooted a selfishness as his son; and no feeling of a kindly nature ever was\nsuffered to cross his mind, whenever his power was concerned, either in ils maintenance or in tbe manner of exercising\nit. In other respects he was a man of amiable disposition,\nand few princes have been more exemplary in their domestic habits, or in the office of private friendship. But the ins-ant that his prerogative was concerned, or his bigotry inter-\nfcred with, or bis will thwarted, ihe most unbending pride,\nthe most bitter animosity, the most calculating coldness of\nheart, the most unforgiving resentment, took possession of his\nwhole breast and swayed it by turns. Tbe habits of friend\nship, the ties of blood, the dictates of conscience, the rules of\nhonesty were alike forgotten; and the fury of the tyrant,\nwith the resources of a cunning which mental alienation is\nsupposed to whet, were ready to circumvent or destroy all\nwho interposed an obstacle to ihe fierceness of his unbridled\ndesire. His conduct throughout the American war, and towards the Irish people, has often been cited as illustrative of\nthe dark side of his public character; and his treatment of\nthe Prince, whom ho hated with a hatred scarcely consistent\nwith the supposition of a sound mind, might seem to illustrate\nthe shadier part of his personal disposition; but it was in\ntruth only another part of his public, his professional conduct; for ho had no better reason for this implacable aversion than the jealousy which men have of their successors,\nand the consciousness that the prince who must succeed him,\nwas unlike.him, and, being disliked by him, must, during\ntheir joint lives, be thrown into the hands of ihe adversaries\nhe most of all detested.\"\nOueen Charlotte.\u2014\" Queen Charlotte was a woman\nof the most ordinary size of understanding, of exceedingly\nsordid propensities, of manners and disposition that rendered\nher peculiarly unamiable, of a person so plain as at once to\ndefy all possible suspion of infidelity, and to enhance the virtue by increasing the difficulty of her husband's undeviating\nconstancy to her bed. Her virtue was so much accompanied\nwith superfluous starchness and prudery, that it set the feelings of respect and sympathy on edge; and though her regularity of life was undeviating, the dulncss of her society, the\nstiffness of her demeanor, her narrowness of soul, tended to\nmake respectable conduct as little attractive as possible, and\nrather to scare away from morality than to entice the beholder. Of a nature rigorously parsimonious, the slave besides,\nof inordinate avarice, she redeemed not this hateful meanness\nby any of those higher qualities of prudence and practical\nsense, which are not unfrequently seen in its company. Her\nspirit, too, obstinate, and not untinctured with spite; she was\nunforgiving; she was not undesigning ; she could mingle in\nthe intrigues of a court, as well as feel its malignities; and\nher pride knew no bounds\u2014combining the speculative aristocracy of a petty German court, with the more practical\nhaughtiness which is peculiar to the patrician blood of this\nfree country. Of the Prince of Wales she never had been a\nfriend, until he became Regent, when she became at once bis\nlool and his slave. On the contrary, on all occasions she had\npartaken of her husband's hatred of him, and had been as\nready an accomplice of his maltreatment of her first-born\nchild, as she now made herself the submissive and willing\ninstrument of injury to his wife\u2014his cousin and her own\nniece. The visitation of God, which substituted that son for\nhis father on the throne, altered the whole face of affairs in\nthe eyes of this unamiable female, who seems to have been\nraised up as a remarkable proof how little one maybe cither\nrespected or beloved, for being above reproach as regards the\nquality sometimes supposed to comprise all female virtue, anil\nwhich indeed is familiarly allowed to engross the name. To\ngratify the Regent's paltry spite, she now refused even'to receive her daughter-in-law at that Court where she might any\nday have become her successor; and the populace, moved\nwith just indignation at tho behaviour of this disagreeable\npersonage, loaded her with every offensive expression, and\neven with more substantial symbols of an extravagant dis-\nust, while she was on her way to hold the court whence she\nmeanly submitted to excluele the Princess.\"\nGeorge, Prince of Wales, afterwards Georoe\nIV., had been educated after the manner of all princes\nwhose school is the palace of their ancestors, whoso teacher\nis boundless prosperity, whose earliest and most cherished\nassociate is unrestrained self-indulgence, and who neither\namong their companions from the acquaintance ofanycquoM\nnor in the discipline of the seminary, ever taste of control.\nThe regal system of tuition, is indeed, curiously suited to its\npurpose of fashioning men's minds to the task of governing\ntheir fellow creatures ; of training up a naturally erring and\nsinful creature to occupy tho most arduous of all human stations, the one most requiring habits of self-command, and for\nduly filling which all the instruction that man can receive,\nand all the virtue his nature is capable of practising, would\nform a very inadequate qualification. This system had upon\ntho Prince of Wales, produced its natural effects in an unusually ample measure. He seemed indeed, to come forth from\nthe school, a finished specimen of its capabilities and its\npowers, as if to show how much havoc can be made in character originally deficient in none of the good, and few ofthe\ngreat qualities with which it may be supposed that men are\nborn.\u2014Naturally of a temper by no means sour or revengeful, he had become selfish to a degree so extravagant, that he\nseemed to act upon the practical conviction that all mankind\nwere born for his exclusive use ; and hence he became irritable on tbe least incident that thwarted his wishes, nay, secmeel\nto consider himself injured, and thus entitled to gratify his resentment as often as any one, even from a due regard to his\nown duty or his own character, acted in a way to disappoint\nhis expectations or ruffle his repose. His natural abilities\ntoo, were far above mediocrity. He was quick, lively, gifted\nwith a retentive memory, and even with a ready wit,\u2014endow \u25a0\ncd with an exquisite ear for music, and a justness of eye that\nfitted him to attain a refined taste in the arts,\u2014possessed, toe,\nof a nice sense of tho ludicrous, which made his relish for\n1:","fullrs":{},"find":"603.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"602","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1756101","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
