<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/351</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>351</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/351/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"Soih -ll-W lis I'JiHN   JO URN A 1.\nlUmss, hammock, fans and moschito bars, with all the other lance, with embroidered sandals, white figured ,ack,t -md r\"cd\n|tt   s that constitute the necessaries ol life to one who turban.    As testimonials of his fi.ness for the office ,\nshcs u, H,(, at his ease.    He proved o be a man who had sough,, he cairi, d about him several certificates to hi effec\nprovcd bl, .oii.d by reading and study, and his long rest- \"Qovendu, ,1,,- bearer of this, is one of the greatest rascals\ntUm ;\u201e that country, entitled him to some attenfon, when he that ever attempted to palm himself off for an i\u201e.,\u201e ..,,.,,,,.,\n^tmed the character ol an adviser. He was very panic,- he will pilfer from your wardrobe, hire out your clothes'\n,irin enjoining upon us the necessity of temperance, rigid .and charge the crime upon the washerman, steal your loose\nlemparnnce, both in eating and drinking, nothing being sojehange, exchange your good hose lor poor ones, and perform\nnmns-\nlinilbrrri good health, to the strict observance of this rule,'faithful in his attentions to his master\" Tnl ifyou'kcep a\nnever drinking to excess, and only taking occasionally a little'(strict eye upon him, he will serve you as well as any other\nbrandy and water or ale, just to keep up the perspiration, that you may chance to meet with.\"    Upon the strength of\nthis   recommendation,   I   determined   to employ   him, and\ninjurious to the constitution in a hot climate, as  immoderate sundry other little acts ol' legerdemain that ale more \u25a0\npotations of wine or spirituous liquors.     He imputed his own mg to hi ar of than  to he made the subject of.    But\nwhich he assured us it was very dangerous to check.    How\nveil his practice corresponded with his precepts, may be infer-\n\u2022d from the fact, that in the course of eight days that he pass\nwhen he left me 1 found there were ample grounds for giving him a certificate similar to the one just quoted.\ncd on board of our ship, lie consumed about two dozen Dot-1 One of the first things to be learned in Calcutta, is the\nll\u00ab of strong eider and port.r, together with a gallon of tact of being gracefully indolent. Nothing so strongly im-\nbrandy, which hitter he was constantly sipping in the form of presses one's servants with a respect for your person, and\nbrandy toddy, just to keep up the perspiration. When tin\nglass was not at his lips, ho had a scgar or charute, puffing\nmvaythe damp fogs that pervade the atmosphere over the\nriver. Upon leaving us he was very particular in warning\nm against the intemperate habits that too many young men\nacquire on visiting Calcutta; and again referred to his own\ntemperate habits in corroboration or the importance of his indispensable requisites of sleeping and eating, they being\npremonitions, and as proof of the advantages to bo insured the only two duties tolerated in good society, but even in the\nby cautious abstinence. 1 smiled acquiescence, and assured performance of these, great caution must be observed, lest\nhim that I would endeavor to profit by his example. some unnecessary act destroy your claim to the character of\nAfter a pleasant passage up the Hoogly, attended with the a man eomme il [nut.    It is considered entirely bad taste to\nusual incidents, we arrived at Calcutta, situated upon its eas- retire for the night without the assistance or three or four\nwall a proper sense or your gentility and good breeding, as\nthe ability to he perfectly passive. One's desires must be indicated by a languid turn of the head or by a gentle look of\nthe eye, and if no servant be in attendance, one must be summoned to your assistance by the soli and feebly enunciated\nqui-hi.    All duties must be performed by proxy, save the two\nMa bank, about eighty miles from the mouth of the river.\nCalcutta is the largest and most important city in the East\nIndies, containing upwards of six hundred thousand inhabitants. There is nothing imposing in its appearance as you\napproach it from the river.     It is necessary to enter the city\nservants at least, or to rise in the morning without the attention of the same guardians of your person. No gentleman,\nwho has a proper regard for his dignity, would pretend to\nwake iqi or himself j he must, as a matter ol' course, remain\nislcep until his valet and head-beaver announce themselves\ntraverse its spacious avenues, visit its crowded bazaars, in readiness to assist in the duties of the coming day, unless\nadmire its ancient mosques, its magnificent tanks, its splendid perchance, he should be accident.illy aroused by the awk-\nediliees, to feel that it well deserves the proverbial appellation wardness of the barber while being shaved. The next cereal the city or palaces. One cannot look upon its magnificence, Imony that one's servants see  fit to enact with your person\nwithout lamenting for the native Hindoo, that the predate\n,y power of the English government has wrested rrom him\nlas birth right, and robbed his rajahs of the government and\nemoluments of a princely possession.\nOur first business after arriving at Calcutta, was to pro-\ntare a house, with servants, furniture, palanquins, baths, and\nthe other necessary appurtenances of comfortable living in\nthe east. To live in any thing like respectable style, one\ntans! bo encumbered with innumerable expenses, which\nthough individually trilling, are very important in the aggre-\np\"e, Each individual must have his private servant and his\nPalanquin, with five bearers. The first performs all the ac-\ntustomary duties or a valet, helps to dress and undress you,\nrails for your palanquin, carries your keys, secures tho best\ndishes for you at table, brings you a bamboo tooth-pick af-\nu'r Jour meal, and steals whatever he thinks you have no\n\"iventory of.    In my selection or a valet, I made choice or\nafter shaving and waking, is to roll you in a bath, then every\njoint in your body must be pulled out or place and reset,\nwith a singular, though agreeable concussion, after which,\nthey may see proper to dress you, by which time probably\nthe breakfast table will demand attention, to which it will\nbe necessary to proceed with all becoming listlessness; your\nvalet in the mean time takes care to place near you, such\ndishes as he conceives will be most likely to please your\ntaste, and after filling your plate with what meets your approbation, he gracefully withdraws, that you may perform\nthe labor or eating it without the intervention or a proxy.\nEntire apathy in every thing is the grand criterion of orthodoxy; inactivity is studied as an art, and the most proficient\nknows best how to avnil himself or the luxurious enjoyments\nor indolence. It is only during the enticing coolness or the\norning and evening, that these rules suffer infraction, but at\nsuch times the superb roads and esplanade of Calcutta, are\ny looking Moorish boy, perfectly neat in his appear-lthronged with people in equipages or all descriplions, pnlnn\niif!\n\u25a0' m\n\u25a0 , \u25a0\u2022'\u25a0\"\n'.' *\u2022.;'' i i\n'&gt;&gt;!\n\u25baa\n\",\n\u25a0\nj\n\u25a0 -----","fullrs":{},"find":"352.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"351","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1719985","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.64 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
