<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 27</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2252</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2252</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2252/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:51">{"title":"Section 7, Page 27","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"L27]\nSOUTHERN RAIL-ROAD TO THE PACIFIC.\nBureau of Topog. Eng., Washington. Jan. 25,1851.\nDear Sir: I have at last been able to have those letters copied, about\n,    oa(j and now send them to you.   In reference to probable cost, recent\nformation induces me to believe, that a road from the Mississippi to the\nRio Grande, passing at the head of sea-navigation of all the principal rivers\nrtf Texas which communicate with the gulf, could be made for less than I\nformerly supposed.\nIf we take this distance at 850 miles, and the average cost of each mile.\nto make the rail-road complete, and bring it into use, at $40,000 the mile,\nit will make the cost of that part of the road $34,000,000.\nIf this part alone of the road was made, it would command all the travel.\nFor from the Rio Grande to San Diego, is a frontier Une of the United\nState**, on which military posts will have to be established, and roads connecting with these posts will have to be made, which will make that route\npassable and safe, and wall occasion it gradually to become settled, and sooner\nor later to be turned into a rail-road. Eut we will suppose the whole to be\na rail-road, and endeavor to estimate its probable cost and probable profits.\nFrom the Paso to San Diego on the Pacific, is about 850 miles. If it be\nsupposed that this part of the route will cost 50 per cent, more than the\naverage cost per mile from the Mississippi to Paso, it will make the average\nof this part of the road $00,000 the mile, and bring the total cost of these\n850 miles to $51,000,000.    Then the whole road will cost as follows :\n850 miles from the Mississippi to Paso, $34,000,000\n850 miles from Paso to San Diego  51.000,000\nTotal, $85,000,000\nTwelve per cent, upon such an outlay would require an income of\n$10,200,000. This would be a gross income, out of which all expenses for\nrepairs, attendance, &amp;c, -fee, &amp;c. would have to be taken. Taking these at\nhalf the gross income, it would leave $5,100,000 to be divided, in order to\nyield an income upon the stock of G per cent, per annum.\nThe question now occurs, from what sources will this road derive such\nau income ?   We will consider two sources only\u2014travelers and freight.\nlrf. Travelers.\u2014In my letter of the 24th September, 1849, I take these\nat 50 each way per day, for 350 days, and at a charge of $68 for a through\npassage.\nAn extremely judicious friend, who has given much attention to these\nmatters, says, that I am seriously wrong in both these items\u2014seriously be-\n\u00b0w the reality in reference to the number of travelers, and equally below\nWhat would be considered a cheap charge for the distance.\nIn his opinion 100 passengers, each way, would yet be much below the re-\nny, and $150 for each passenger vastly below what each has now to pay.\n\"M at these rates, and with the time saved, the road would, without doubt,\ncommand the travel of the world from the Atlantic to the Pacific.    Taking\n2rf rpG3' tlie income from passengers would be $10,500,000.\na- flight\u2014The same friend has remarked, that the road should be\ni ui reference to the commerce it would generate and command, and\n\u25a0hoi's ?efcrence to anJ\" Proflt from freight.    That, except for passengers, it\nu'a be a free road, making no charge for freight, thereby enabling it to\nI \"umaad the commerce of the world with the Pacific; and from this mo-","fullrs":{},"find":"2253.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2252","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"610089","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.58 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
