<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 19</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2128</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2128</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2128/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 19","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"ADDRESS. 19\ni r. of East Mississippi and Western Alabama, and their supplies for thai\nthoprou'ic\" probably find  their way upon  this road, mid the  branch\n*&gt;g\u00bbn \u00bb\\ c. '.;,;,\u201e{; ll)B ^.th-eastern part of Mississippi. The Southern route\n\u00a3 wiUbecome tho great thoroughfare of northern and eastern travel It will\n^'\\ le ueral resources of North Alabama. Its rich aud inexhaustible\ndevelop i \u00a3 \u2122ro now workea in 5[(*te of tho difficulties of getting to a market,\nm\"iel' ,;il rmata and open a way to trade, the vast extent ol winch cannot be\n8 11 hlv estimated. We think it within bounds to assert, that 200.000 bales of\n(\u00b0o \u00ab will probably come over this road, and the branch extending through the\n^eastern portion ofMississippi to New-Orleans, iiotone bale ol which now ever\nrZXes it Detailed estimates, made by an engineer who has surveyed the route\nfrom Brandon to the Alabama Hue, of the amount required lor the completion of\nthe road that far, are in our possession, and may be set down in round numbers\nat one million ol dollars. If New-Orleans were to pay ihe whole cost of budding\nthe road that far, it would return to her in the increase of trade alone, without\nestimating the odier advantages, a handsome profit upon the investment. Eut\nthere are inducements to render the stock of this road valuable, th|t arc not presented by any other rail-road in the United States. From Jackson to Braudon\u2014\nfourteen miles and a hall'\u2014the road is completed, and in profitable operation.\nThese fourteen and a half miles, with the cars, locomotives, fixtures, depots, town\nfota, Sfcc., attached to the road; sixty choice and^iicked negroes; the two pe*\ncent, fund now on hand, being about \u00a912.000, and that which may lit reader bo received, now the property of the State of Mississippi, aud valued, upon u careful\nestimate by ihe President of the Southern rail-road, including ihe grading and labor dune east of Brandon, at $373,030, are all off-Ted by a recent act of the Legislature, as a lamas fur the organization of th\u00bb company, and the completion ol\" the\nroad to the Alabama line in six years. This act was passed in 1850, aud provides\nthat the whole property shall come into the possession of the company so soon aj\ntwenty miles of ihe road beyond Brandon has been nnisuVd.\n'\u25a0To organize the company requires a subscription of $500,0 0U of stock, with a\ncash payment of $j0,O00. immediately upon which the company becomes the\nowner of nearly a half million more of valuable aud active property. This statement shows of itself a conclusive inducement to take slock iu this road, and ren-\nden\u00bb it absolutely certain that it will be valuable.\n\" But there are other causes at work to render this road profitable stock,\nCongr ss has already displayed a liberal spirit in the donation of public lands to\n\u25a0similar works, and the Senate has twice passed bills in behalf of this road, granting hinds to aid iu its construction, worth, at the government price, over one halT\nmillion of dollars. It is believed a similar bill will become a law at the next\nCongress.\"\nThe Holly Springs road was proposed by Col. Walters, who offered\nthe following resolutions, which ^\\-el\u2022Q unanimously adopted in the\ninvention, and sustained them in a speech of great force and ability.\nJfo'ohcd* That the citizens of North Mississippi be, and they arc hereby\nrai r. yrS\u00b0 ,tC . t0 l\u00bbr\u00b0cure from the legislature of that state a charter for a\nrail-road from Jackson, Miss,, to Holly Springs, Miss.\nOrlcTnl  I Sh0Ukl saidcliartpr l,e procured, that the citizens of New-\nthe rn,,'J!,\"1S:;ini' ?nd Jacka\u00b0n. Mississippi, through their representatives irt\n\u00ab\u00aby) U contt?' i      \"\u00b0 thcmsclves for a llijeral ^ (\"h\u00b0uld \u00ab\u00ab same be neces-\nj; in constructing said road.\nand thenar,, h !'1C citizcns of Western Tennessee and South Kentucky be,\nrespective st ,7   y ea,rnest|y solicited, to procure from the legislature of their\n\"When, h\u00a3$L HneT'P \u00b0T * tM~TOad E\u00b0 CXte\"d from S01I1C Point 0n th\u00b0\nnear Cairo, Illinois Tennessee, to some point in Kentucky, opposite or\nthrougVtts ronr^e ^.u.I.dsaid charter he procured, then the city of New-Orleans,\naiJ in the coni* ,,fft;        5S m,thls Convention, pledges itself for a very liberaJ\n\"ouucuon ot said road.\nlaboma.\u2014Tha rail-roads of this state, which are now confined","fullrs":{},"find":"2129.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2128","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"504025","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.48 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
