<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 6</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/367</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>367</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/367/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 6","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\ncoarser objects, such as men, animals, trees, cities, mountain:\nand rivers, while we perceive not the. thousand kinds of lift\nand motion, the worlds in miniature, which are concealed in\nour shallow and hurried into unnoted ruin, by every step W(\ntake,\n\"Felix qui potuit rerum cognoscere causas,\" has alway.'\nbeen a sentiment of human nature, and will he no less so it\ntime to come, The causes of those facts and phenoment\nwhich we do know are beyond our reach, and probably bo\nyond our comprehension. When ono supposed cause lint\nbeen traced up, it terminates in other causes still more mysteri\nous; and those again in others until the mind becomes hewil\ntiered in thi chase. Wo can at most discover only a succession of events, and the order in which they occur without\nknowing why it is so.\u2014Who can tell what impulse is ; how\nit is communicated; what peculiar property is superadded?\u2014\nWhen one body receives a blow\u2014how is it that the body\nwhich strikes loses motion, and Ihe one stricken takes on mo\ntion? what invisible change has been effected in the particles\nof each by their approximation ? As it is only by the perceptions of our minds that we can know any thing of mutter or\nspirit, it liillnu s that we can know only such things as are capable of making an impression upon our minds: those objects\nwhich have mi properties, that will answer tt one ofourfivi\nsensesmusl pass hj entirely unknown, as if they had no exis\nicnc\". i lad we as many years of life, anil as many senses as\nVol, tire gives to tho inhabitants of Saturn, or seventy two,as\ndistinct ns our presi nl live, with a life of fifteen thousand years,\nwe mi lit n netrnte intothemysteriesoflho universe;\u2014or had\nwe tin- number of senses he allows to the inhabitants of those\nplan '(\u2022.- which revolve around the I), g-stnr as tin ir sun Bnd\ncn'.r\", thai is u arly one thousand, with a lili- seven hundred,\ntimes longer than those of Saturn, we too might find in matter\nthat \"three hui Ired\" essential properties did nol hill'fill up\nthe catalogue, which now, to our five --uses, is restricted to five\nor six. We tin n might ascertain v. hat are n-ally the essential\nnatter\u2014as will :,; of spirit.\nil our remarks a little more to particulars, and\n\u2022r ourselves familiar:\u2014and\nprt\nto th I\nfirst w\nIll's\ntitratei\neh we cons\n\u25a0 inization has been analysi d : his physiology inves-\nle different structures and tissues, and their respective functions have been minutely studil tl, ami the amount of\nknow! il \u25a0\"-. gained on the subject, is such as to make us proud\nof our advancement. The five filaments of nerves have been\ntraced from their origins to their extreme tissues, and their\ncontrol over voluntary and functional motion has hem deter-\nmined:the arteries mid veins have been traced to their ultimate\ninosculations; their morbidand healthy actions defined: in short,\n'he whole structure and functions so completely understood\nthat it has been supposed by some thatanntomy, if not physiology, might be ranked among the exact sciences,\nBut we cannot i nter into the mysteries of life: Who conli\ntell in what it consists? how vitality is connected with tho body ...\nami how leparated ? Howdoes life, which is diffused through- I\nout the whole body, become extinct when a single member is\ninjured ? or what sustains the powerful and incessant action of)tl\nthat force-pump, the heart, for three score years and ten? or\ni,|why does any muscle contract at all? What minute change\ntakes place in the ultimate fibres when health ceases and be-\nfore disease begins?\u2014These with thousandsof other phenomena\nare beyond our search.\nVision is the result of reflected and refracted light upon tin-\nretina of the eye, where the images of external objects are\npainted inverted ; and, when objects are distant or numerous, the inverted images in the eye are so small,\nas scarcely to occupy a point to each. Still we see objects as\nlarge, and at their proper distances, from the. mountain down\nto the atom. We know the theory of vision as taught by our\nmost enlightened philosophers ; but can any one explain what\nis tho essential nature of light; how and why it exists? why\ncertain objects refract it\u2014why others reflect it; and why others\nabsorb it, and it is forever gone; why another body generates\nand throws it off?\u2014why does it pass through the impervious\nchrystal, and not through a piece of porous black paper?\u2014Or\nhow is it that certain particles of light, refracted and impinged\nupon the retina in points not the hundredth part of an inch in\nhaunter, should represent to our minds, bodies, one hundred,\nand even ten thousand times larger than our whole bodies, of\nwhich the eye is a small portion? or how do we see objects remote to any distance, even to a fixed star, when the only change\nto us is a few rays in the interior of the eye ?\nHearing, we believe, is simply certain vibrations produced\non the tympanum of the ear by peculiar kinds of undulations\nin tlie external air. From ihe varied nature of these proceed\nall tin- phenomena of sound nnd healing We hear sounds\nnt a distance, notwithstanding tho vibrations of the tympanum\nair effi eti tl immediately by the air in the external ear. We\ncan tell the direction whence sound comes, and yet the undulations of air, from all points', must enter the cur at the soma\nplace: how is it, that certain sensations follow certain vibrations of the tympanum? of joy, melancholy, fear, admiration, or courage? none of ns can tell.\nThe mind is essential to nil sensations, as well as to all the\noperntionsof reasoning. Yetof its nature we know nothing.\nixcept by certain operations attributed to it. Independent of\nilir sensations, which are altered stales of mind, operating\nhrough matter, we know nothing of its essential qualities.\nPhilosophers have speculated and written much respecting\nits various operations, and upon its nature and i ssentinl qualities: hut can tho most proficient in tho science of mind, tell\nus \/\/\u00ab,-'\u2022 ntiiitl ami matter an- so mysteriously united? or what\nare the properties of the mind indi pendi ntlyof the body &gt; f&gt;i\ncan any ono i xplain what changes take place in the ultimate\nfibres by their contact with mind? Tin- mind, as a whole, is\ncapable of operating in opposite modes at tin same time, so\nas to produce fear and hope, or expectation: to will a thing\nand still In- adverse to it: to desire ease whilo ii dreads evil:\nit operati's rationally in part and is irrational in others; istlm\nniiitl divisible; or is ihe change only in the condition of .lie\nlltimate fibres, with which tho mind comes in contact? These\nre only u lew of Ihe mysteries of mind which are entirely\nii-yontl our research.\nAstronomy,\u2014In in\niiiginatiiiii man has travelled through\n10 regions of space; he has visited planets and .suns; counted\nlieir revolutions, measured their magnitudes, and estimated\ni","fullrs":{},"find":"368.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"367","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1842046","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.76 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
