<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 32</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2096</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2096</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2096/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 32","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"32\nOrleans I    With  a railroad penetrating into the heart J\nterritory, almost inexhaustible in its agricultural resourc]\nand capable of being divided intr seven or eight  states,\ncapacious as the Empire Stale of the Union, what might I\nthe Crescent City in a few years become I    We need not co\nceal from ourselves the fact that her comracrce is languish!\nand that less  favored cities are outstripping her in the j\nof commercial enterprise.   Now is Ihe opportune nromer|\nmake a bold movement, to secure to herself the trade of ilfl\nimmense country west of the Mississippi.    She is now \\M\nout a competitor for ihe prize ; aud the stand which she tal\nin this convention, may .fix forever her commercial relation\nwith the opulent empire of the west. Let her launch her b\nboldly on the tide that leads to fortune ; and, in a few year\nshe will rival New York, in wealth, magnificence, and g|\nral prosperity.  The capital that now flows abroad, will ret\u2122\nplenteously to her treasury;  and from being crippled in In\ncommercial operaiions, her pecuniary resources will be I\nlimited.\nBut in advancing this great public improvement, there\na consideration which rises even above our future wealth a|\ncommercial grandeur.    We shall be grappling to ourselii\nwith hooks of steel, an empire in the  southwest, not onl\nidentified with us in trade, but in the protection and prcseri\ntion of that peculiar institution, which was guaranteed ten\nby the constitution.    We shall aid in carving out of tbl\nvast empire, new and powerful states, lo preserve the balanl\nof power between the north and the south.    We shall a\nequalizing the representation in the national  Congress, arl\nrendering ourselves adequate to the preservation of our ga\nrious Union.    And it will hereafter be to us a gratifying n\nflection, that we have done more to strengthen the positio\nof the Southern States, by the peaceable march of our publi\nimprovements, than could be effected in the national eounci","fullrs":{},"find":"2097.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2096","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"526499","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
