<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 15</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/520</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>520</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/520/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 15","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH.WESTERN JOURNAL.\n169\nOptions, a more accurate idea ol the movements of the hu-lthe editor by Mr. Wm. C. Woodbridgc, the wolTknown Z\n\u201ei,n hcnrt, than  we can of the ^movements of nnturc.    A ographei, and dated Paris, Aug. 29, 1829. '\n\" In passing through Bonn, upon the Rhine, I visited Pro-\nlessor Noeggeratti, a distinguished mineralogist of that university. He spoke with great interest of our efforts in reference to mineralogy, and especially of the American Jour-\nnal. He observed to me that, singular as it was, he had received through that Journal iho first account of nn interesting fact in his own neighborhood.\n\" He had heard many years since of a large mass of iron\nlying on one ofthe mountains termed 'the Seven Mountains,'\nin this vicinity, but which was supposed to be a remnant of\nan old furnace. He designed to examine it, but delayed from\ntime to time, and at length heard that a foreign officer had\nbeen there and taken away a large portion, He thought little more of it, until some time after, when ho saw in the\nAmerican Journal of Science, Col. Gibbs' account of his\ndiscovery of a mass of meteoric iron on this very spot. He\nimmediately went to examine the fact: he found that the\nmass had been cut up and put into the forge, but the smiths\nnot having skill to work it, it was again thrown aside, nnd\nay buried under a heap of scoria. Professor N., after some\nsearch, discovered a very large quantity of this iron, and\nverified the existence of nickel, and tho truth of the account\nwhich the American Journal had been the medium of announcing to the world, of one of the largest masses of meteoric iron yet discovered.\"\u2014Silliman's Journal.\n. may read all his life, and form no conception of the\nish of ii mountain-torrent, or the waving of a forest of pines\nin a storm J and a man may study in his closet the heart of\ni:.- fellow-creatures forever, and have no idea of the power\ncf ambition, or the strength of revenge. It is when we have\nuctcd ourselves, and have seen others acting; it is when we\nhave labored ourselves under the influence of our passions,\n:ad have seen others laboring; it is when our great hopes\nhave been attained, or have been balked; it is when, after hav\nlog had the human heart revealed to us, we have the first opportunity to think; it is then, if we can think, that the whole\ntaitli lights upon us; it is then that we ask of ourselves,\nivbether il be wise to endure such anxiety of mind, such agi-\ntation of spirit, such harrowing ofthe soul, to gain whntmay\nrtase to interest to-morrow, or for which, at tho best, a few\nrears of enjoyment can alone be afforded; it is then that we\nwaken to the hollowness of all humnn things; it is then that\nthe savings of sages, and the warnings of prophets, nre explained and understood ; it is then that we gain experience.\nMETEORIC IRON IN TEXAS.\nA gentleman returned from a five years' absence in the\nprovince of Texas, during which time he had been frequently with the Camanche Indians, and a small party of them\nconducted him to a mass of metal lying on the bank of a\ncreek. Its length was four feet, and it was about one foot\nH|tmm [at the end.) It required six of the Indians to raise\nii on end. A piece weighing two ounces was cut off by a\ntomahawk. It possessed great hardness and tenacity, and\nv.'hcn hammered (in the cold) shewed great malleability, be-\ning easily beaten out very thin without cracking or scaling.\nThe color was stated to be between that of gold and silver.\nIts lustre was remarkable, and could not be tarnished by any\nthing that was done to it, oven by the application of heat,\nI'll- large mass of metal seemed to defy every attempt to\nmake an impression on it, except under the hammer, when it\nbecame pliable and soft. From the acquaintance which we\nhave wilh the large mass alluded to above, wo cannot doubt\nthat the piece described in Mr. Cox's letters is nickeliferous\nmeteoric iron Those that saw tho piece were disposed to\nmake it out to be gold, and probably saw a yellow tint quite\nas strongly as it existed, if indeed it existed at all, for the\nmalleable iron which we have from tho same region is like\nthat of Siberia, of a remarkable pure grayish white, with a\nUgh degree of lustre\n\" i' have recently seen a gentleman, who stated that he\nhew of several large pieces of malleable iron in Texas,\nand we hope to obtain some more precise information con-\nc(,rning them.\nMETEORIC IRON IN FRANCE.\nThe late Col. George Gibbs brought to this country some\nfeces of meteoric iron which he detached frpmalarge mass\ntying on the mountains of Auvergne in France, and a notice\n\u00b0&lt; h was published in Dr. Bruce's Journal of Mineralogy,\n&gt;n connexion with one of the Louisiana iron.\nThe following extract is taken from a letter addressed to\nTHE FUTURE CAPITOL OP THE UNION.\nWe climbed the hill, wild with tall grass and shrubs, and\nobtained a view of Cincinnati, which is considered (he com-\npletest. I now perceived that, instead of being shut in between two hills, the city stands on a noble platform, round\nwhich the river turns while the hills rise behind. The platform is perfectly ventilated, and the best proof of this is the\nhealthiness of the city, above all other American cities. A\nphysician who had been seven years a resident told me that\nhe had been very delicate in health before he came, like\nmany others of the inhabitants; and, like many others, he\nhad not had a day's illness since his arrival. Tho average\nof deaths in the cily during the best season was seven per\nweek; and, at the worst time of the year, the mortality was\nless than in any city of its size in the republic. There is\nample room on the platform for a city as large as Philadelphia, without encroaching at all on the hill-sides. The inhabitants are already consulting as to where the capitol shall\nstand whenever the nation shall decree the removal of the\ngeneral government beyond tho mountains. If it were not\nfor tho noble building at Washington, this removal would\nprobably take place soon, perhaps after the opening of the\ngreat Southern railroad. It seems rather absurd to call\nsenators and representatives from Washington to Missouri\nand Louisiana, while there is a place on the great rivers\nwhich would save them half the journey, and suit almost\nevery body else just as well, and many much better. The\nperil to health at Washington in the winter season is great,\nand the mild and equable temperature of Cincinnati is an\nimportant circumstance in tho case.\nI'U\n\u25a0\u25a0$m\nm\nMi\n--.lib\nV\n\u25a0\nt \\\niXtf","fullrs":{},"find":"521.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"520","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1614516","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
