<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/513</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>513</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/513/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"iW^\n\u2022Hi;.\nii i\n'ti y\u2022\n\u25a0P-fE.\n;i&gt;\u00bb:\nI \u25a0;\u25a0\u2022&gt;}\n-:\u25a0\n152\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nis generated, and speedily the malarious district becomes the\ninfected district: which result would have have been prevented by a storm, or change of weather previous to those cases.\nIV. That when the malarious combination is sufficiently\nconcentrated for this purpose, a large quantity of infected\nair, brought from an infected district, or a large number of\ncases of yellow fever introduced from another poirft, will\nconvert that malaria into infected air, and produce an epidem\nic likewise.\nV. That, consequently, although yellow fever is very\noften a disease ol local origin, ii may, under peculiar circu\nstances, be carried from one city to another, and there progu-\ngated.\nVI. That accordingly epidemic yellow fever may be\naverted sometimes by one or all of the following measures,\nenforced at a time, when, according to the principles herein\nsot forth, the malaria is forming rapidly; viz:\n1. By a dispersion of tho greater portion ofthe citizens\nto the country.\n2. By removing from the city, and especially from the\ndistricts usually infected, all strangers, or those who have\nnot become acclimated by a residence of two or three years,\nand who would in course bo the first attacked.\n3. By prohibiting the introduction from foreign places of\ninfected air, or fomitcs, or patients laboring under yellow\nfever, during the prevalence of malarious accumulations.\nVII. That the vicinity of any of the largo bayoux, or\ngullies about Natchez, is more dangerous as a residence than\nmore remote points: that these ravines are the reservoirs in\nwhich the malaria mostly accumulates before it is dispersed\nthrough the city by gentle winds: of course persons should\navoid them in ihe sultry, autumnal months.\nVIII. That this miasm, or even the malaria, is not the result\nof animal or vegetable decomposition; or of exhalations\nfrom city filth and such like sources.\nIX. That tho general atmosphere in the country may be\nas healthy us ordinary, while in the city yellow fever may be\nsweeping off the population like a pestilence: of course,\nthat the disease is the result of some local atmospheric contamination.\nX. That when the infection has spread, or is beginning\nto spread, the only safety for those who arc strangers, or un-\nacciimaled to yellow fever infection, is speedy flight: for no\ndisinfecting agents heretofore known, or tried, possess any\npower to destroy the infection of yellow fever in the general\nair, cold alone excepted.\nXII. Thai those who seek safety in flight, should carry\nwith them as few bulky, light articles, of a woolen or porous\ntexture as practicable, lest they might generate on infected\nnir in their retreat: That they should not return to their\nhouses until after cold winds and frosts, during which their\nrooms, bedding, &amp;c, have been freely exposed to ventilation\nand to the action of the frost.\nSOUTH-WESTERN  JOURNAL,\nNATCHEZ,  APRIL 30,   1838.\nThe Planet Saturn.\u2014The Leipsic Gazette announces\na discovery, made by Dr. Eucke, Professor of Astronomy at\nBerlin, that the planet Saturu has three rings, instead of only\ntwo, as hitherto believed.\nBesanoon's Annual Register of the State or\nMississippi. This valuable annual for 1838, will be issued\nfrom the press during the present week, and will be found worthy the patronage and support of this community, jj Waj\nthe intention of the publisher to have brought out the worlc\nabout two months earlier; but the unavoidable delay, caused\nby tho suspension of business in Natchez, during the three\nmonths of the epidemic, prevented his first innr.lion. Yet\nthat delay has not been without its benefit; it has rendered\nsome of the statistical tables in the Register more peifect, ord\nenabled Mr. Besaucon to present the recent legislative, iudi-\ncial, and county organization, in a better form, than if lie bad\nput his annual to press before the first of January, at which\ntime the resulls of the November election became known.\nIn the next number of the South-Western Journal, we\nshall enter into a more ciitical notice of the contents of tho\nRegister, contenting ourselves, at present, with a single extract :\n\" REMARKABLE RUINS AND TRADITION.\n\"On the eastern shore of Pascagoula Bay, in Jackson\ncounty, State of Mississippi, near its mouth, are the luins of\nan ancient fortification, built, apparently, many centuries oco\nIl appears to have been constructed chiefly of sea-shells.\nWithin this ruin, several feet below the surface, have b\u00abn\nfound charred coals, and fragments of a peculiar kind ol\nearthen ware, together with many human bones. Amongst\nthem were discovered parts of a human skeleton of gigantic\nproportions. The upper part of ihe skull was said lo be sufficiently large to fit loosely over the largest modern heods.\n\" All historical traces of the origin of this fortress have\nlong since disappeared. There is, however, a tradition still\nextant amongst the old French scitleis on the Bay, said lo\nhave been derived from the Indians, who inhabited the coast\non ils first settlement by the French, that this fortification was\nbuilt by a tribe of Indians long since extinct, known as the\nBiluxies. *\nAccording to the legend, this tribe was at war with a more\npowerful neighboring tribe. After many successive defeats,\nthey were driven to tho sea shore, where they built thisfoiti-\nfication; they were closely and vigorously besieged for n\nconsiderable lime, till their suppliis became exhausted, and\nthey were reduced to llic last extremity. Hope having deserted them, they marched into the ocean and perished!\n' In this neighborhood is frequently heard the most extraordinary and strange music. It is heard in the summer months\nonly, and on tho most calm and serene cve'iiings, usually after\nsunset. It is said to bo truly melodious, resembling several\ninstruments in conceit: the most perfect harmony is preserved through its various cadences, though no peculiar notes or\ninstruments are imitated. The sound appears to have no peculiar or limited bounds,\u2014but seems to be transitory,\u2014sometimes appeariug to be in the water,\u2014then immediatelj'\nchanging its position, seems to be transferred to tho atmosphere, approaching and receding nt intervals, sometimes dr-\ning away for some minutes, and then suddenly reviving w\"11\n'   I-,","fullrs":{},"find":"514.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"513","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1854992","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
