<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2172</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2172</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2172/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 12","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"12\nBullitt and P. A. Ross, the Committee to draft aB\nAddress to the public on the subject ofthe Opelousas road\nand to memorialize Congress and the Legislature for tracts\nof land along- the route, and other assistance, in aid of the\nenterprize, as directed by resolutions of the Convention\nadopted yesterday.\nOn motion of Mr. Eichaedson, the Committee took a\nrecess of thirty minutes, to afford opportunity for the dele,\ngations to nominate members of the Permanent Committee\nin the respective Parishes.\nAt the expiration of the half hour, the assembly was\nagain called to order by the President; whereupon the\nfollowing Permanent Committees, nominated by the\nrespective delegations, were, on motion, unanimously\nelected by the Convention :\nPERMANENT   COMMITTEES :\nOrleans\u2014M. M. Cohen, M. 0. H. Norton, Bnckner H. Payne, P. Simra,\nA. Lanfear, Maunsel White, J. W. Stanton, A. Chaipella, A. B. Seger, A\nThayer, J. Hews, K. F. Nichols, L. Bernard, W. P. Converse, P. Siewersseen,\nJ. B. Dolhonde, Thomas A. Adams, Maj. Heisse, Alexander C. Bullitt, A.M-\nBuchanan, George Eustis, P. A. Kost, T. H. Kennedyr, B. F. Flanders, J.Y-\nDeEgana, Edgar Montigut, P. Marsoudet, John L. Lewis, W. A. Gordon\nCol. Seymour, J. H. Maddox, Samuel Bell, Rohcrt Geddes, Dr. II. Kennedy,\nP. Gr. Collins, Emile LaSerc, John Hal], Moses Greenwood, Dr. S. Barby.\nA. R. Hawkins, Wilhelmenus Bogart, Samuel J. Peters, James Rohh, Kandi\nHunt, J. P. Benjamin, H. Wright, L. LeBeau, P. Conrey, A. D. Grossman-\nJefferson\u2014Pierre Sauve, C. G. Forshey, Valmont Soniat, H. E. Lawren*\nD. S. Dewees, S. H. Peck, W. W. Vaught, D. A. Harris, G. AV. Squiers, C-\nT. Buddecke, J.H.Harvey, Silvester Bennett, Fergus Gardere, D. Vl-'-\nBisbee, Gustave Leroy, B. Buisson.\nTerrebonne\u2014I. C. Potts, J. J. Hanna, H. C. Thibodaux, Thibodauxrill'\nPostoffice; E. Hotard, J. C. Navarre, J. Aycock, G. F. Connelly, F. Gag^\nA. Linette, Louis Pitre, A. MeCullum, H. Arcenaux, I. V. Boutelou, J- *\nCaruthers, Houma Postoffice; Michael Knight, Tigerville Postoffice. .\nLafourche Interior\u2014G. S. Guion, A. Collins, A. J. Donaldson, L. Bn*\nE. Murphy, Jonathan C. White, L. Polk, I. S. Williams, F. Webb, J-*1\nTuker, J\u00bb A. Scudday, J. C. Beatty, A. Kees, C. ftaude, 3 l^\nThibodeaux Postoffice","fullrs":{},"find":"2173.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2172","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"643410","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.61 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
