<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/461</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>461</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/461/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH- W E S T E R N  JOURNAL.\n89\nplay, in bold relief, the human character; and ho should be\nadorned with moral courage and freedom, to pronounce, from\nhis exalted station, tho judgment of posterity. Like the great\np.-irtrait painter, who is perfectly skilled in anatomy, he should\nhe able w present men on tho canvass of history, with strict\nregird to thoso lights and shades, which are found in every\nindividual who is distinguished for talent, and placed in an\neminent station. '\n.Mr. Sullivan is always tho friend to religion, and to the\ntrreat principles on which society rests. He could not breathe\na thought which would disturb ils beautiful order, or which\ncould be construed, even by a malignant foe, into an attempt\nto array the poor against tho rich, or the weak against the\nstrong. Not all the merit of Gibbon, great as it is, can atone\nfor his occasional departures from modesty, or for his disin-\n(j.-icuoils attacks on the christian religion. It is but a poor\napology for a scholar, that ho places in a note, or veils in a\nlearned and unspoken language, an offence against purity.\nWe cannot deny to Gibbon, that he has produced an immortal work; but all its splendid merit cannot conceal what we\nregret, for tho honor of his fame, that it is not free from\nfault.\nMr. Sullivan has promised another volume, in which he\nproposes to treat of causes nnd effects among European nations\nami their colonies, during the last three centuries. The diffi\neultyof condensing tho events of this period into so narrow a\ncompass, and, as he approaches our own time, of making a\nwise selection of facts from tho chaos of materials, will, we\ntrust, only give ardor to his courage and strength to his purpose' But even virtue, to succeed, must have an ample field\nfor action; and it is one of the canons of history, that to be\njierlitt, it must be limited to a brief and interesting period,\nthat the writer should rigidly adhere to his plan, and that he\nshould give to it all the dramatic effect of which it is capable.\nMay the laurel be growing, which shall crown the author,\nanil best reward his success.\nT\n1######-\nAN ESSAY.\nTHE BKFECTS   01'  HELHIION   ON   Tim   POLITICAL,   INTELLECTUAL,    MORAL.\nAND SOCIAL   STATE 01' MAN.\nKm.I before tho JeffersonCollcge and Washington I.v\n1837, by IInv. II. M, Iiiiakk.\ni-iiin, Sept. '2,\nThere is, in the government of God, a wise adaptation of\nlaws to subjects. The laws of the physical world are absolute and irresistible, and, from their combined operation, are\nproduced the admirable regularity and harmony seen in the\nuniverse. Were it possible that one of these laws should be\ninfracted, for instance the law of gravitation, into what confusion and discord would the heavens and earth be instantly\nthrown.\nImportant as is the law of gravitation to the order ofthe\nnatural world, it is not more so than are some of the great\ntruths of religion to the moral world: for instance, the knowledge of a Supreme Being, to whom man is accountable.\nThe knowledge of this truth lies at the foundation of all intellectual improvement and social order. Take this from\nman, nnd you remove the strongest motive to intellectual culture and moral restraint.    You blot the sun from the universe,\nand unloese the strongest bonds which unite society. You\nreduce man to a mere floating atom, without aim, or end, or\nmotive. But acquaint man with this leading truth in religion, and you, at once, set before him a high caiccr of glory,\nhonor, and immortality. You supply him with motives to\nmoral and intellectual culture, high as the heaven to which\nhe may aspire, and deep as the ruin to which he may sink.\nThese principles, which appear to me almost with the force\nof intuition, have been disputed by many. It has been contended that religion, in al! its forms, contracts tho mind, dissolves or weakens the bonds of government, dissocializes\nman, and, still more strange, weakens moral obligation. Nor\nhas it been the avowed enemies of religion alone, who have\nthus traduced its influence. Professed friends, nnd even real\nfriends, have been misled by the bold assertions of enemies.\nIt is not uncommon to hear it ns gravely asserted, ns if it had\nbeen a thousand times proved, that religion has been the\ncause of more bloodshed than anything else; Ihat it has\ntrammelled free inquiry, and thus kept the minds of men in\nlarkncss. Hence the revival of letters has been considered\na triumph of free thinking over religion. The moroseness\nand unsociability of the anchorite, have been attributed to its\ninfluence, nnd even duplicity and fraud have been considered\nils legitimate effects.\nI should consider it fin easy task to show that there is in\nreligion, abstractly considered, nothing to produce these consequences. But abstract tendencies are seldom appealed to\non this subject: we arc referred to its fruits, and by this test,\n\"by their fruits ye shall know them,\" we are willing to\nabide.\nBut I would not be understood lo present myself ns the.\napologist or extcnuator of all Ihe crimes which have been\ncommitted under thegarband pretext of religion. Religion,\nas well as patriotism, friendship, aud philanthropy, has been\n1 miller contribution to ambition, avarice, and voluptuousness. But so soon as these nre admitted to be the governing\nmotives, you clear religion of the crimes, to which it is the\nunwilling pretext. I am farther prepared to concede, that\nlonest persons have been so far misled, as to commit crimes\nigainst society for the sake of religion; but even this should\nbo set down to the account of the frailty of our nature, rather\nthan to religion, which has not, abstractly, any tendency to\nproduce such effects.\nAfter all the offsets which lukewarm friends, or malicious\nenemies, can demand, I will still venture to maintain, that,\nupon tho whole, religion is beneficial to the human family. I\nam disposed to think that this is a truth, if applied in the\nmost extended sense ofthe term; but it is my purpose to make\nmy observations especially in reference to the Christian religion. I would, however, make one or two general remarks.\nThe first is, that it is very difficult to find points of comparison : as, on the one hand, it is hard to find any community\nwholly governed by the precepts of religion, so, on the other,\nt is impossible to find a nation without some of its influences.\nAll wc can do, is take the points of greatest divergence. Another remark, which I would make at this place, is, that although heathen religions, the Mohammedan religion, or falsi\nnotions of Christianity, may have in them many things very\nVOfc. J. VI.\n\u2022';\u25a0: i\nM\nm\n,' \"\u2022'\u2022*:\n;\u25a0;\n\u25a0\ni\nI\nI\n!    -tit\nm\nil\n:]\n.1\n'\u2022''\n|","fullrs":{},"find":"462.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"461","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1800366","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
