<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 19</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2216</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2216</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2216/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 19","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[19]\nWe have reason to believe that Texas will look with favor upon this route. It has\n. !v i,een mentioned that a large number of her must populous counties have held\nlef-inns alld passed resolutions in favor of it, and instructed their representatives aceord-\n'Hv We have also reason lo believe that Texas will not permit her territory to be\n\"\"enetrated by a rail-road on the east, south of the 32d degree of latitude, and she will\nlook w\u00bbh indifference upon any project that does not connect her by a direct line with the\nMississippi River. To do this, the road must cross Red River at Shreveport, for there is\nother practicable crossing for more than three hundred miles. A road through the extreme northern portion of Texas, to Little Rock and Memphis, might, indeed, cross the\nriver at Fulton. This road has already been spoken of. It is an important route, and\nwill no doubt, ultimately be built, but it can never compete for the transportation of\ncotton with a road running to Vicksburg. But to return. Tbe information already given in\nthis report, touching the nature ofthe country through which it shall run, shows this road\nto be important to the city of New-Orleans, as opening up to her a new and abundant\nsource, from which she may supply herself with beef, mutton, flour, and other articles\nof liviri\", of a superior quality, at reduced prices, whereby she may greatly cheapen the\nexpenses of living of her citizens, and reduce the price of fare at her hotels and boarding-\nhouses, which will operate to produce a rapid increase of her population, both transient\nind permanent. This road is important to the state of Louisiana, because it will procure\nthe settlement of four millions of acres of her vacant land, and add within a few years\ntwenty millions to the amount of her taxable property. It is important to the federal\ngovernment, because it will save her half a million annually in the cost of transporting\nsupplies to her soldiers on the frontiers of Texas and Mexico. Finally, this road is\ndeemed important to all sections of the country, as forming a part of that great central\ntrunk, which shall belt the continent, and with which all other roads on the continent\nmost connect, to perfect the system.\nC. G. You-jg,\nChairman of tbe Delegation from Northern Louisiana.\nTHE  COMMITTEE TO \"WHOM WAS   REFERRED   THE   QUESTION   OF   A   SYSTEM\nOF RAIL-ROADS FOR ARKANSAS, BEG LEAVE TO REPORT\t\nArkansas, in point of territorial extent, is larger than any southern state\u2014Texas alone\nexcepted\u2014embracing in its limits an area of over 50,000 square miles, or 33,000,000 of acres.\nHer soil is one of unsurpassed fertility; the northern portion of the state, from its climate,\nbemg admirably adapted to the production  of provisions, with the capacity to produce\n^\"k-10 a\" lmlimiCed extent; also embracing a belt of mineral region, rich in anthracite\nwdbituminous coal, lead, zinc, copper, gypsum, manganese, silver and gold\u2014needing only\n^outlet by rail-road to the Mississippi'River, to make it a more profitable mining district than California itself, while the southern part of the state is safer for heavy crops of\ncotton than any other portion of the South. This is established, beyond all question, by\nJ\u2122J8 \u00b0' experience;\u2014further south, the crop has become a precarious one, from casualty\nproduced by the caterpillar, boll worm, grub, or cut worm.   West, there is  not rain\noagli more than one year in four, and in other states of the same parallel east, the soil\n\"exhausted.\nPro Ut Arkansa3&lt; with all that Nature has done for her, is far behind her neighbors in im-\niitt,6mentS' P\u00b0Puhiti\u00b0n, and general prosperity. It is a source of humiliation to your com-\nhea      % m^e t'lese acknowledgments; but the truth  should be  told,  \" though  the\nMood}iCiUlSe \u00b0^ ^k State \u00b0*\" t^n&amp;s' to tne intelligent resident of Arkansas, who has under-\ntnrel i1\\\u00a3enpr,'d state policy, is no mystery. She was admitted into the Union prema-\ns|JPDoM- sne had lhe basis of wealth and population upon which to raise a revenue to\nschem a &amp;tatc government; consequently she was forced to resort to some financial\nthe eTi t0raise the deficit. The State and Real Estate Banks were chartered, and\nthe L'e , m'-nt of' the state placed on $3,500,000 of their bonds ; they both suspended in\n'town ti Craslt of' I837 ; and sillce tlie!1 liave not more than managed to keep the debt\nWhole - tile original amount. This constitutes the state debt of Arkansas, and the\nhQt 2 \"? s.et dc?wn as state liability. The state is undoubtedly liable for the entire debt;\nmortBnfre 1S 3?li a VilluaWe aaseE in the banks, consisting in notes, and in bonds and\nbe afi\\ L-'N \u00b0n hirge tracts of the most valuable lands in the state ; and should these lands\nthat h f y rail-\"*oads, as lands have been   every where else, there is but little doubt\nei\u00bbre the maturity of the bonds in 1882, the debt will be paid by the bank asset.  At","fullrs":{},"find":"2217.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2216","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"619088","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.59 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
