<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/597</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>597</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/597/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:56">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"fit\n51.,..'.-.\nP If\nIP'v\ntil i;( 1\n\u00bb'\u25a0'''\n1\n1\nI?\n;;;;;\n1\n\u2022ii.'   r\nI\nI\nil\n, \u25a0\u2022\u25a0! \u25a0\ni\n1 \u25a0&gt;&gt; \u25a0\n3-\nI:\nSOUTH- WESTER N J0U RN A L\ntimo we may aid in giving a salutary bias to public taste\nFor this purpose we have made a joint stock of our united\nfunds, from the proceeds of which each one of us may draw\nhis proportional dividend. Thus like all other joint-stock nsso-\nciations, our design is to benefit on rselres, and probably to confer some advantages upon those whoso favor wo desire to\nsecure:\u2014-with this exception, that if we fail and prove bankrupt in our enterprise, we wrong none, and the community at\nlargo will not havo to bear the. burden.\nThere is much lo be done in improving the public taste, in\ncorrecting the vitiated habits of the reading multitude, and to\nexcite the latent genius of our south-western states. How\n\u2022liter, do we see young men of talent nnd acquirements, once\nispirants for literary honors and fame, seduced from tho paths\nif literature, and intellectual pursuits, by that grcat demora\nizing principle, tho inordinate desire of wealth, until their\nlovo of learning, and ihe fire of their holy ambition, is for\n,-ver quenched by the chilling flood of avarice? For want\n\u25a0 if some intellectual feast to allure them, or some amusement\nM regale their finer feelings, they yield to the seducing allurements of vice and dissipation, until despair spreads her lurid\nmantle over their ruined prospects:\u2014or, for want of some\nallurement and associates in tho paths of knowledge, the\nmost exalted powers of mind have been prostituted to the\nmost ignoble purposes, and are tied down to the incessant\nstrivings of avarice. It is our object to guard against these\n'liings, and to fortify ourselves and those who may unite with\nus, against these insidious foes, while we cultivate those intellectual enjoyments, which are only excelled by the pure and\n\u25a0\u2022hastening influence of religion.\nThe few hours which may be devoted to our literary exercises occasionally, or to the researches connected therewith,\nire not unprofitably spent; they are not hours misapplied, to\nwhich in subsequent years wo will recur with regret: but\nthey nre hours to which we can look with fond recollection,\nis hours profitably spent in a necessary relaxation from the\nvexations and toils of ordinary business; by which our\nminds are improved, and our hearts bettered. Bet us thcrc-\n\u2022r,re give a portion of our time to the cultivation of our minds,\nand to improvement in literature, arts, and sciences; and we\nshall find it the guardian angel which drives the obtrusive\nmoney-changers out of the temple of tho mind, nnd leaves it\nin possession of every human virtue.\n1: we wish our association to prosper, wo must individually feel an ardent zeal for its prosperity, and our works must\nbe the test of our zeal. Let each member feel that ho is in\nhonor bound to perform the duties assigned him : thnt the\nobligations, under which ho has voluntarily placed himself,\nrequire of him a strict performance of these duties; without\nwhich he cannot acquit himself honorably of his obligations.\nLot each ono be assured, that delinquency in these matters,\nis but the evidence of a tendency to still greater delinquencies in moral obligation, which cannot be too much avoided.\nIf these arc our feelings and our determination, our association will, it must, and with the blessing of Divine Providence,\nit cannot fail to prosper.\n1 ientlemen, nothing shall be wanting on my part, to ct-;vi..\ncharqeter and dignity to our institution, so far as my feeble\nabilities can eflect that object: but I ask your aid, and your\nzealous co-operation, to accomplish this desirable end. With-\nout this our association cannot prosper, or bo productive of\nsuch advantages lo us individually as we all must desire\nThe obligations imposed by our association is a salutary\nstimulus to industry and exertion in tho extension of our researches, and in the acquisition of knowledge: a stimulus\nwhich all require, otherwise they will settle down into indu-\nlencc in their literary exercises and acquirements; and instead of advancing in ihe paths of science and literature, thev\nwill retrograde, and lose not only the acquisitions whicii\nthey have made in their earlier scholastic years, but will\neven lose their taste for intellectual pursuits and forfeit all\nclaims to their former well merited literary and scientific\nhonors.\nREVIEW.\nVegetable Diet; nee snilctlollcil by medical men, anil by G-xpcrloncQ ill all Bgci,\nBy Willi.iii, A. Alcou.  pp. 970.   Boston | starch. Capon te J.yon,  1803.\nThat life may sometimes bo prolonged, and health promoted, by confinement to vegetable diet, probably no man of\nreflection will question. But that total abstinence from animal food is in all cases demanded by the laws of our physical nature, is more than any man of sound mind will contend\nfor. Animals were created, and given to man for food as well\nas for other uses, by Him who made man ; and they may be\nso used, under tho direction of an enlightened judgment, nut\nonly with impunity, but with positive benefit. It is sheer\nfanaticism that proscribes a whole class of heaven's bounties\nto the whole race of man, on the ground that lo some consli-\ntutions, and to some individuals positively diseased, they arc\nnoxious. A mixed diet is called for by nature when healthy;\nand none of llioso articles of food which appetite selects, arc\nworthy to be condemned, however censurable may be an immoderate indulgence in the use of them. Indeed wc are\nled to this conclusion by a cursory examination ofthe volume\nnow before us; although the evident design of it is to press\nthe paramount claims of vegetable over animal food. Tho\nopinions of scientific and practical physicians, scattered over\nthe land, and the experience of distinguished men in the various departments of life, are worthy of great respect ainl\nconfidence', on every subject pertaining to the health of tin-\nbody and the mind. And here they arc collected and duly\narrayed, and commented on with great skill; but, after all,\nmen will eat flesh, as the patriarchs and the prophets anil\nthe apostles did, \"asking no questions for conscience sake,\nand were fully justified to their own consciences in eating\nwhatever is set before them. It is neither possible nor desirable to change tho \"course of the world,\" in regard to the\nnature of their food, but the physiologist renders an important service to mankind, when he unites with the theologian\nin pressing the duty of moderation; and when he exposes errors in tho prevailing modes of preparing food, and the indulgence of appetite : and urges on man the duty, whether\nthey cat or drink, or whatever they do, to do all to the glory\nof (Jod.\u2014Boston Recorder.\nA secret can -only be safely kept by a single person, not by\ntwo; what three men know, is no longer a secret.","fullrs":{},"find":"598.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"597","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1768954","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
