<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 07</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/546</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>546</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/546/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 07","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n,lcr being in the affirmative, my shivering applicant for ad\nmission, conjured mc in \" God's name\" to get up, and speed\nmy way to Thornhcdge Lodge, where I was expected anxiously by Col. Perryan, whom he had left a half an hour\nprevious, in despair of his daughter's life. Confused and\nhalf asleep, I hurried on my clothes; my vest inside out, my\npantaloons reefed above my boots, and with my cap wrong-\nside-before, I mounted the messenger's horse, having previously strapped on my portmanteau, and at full speed wound\nmy way to the Lodge, three miles distant.\nI met the Colonel nt the hall door, who greeted me with\u2014\n\"glad to see you, Doctor,\" and with a countenance that illy\naccorded with his salutation, ho \" begged me to walk in, and\nas soon ns possible to repair wilh him to his daughter's apartment. Upon coming to the light, for the. first lime I noliced\nthe ridiculous figure I cut, owing to tho hurry of dress, and\nwith a remark upon the \" extreme coldness of the weather,'\nbefore the Colonel turned round, I buttoned my overcoat\nf|'iite to the stock. Having reached the centre of the room,\nand thinking it time to uncover, in the midst of a speech of\ncondolence', which I intended to finish with a bow, I made\nthree successive efforts to find the visor of my cap, but without eflect, and like a country urchin who enters a school\nroom for the first time in his life, I grasped it by the crown,\nhauling it down over my face, when the Colonel's gaze of\nastonishment at my silly appearance, disconcerted my speech,\nand 1 stammered out the remainder with a bow so low thai\nmy boots met my eye one red-top the other white, and gap-\nin? about my left leg so widely that I could not get my pan\nlaloons over-it, In the fulness of mortification, I perceived\nI had drawn on one of my room-mate's boots, and with what\nI intended for a smile, grinned out hurry as an apology for\nnot having paid some attention to my toilette. The Colonel\nsmiled me into self-complacency, and the effort appeared so\ngreat in his then slate of mind, that I forgot my laughable\nentree', and anxiously requested him to show me to Miss\nClara's room.\n0 Frank ! thank your stars for not having embraced my\nprofession, unless wilh the feelings of Zeno, you could witness the heart-rending scenes to which a physician is often\nsubjected.    They have caused mo many times to regret that\nI ever opened a volume which  treated upon the science of\nmedicine, and I assure the feeling was never feigned.    Bul\nthe subjoined case  will give you some idea of the melancholy task which   sometimes unavoidably kills to the lot of\nour profession.    With my portmanteau in  one hand, I fol\nlowed Col, Perryan across the hall; he opened the door op\nposke, and having both  entered, a single sweep of the eye\n'old me that I was indeed in the abode of grief, while from\nevery quarter of the partially lighted room, there came the\n(instilled wail of heart-rending sympathy for the fair sufferer\nWho lay in the other corner of the apartment, the subject of\nhysteria.    At the moment I entered, for the first time in my\n'jfei 1 realized the deep responsibility attached to the practitioner of medicine, for 1 had no sooner lisped forth a gener-\n\u25a01 salutation, when with a simultaneous movement, the mem-\n*\u00ab of the family crowded around me, and with tears and the\n\"lost feeling supplications,  implored me not to  leave the\nLodge till I had arrested the terrifying paroxysms. With\nthe assurance that I would exert every effort in my power to\nrelieve Miss Clara, \"I entreated them to be calm, as I thought\nher illness was more frightful than dangerous.\"\nAllow me, Frank, to introduce you to a portraiture of my\npatient when enjoying perfect health, and under circumstances when intellectual superiority alone could have empowered her with the electrifying influence she exercised over a\nliterary cotery, of which I was an honorary member. Three\nmonths previous, Clara Perryan was the centre of attraction\nat an assembly of this chosen circle which met in the evening at Professor A's residence, where, prior to having mixed\nwith the group, I had an opportunity, unobserved, to admire\nthe fair creature in all her loveliness. Fashionably attired,\nher rounded form did not lose its symmetry, anel seated upon\na piano stool, her person from temple to girdle, rose above\nthe rest, as if her apparent superiority received the tacit acknowledgment of those around her. Her eye, which seemed the \" throne of expression,\" sparkled an assent to the\nrhapsody which George Herbert was at that moment pouring forth in his usually happy strain, upon the influence of\nmusic on the feelings, regretting at the same time \"that ho\nwas insensible to ils charms.\"\n\" You are at home on the delightful effects of music, Mr.\nHerbert,\" observed Clara, \"anel if I did not run the risk of\nbeing charged with flattery, I would add, that you are no ordinary master of that accomplishment upon more instruments\nthan the one behind mc ;\" pointing to the piano as she spoke.\n\" Indeed ! Miss Clara,\" rejoined he, \" while I appreciate\nyour compliment, allow mc to observe, that I am extremely\ncareful not to jar the nerves of my friends after you have entertained them on that instrument, nnd believe me, my execution upon others, will not allow me to be perfect on any.\"\n\" I was not angling for fulsome praise, modest Oeordic,\"\nreplied Clara, and the blush on her cheek (which seemed a\nglowing emblem of the vestal deity thai throbbed within her\nbosom) had  not yet taken  flight, when with animation she\ncontinued, \" your illustration, Mr. Herbert, struck me so forcibly that I could not but think, that you were either not a\nStranger to the pages of a certain legend which tell us how\nthe enthralling strains of \"AnnotLylo\" subdued the outbreak\nof feeling so often engendered in the bosom of Ihe morose\nAllan McAuley, or that your boasled stoicism had yielded\nto the melting  influence of a love-dilty, perhaps  from the\ncoral lips of some pretty inamorata.    No, Geordie, I spoke\nmy honest conviction of your skill, and your observations\nupon the sympathetic alliance between music and our feelings accorded so truly with what I experienced but yesternight when the operatic company honored our residence with\na serenade, that I would have assented to your doctrines with\nmy prettiest courtesy, but that your effort to plaister me with\na little crude adulation, face-to-faco, precluded the possibility.\"\n' However,\" added Clara, \" we will not quarrel about this\nnatter, and if you will promise never again to make such a\ndrive at my vanity in this circle, I will make you a present\nas publicly as you make the promise.\"\nHerbert, who had been writhing with a clouded brow under this playful bilterism, again looked at case when she con-","fullrs":{},"find":"547.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"546","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1751276","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
