<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 29</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2093</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2093</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2093/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 29","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"29\nled. it is but reasonable to suppose that it will constitute the\nprincipal line of travel to that growing state. And this tide\n0f emigration, as it annually pours through our borders, will\nmaterially aid in swelling the profits of the road, developing\nthe resources of the country, stimulating its enterprise, and\npeopling its solitudes, with a busy, thriving, industrious and\nenterprising population.\nBut as I have already said, it is not my intention to discuss\nthe general advantages of the road. This has already been\ndone by abler men. And if am not mistaken in the signs\n'now before me, in this enthusiastic meeting, and in this numerous concourse of people, there exists no difference of\nopinion on this subject. But we have met to confer freely\nas to what may be done to accomplish our object, and to ascertain how far the city will co-operate with the country, in\nthe great enterprise, which is to develop the resources of the\none, and add to the commerce and the opulence of the other.\nWe of the country, are impatient to open for ourselves, a\nrailroad communication with the market for our produce.\u2014\nWe have had other projects in view, which we thought suited\nour purposes : bat which were of far less importance than\nthe one which has called us together. We were ripe to build\na railroad to Berwick's Bay, as suggested by Gov. Mouton ;\nor, in the event of receiving no support from our neighbors, we\nof St. Landry, felt ourselves prepared, and feel ourselves yet\nprepared, to open a railroad communication with Morganza.\non the Mississippi river. We have abandoned these schemes\nfor the present, and hope and believe that the success of our\nnew undertaking, will compel us to abandon them forever.\u2014\na he direct road to New Orleans, we prefer to all others. We\nbelieve it to be a work of great public importance ; and feel a\nSHOW of state pride, while looking forward to the day, when we\nsnail be able to point to it, as the first great monument of the\npublic enterprise of Louisiana. Our friends of New Orleans,\nWhile we entertain these views, will, we trust, appreciate our","fullrs":{},"find":"2094.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2093","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"512714","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
