<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 25</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2222</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2222</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2222/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 25","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[25]\nnd at Montgomery will connect with the  rail-roads running east through Ala-\nrtltea' rteor'na, uud South Carolina.    It will pass  in the  state of Mississippi entirely\n'*lD0'l ihe\u00b0coi\"ntics of Rankin, Scott, Newton, and Lauderdale; and in Alabama, before\n^U(!i\\3 Selma, one of the termini of the Alabama and Tennessee River Rail-road, it\nli Sumter, Marengo, Perry, and Dallas counties.    Nearly all these, and\nlemmas counties, both north and south, now haul in wagons their cotton and\nthence to Mo-\nannually about\n\"      -nnrilTUOUS  COUUUUB,    UUM1   ui\"'\"   \"\"i-i   uuumi,   nun   imui   m   waguiiD    men   v;ulluii  auu\nof export to the Tombigbee and Alabama Rivers, and ship thence to Monties of Sumter, Marengo, Green, Perry, and Dallas, produce annually about\nvi 000 bales of cotton, all of which now goes to Mobile, but much of which will probably\n'     j \u00ab, j&gt;jew-Orleans by means of this road.    In fact, nearly all the products of East\nujMJasippi and Western Alabama, and their supplies for that region of country, will pro-\nhlblv find their way on this road, and the branch extending through tbe north-eastern part\n,r, The southern route then will become tbe great thoroughfare of northern\nrodeastern travel. It will develop the mineral resources of North Alabama. Its rich\nmd inexhaustible mines of iron are now worked in spite of the difficulties of getting to a\nmarket; and it will create and open a way to trade, the vast extent of which cannot be\nmo highly estimated. We think it within bounds to assert, that 200,000 bales of cotton\nwill come over this road, and the branch extending through the north-eastern portion of\nHasissippi to New-Orleans, not one bale of which now ever reaches it. Detailed esti-\nBBtes, made by an engineer who has surveyed the route from Brandon' to the Alabama\nline, ofthe amount required for the completion of the road that far, are in our possession,\nrod may be set down in round numbers at one million of dollars. If New-Orleans were to\nj.- cost of building tho road that far, it would return to her in the increase of\ntrade alone, without estimating the other advantages, a handsome profit upon the investment. But there arc inducements to render the stock of this road valuable, that are not\npresented to any other rail-road iu the United States. From Jackson to Brandon\u2014fourteen nules and a-half\u2014- the road is completed and in profitable operation. These fourteen\nrod a-half miles, with tho ears, locomotives, fixtures, depots, town lots, &amp;c. attached to the\nroad; sixty choice and picked negroes; the two per cent, fund now on hand, being about\n112,000, and that which may hereafter be received, now the property of the State of Mississippi, and valued on a careful estimate by the President ofthe Southern Rail-road, including the grading east of Brandon, at \u00a9378,000, are all offered by a recent act of the\nlegislature, as a bonus for the organization of this company, and the completion of the road\ntone Alabama line in six years. This act was passed in 1850, and provides that the\nwhole property shall come into possession ofthe company so soon as twenty miles of the\nwad beyond Brandon shall be finished. To organize the company requires a subscription\n\u00ab (500,000 of stock, with a cash payment of 1.50,000, immediately upon which the company becomes the owner of nearly half a miliou of valuable and active property. This\nitatetnent shows of itself a conclusive inducement to take stock in this road, and'renders\n\u00ab absolutely certain that it will be valuable.\"\nIonr undersigned fully concurs in the opinion expressed in the foregoing report, that\nWis of incalculable importance to New-Orleans.    By it, so soon as the Jackson and\n\u25a0\u00abw-Orleans Rail-road is completed, an inland highway of commerce and travel is at\neffected between New-Orleans and the whole of the south-eastern portion of the\nin aTk ' ^ *r' 'm immediate junction is effected with tbe great system of rail-roads\n!orgia, and South Carolina. By this road, in connection with the Selma,\n\u00bb\"wassee, and South Valley rail-roads, New-Orleans will find her most direct and\nT^ route to the whole of the'north-eastern and eastern portion of the Republic. By\nOtlenn hCClT 'S n?ade witl1 tlle Nasb\"h\u00ab and Chattanooga Rail-road, and thus will Newark RjLre Pjaced in immediate contact with Louisville, Cincinnati, and the lakes. Your\n4jt a W1 \u2122es not deem it necessary to add more upon this subject, than simply to say,\nijppj an\u00a5c, Porti|'n of the stock in this road has already been taken by citizens of Missis-\nthrou\u201ev   :.    a httle assistance from New-Orleans will, in a short time, place the work,\nIn refe \"5 wliole )ength, iu process of construction.\n'Me, if a\"6\"^ to tlle New-Orleans and Nashville road, the undersigned can add but\nl*entjve\/ 7V&gt;' to w'lat has already been said or written in its favor. For nearly\n^nnedi-T \u25a0 road llas beei1 t!ie kvored project of New-Orleans, Nashville, and the\n^isiana*1 T ^oints- -^ has enlisted to its support the talent and ability of the states of\ntei\"ioii tiie le.ssee&gt; antl Mississippi. But its advocates might now find in this Con-\n^e&lt;eat3 'iaost''orci'Jlsand'i'ts?i&amp; areumentin its favor that could possibly be presented.\n*e How v-J rePilred for the delegates from Nasliville, Cincinnati, Pittsburg, aud St. Louis,\n**\u00b0iion. \u2022V]X't' ^ey speak in mute eloquence to the reason and judgment of this Con-\n4 *4\"iiii2 wf^ Seem co^ an(* cheerless, like the icy chains that bold back their occupants.\n'&lt;?''[\u25a0:;.,7 vlll3Peris beard from them to this city, and they tell her that the greatest\n*^\u00b0 'he Wj eyclal emPoriurn of the New World may well fear for her future dee-tiny,\n^\"j rind n 3 'rost or l^e summer's drought can bar her from die sources of her\nr^ftance of T-1\"' New-Orleans has listened to ibis warning, and she is seosiblc of the\nS^*6 ^d t re W\"rlt- Tllia toad would bring to this city, for the present, more com-\nK^tes n       r tlla\" aTiy otber branch of her contemplated   system of railways.    It\ntCo\u00abHmer     \"!\u25a0       mast extensive, rich, and fertile portions of the State of Mississippi.\nce of the Tombigbee valley, along which this road will run for a considerable","fullrs":{},"find":"2223.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2222","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"566478","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
