<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Great Southern Lumber Company Collection, 1924-1938</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-sc-gsl</identifier>
  <name type="corporate" displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
    <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">The Great Southern Lumber Company was chartered in Pennsylvania in 1902.  It purchased land and erected a sawmill for the cutting of pine timber in Washington Parish, Louisiana, at the future site of the town Bogalusa.  The collection contains photographs of buildings, machinery, and operations of the Great Southern Lumber Company Sawmill and its subsidiary, the Bogalusa Paper Company.  Photographs depict reforestation, tung oil groves at Isabel, Louisiana, the pine tree nursery, stands of slash and long-leaf pine, "turpentined" trees, and the Bogue Chitto stock farm.</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">The Great Southern Lumber Company purchased land and erected a sawmill for the cutting of pine timber in Washington Parish, Louisiana, at the future site of the town Bogalusa.  The collection contains photographs of buildings, machinery, and operations of the Great Southern Lumber Company Sawmill and its subsidiary, the Bogalusa Paper Company.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordCreationDate>2021-06-09</recordCreationDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>