<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/347</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>347</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/347/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:02">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"JL\u00b0 UT il' W K s T E il N JOUK N A L.\n131\n. ril: fur he hath triumphed gloriously. The horse and\nI:, fidel' hath he thrown into the sea.\" Then Miriam, the\nroLihctess, took a timbrel in her hand : and all the women\n\u2022,nt out with timbrels and with dances, and responded, with\nthrilling accents, \"Sing ye to the Lord ; for he hath triumph\n,.| rrloriously. The horse and his rider hath he thrown into\nthe sea.\"\nFor the same reason, do doubt, was it, that some of the\ndoctrines of 'h\u00ab Jewish faith were taught in poetry. The\nsong of Solomon and the Psalms of David contain much of\ndie Christian religion. The same truths, related in prose,\nwould make not hall so deep an impression as they do in\nlb,- sublime odes of the monarch bard.\nThe character of the ancient dwellers in Judea, was similar to the character of their poetry, simple in structure and\nraits, hut grand and noble in its subject, and possessing a lofty\nmorality.     The service of the temple at the daily sacrifice's,\nanil the great feasts, and the noble poetry of the psalms, sung\nby a thousand voices, swelling in rich thunder on the morn-\niiin- breeze, and melting in waning majesty on the evening's\near, tended greatly to elevate and solemnize the minds of an\nenthusiastic people.     The love of the temple and their pecu\nliar rites, was the last feeling which clung to the Jewish heart\nwhen God, in his wrath, gave them up to hardness of heart\nan I their numerous crimes deluged the devoted streets of Je\nriisalcm with blood.    And never was there a more tremendous outbreaking of bitter anguish, than when the last victim\nwas slain upon the altar of the Most High, and the solemn\nservices of the temple ceased.*\nThe sacred poems seem designed by the God of Israel to\nanswer a great end.    The descendants of Abraham were a\npeculiar people; and  their  peculiarities  were   induced   as\nmuch by prophecy, as the institutions of Moses; and almost\nall their prophets wrote in  poetry.    Jehovah spoke by them\nin the noblest language.  All descriptions of that great Being,\n\"who maketh darkness his pavilion, and thick clouds of the\nsky;\" most of the sublime doctrines of the atonement, and\nregeneration of the world by the promised Messiah, are poured out in loftiest strains of majestic verse.    Isaiah, and  Ha-\nbakkuk, and Jeremiah, and David, contain thoughts too great\nlor mortal grasp, too mighty for utterance; and while we\nlean over the sacred page, we can but weep, and pray, and\ntremble.    Not only is  it among the ancients that poetry has\nexerted so great an  influence.    The moderns arc equally\nsubject to its control.     The great poems of a language give\ncharacter,  in  some  degree,  to those  who speak  it.     The\nI''reach, though a highly polished people,  must ever be destitute of superior epics; the genius of the language forbids,\nlo the refined and tasteful, they excel; but in the awful grandeur and majesty of epic poetry, they must ever be behind\nl\u2122 English.    Their national character is of the same type;\n\"ght, gay, and sprightly, forever changing, yet always generous, brave, and enthusiastic.\nPerhaps in no language on earth, not even excepting the\nweek, has epic and dramatic poetry reached the same cleva-\n110,1 \"lat it has in English.    The Greek may claim pre-emi\nnence in refinement and polish of diction ; but in moral majesty, it must yield the palm. There is a stern grandeur a\ngothtc magnificence, which is equalled only by inspired poets\nof the scriptures. I\u201e these characteristic excellencies, our\nMilton is second to none. His Paradise Lost elevates the\nmind to an eminence far above all sublunary things. Whether he leads you through the crystal fields of paradise, in the\nwinged chariot, instinct with life, to the mount of presence,\nwhere resides the Ancient of Days, who, \u00bb in the majesty of\ndarkness, round circles his throne, his glory unobscured \u2022\" or,\non the untiring wing of the Archangel, \"where utter'nothing dwells,\" the same mightiness of intellect and perfection\nof harmony appears. An imagination unaccustomed to dar-\ning flights, shrinks into itself, and trembles at the vast, the\ndeep, the gloomy, and the terribly sublime conceptions.\nDoes he lead you to the perennial fountains, and ever-ver-\nlant plains of bliss?\n' Heaven opens wide :\nHer everduring gates harmonious sound,\nOn golden hinges turning,\"\nto receive the welcome visitant,\nmansions of Despair?\nDocs he lead you to the\n\" On a sudden open fly,\nWilli impetuous recoil, and jarring sound,\nThe infernal doors,and on their hinges grate\nHarsh thunder.\"\n\"'.i\"' Batttthlol,\nBeings, not the offspring of a diseased mind, hideous, deformed, satyr-like, meet your gaze; beings who have not lost all\nf their \"original brightness, whose expansive forms and\nnoble countenances, show proud intellect, blasted by sin,\n\"great, though in ruins, horribly illustrious: \" as you urge\nwith fevered haste, your way \"through the palpable obscure,\"\nthe vivid lightnings \"blaze sulphureous,\" the thunders crash,\nand globes of iron hail, glowing with the terrors of Omnipotence, fall, with fearful weight, on objects of eternal wrath.\nTrembling, you seek the upper light.\nFew can read Milton, and not be deeply impressed with\nthe fearful consequences of crime, and the beauty of virtue.\n[ really do believe, that no one can read Milton's Paradise\nLost, without receiving lessons which he can never forget.\nNay, he who can pass through that work, and not stop to\nponder on the sense, and even pray, must have more stoicism\nthan commonly falls to the lot of man. The moral and reli-\nious influence of such poems, must be powerful. One fact\n\u25a0ill suffice. Nothing is more common than the quotation of\nthis poet by enthusiastic Christians So universally diffused\nare his thoughts on religious subjects, that they arc confounded with revelation. And not unfrequently the eloquent\npreacher draws as largely from this fountain of sublimity as\nfrom the Bible itself.\nCowper, as a religious poet, stands next to Milton. In\nreading the works of the latter, we do not think of the poor,\nold, blind man; but, in the works of the former, we become\n.ill acquainted with the author. A man of excellent heart\nd great genius, but one who shows his weakness in every\npage. His fastidious love of trifles may sometimes raise a.\nsmile, but his genius will command respect, and his plaintive\nstrains, lamenting over the woes, mid sins, and follies of man,\n'Hi\n\u25a0' '.-&lt;.\u25a0.!\n:.\u2666 f:\niv*\nml\n\u25a0vMlii\n\\v\nII\n:,\n\u25a0*--\"--**\"L*","fullrs":{},"find":"348.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"347","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1737073","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
