<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 3</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/364</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>364</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/364/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 3","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"vivw***,;\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\nBut it is not to the narrow limits of our association alone,\nthat these beneficial influences are to be circumscribed.\u2014\nThey will be diffused throughout the community, to an indefinite extent.    We nre virtually engaging the attention, and\nmerits strictly compared. Prescription, whether in politics\nor morals, is no longer admitted a legal right. Changes of\nvarious kinds are continually being made, and it must depend\non general intelligence, whether they arc judicious or injuri-\neliciting the united energies of society; we arc drawing on the oils: whether innovation bo not mistaken for improvement, and\nfund of thought accumulated in the minds of all thinking men.\nAs the fall of a body into still water produces circular pulsations which continually widen until they are lost in the distance, so the intellectual impulses given here, may arouse nnd\nquicken the public mind in a manner that can be confined by\nno boundaries. These anticipations are not to be esteemed\nvisionary or even extravagant.    Facts and experience support\ninstitutions truly valuable be not exchanged for crude and undigested substitutes, which lead to consequences more deleterious\nthan those intended to be avoided. Especially is it necessary\nunder such a government as ours, that premature action be\nguarded against. All acquainted with the legal history of\nthe different states, will assent to the proposition, that innovation is not always improvement.    Hatml to the mother coini-\ntlicm.    The learning of Pluto was not limited to those only try produced a spirit of ruthless persecution, that strove to lev\nwho daily visited tho groves of the Academy; nor did the doctrines of Zcno influence those only who assembled with him\nat the Porch. Their wisdom flowed by a thousand channels,\nthrough all the nullifications of society in Greece and Italy.\nAnd even where ihe names of Plato and Socrates, of Zeno and\nPolemo, were never heard, their philosophy wielded a salil-\ntary sway. Nay, even now, Ihe remains of these eminent\nmen still command respect and admiration. The schools of\nGreece and Italy were essentially of the same character as\nsuch associations as this. Then, men of learning assembled\nto receive instruction from some sage; now, we, aggregating\nour stock of knowledge, form a fund, which, without deserving\nthe imputation of arrogance, we may think equal lo theirs.\nThen, Philosophers collected materials, ami having formed a\nsystem, taught lo their disciples their dogmas : now, we co.\"\nwith the dust the whole of that venerable fabric of antiquity,\nthe common law. Legislators who but imperfectly understood that system, and perhaps never studied any other, by\nvirtue of invention alone gravely attempted to make a code entirely new, or amend the old in such a way as to remove every objectionable feature. Numerous changes were accordingly made, hut few improvements. And it is a fact we'll\nknown to every lawyer, that most departures from the principles of the common law have been real and grievous injuries.\nThe acts of amendment or substitution, have been corrected\nimproved and altered ; and it has been admitted, that the nearer\nthe spirit and even the antiquated phraseology of the old law\nhave been approached, the nearer have justice and the end proposed been approximated. Oftentimes, after various attempts to\nre-model and simplify, even iis grotesque, though venerable\nled, arrange mid leach them to each other.    Then, ideas were fictions have been revived, and occupy their former  post.\nU) he origin.Hi d by the instructor; now, we have hut to reach\nforth and appropriate what the wisdom, observation and labor\nWhere all power resides in the people, if that people he ignorant, power will be  abused.    Anarchy and  confusion  will\nof ages have accumulated for us.    True, we cannot hopo to triumph over government and order, and freedom will (legem;-\nread on our lists-, the names of such men as Aristotle, Zono- rato into licentiousness,\nphon or Pythagoras, hut, in addition lo their systems we have\nthe works of Bacon Locke, of Newton, Laplace, Lnvoiser,\nJ'he only safeguard against improvident change, is an extensive diffusion of useful knowledge.    Knowledge and vir-\nII ivy an-I others; compared with whose scientific researches,|tue are not necessarily concomitant, but they mutually assist\nthe philosophy of (Ireece is us the wild dream ol the truant ieach oilier. The moral worthof every iinlion is found in ihe\nschool-boy. Destitute of tin-same individual talent, our sue-'middle class of society, nnd it should be a desiderated point to\ncess may not be so brilliant, but it will be tho same in kind, ill ''*&lt;&lt; '\"\u2022 intelligence to them also. A king of Persia once en-\nriot in donee. quired of a (ireek in his court, if it were not wiser, in order\nTin- wonderful power of companies in commercial under- t\u00b0 lll'^'t the &lt; Irecian armies, to bribe the officers. No, said\ntakings, has long been known. Bill m v, r before tin- last t\"\u00b0 proud Greek, you cunnntelo it; for every private soldier i&gt;\ntwenty years, hi-uh - application of this principle been so gen-la general and can lead an army better than your majesty. Lei\nera! nnd so successful.    Political reforms nre hastened, benev-\neilent objects are promoted, moral reformation is wrought, science is cherished and improved, knowledge is diffused; in\nshort, the whole world is being revolutionized by societies\u2014\nby the united capacity, wealth and influenco of many.\nThe general utility of such associations, is inducement\nenough to urge their formation. But at the present time their\nclaims an- of a peculiar nature. This has been called tho age\nof improvement: It may with as much propriety be termed\nthe age ofli-ee enquiry, Tho human mind seems to have received a new impulse. Advancement in physical and moral\nscience, has produced corresponding changes in \"modes of\nthinking,\" Institutions which have for ages been honored\nand revered ;i3 sacred; aro now   unceremoniously called in\nLa. question; their claims investigated, and their merits and de-\n051\nit he said with equal truth, that every American mechanic\nor farmer isa man of intelligence, and America will he more\ninvincible than was Greece\nThat reign of terror, which fettered the mind at the same\ntime with the body\u2014which forbade men to think\u2014is past.\u2014\nThat system of religion whichbinds the conscience and mak&lt; s\nthe judgement subservient to the dictation of a crafty priesl, is\nfast yielding to the benign influence of the Gospel. Men will\nthink and examine, destroy and build up, as they please. Their\ndecisions will he right, in the direct proportion of their information. Hence there can be no way in which a man can\nbetter promote the interests of his country than by advancing\nIhe cause of education. The soldier, who bravely repels from\nhis native soil the foes that invade it, follows the imjiulso of a\ngenerous nature:   The statesman, who by his wisdom averts","fullrs":{},"find":"365.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"364","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1493157","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.42 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
