<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/388</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>388</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/388/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 10","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"21\nS 0 II Til- W E STERN   JOURNAL.\nI\n-\npiranl upon his own impotent resources. This will ever be\na delicate and difficult task, but ihe press, sustained by intelli\ngent citizens, is equal to it.\nMuch of the power of a newspaper over public opinion\nsprings from the fact that it is the expression of a mass ; ii\ndeclares a common sentiment; it is the organ of a party. lis\ncommendation or its censure, coining as it were from hundreds\nand thousands, is influential and effective. A correspondent\n(il'.i paper in this city, the present week, describes this influence\nin language we can belter borrow than imitate.\nUp Says :\u2014\" When the censure of the press, echoed from\npaper to paper, as thunder from hill to hill, is taken up ami\nresponded lo by the great mass ofthe people, thus becoming\nthe denunciator*-' \" voice of God himself.\" then indeed, is iis\ninfluence potent and irresistible !\nThe stale argument used by the unthinking against die press\non account of its licentiousness, as i, is called, falls in the\nground from this consideration : Sctirilily always finds lis\nlevel without injury to the character against which it is direct-\noil j while a close, searching, constant investigation must be\nmade into the character, ability, principles, acts, merits and demerits ol all men in public life, or who aspire lo stations in the\ngift of their fellow citizens.    They tacitly consent to pass the\nlierv ordeal when they limit themselves to run Ihe gauntlet\nfor public favor, and they should never wince or complain\nshould the shower, tho hail-stones and ihe scorpions fall thicker\nand faster, and stint; die deeper ! For this llley listed, and a\nfaithful discharge of die stern duly ofthe censorship uf public\nmen is one of the holiest prerogatives of the Press ol Freedom !\nNo patriot who loves the Republic more than he desires his\nown success, will complain of die open-mouthed, undisguised\nexpression of private opinion upon public men and public measures. The Constitution ofthe United Stales guarantees this\nsacred right to iho Press ; and when that press shall cease to\nwield it, il shall have heootne a traitor 10 ''oar country's cause.\"\nThe average amount of talent, engaged in conducting tho\nAmerican press, is, probably, unsurpassed in any civilized nation, although there are individual newspapers, both in England and France, where there is high talent engaged, and a\nmore rigid and systematic division of labor adopted in the\nvarious departments. For instance, no American nowspaper\npress is able to sustain such a number of literary attaches ns\nthe London Times, which has a daily circulation of 11,000\ncopies. It has 3 editors, 12 regular reporters, 3 proof and\nnews readers, 2 publishers, news collectors, foreign corres-\npendents and agents, besides a cashier, 3 clerks, 50 compositors, 12 attendants on ihe machinery. The London Morning\nHerald is scarcely less expensive and ample in ils establishment; whilethe leading Parisian journals have each from two\nin live editors, generally gentlemen as much distinguished\nfor their high birth as for their literary and political attain:\nincuts.\nIt is said that there are more gentlemen of liberal cduca-\n\u25a0lion connected with iho political and news-press in the United\nStates than in the whole of Europe. To arrive at this conclusion, it should bo recollected that, the newspaper press of\nthis country is generally under the conduct of a single editor,\nwhose mind alone must grasp, study, digest and herald forth\nnews, morals, science, literature and polities; therefore, tho\nclassic mould, ihe set phrases, the well turned periods and\npolished sentences, arc not as generally mi t with as in that\nofthe foreign press, where the division of labor is such that\nbut one subject is touched by one pen. What is lost ill polish\nis more than gained in vigor and perspicuity, and the method\nof our press is best suited to the genius of ihe American\npeople,\nIn point of enterprise, the American character would forbid us to be far behind in any pursuit; although it has not yet\ntranspired that any American newspaper was ever, as a late\nLondon paper has been, sent oil' 200 miles into the country,\npartly printed, in order lo be filled anil finished on the localiiy\nof some exciting transaction. This was effected by sending\nnil' mi edition with iho reporters, some printers and a lew\ncases of type, sons to astonish the country ut large by seeing\ntin- report of a celebrated provincial trial (he same hour it\nended, in a London paper, two hundred miles distant. This\nwas a solitary case for eflect Hut no European newspaper\nestablishment 1ms ever yet evinced the enterprise, or been at\nthe expense, of sustaining news-boats, ns the New York press\nhas, to scour ihe sens lor foreign vessels, and virtually extract\nnews from \"the vasty deep\" fifty leagues from shore.\nThe entire aggregate of the American newspaper press,\nboth in talent nnd in numbers, is highly flattering to the United States. The United Kingdom of England,Scotland nnt\nIreland, in 1833, sustained but 3G0 newspapers, of which\nonly 17 wen- daily\u2014making only one third the number pub\nlished by tho American pn ss. Out of London and Dublin\nthere is not a daily paper printed in the three kingdoms. In\nFrance there were in 1820, 343 newspapers, of which 34 of\nthe Parisian journals wero daily. There is not a daily paper\npublished in Franco out of Paris. There are only three\ndaily papers in Paris and two in London, whose average daily\nsale exceeds the subscription lists of some of the New York-\ndailies. One great reason why the American news-press is\nso much more prolific than the European, is, doubtless, the absence of stamp duties, and the free transmission by mail of\nexchange papers and printed documents to editors and pub-\nlisliersof American newspapers.\nIt belongs lo my subject, and would be u most pleasing part\nof it\u2014which I may indulge in at some future day\u2014to institute mi examination into tho characteristics of the newspapers,\nparticularly ihe leading ones of the various towns of the\nI Initial States; but iho I hue allotted to my essay will not now per-\nniil ''\u2022 1 have given a history of the press, and endeavored\nbricflylo consider the mural influence nnd political power ol\ntho American press, and also to contrast its enterprise and the\naverage ability with which it is conducted with the journal\npress of other countries; nnd now, in concluding, I shall in-\ndulgo in a few general remarks, but which will apply with\nmore force to our own\n\" Land, of every land the pride,\nBelov'd of Heaven o'er all the world beside.\"\nIl has been said that an accurate judgment may be formed\nof the state of society in any city, village, or town, by mi examination of the papers published in those places, The\nAmerican press, more perhaps than that of any nation, is the\n\u25a0 ii^aga- .   '.,\u2014 .","fullrs":{},"find":"389.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"388","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1852228","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.77 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
