<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 22</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2086</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2086</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2086/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 22","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"22\nparishes, of above two hundred and sixty thousand dollars\na sum, I should think, worthy of serious consideration^\nwhilst the same parishes, on the plan proposed, as befoj\nstated, would pay for the road but about eighty thousan\ndollars per annum\u2014and if successful, a much less sum won\nsuffice; and all this exclusive of the increased value give|\nto property, and many advantages not enumerated.\nEvery planter who makes one hundred hogsheads of sujl\nand proportion of molasses, would save, in freight, i nsuranci\nand one passage going and coming, about $329\nThat railroads contribute greatly to the prosperity of\ncountry, we have too many proofs in the United States tl\ndoubt. Our sister State of Georgia has, it appears, iJ\ncreased more in population within the last ten years, in prJ\nportion, than any other state in the Union ; and her agricul\nture, manufactures and resources are in a more flourishing\ncondition than any of the Southern States ; and all this il\nattributed mainly to her system of railroads traversing the\nwhole state.\nWhen I first descended the Mississippi, although then quitl\na youth, I retain a vivid impression of the whole scene: then\nwas not a white inhabitant on its banks, from the mouth oj\nthe Ohio to the Walnut Hills, (now Vicksburg.) save at Xel\nMadrid and neighborhood. The whole valley of the Mia\nsissippi contained but a few thousand souls : its whole trad]\nwas carried on in a few flat and keel boats. Steamboat!\nwere ihen not known. Well do I recollect the sensatiol\ncreated by the landing of the first steamboat at the levee il\nNew Orleans, in 1812. I happened to be here, and wal\namong the passengers on its first departure. Now look a]\nthe change of scene ! You have now thousands of floating\npalaces, gliding, as it were, by magic, along this mighty\nstream. This great valley contains now upwards of tea\nmillion of souls. The export of domestic products to fo-,\nreign countries  exceeds in value forty millions of dollars)","fullrs":{},"find":"2087.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2086","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"539969","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
