<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 37</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2101</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2101</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2101/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 37","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"37\nof su\"ar, and will be the means of uniting the whole parish\nin support of the main road, and thereby secure the means,\npromptly and certainly, that said parish should contribute to\nits construction.\nThe resolution, on motion of Col. B. H. Payne,\nwas adopted.\nMr. Lawrence submitted a proposition for build-\nino- the road, and also leveeing the Mississippi on\nthe lower part of the river, where it is without embankment now, and declared his readiness to give\nany security that may be required for the fulfillment of the contracts. His proposition and some\nremarks with which he accompanied it were cheered.\nNo action was had on the matter, however.\nA general cry here took place for Col. Payne, and\nthat gentleman came forward and briefly addressed\nthe convention. He expressed his high gratification\nat. the prompt and business-like manner in which the\nproceedings of this convention had been conducted.\nThey had shown that, as sensible men, they knew\nhow to take hold of a great enterprise. Their proceedings had resulted in bringing about a feeling of\nkindness, of mutual sympathy and interests, which\nwould produce the happiest effect in furthering this\ngreat enterprise. This road was boipd to be built\u2014it\nwould be built. He had already spread before gentlemen in the country his views at length, and in was\nquite unnecessary for him to say anything more than\nto express his thanks for the kindness which had\nbeen extended to him as an humble instrument in\nthe great enterprise. These few remarks of Col.\nPayne were heartily cheered.","fullrs":{},"find":"2102.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2101","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"511084","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
