<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2213</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2213</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2213/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 16","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[161\ncourses which unite to form the D'Arbane, and those which empty into the Dugdem0 \u2022\nand Black Lake waters, &amp;c., are good water privileges, which may be used to \"^\npel machinery. This country is not, therefore, likely to remain entirely 'rural but'\"0'\ntensive manufactories will spring up along the road, and add another element to \u00a3\nwealth and prosperity of our state. These advantages, so feebly set forth, might h!\ndeemed sufficient to engage the attention of this Convention, and secure its favorable\ntice ; but the project looks beyond the limits of our own state, and proposes to penet^\nWW ; out tne pn&gt;|ect Iouks neyouu Uie linin-s ui uui uwn builg, anu piuposes to penetata\nthe heart of Texas between tne 32d and 33d parallels of latitude, to open up tlle vast\nsources of that immense country, and secure to ourselves the advantages which alwan\nflow from enlarged views and a liberal policy. Here are thirty organized counties iJ?\ntially settled, covering as many thousand square miles, and containing not far fromtw^L\nmillions of acres of land. These counties produce at present about 50,000 bags ofcottm?\nMore than half of this is grown in six of these counties, most conveniently situated to th.\nnavigation of Red River. The other forty-four counties are engaged chiefly in tbe b(jJa\nbusiness, and exported during the past season not far from fifty thousand head ofhwf\ncattle, and twenty thousand head of sheep. This business has been found profitable and\nis rapidly on the increase. To this may be added for peltries $200,000, and 8300m\nfor beeswax. Some of these counties are erecting mills, and already produce con.\nsiderable quantities of flour, which, however, is consumed in the country. To find i\nmarket, this flour is hauled two and three hundred miles in wagons. Northern Teiasu\none of the best wheat growing countries on the continent. The average crop is said tobe\nthirty bushels per acre of a very superior quality. And it is worthy of remark, that, aided\nby the construction of the contemplated rail-road, this country would put down flour in\nNew-Orleans one month earlier than it is possible for any part of the country to do, froa\nwhich she now draws her supplies. The importations of good*, groceries, and family sap-\nplies, into this country, may be determined by the amount of their exports. Tho waatsof\nthis people are so urgent, that their purchases have no other limit, than their ability to\npay. In these estimates we have confined ourselves to those counties in Texas\u2014the north,\nern boundary of which reaches beyond the 32d degree of latitude, and which are pretty wdl\nadvanced in settlement. To our other estimates should be added, a trade carried on wiA\nthe southern portion of the Indian nations, which now finds a channel through Red River,\nand amounts at present to about $200,000, and is susceptible of a large increase. If we\nlook to the extent of this country, and its cupubilil i&lt;'s of future improvement, we shall see\nthat it can no longer be neglected, unless we are determined to lie down in idleness end\npoverty, in utter disregard to the sources of wealth which the bounty of Providence has\nplaced within our reach. Probably no other spot upon the globe, of the same extent, co-\ntains so large a proportion of rich and fertile laud as the region of country of which we\nare now speaking. The road will scarcely pass over a section of laud that will not re-\nwnrdlhe labor of the husbandman and contribute to ils business and support. Wlioeffl\ncalculate the future of this country, and tell what it shall be, when its productive resources shall have been fully developed by a judicious system of railways? Wc have act\neven mentioned all the known sources of wealth which it contains. In some ofthe comities are extensive quarries of limestone, mines of salt, stone-coal, and iron ore; andn**\nfar beyond the western limit of the country indicated, are mountains, said to aboundm\nthe precious metals, silver, gold, and platina. The natural advantages of this country \u00abH\nbecoming more generally known ; and there is, iu consequence, an immense tide of emigration pouring into it the present season; and not only is the number of eraigran\"\nvery much increased, but they are of a better class, and take with them a much laW^\namount of negro property. So that the population, wealth, produce, and trade of tw\ncountry are increasing in an arithmetical ratio. A very large proportion of the COB*\ngrown in these counties is sent to tins city at an average cost of $i per bag. In most**\nthe counties the cost of transporting cotton to market so far exceeds the prolits ot P'?DtB'|\nthat it is not attempted; and should the present low prices continue, and the building i\nthis road be delayed a few years, planting will be abandoned, and the negroes re^*J\nnear the Gulf in western Texas. These people receive their supplies at the same ne'v\ncost for transportation, and this double tax necessarily makes them very small cobsuih*\nThere is another view which the undersigned have taken of this route. It is l'wJe\u00b0jr,\non the same line of latitude with Charleston, Montgomery, Vicksburg, Monroe, Sbrevept\"\nMarshall, Dallas, El Paso, and San Diego. If ever the Atlantic is connected witftJJ\nPacific by railway, it must be upon this line. No other route presents so few \u00b0bB\u2122\nor combines so many advantages. It is central in geographical position, crosses^tiJ'.\ntinent at the narrowest point, is far enough south to avoid the snows and frosts of V\nand far enough north to strike the rivers which empty inio the gulf at practicable ^\nings. It will best accommodate the different parts of the country : and to it cities-^\nstates, north, east, and south, must all come, who seek to connect themselves wi,\ntrade of California. When the connection shall have been formed between Jacks ^\nMontgomery, this great central road will be connected with all the principal fItie\u00abre id\nUnited States: and, like the great central artery of the human body, it will infuse \"ber8flf\nvigor into every one of its branches, and animate with health the remotest nieiBj^\nthis great confederated body of states.   The section of this route, which more n*\"11","fullrs":{},"find":"2214.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2213","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"581951","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
