<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/502</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>502</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/502/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I*\nP\n: \\M\ni\n12(3\nSOU T H - W E S T E B N   J U U H N A 1..\n'\u25a0 \u25a0ti\n'h it'.\nluckily with all our sails close reefed, through a warm, but\ngloomy rain, at nine knots. We were on the edge of the\nVcu'.f Stream, and took the full benefit of what the sailors\ncall the butt-end of a north-wester, The rise of this whirlwind was instantaneous. It had been blowing pretty still all\nday, when, suddenly, I saw the fore and main topsails carried\naway, and a wave burst inlo the round house, and rolled backward and forward, there leaving us all nearly knee-deep in\nwafer. In an instant the wind was\u2014not blowing\u2014but bursting over the vessel, in a rapid series of explosions, each one\nlike water forced violently from tho spout of an engine. The\nsea and air wero foam to the lop-mast. The ship lying over\nlow, her gunwale under water, her deck scattered with pieces\nof broken bulwarks, and great fragments of sail, ropes, spars,\nand entire blocks flying off and up upon the gale. The sounds\nexceeded all I had ever imagined: a mingled and fierce crash:\nthunder, whirl and tumult almost beyond conception. The\nmusls bent like willow wands. The noises resembled those\nof some tremendous conflagration, ihe roar of broad flames,\nnnd the crush of beams, roofs, walls, and timber. There is,\nindeed, a similitude between the extreme fury of fire and water, when those elcmets attain mastery. Above our heads,\nsails, blocks, and cables, loosened and rent, were hurled up\nanel down again upon the roof of the round house. It is not\npossible for ono unacquainted wilh the sea, to conceive fully\ntho phenomena of such a scene. Tho wind is there a new\nand appalling power, or rather a fiend omnipotent and infernal. It breaks in volumes and audible billows over your\nhead; producing sounds which seem like ihe conflict of unseen demons in the air. Each separate part of the rigging\nin motion, the huge fabric!, strained to ils utmost tension;\nropes, waves, sails, spars, cables, chains, blocks, doors, beams,\ninstinct with the phrensyof nature. We were deafened with\nthe slamming, banging, crackling, crashing-, snapping, splitting, flouting, roaring, thundering. It seemed impossible\nthat such fearful noises could be produced, except from the\ncruching to pieces of planks and timber. Each moment, as\nI turned my eyes from the masts, I thought I heard them go,\nanil could scarcely credit my sight that they were not yet\ngone. The prominent f'eatuic of this hour is the noises. In\naddition to the full thunder of the sea and wind, a thousand\nwhips cracking, a thousand doors banging, a thousand planks\nsplitting\u2014all together\u2014all with the most incessant, phrensied\nintense violence and rapidity. It was a madness, a delirium\nof the elements, a paroxysm, an ecslasy of rage and ruin.\nTho philological editor of tho New Yorker thus addresses\ntho American Johnson, the king of lexicography:\nLETTER TO DR. WEBSTER.\nNew York, Dec. 23,  1837.\nNoah  Webster, LL. D.\nHear Sir\u20141 have resolved lo trouble you with a few casual suggestions respecting the Etymology of our language, in\nconnexion with your Dictionary. My course hitheito, as a\ngeneral and public defender of your views in opposition to\nthose of Johnson and Richardson, will, I liust, excuse the liberty. Bear with me, then, while I suggest a few instances\nin which I am compelled to depart from your standard.    If\nlyou think it worth the trouble to enlighten mc on tli,.,,,\n'points, you will do .so; if not, it matters little. Here are my\ncavils:\n1. Judgement one) its derivatives, yen spell without the\nmiddle c, and also abridgement, acknowledgement,and other\nwords of this class. Why so? Many of them you derive\nfrom the French, where the e appears. As the sole use ol\nthe e is lo soften the g preceding it, I see not why it may not\nbe us properly omitted in judge as in judgement.\nV. Wo, you spell indifferently with and without an e. [\nhold tho c superfluous and very unsightly. The word looks\nto me just as go and no would to you, if spelled goc and not.\nBut, more than this, yon give us woesome (with the e) and\nleoful (without it,) and use the latter to define the former.\nHow can (his be justified ?\n3. Acre you spell correctly, yet give us theater and kindred abominations. As you frace this word to the French\ntheatre, and as its derivatives nre; theatric, theatrical, &amp;c, I\nthink your innovation on the established usage unwarrantable.\n4. Bituminous, &amp;c, from bitumen, do not suit me. I know\nothers nre with you in, this instance, but that does not satisfy\nme.\n5. Waggon 1 want with two gs, in accordance with the\nanalogy of our language, just as in cragged, dogged, lugger,\nbaggage, &amp;c. Can't you help mc to a reason ? The derivation is nol sufficient, as our language oflen doubles consonants after short vowels, in spite of the primitive I know-\nthere is flagon in the way; but that is not one of our rugged\nnorthern barbarisms, but (as you have it) an irregular offshoot\nof Lantinity. But I would gladly writeflaggon forthesake\nof waggon. I will give up the point if you say I must, but\nI hate lo do it.\nG. Launch is the good old way; and you restrict us to\nlanch without u reason except the derivation, which looks\nquestionable. (1 would take your word for it sooner than\nany other man's; but Lexicographers have so demolished\neach other's characters in this matter of deriving words from\nother languages, that I trust implicity to none.) Beside, the\nderivation is not conclusive. You give us laundress from\nlavandicrc and laundry from lavade.ro. 1 think I must Still\nwrite launch, staunch, &amp;c.\n7. Traveler looks horribly, but 1 am coming to it by degrees. You are probably right in this instance\u2014(I mean\nyour principle; is a sound one)\u2014but to follow you goes against\ntho grain.\nEnough for your patience. Perhaps all my difficulties\narc solved by your Quarto; but how shall a poor Editor indulge in such luxuries? This brings me to the point on\nwhich I was first impelled lo address you. Several persons\naround mc in the common walks of life, say they would contrive to purchase your Quarto if your publishers would but\nissue an edition in numbers (like Richardson's) at a moderate\nprice and at intervals\u2014bi-mothly, for instance. How does\nthe suggestion strike you ? I am sure many would subscribe\nto it, and much good result from the undertaking.\nYours truly, HORACE GREELEY.\nNew Yorker, 1-J7 Nassau-street.","fullrs":{},"find":"503.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"502","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1748043","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
