<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2132</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2132</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2132/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 23","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"ADDRESS. ^\n,   r\u201e\u201e._We are not aware of any rail-roads at present com-\n, 7\"Texas, though considering the fertility of many parts of that\n&gt;:'      , c taterruption in the navigation of its rivers and the growing\n7   ,1 -ion, there would seem to be a necessity for her ^mediate\n1 The people of New-York arc already controlling the trade of\ntc v, l.v her gulf ports. A route for a road has been examined by\nCM Jotason, from Lavaca Bay to El Paso, on the Upper Rio Grande\nWe are confident that these surveys, when completed, will show, that\ntho southern route for a rail-road connecting the Guli of Mexico with\n,1,'e Gulf of California, extending from Galveston or Lavaca Bay,\nby El Paso is far preferable to the northern route through Missouri.\nIt is shorter, and the country is so uniform, rising by regular gradations from the gulf on the cast to the summit of tho table-lands of\nthe Gila, and declining by equally regular gradations to the Pacific\nCoast, that the eost of constructing a rail-road on this route will\nscarcely amount to two-thirds of the cost on the northern route.\nTexas has a deep interest ill connecting herself with the great pub-\nlie works of the United States, and she has public domain enough to\nbuild more roads than are in all New-England. A grand trunk road\nfrom Austin, with branches to Houston and Galveston, passing in the\nvicinities of Montgomery, Washington, San Augustine, Nacogdoches,\nwould enter Louisiana in about the same parallel of latitude with\nAlexandria, and connect with the proposed road from thence to New-\n&lt; lileaiis. In the other direction, her roads should radiate towards\nNew-Mexico and the valleys of tho Pacific. The committee have\nbeen instructed, particularly and urgently, to invite the co-operation of\nTexas.\nA rail-road from Brazos, Texas, across to Harrisburg, on the Buffalo\nBayou of the Bay of Galveston, is commenced, and 20 miles contracted to be finished this year.    Efforts are being made to connect\nre irs owners. Our only object is to^xpose the folly of the pretensions which it\nmikes to the patronage of N'ew-Orleans capital. And first, as to tiie claim set up in favor\nhis road, on the ground of its being a part of the most direct route between New Orb-am and New-York.    The Memphis and Charleston road, we have justseen, intersecM\nhville aud Chattanooga road at Crow Creek, which is forty miles west of Cliatta-\nogn.    From that point, the route, east, is by the way of Dalton, and thence, north, by\nion anil Knoxville Railroad. It is probable, however, that a road will be charter-\nind bud, from Chattanooga to Cleveland, on the East Tennessee road, which would\n\\V. \" rn\"S\"C\u00b0,\u00b0' '\"\"^ \"\"'\\b?,cott'?? off 'h' a\"Sle m'ule \u2122 running down lo D.lton.\nZf\u2122S? \",\"t '?\"','\" I,e b\"lUr \"&gt;&lt;&lt; \u00bb \u00ab\"\"\u25a0 UW\" I\" seen that the two routes from New-\nbilc ,\u201e\"l ,W 7\"h' \u25a0\"? iT by i'.V\u2122,' \"' .'\"Tiliis, \u2122l *\u00bb other by the wa, of Mo-\nKrVectt oh nbe 7A\"\"bile and Rirord road, through West Point and Atlanta, will i\u201e-\nn\"v,S tl.er'il ,\"el\u2122A \"\" \"c East Tennessee Ilail-road. From that point to\nrwo \u2122,,7   \u25a0    f !'' \"\"\"V\u00b0 b\u00b0d:-    In \"\u2022\"\"ting the comparative distance of the\noN\u2122 Or la\u201ef\"Jro\u201e ne 77\" 't\u00b0 '^\"\"\"\u25a0'crttionthe distance from Cleveland\nGo\u2022. W \u201e\u00ab, tw X Bttl U\"\"P\\'. &lt;\u25a0\u00a5 Stance is 351 miles, and allowing\nMemphTt* EoZ.\"  &lt;*** Pet.\"\"\"' \"\" ',\"\"\" 'e1\"irrf is r\u2122rt\u00bb\u00bb ''\u00bb\u00bb'\u00bb\u25a0    Front\n!- am cTc?el, ,' K n? '\"\"? 'Wa ''\u00bb&gt;\"' ,ncl '\"dv\u00ab ''our,, making the en-\n\u00bb\u00abte he ,\u2122e \u201e\u00ab. S*\u00a3S 1 ?\"*' i1'\u2122\",^' \u00bb\"\u00ab \"\u2122 hours. Wc will now csti-\n\u2022\"d Dalco\" Fro' New n ' Grrard Rad-ro.d, and through West Point, Atlanta\nCol\u00abmb',\"\u201ei\u201ee mors f\"\u201em C\u2122,'\" \u00b0 \"\"^ B,T' r'lice\" &gt;\u00ab\u00bb\"\u00b0 F\u2122\u00bb Mobile Bay to\n*- \u00bb..! S one d.v anA fcnai'id\". T ? 7e,\u00bbd. T\u2122a &lt;\" \u00bb\"&lt;' \u00ab half hours, making\nof the lower   \u2122,,'ir, J \", M,f \"0\"ra-\u00ab. difference of forty hours in favor\n\"f the lower rou?c wouV-ilwT'\u2122' \"'\"\"''i T\" f\"\"\u00b0 th\u00b0 \u00bb\"\"\"\" ral7 \"d r&lt;=\"\u00bbi\"&gt;i'\n\u00ab\u00bb\u00abL\"       '\u2122\"\".\u2122\u00bbl&lt;l&gt;l\u00ab\u00bbJBoaii,\u2122Dd ilie mail ,\u201ed the  great bod, of the throush","fullrs":{},"find":"2133.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2132","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"519252","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
