<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 18</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/607</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>607</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/607/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 18","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":", ,f:!\nk \u25a0',\u2022-;.\n!'\u25a0$:\nI'C-'Hf'i\nBfhl \u2022\u2022:\n.\u2022!i\u00bbil\n244\nS 0 U T 11 - W E S T E R N   JO U R N A L.\n'\u25a0KM \u25a0\n1' I\nm\n\u00a5]\n:\u25a0;\u2022\u25a0\n\/    '\nBUc\n1 \u25a0\nI\n1\nj;]\nI\n. t?\nft')\nsums with them to pay for the corn which they wanted. The\ndrinking-cup put into Benjamin's sack was of silver. The\nprocess of embalming was practised ; and when Joseph attended the funeral of his father, he had in his train \" a great\ncompany of chariots and horsemen.\" His wife was the\ndaughter of a priest of the celebrated temple of Heliopolis,\none of lhc obelisks of which exhibits the remarkable skill\nthat must have been attained even before that remote age by\nEgyptian artisls in sculpturing granito\u2014an operation even\nnow found to be attended with extreme difficulty.\nSome of the expressions used by Joseph, when he accused\nhis brothers of being spies, appointed to observe the \"weaker\nparts of the land,\" as well as the memorials of Beni Hassan\nand Thebes, distinctly prove that the Egyptians had already\ncarried their arms into Asia, and had there encountered foes\nof a formidable description. Amongst these were the Shaire-\nlan ; probably, if wc judge from the name, the ancestors of\nthe Saracens. They appear to have inhabited the Asiatic,\ncoast, near Egypt. It is a popular supposition that crests and\ncoats of mail date from the Crusades. The Shairctana wore\ncrested helmets, cuirasses, and coats of mail, composed of\nbroad metal plates which overlaid each other, wero adapted to\nthe form of the body, and secured at tho waist by a girdle.\nThat people wero distinguished by their light hair and complexion, as well as by the aquiline nose, from tho Egyptians.\nThey wore large ear-rings, and employed many ships,so that\nthey must have been a commercial, as well as a warlike and\nenterprising nation. Their appearance, as presented by the\nEgyptian artists, is that of a highly civilized community.\nThe same artists have preserved the features of severa\nother nations, whose names havo been lost in tho stream of\ntime, and who, according to the representations given of them\nhad attained a degree) of refinement unknown to the Egyptians, A people called the Rebo were frequently engaged in\nhostilities with thedrinkers ofthe Nile. They brought into the\nfield immense masses of troops, and were pre-eminently skilled\nin the art of war; they lived in Asia, at a considerable distance\nfrom Egypt; their climate was temperate\u2014their complexion\nalmost European ; their dicss was an under garment, a short\nkilt, a long outer robe highly colored, richly bordered, and\nornamented with fanciful devices. Beneath the outer robe\nthey wore a girdle splendidly ornamented,the extremity falling down in front and terminating in a large tassel. They\ndecorated their persons with ear-rings, necklaces, and various\ntrinkets. The chiefs decked their heads, in the Mexican and\nPeruvian style, with feathers, and painted or tattooed their\narms and legs. They were distinguished from the African\nraces by the aquiline nose, blue eyes, and small red beards.\nThe fact of such a nation as this exhibiting all the signs of\norganized power, moving vast armies from a temperate, and\ntherefore a distant Asiatic country, and frequently resisting\nwith success the forces brought against them by the Egyptians, must tend to open new views about the early history of\nthe world.\nAnother remarkable nation recorded in the Egyptian paintings, are the Shari, Among the ornaments worn by these\npeople were necklaces, lo which a small crucifix was suspended,    The Rebo also frequently wore a cross in ihe same\nmanner, or figured upon their robes, full fifteen hundred\nyears before that emblem became snered as tho token of o\nideinption.    About ihe same period, a people, supposed to\nbe Lyeiians, drove a battle in four-wheeled chariots and curri\ncles, and appear to have been possessed of rare woods\nohl and silv\nivory,\nmil silver vases of tho most exquisite form and workmanship, rings of tho same metals, porcelain jars filled with\nchoice gums and resins for making incense (which they probably obtained from Arabia).\nOur modern modes vary so frequently that I really do not\nknow whether at this moment wide sleeves or narrow sleeves\nflounces or no flounces, long gloves or short, are the fashion\nI find, however, that at the period just mentioned the Lydian\nladies were accustomed to wear long gloves, flowing erar.\nments, secured at tho waist by a girdle, and trimmed with\nthree rows of flounces; that their sleeves were sometimes\nlarge and open, sometimes fastened tight round tho wrist, and\nthat some of them wore caps to which a long tassel was appended ; while others, tho maidens I presume, tied a band\nround the head, and permitted the hair to fall at each side in\ngraceful ringlets. Only imagine the triple flounce, the balloon sleeve, and tho fcronierc to have been in vogue three\nthousand three hundred years ago !\nThe new Egyptian saloon recently opened at the British\nMuseum is at once tho most interesting nnd perhaps the most\nperplexing room in Europe. Wo have here, a collection of\nobjects, many of them found in tombs in which they must\nhave been deposited even before the remote period just referred to, and exhibiting unequivocal tokens of civilization\nadvanced to a stage that must surprise the schools. We have\nhere small figures of Egyptian deities, of quadrupeds and birds\nbeautifully wrought in bronze, stone, and porcelain; chairs,\nsome plain like those used in our kitchens, some inlaid and\nhighly embellished; three-legged stools wilh concave seals,\nmuch moro agreeable than our horizontal ones; a model\nof a house, and a great variety of vases in glass, bronze,\nearthenware, and alabaster, and in a semi-transparent kind of\ncomposition resembling our Derbyshire ornaments; leather\nsandals and shoes; metallic mirrors: wooden combs for\ncombing the hair exactly like those which we use; hair pins\nof wood and ivory ; bowls, cups, and spoons , a pair of roast\nducks found in a Theban tomb; a rope ladder, by which probably a Don Giovanni of those days ascended the balcony of\nhis mistress; implements for writing and painting; several\nglass phials; and a complete set of carpenter's tools, the saw,\nthe mallet, the chisel, the axe, the drill, nails, together with\nthe basket in which they were found by Mr. Burton, all resembling thoso now used by artisans of that trade. Fan-\nhandles, small boudoir boxes of ivory, children's dolls, musical instruments, rings for the ears and fingers in gold, ivory,\nand various metals ; necklaces of gold, of beads in glass and\nother substances, are also to be seen in this mysterious chamber, which moreover, abounds in mummies of bards and priests,\nand in coffins so exquisitely painted that they beguile death\nitself of its horrors. A great majority of these articles must\nhave been wrought almost four thousand years ago; aim\nwhen we pass from them to the statues, sarcophagi and fragments of sculptures and paintings brought from Egypt by out","fullrs":{},"find":"608.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"607","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1826806","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.74 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
