<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 18</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2127</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2127</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2127/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 18","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"18 ADDRESS.\nscribe 300,000 dollars; and surely you, gentlemen, are sufficient\ninterested in this road to subscribe the balance\u2014100,000 dollar\nYou will not trouble yourselves in the mailer'? But better thinta\nare to be hoped of you. An untamed earthquake tore those Ar.\nkansas and Missouri riches from the bowels of the earth for ypj\nspeak the word, and a tamed, a harnessed earthquake, shall lay then!\nat your feet.\n\" A rail-road from Natchez, by way of Bed River to Little Rock,\nrecommends itself to the support of New-Orleans, by the influence\nit must, exert on the development of the whole of northern Louisiana\nand southern Arkansas; and above all, in the advancement of the\npresent incipient state, inhabited chiefly by that interesting pcopk\nthe Choctaws.    This road defines a system of roads that, under its\nfostering influence, will spring up. immediately on its completion:\u2122\nbends sufficiently westward to unlock tho trade of  north-western i\nTexas by a branch road :   it runs far enough towards the bordersH\nArkansas to ensure a future extension to the upper Arkansas, in the [\nterritory of the  Cherokees and ('reeks:  and in conjunction witbfl\nMemphis and Little Rock road, its upper bend runs sufficiently west -\nward to place the starting point of a southern route to the Pacific on\nthe borders of Texas.\"\n4. Mississippi.\u2014With only the short road which connects Jackson\nwith Vicksburg, which has been lately extended to Brandon, now in \u25a0\noperation throughout her limits,* Mississippi proposes to extend that\nroad still further to the Alabama line, and thence to Montgomery, .\nand also to connect Jackson with Holly Springs on the one hand, [\nthrough the richest portions of her territory, and on the other with I\nNew-Orleans by whatever route shall appear most advantageous*.\nShe also is contributing largely to the construction of a road through\nher eastern limits which has its terminus at Mobile.    Of the New- I\nOrleans and Mobile terminii wc shall hereafter speak.\nA committee of the citizens of Vicksburg reports to the convention I\nwhich lately assembled in New-Orleans, in rcga\/d to the Alabama\nroad:\u2014\n\" Tins roar] is to extend from Jackson, Mississippi, to Montgomery, and ff'U\nconnect at Selma with the Alabama aud Tennessee River Rail-road, by which*\nand the roads now under contract and in contemplation, a (.\u25a0nniiiiii\"1\"*'rii'lWjV\ncommunication will be opened through Tennessee, Kentucky and Ohio, with tM\nlakes,\u2014and through Tennessee and Virginia with \u00bb\\\\ ibo Atlantic and Northern\nStates, and at Montgomery will connect with the mil-roads running east il'i'\u00ab\"5?\nAlabama, Georgia and South-Carolina. It will pass, in iltt State of Mississij'P,1*\nentirely through 1 lie counties of Rankin, Scott, Newton and Lauderdale; a'11' '\"\nAlabama, before it reaches Selma, one of the termini of the Alabama ami Tj*\"\"\nnessee River Rail-road, it will pass through Sumter, Marengo, Perry m.d Da\" I\ncoiiude*. Nearly all of these and the contiguous comities, both North ami P\"\"\"**\nnow haul iu wagons their cotton and other articles of export to the Toiiil*'S',e\nand Alabama riverf, and ship them thence lo Mobile. Ihe comities of Sun'tf'\nMarengo, Perry. Green and Dallas, produce annually about one hundred \u00bb\u00bbd \u00bb 9\nthousand hales of cotton, all of which now goes to Moi die, bill much of winch *\nprobably be turned to  New-Orleans by means of this road.     \\n fact, neatly\n# The fow other very short roads arc scarcely worth mentioning.","fullrs":{},"find":"2128.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2127","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"588006","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.56 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
