<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 22</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2219</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2219</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2219/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 22","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[22]\nRAIL-ROADS IN PROGRESS OF CONSTRUCTION, AND PROJECTED, IN MISSOtTRt\nThe Atlantic and Pacific Rail-road (being a continuation of the rail-roads from B\nNew-York, Philadelphia, Baltimore, and odier cities on the Atlantic coast, wesrlton'\nthrough the states of New-York, Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana and Illinois) crimen* ^\nat St. Louis, on die Mississippi River,  and running thence south-westward! v J*]\nwestern limit ofthe state of Missouri, with the expectation that the same will be conth,\nacross the plains to California and the Pacific Ocean.\nThe Hannibal and St. Joseph Rail-road, connecting with Chicago and the Great LaW\ncommencing at Hannibal, on the Mississippi River, and terminating at the town of q!1\nJoseph on the Missouri River, with the expectation that the same will be extended so\nto intersect the Atlantic and Pacific Rail-road.\nThese two roads have been commenced under very favorable auspices, and ore now in\nprogress of erection.\nThe Missouri Central Rail-road, commencing at St. Louis, and running north- westward1!\nto Jefferson City, Boonville and Lexington, ou the Missouri River, and extending u, [i\u00bb\ntown of Kansas at the mouth of the Kansas River, with the expectadon that the same\nwill intersect the Atlantic and Pacific Rail-road,\nThe Iron Mountain Rail-road, commencing at the city of St. Louis, thence to the I\u2122.\nMountain, in a southern direction, and continuing in that course to intersect likeim-\nprovements in the state of Arkansas, in order to connect with the Southern Pacific Rail,\nroad.\nThe South-western Rail-road, commencing at tbe city of Cape Girardeau on the\nMississippi River, to the city of Boonville on the Missouri River.\nHenkt Chouteau,\nDelegate from St. Louis, Missouri.\nNew-Orleans, 6th January, 1852,\nJLOBIDA.\nWhereas Georgia, with her vast system of internal improvements, has already stretched\nher iron lines to within a short distaricc of the Chattahoochee\u2014and a bill is now before\nthe legislature of that state to insure the completion ofthe South-western Rail-road tram\nMacon to Eufimla, Fort Gaines, or other point on said river ; it is therefore expadienttfcit,\nto complete the chain of roads from the seaboard of the Atlantic: to tbe Gulf, a Une\ncommencing at the point at which the South-western Road will terminate, running thence\nto the waters of Pensacola Bay, should be established.\nThe distance of this proposed railway is about 140 miles, passing through the connOM\nof Barbour, Pike, Covington, and Conecuh, in Alabama, and Santa Rosa iu Florida, o\u00abr\na country admirably adapted for the purpose.\nThere arc no large streams to cross; and the lands, for a great portion of the way, **\nquire but little grading\u2014it can, therefore, be built at less than the ordinary cost of roadi\nin the South. The advantages to be derived by New-Orleans and the states boroemig\non the Gulf, from tbe completion of this road, are great.\nA daily fine of steamers, from the terminus to the city, would bring a great P^\u00b0?\nthe Atlantic and Pacific travel hither\u2014the cotton-growing region of Alabama, Fiona\nand Georgia, in the vicinity of tbe route, would make this their great mart; in TC(t\nthey would receive the products of Louisiana, and those of tbe broad West; t'ier7^\nNew-Orleans would be benefited by this route, and the roads which she ProP^\nstrengthened by the connection. The link, to complete the chain, could be m; 7^.\nthe states bordering on the Gulf would feel the benefits of its influence, before L,lher.I11\u2122g\nextended routes can be completed. It would open a district of country, where lan(ls\nnow comparatively valueless, which would be of great advantage to our national gov\nment' Id en-\nGovernment, having spent millions for the naval station at Pensacola, sh'ls at\ncourage this enterprise, as it will be found necessary to secure every facility foi* .r?7e\nimprovements. The power possessing the harbor of Pensacola, as a rendezvous in ^\nof war, holds complete control over the trade and commerce of the Gulf. Hence, a ^\namount has been wisely expended in constructing fortifications at the entrance ^\nbay, and that point must ever be one of great importance in time of war.    And","fullrs":{},"find":"2220.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2219","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"685215","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.65 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
