<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 16</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/555</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>555</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/555/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 16","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"192\nSOUTII-W1\nT EflN JOURNA I,.\nI\nI .-if.-,\n! ;\n'it\nIS *\niff\n!; if!':'\ni-.,\u00ab&gt;!\n; ite\n\u2022 ''Sji\nI   .i.Vrf*\n'..\u00ab\u00ab\u25a0\ni,'r-\n&gt;' V\n'\u25a0' J,\n'\u25a0\u2022\u25a0''\u25a0\n' \u25a0 \u25a0:\u2022\n; *\n\u25a0 \u25a0 ti\n\u2022T\n'r,\nI\n\u2022 \u2022;\n\u25a0\nfrom Sunday that his people wore very much frightened\nthe approach of our vessel, and that he had some difficult,.\nmentit was recognized by Sunday, he suddenly uttered such\na. shout of heartfelt rapture, as thrilled through every bosom\n,      i convince them that 'ho was himself I'\non board.\nIt was very unpleasant to be becalmed in sightof this long: At ten o'clock, Mr. Jarvis, our supercargo, and myself, ac-\ndesired bind.' Our curiosity was en tiptoe, to witness the companied by Sunday, and some of his relatives, went on\nmeeting of Sunday with his people, who must have mourn-shore in a largo ennoe. When we arrived near thereof,\ned his absence as ono long since remembered with the dead. \\Sunday advised us to take off our shirts, that hi3 people\nAt about six P.M., a very light breeze sprang up, which might see that we put confidence in their profession of ami-\nwafted us g&lt; nlly onward for some time; but v. o did not gi I ty, and were not afraid.     Our cai.ae was soon surrounded by\n'  natives, up to their middle  in  water, ond nearly one fotulli\nof a mile from the share; tho men and boys all armed with\nnot\nh,\nliic land until after dark, when we hoisted a lighl\nand kept it burning until midnight, (we had been lying to\nfor about an hour and a half previous) when we hauled our spears.    The chiefs repeatedly came to us, exhorting us m\nwind, and stoo 1 for the small island Raja, as it is called by|lo be afraid, e&lt;ic.    As soon as  our canoe touched the bead\nolony and dependent of Sundaj\/s islam\nthe nativ\nwhich it is adjacent.\nAt eight o'clock, A. M., the weather was fine, with a two-\nknot breeze, when wo were close in with ihe small island.\nThere being no anchorage here, wo ran in close enough to\nthe share to be abb; to hold a conversation with the natives,\nthrough Sunday, from the flying-jib-boom, which soon cause d\nan assemblage of the natives, who collected on the beach,\nnear the vessel, armed with long spears. Sunday soon informed them who he was, and that he had returned to his\nnative land, and requested them to send oil' a canoe to convey him ashore, As soon as they understood the case, they\nuttered a shout of joy that made the very welkin ring, and\nbegan to cut the most ludicrous ami extravagant capers em\nlay was immediately surrounded by the oldest men and\nwomen on the island: some seizing him by the hands, ami\nothers embracing his legs and feet, while several caught him\nround the neck, \"and blubbered liko school boys on his bosom.\" Sunday was much affected by these unequivocal\ndemonstrations of affection; und while the big tears rolled\ndown his cheeks, ho had some difficulty in disengaging himself, and come lo our relief; for by this time we were socom-\npletcly surrounded by a more youthful class, as to find ii almost impossible to move hand or foot; some of them rubbing our hands and arms with wet fingers, to ascertain\nwin ther the color of our skill was natural and permanent,\nor only artificial; others playing with anel admiring our\nhair, while the females indulged their inquisitivencss by ex\nilic beach and in the water, bul were all loo much afraid of nmining our clothes, trying on our shiits and caps, and niak-\nour big canoe, (die brig.) lo come off with a canoe to receive ing many awkward attempts to get into our trousers. Sun-\ntheir chief. Sunday, therefore, announced his determination\\day was at length enabled to conic to our assistance, and\nto swim on shore, and commenci el stripping for that purpose.(caused his people to form a circle around us, providing ns\nCaptain Morrell, however, ordered the boat to be lowered, I will) the means of sitting down and gelling a little fresh air,\nand prevailed pn Sunday to make his landing among.his while the natives were affordeda better view of us, Smithy\nsubjects in a more kingly style than he had contemplated, and the principal chiefs remained inside the circle, all listen-\nHe therefore embarked in our boat, which was ordered to ing with the most greedy avidity to his wonderful relation)\ntake him lo the edge of the reef, which ihe impatient chief of the adventures which he had encountered since his strange\nhad no sooner leached, than he stripped off every thing but and mysterious captivity and exile from his beloved country,\nn red cap, and sprang into the. water, while the boat I bad already learned enough of Sunday's language, which\nimmediately shoved off for tliL vessel, as we knew not I had studied during the voyage, to hold long and interest-\nwhat might bo tho reception of our seamen among these ing colloquies with him. Indeed, I was his favorite on board\nsavages, the brig, and to me ho always communicated his doubts and\nAs soon as Sunday was on shore, he was surrounded by\nfears respecting his ultimate return to  his island: for such\nihe natives, all armed witii spears. But he was instnntly doubts and fears lie actually entertained, notwithstandingbu\nrecognized by his people, who testified their joy and affee- confidence in the nautical skill und verbal promises of Capt.\ntion by breakingtheir weapons in pieces, and littering shouts [Morrell. I could now perceive, that in gratifying bis won-\nof welcome tint might havo been heard for miles. These dor-loving countrymen, he indulged the traveller's licensed\nwere quickly followed by a gi ni ral i mbrace, by every indi- an almost unpardonable extent. Put, as the father of Maty\nvidual, and I will venture to assert that a moro happy meet- Stnpleton says\u2014\" It is all human nature.\" At least it mn-sl\ning never took place between  an exiled monarch and his have so appeared to his auditors, whoso credulity was now\nprepared to swallow any thing, and the temptation to feed\"\npeople\u2014not oven excepting Napoleon's return  to France\nIrom Eiba.\n'\u2022Sun-Jay remained on shore about an hoiij, and then returned to the brig in a canoe, accompanied by an old man, He\nbrought with him a handfull of spears, to convince the captain that his people wero at peace with us. Aftor he had\nbeen on board some time, several other canoes ventured oh\"\nbringing cocoar.uts and other refreshments.    We understood\nproportionably strong,    He 'repeatedly appealed to us fort\nconfirmation of his slory, which was readily given.\nThis occupied the best part of an hour; after which we\nall adjourned to tho house of the principal chief) who no\"1\npresided, and where were assembled many aged chiefs lo\nwelcome  Sunday's  return.    One of them, in particular,!\nihould iuda\njudge was one hundred and fifty years of age.","fullrs":{},"find":"556.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"555","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1780169","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
