<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Adrienne LaCour Four Corners Oral History Series</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-thwcoh-fourcorners</identifier>
  <name type="corporate" displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
    <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.). T. Harry Williams Center for Oral History</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">Interviews for this series were conducted by Adrienne LaCour as part of the research for her MA thesis in landscape architecture at LSU. Interviews focused on the experience of both blacks and whites on sugarcane farms at Four Corners, an unincorporated community south of Franklin, Louisiana, and near New Iberia, Louisiana. LaCour was interested in land use patterns and community history in the predominately African-American community of Four Corners.&#xD;
&#xD;
The topics of the interviews include life of workers on plantations, recollections of grandparents who were slaves, growing and processing of sugar cane, foods grown for self-subsistence, and horse and buggy transportation. Interviewees discuss South Coast and other plantations of the Four Corners area, plantation stores and debt peonage, recreational activities including gambling and baseball, Sunday visiting, and dancing. Other topics include the impact of World War Two, various religious beliefs, burial and birth traditions, and natural remedies for childhood illnesses.</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">Focuses on land use patterns and community history in the predominately African American community of Four Corners, located near New Iberia, Louisiana.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordCreationDate>2021-04-01</recordCreationDate>
    <recordContentSource authority="local">lsu/jg</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>