<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 24</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2249</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2249</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2249/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 24","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[24]\nIt will appear that these expenditures have been diffused over\nnearly every state; not to the same amount in each, because, as\nmust be evident to every reflecting mind, it is not every state -whiA\nhas, within its limits, harbors or rivers which require improvement\nor which admit of being improved. But every state must experienn\nthe benefit of improved harbors and rivers of an adjoining state,\nMuch misconception has arisen in reference to amounts which have\nbeen appropriated for these harbors and rivers. Allow me to call\nyour attention to page 25 of the report, marked No. 2. It is there\nstated, that the whole amounts appropriated (from 1806 to I845)\nare,\nFor lake harbors $2,790,500\nFor the western rivers 2,758,800\nBy which it will be perceived, that the whole amount appropriated\nand expended on these two interesting and important parts of the\nsystem, does not exceed $5,549,300.\nThese facts are adapted to dissipate many erroneous impressions,\nand to correct many errors.\nNow, if it be desirable to know how the balance ofthe seventeen\nmillions over and above the amount for lake harbors and for western\nrivers has been expended, the information will be found in the report\nmarked No. 1.\nBy referring to the facts of the report marked No. 3, it will be\nperceived that\nThe nett commerce of the lakes was, for 1848     $93,242,633\nAnd for the western rivers, for the year 1849     256,233,820\nAs the \" exports\" of one place are presumed to be the \" imports\nof another, the \"nett commerce\" is taken to be one half of \"exports\nand imports.\" These latter constituting what may be called the\n\" gross commerce,\" which last would be double the amounts stated.\nThis idea is not rigidly correct. \"Without doubt, the \" nett commerce\" is more than half of the \" gross commerce.\" But yet it was\nconsidered the safe rule to adopt. Reasoning upon such a subject,\nto obtain credit, should exhibit the desire of avoiding exaggeration,\nor of assuming conjecture as a basis of the reasoning.\nThe passenger trade on the lakes, (see page 5 of the report\nNo. 3,) can be stated for the year 1849, at, passengers      356,000\nAnd, supposing the passengers to have a direct relation to\ntonnage and amount of trade, the passenger trade on the\nwestern waters may be safely stated, for the same year, at.\npassengers '   1,500,000\nFrom these facts can be inferred sound reasons why so many ra\";\nroads are well supported, and why so many are required, as, withou\nthis immense internal trade,  and the consequent number of passe\ngers, these rail-roads would be without support.","fullrs":{},"find":"2250.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2249","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"575490","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
