<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Lutrill Amos Payne Sr. Scrapbook, 1951-1988</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-sc-payne</identifier>
  <name type="corporate" displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
    <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">text</typeOfResource>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">Lutrill Amos Payne Sr. (1910-1999) was born in Lillie, Louisiana, and earned a B.S. degree in agriculture from Southern University in 1936 and later served in World War II. Payne was an instructor in agriculture at Allen High School in Allen, Louisiana, when he filed suit to integrate the Louisiana State University Graduate School to study agriculture. He won a judgment in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana in 1951. Payne later earned a M.Ed. degree from Southern University in 1961, taught school in several Louisiana parishes, and became the first African American in Natchitoches Parish to run for public office.  This 15-page scrapbook kept by Lutrill Amos Payne Sr. contains clippings, telegrams, and other items documenting his legal efforts to enroll in the Louisiana State University Graduate School and his attendance there in the summer of 1951. A smaller number of items concern events in Payne's life between 1953 and 1988.</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">Lutrill Amos Payne Sr. (1910-1999) was an instructor in agriculture at Allen High School in Allen, Louisiana, when he filed suit to integrate the Louisiana State University Graduate School to study agriculture. He won a judgment in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana in 1951. This 15-page scrapbook contains clippings, telegrams, and other items documenting his legal efforts to enroll in the Louisiana State University Graduate School and his attendance there in the summer of 1951.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments abo</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordCreationDate>2020-07-17</recordCreationDate>
    <recordContentSource authority="local">lsu/hcr</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>