<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/387</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>387</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/387/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOU T H-WESTERN J 0 U RNA L.\n23\nStates. The impressions of newspapers in the State of New-\nYork have been computed, with tolerable accuracy, at six\nlee'll millions annually. Estimating this at one seventh pari\nof the impression of the entire Union, it will give one hundred nu I twelve millions of sheets, as tho annual harvest\nof the American newspaper press: about eight newspapers a year to every human being in tho United States, besides one periodical, onnn average of Gl page's, lo each individual capable of reading.\nTh \u2022 array of names, that greets the eye of the inquirer\ninto the newspaper literature of the United States, is truly\nlaughable. We have the 'Globe' talking saucily to the '.Sun,'\nanil ihe 'Sun'complimenting Ihe '.Moon,'and the 'Stars'courtesy-\ningtolho 'Comets-,'and the 'Torch high t'dnzzling the 'Deacon,'\nand the 'Trunipei'soundiiigut the 'Clarion,'and die 'Bee' sling-\ning the 'Hive,'and the 'Gazclte'publishinglhe 'Advertiser,'who\nadvertises tho 'Courier,' which has run away uftcr ihe '.Messenger,' which has taken the 'Mail' lo catch the 'Idler,' who professes to be a lame 'Special! r' ofthe 'Eagle,' who overlooks ihe\n'Hemisphere,' in search ofthe 'Keystone' ofthe 'Arch of Freedom.' We have a hundred 'Republicans,' as many 'Democrats\none 'Federalist,' twenty 'Spies,' and a 'Reflector,' gazing at his\n'.Mother's Magazine' in the 'Mirror' of ihe 'Times.' We have a\n'Pear!' ioenclo-o in a 'Casket,' together with a 'Southern Rose'\nfor the 'Lathes' Companion'\u2014and we have a suitable \" Offering\" for Wolverines, Buckeyes, Hoosiers and Yankees.\nA witty writer in tho Now York  .Mirror has many times\ntaken off\", in a vein of sly humor, the Americanism of at\nunpretending is the gazelle he takes. It is next to impossible\nto fill a sheet fifty-two limes a year, without putting inlo it\nsomething thai is worth the subscription price.\n\" Every parent whose son is oil' from him at school should\nbe supplied with a newspaper. I well remember what a\nmarked difference there was between those of my schoolmates\nwho had and those who had not access to newspapers,\nOther things being equal, iho first was always decidedly\nsuperior lo the last, in debate and composition at least. The\nreason is plain ; they had command of more facts. A newspaper is a history of current events, as well as a copious and\ninteresting miscellany, which youth will peruse with profit\nand delight, when they will read nothing else.\"\nThat a newspaper is primed in the outskirts of civilization,\nwith antediluvian looking type, and on paper never bleached\nby the dews and rains of heaven, is no argument against its\npower or influence.\nTear the lilile ill-looking sheet to shreds, and the fragments\nas they are tossed through the fields by the winds, will still\nspeak, and say something that he who looks upon it will\neither believe or know lo be fact and receive in aid of his\nopinion, and as a make-weight in some theory.\nThe fads detailed by the press, and the sentiments there expressed, are the elements thai insensibly form public opinion.\nli is not uncommon for an editor to hear tho same sentiment\n(often in the very words) which ho had hut recently thrown\nout, advanced to him again ns an original idea, by some one of\nhis readers, who hail forgotten or never knew the source from\nlaehing magniloquent titles to insignificant and miserably w|licll J|B obtniHfltl iti    Aml if that editor has always known\nprinled newspapers i and Ihe Now York Knickerbocker has his own when it comes back again to him,  he may be well\nlately made a dash at tin; same \"infirmity of noble minds,\"\nthat would seel;, by the larger, to elevate and dignify the\nsmaller.\nWilli regard to the character of American Periodicals, Reviews, .Monthlies, Quarterlies, Annuals, .Magazines and .Miscellanies, I shall say  but little.    Many of them  have been\nlong before the  public, and  their reputations arc well established.   The gifted but unfortunate Donnie was tho father of\nAmerican Periodicals.   His Port Folio, established by him in\nPhiladelphia in 1801, survived him, and had a life of nineteen\nyears.    This was the first American publication that arrested\nthe public mind, and made a reputation lor ils editor, which\nsurvives as his monument.   The North American Review was\nestablished at Boston, in 1813 : il has been edited by Tudor\nSparks,   E.    T.  ('banning,   Ed.  Everett,   and  since 1830,\nby   Alexander II.    Everett\u2014acute    scholars    and   learned\ncritics all.   The Philadelphia and Now York Reviews are of\nmuch more recent origin, and the Charleston Sou,hern Lite-\nraty Review and Ihe Literary Messenger of Richmond were\nstill more recently established.    I pass without further notice\nto a consideration of the influence of the American newspaper\npress\u2014the average ability with which it is conducted, and the\ncomparison it holds with the Journal press of other countries.\nFrom Ihe observations of a life thus lar connected with the\npress, I fuel prepared to adopt the language of the lion.\nJudge Longstreet, who says :\n\" Small is ihe sum required to patronizo a newspaper, and\namply remunerated is the patron, I care not how humble and\nthought of for philoprogenitivoness in acknowledging his own\noffspring after their brief absence.\nThe circumstance that the political journals of our country\nare ranged on the opposing sides of great questions of political\neconomy, and of the science of government,involving a discussion of the true principles of liberty and their fate, is no dis-\nndvantaugo to  iho progress and dissemination of enlightened\nfreedom ; on ihe contrary, it is truly essential to a full develops-\nincut and a  fair understanding of the whole system of human\ngovernment, and all the principles of political freedom.  In law\nit has been considered by all  civilized  nations necessary to\nhave opposing counsel and advocates upon every question at issue : then, why not as necessary to have opposing advocates to\nplead for and against proposed measures or newly presented\nhypotheses .'    How else can we arrive at truth and receive the\nbenefit of wisdom .'   The people al large form the jury of the\ncountry by whose decision  men  and measures, projets and\nprinciples rise  or fall: let  the ease bo well argued before ihe\njury previous lo their decision.    Again, the parlizan press respectively becomes the natural defender of tho rights of the\npeople against the encroachments of those who are in power,\nor the designs of the ambitious who are out, as the case may\nbe.    Often too, talented and ambitious men honestly conceive\ntheir own success or the success of their particular measures\nor schemes as identical with the salvation of the country and\nthe rights of the people.      Here then it becomes tho solemn,\nhigh and sacred duly of the press lo arouse the people, separate\ntheir interests from ambitious schemes, and hurl back the as-\njfiiti","fullrs":{},"find":"388.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"387","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1736936","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
