<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 05</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/561</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>561</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/561/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 05","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"'.SPU-T 11 - W E S T E It N J 0 U R N A L.\n197\nultingly exclaimed, \" lhc medicine works !\" I foil the hope\nalso, that I might, through North, implant in his bosom the\n\"green-eyed monster,\" which would yet wring from him a\nconfession of his perfidy and a menial snilfor my hand. We\nrose from the table, and re-entered our cabin, where the ladies were left alone fir an hour, when young North came\nan I asked permission lo introduce his friend. No one object-\ni-J. mid he retired, shortly afterwards returning with Herbert,\nwhom he introduced to ns separately; tho latter seeming\nmuch embarrassed at first, but soon recovering, labored to\ncommonplace, until our way was obstructed by a bayou We\nstopped on the very verge of the bank, and Herbert broke\nihe silence, after a lapse of live minutes, in the following man-\nher:\n\"Miss Clara, what can you think of mo alter my unnati,.\nrnl conduct towards you, when I tell you, that in severing the\nholy pledge which bound us together, the blow intended for\nyou, fell upon myself, and has left me a walking monument\nol shame and wretchedness?\"\n_ \"Mr. Herbett,\" I replied, \"I know not how to answer you,\nfor, whilst I have no (lisp\nplease. I\"-\", wuiiot i nave no disposition to sit in judgment en your\nMelmoth, when I again found myself in tho presence of treachery to me, 1 have no desire to subject myself nsrain to\none Ibr whom I entertained a hatred which knew no bounds, the hollow professions of a man who has treati ei my love liko\nthink you that I could allow any power of mine to sleep, a bauble, and might again strive to poison the source whence\nthat would secure mc revenge? No, no, no I\u2014heart for\nIhrl was engraven upon tho \" tablets of my memory,\" as\nindelibly as if burnt there by the sunbeams of Heaven, and\nwith a calm exterior 1 exerted myself to woo, without seeming lotlo so. I watched each look, each movement of my\nvictim, and, like the wary falcon, beat around the quarry with\nit sprang.\"\n\" 0 &lt; llara ! 1 deserve all of this from you, nay more I but\nif you knew of tho sleepless nights, the daily'misery, and\nihe scourges of conscience that I have endured since I sent\nthat accursed note to you al tho Lodge, you would at least pity\nme, nnd allow me to look to lhc future for forgiveness.    If I\nevery seductive ruse that would lull suspicion to vest, till al cou''' hope for this last, a burthen would be taken from my\nlength Herbert and myself were engaged in easy converse- sou' '\u2014your happiness would be the highest object of my million, nnd even bandied witticisms as though wc had never bition.and if a life of servitude would blot out the deep wrong\nbeen other than boon friends. Ho seemed almost happy, and\nny vanity then prompted the thought that our former associations had engendered in his bosom a love for me of which\nhe was not conscious till he hail made his thrust at my peace\nnl'mind The gentleman rose to leave at ten o'clock, and\nafter the \"good evening\" was pronounced, a furtive glance\n\u2022rmii Herbert towards me, was returned with a smile from\nI havo done you, mine shall be devoted to you even unto\ndeath! I throw myself upon your clemency, conscious that\nI deserve it not.\" He had no sooner done speaking, than he\nsunk upon his  knee before me, and buried  his face in  his\nbands.\n\"George Horbert,\" I resumed, with a solemnity I really\nfelt, \"in the presence ol your God, with these wild evidences\nof his existence around you, and in an attitude suited for your\n\\\\'\\\nf, which I intended should be rouged.\n,    ,      , ,.       ,,        i r      approach to tho Deity only, do you, with tho fear of sharintr\n\u25a0 again met al the breakfast (able, and as we rose from   .\" ,.       ...        , it   -i- ,   ,-,   ,\n.     ,   , ,.     \u201e . , ii the late ol condemned souls il you speak falsely, vow ihat\nii, the signal for\" wooding   was given, when a -walk upon .   . .       .,\n,,,\u201e,. , ,. , \u2022     r n   i vou bmelly love me; that you are'Ueil nuw fimperuig with my\ntin; banks ol the  river was  proposed, to which wo (uymHy  .      . .    ii       \u2022\n'    '. ,   , \u25a0 i   feelings, and that no other motive than our mutual happujess\nassented, as the morning was as lovely as had ever been ush\ne red in upon delighted mortals by the fair A mora. I ran to\nmy stateroom to bonnet myself; strapped on a pair of gaiters,\nand was just ready to leave, as the chambermaid entered and\nhanded me the following note, written with a pencil.\n\"George Herbert presents his regards to Miss Clara Per\nhas induced you thus to importune met\"\n\" 1 do, I do I 1 make the vow, and if you doubt my protestation, I now pledge myself, in the name of all I hold elcaron\nearth\u2014my honor, my hopes centered in yourself, every thing\nwhich makes life worth the having, that I am indeed sincere I\nO Clara I you will not credit an appeal from me, however\nryini, and solicits the pleasure of her company during the honest, but if I wen' permitted to prove my fidelity, there is\nmorning walk.   Miss Clara will please intimate her pleasure one way to do so which you could not doubt? \"\n\u2022Name it!\"\n\u25a0You will not bate ine if I do?\"\n\u25a0 I will listen to anything that will redeem your cliente\nle) the bearer.\n\" Gentlemen's Cabin, January Ith, '34.\nThe maid was in wait for an answer, and nodding anas-\nsent, I had scarcely time enough to train my nerves for any tcr.\"\nemergency, when tiie gentleman entered our cabin, and Her- \" Then hear mo! and if you would save one whoso lovo\nbert stepping up to me, offered his arm, with the expletive re- is as pure as if engendered in Heaven from being engulfed\nmark\u2014\"that he hoped I was quite well this morning?\" \"In- in the vortex of self-immolation, f conjure you by your hopes\ndifferently well,\" I replied, and we made our way to terra of happiness beyond the grave, by tho love you once conferred\nupon my unworthy self, and by those tics of endearment\nlirina.\nWhen wc reached the summit of the hank, the mildness\n\u00b0f the scenery and the stillness of tho dense forest, shaded\nalmost to gloominess by the thick foliage, which prevented\nan intromission of the sun's rays, accorded with the dark feel-\nlngs I nursed in disguise. We unconsciously strayed from\nNorth and his sister, indulging in conversation altogether\nwhich kind you to your family, to save me from drowning tho\nodious past, ivilh myself, in every sink of pollution, that can\nhasten tho last spark of life from this shrinking frame of\nmine. Doubt me no longer, Clara, for I will prove my sincerity by accompanying you to the altar, at the shortest period\npossible after our arrival at New Orleans, and, in the sight of","fullrs":{},"find":"562.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"561","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1746753","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
