<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 06</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/456</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>456</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/456/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:00">{"title":"Page 06","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"85\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nIRff'4\nfever are so ready to bestow, he will find ample reason to admit,\nthat the atmosphere about the wharves was contaminated\nby the infectious air imported in ships from tropical climates.\nTo those who are at all conversant with the history of nautical diseases in hot climates, it cannot be a matter of doubt,\nthat vessels frequently become infected, while cruising in tropical seas, and lying in tropical ports, and the sailors and passengers, especially when they are unaccliinated natives oil\nnorthern latitudes, will sicken and die. An infected air also\naccumulates gradually, in some manner, in the holds, which\nwill infect strangers, although the crew may not suffer\nWhen large quantities of this air is brought into our ports,\nin hot, sultry weather, as was the case at New York in 1822,\nit will certainly infect the contiguous local atmosphere; or\nact as a morbific \" leaven\" to it, just as the infected air of an\n\" infected district\" gradually extends itself over other parts\nof u city. It docs not change the nature of the case, whether\nthe infected air depend, in any degree, upon personal \"contagion.\" But if the yellow fever, ns an epidemic, depend sole.\nIy upon \"an epidemic constitution of the atmosphere,\" we\nwould inquire, why it does not affect every part of a city indiscriminately, and not that part only near the shipping?\nIf any one admits that the air of a city can be infected from\na pile of putrid matters or filth, why can he not perceive that\nit can be much more readily infected from a source where the\ninfection is completely formed, and virulent, and only requires\ndiffusion in the air? Let not the specious term \"contagion,\"\nmislead.\nIf these sources of miasm or infection be capable of exciting yellow fever in those persons who reside near the landings, although highly predisposed by the impure air of the\ncity, but who might otherwise escape, it is but poor consolation to be informed, that it is not \"contagion,\" or that the in\nfection is not brought from a foreign port. To them il isim.\nported, although it may have been generated only three days\nor twenty-tour hours before the ship arrived in port. If only\nthe exciting cause is thus imported, would not all cities do\nwell to prohibit the introduction of this exciting cause?\nWe have said yellow fever is a commercial disease; and\nthat it prevails mostly in ports which carry on extensive\ntrade with tropical countries or ports. Those towns and cities\nwhich do not carry on such commerce, are mostly exempt\nfrom yellow fever, although in the same latitude with those\nafflicted by that disease, and under the same general circumstances. To say the least, they arc exempt from the exciting\ncause, whether it be infected air from ships, or the simple fatigue and exposure of seamen about the ships. In certain\nyears, a general predisposition exists, as the effect or result\nof continued hot, sultry weather, from New Voile, or even\nfrom Boston, along the whole sea-board, to New Orleans.\nThis general predisposition, which may, however, vary in\ndegree at different places, finally, in most places, passes ofl\nwithout any epidemic, yellow fever, except in a few towns or\nports, which, have line deep harbors, and enjoy extensive commerce with tropical countries. In others not possessing\nthese advantages, it docs not prevail. Hence we find it prevails in Philadelphia.   New  York.    Baltimore.     Norfolk,\n1 -\nCharleston, Mobile, and New Orleans; but why does it not\nprevail, at the same time, in Harrisburg, nt Troy, at Washington City, at Richmond, at Columbia, at Oppelousas, at Tuscaloosa, and other inland towns ? The same general predisposition, or \" epidemic constitution of the air,\" exists in all these\nplaces; but only a few of them are exposed to the \" exciting\ncause, necessary to produce an epidemic:\u2014the \"leaven\"\nfrom the infected air of ships, or goods from infected places,\nare wanting to complete the train. Those towns that arc\ndestitute of these, avoid the pestilence. Sporadic cases may\noccur from high exciting causes of another kind, but in a\nfree, pure air, it passes off without exciting other cases.\nA case presents directly in point, on this subject, as well\nas in relation to tho agency of putrid exhalations and marsh\nmiasm in the production of yellow fever.    The town of Cam-\npcachey is situated on the Gulf of Mexico, in latitude 19\u00b0 45'\nN.\u2014Vera Cruz is situated about three hundred and fifty\nmiles distant, but in about the same latitude.    Campeacheyis\nhealthy, and Vera Cruz is visited annually with yellow fever,\nThe circumstances  generally considered most favorable lo\nthe production of yellow fever, are equal in both places. Cam-\npeachey is built mostly of stone, upon a substratum of limestone rock; the soil of the surrounding country, as well as a\npart of the town, is a sandy loam, and often becomes very\nmuddy; the town is surrounded by a stone   wall about ten\nfeet high; the streets are wide; the houses are large and\nliry ; on the back part of the town, there is a high hill, or\nmoderate mountain, which greatly interrupts ventilation, so\nat the inhabitants suffer greatly, from \"all tho inconveniences of a sultry, confined air.\"    \" In front of the middle\nof the city, is a large wharf or mole, extending one hundred\nyards into the water.     Along this mole, there is constantly\ndeposited large quantities of filth of every kind, together with\n\u2022 large quantities of putrid fish. \"    \" When the tide, (which\nrises and falls two or three feet,) retires, all these matters are\nleft exposed in the mud, and on the shore, to the direct rays of\na vertical sun, until the stench  is intolerable to strangers.\"\nBesides these things, there are also other \"accumulations of\nlillh in other parts of the town.\"    Yet \"the inhabitants are\nvery healthy \" : there is only one physician in the place, nnd\nhe has not half employment in his profession, although \"the\npopulation is about ten thousand.\"    See Med. Rep. vol. 4, p.\n5-8.     Vera Cruz is situated upon a sandy plain, with sand\nhills in its rear; contains no more  filth than Campeachey:\nthe air is no more confined or sultry ; the inhabitants are no\nless temperate; yet Campeachey is healthy, and Vera Cruz is\nannually visited with yellow fever of the most malignant\ntype.    See Med. Repos., vol. 4, p. 7 and 8 : also, vol. 3, p.\n46, &amp;c, A. D. 1800.\nHow is this paradox explained?\u2014Campeachey has an extensive, but shallow harbor, so that large ships cannot approach near the town; only boats and small craft can enter\nthe harbor, such as do not exceed fifteen or twenty tons.\u2014\nHence, so far as commerce with remote regions, and the foul\nair of large ships, from long tropical voyages, are concerned,\nit is equivalent to an inland town: and it is also free from lh?\ncrowds of strangers, who infest large commercial ports. Bill\nVera Cruz carries on an extensive commerce, has a fine deep","fullrs":{},"find":"457.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"456","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1897784","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.81 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
