<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 9</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/370</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>370</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/370/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 9","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n,hat an extraordinary display of meteors did occur on the night\nof the 12th and 13th of November, 1830; and that similar\nshowers have been witnessed on each anniversary since the\nmagnificent display, Nov. 1833.]\n\" From the foregoing accounts compared, we arc led to conclude that tho meteoric shower increased in intensity from\nnorth to south, that of South Carolina having been the most\nconsiderable of all, so far as  accounts have reached us.\n\" I lues not the recurrence of (his phenomenon for six sue\neessive years at the same period of Ihe year, plainly show its\nconnexion with the progress of tho earth in its orbit ? and does\nnot the fact that the greatest display occurs every where in\nplaces diflering widely in longitude, at the same hour of the\nday, as plainly indicate its connexion with the motion of the\nearth on its axis? Tho supposition of a body in a space\nconsisting ofan immense collection of meteors, stretching across\nthe earth's orbit obliquely, so that the earth passes under it in\nits annual progress, while places on its surface lying westward\nof each other are successively brought by the diurnal revolution to the point of nearest approach, will satisfy both these\nconditions. I can think of no other that will. The \"point\nof nearest approach\" may be merely the extremity, or the\nskirl of the nebulous body, while the greatest part of it, and\nconsequently its centre of gravity, lies Ico distant from the\nearth to be much influenced by its gravity. It would not be\nat all inconsistent with the known extent of astronomical\nhodiis, to give to the body in question a breadth of thousands  and a length of millions of mile's.\n\" 11 was an accidental observation, made after the conclusion was formed, which ascribes the origin of the meteoric\nshowers to a revolving nebulous hotly, that first led me to\nsuspect the Zodiacal high! to be the body in question.\u2014\nThis, according to La Place, is such a nebulous body, revolving around the sun in the plane of the solar equator.* Wo\nactually observe it to reach over the orbit of the earth, making\nan angle with its plane of only 7 1-1 degrei s. It is not difficult to place it in such a situation that the earth shall come\nvery near to the skirls of it at least. We should, indeed, expect this meeting of tho two bodies lo take place at the nodes\nof the solar equator, and therefore in December anil Jiint\ninstead of November and April. It is easily conceivable,\nhowever, that the aphelion of the Zodiacal Light, at which\nplace it approaches nearest to the earth, does not lie exactly\nat the node, but so far from it that the earth passes it a month\nbefore it comes to its node, at which time, moreover; the earth\nis mure than a million of miles nearer to tho sun than its\nmean distance. In endeavoring to fix the periodic time of\nthe meteoric body, since it must be either a year or half a\nyear, (for no other periodic times could bring the two bodies\ntogether at intervals of a year.t) several considerations induced the belief, that half a year was the true period\u2014an\nan inference drawn especially from the apparent great excess\nof velocity of the earth at the point of concourse; but the\nperiod of a year, (or more probably, a little less than a year,)\nby implying that (he two bodies are always comparatively\n\u2022 M,-,-. Coleatf, (lliiwillli-li.) Vol. II. 025,\n\u2022 See. Vol, XXVI. p. lew, of tlii.-t Journal,\nnear to each other, would better explain the occurrence of\nshooting stars at all seasons of the year, and would be particularly favorable to the explanation of those meteoric showers which have on two occasions, at least, j occurred near the\nlast of April,\u2014a time distant about half a year from November, and therefore sustaining a like relation to the opposite\npoint of its orbit. In such a case, meteoric showers would\noccur in April and November, for the same reason that the\nTransits of Mercury take place in May and November exclusively. The grenter frequency of meteors in November than\nin April, naturally results from the greater proximity of the\nearth to the sun at the former than at the latter period; to\nwhich, perhaps, may be added, the effect of the eccentricity of\nthe orbit of the meteoric body, the aphelion being on the side\nof November. In the present state of our knowledge on this\nsubject, 1 regard it as a point open for inquiry, whether it will\nbest accord with the phenomena of shooting stars, to give to\n(lie meteoric bodya period of nearly one year, or of half a year.\nI have been somewhat disappointed, that astronomers should\nhave paid so little attention to the remarkable changes which\ntake place in the Zodiacal light, about the 13th of November, as has been repeatedly mentioned in ibis Journal. It\nippoars to me a fact deserving their attention, that the Zodiacal light, which for weeks before the 13th of November, appears in the morning sky, with a western elongation of from\n00 to 90 degrees from the sun, (while up to that time not a\nlimpseof it can bo caught in the evening sky,) should immediately afterwards appear after the evening twilight in the\nwest, and rapidly rise through the constellations C'apricornus\nand Aquarius, to an elongation of more than 00 degrees\nastward of the sun, while it as rapidly withdraws itself from\nthe morning sky, and within a few days vanishes entirely from\nthe western side of the sun. For three years past I have\nobserved these changes with much interest, and feel warrant) il\nin asserting, that they have been repeated with uniform regularity. The present year, the light was very feeble in the\nmorning sky, an effect partly owing to the presence and peculiar splendor of the planet Venus; hut as soon after the 13th\nof November as the absence of the moon would permit observations, the light appeared in the west immediately alter\ntyillght, crossing the Milky Way, and rising in a pyramid\nalmost as bright as that, the triangular space between it and\nthe Galaxy, embracing the Dolphin, appearing, by contrast,\nstrikingly darker.\nI can account for this great and rapid change of place in\nthe Zodiacal Light, a change which is unlike any it sustains\nat any other period of the year, only by supposing, that on or\nlbout tho 13th of November, it comes very near to us, and\nthat we pass rapidly by it, thus giving it a great parallactic\nmotion, an effect which is in perfect accordance with all our\nprevious conclusions.\nAccording to this view of the subject, the Zodiacal light\nwould no longer be regarded as. a portion of the sun's atmosphere, but as a nebulous or comrjary body, revolving arounil\n: In Virginia, tin.I various othor purls of tin- llnitfil Slates, In 1803, anil in Prance\nt looo,   Malum,' suitable allowances for i]\\t- more rapiil progross of tint eartli\nthrough the winter signs, ami fin- the change of style, ami the nfeteorleshower el\n26lhofAprll,^095, occurred at very nearly the opposite point of tho earth's orlili\nVol,.  I.\u2014I,","fullrs":{},"find":"371.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"370","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1729138","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.65 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
