<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/509</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>509</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/509/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"148\nSOUTH-WES T E K N   JOURNAL.\nIhe height of from five to thirty feet, for the purpose of pro\ntecting the. low lands from the inundation of the. river. Yet\nin no instance hive: they produced yellow fever among those\nwho were engaged in the work, or in others; although the\nlaborers, in many instances, were unucclimtited Irishmen and\nGermans, who would be most liable to the disease.\nOn the other hand, some medical men of eminence have\nbecoino satisfied that fresh exposed earth is decidedly healthy,\nand is in some degree a protection from infectious diseases.\nIn addition to the facts stated by Dr. Rush, it is the opinion\nof Dr. Tilion,\" before cited, that the infection in a city might\nbe arrested in some degree, by covering the streets freely\nwith fresh dug earth, by which the miasm might be absorbed, or neutralized, Ho says, that persons fleeing from yel\nlow fever, as well as those laboring tinder it, are less apt to\ncarry with them imd accumulate an infecting air. in tents and\nopen grounds, than in wooden houses with plunk floors; and\nthat diit floors in wooden houses arc preferable to plank.\nHe gives this opinion as the result of extensive observation.\nHe thinks that pure: eurtl) is the best purifier of infectious\nclothing, and articles of any kind, as has been frequently experienced from burying such articles for a short time in the\nground.\nAs wo conceive the epidemic yellow fever of Washington\nin 1825, to be n branch of the Natchez epidemics, we will\nis history and origin. It may bo proper to\nhington is an inland town, six miles east of\nrolling; or undulating lands, about fifty feet\nlite of the city. It is a village thinly scat-\ntccts, of which the middle one is a mile in\nwidth of the town is nearly half a mile.\ngive a sketch of i\npremise, that Wc;\nNatchez, on high,\nhigher than the :\ntend over throi si\nlength; the entire\nIt is remote from any marsh or stagnant water; only a small\nbranch of running water passes within a quarter ol a mile\nof the Main street, The population, previous to the epidemic\nof 1825, Mas about four hundred whiles, and about one hundred blacks. Tho bouses arc mostly detached, surrounded\nwith open grounds and commons, and finely shaded by the\n\"Pride of China.\" During the first fifteen days of September,\n1S23. while the town was crowded with the people and goods\nfrom Natchez, ihe population must have been nearly double\nthe ordinarj number, or about eight hundred or one thousand\nsouls, besides the unusual number from the country, whoso\nbusiness was done altogether in Washington. For this pur-\npose, large quantities of dry goods, blankets, &amp;c, were carried out for ihe loll-mid winter use of the planters; besides the\nbeds, bedding, &amp;c, taken out by aboul forty families,! who\nwere crowded into every vacant apartment that could be procured in private houses; and often temporary partitions were\nerected to make separate apartments of one room. -Several families kept boarding houses, which were crowded by\nclerks and young men from Natchez. The town has no\nlarge manufactories of any kind, whore animal or vegetable\naccumulations could take place, nor are the houses crowded\ntogether, so as to accumulate the materials of common citv\nfilth.\nPreviously to the. present epidemic, Washington had been\n\u2022 Med.-Repos1, 111., p isa to 131,\n' Med. Kecurd, v x., p. ss?.$\nnoted as a healthy retreat from the yellow fevers of Naithtz\nand that disease never spread among the citizens before- ai.'\nthough there hud previously been numerous cases and death,\nfrom yellow fever brought from Natchez. High grades of\nfever have and do still occasionally appear in the village during the mouths of August and September, but nothing li]\nyellow fever, unless it has been contracted in Natchez: nor\nhns the number ofensos previously introduced from Natchez\never infected the air of ihe village. It is but justice testate\nthat Dr. Branch, one of the oldest practitioners in the com,,\nty, declares that in the fall of 1821 there were a nnmber of\nsporadic, cases of yellow fever in Washington, although there\nwas no epidemic in Natchez at that time. Thoso cases lelid\nnot witness, but I have occasionally, within the last fifteen\nyears, seen sporadic, case's of yellow lever in the vicinity, when\nno epidemic prevailed in Natchez: bin they were always the\ncffecls-of extraordinary fatigue or exposure lo ihe sun at that\nseason, or of being (or .several hours among tho boats ai the\nNatchez landing in tho hot sun. During the first two weeks\nof September, 1825, there was no violent grade of fever\nin the; town, until it broke out as yellow fever about the\n15th.\nSuch was the condition of the place, win n the yellow ftier\nin Natchez, caused the citizens to seek refuge in Washington and the surrounding country, On the 1st and 2d dnysof\nSeptember, the latter place became crowded wilh ihe people\nand goods from Natchez. During the first ten days of September, there were about ten cases of yellow fever in Wash\nington, and several deaths ; all of which were unequivocally\ntraced to Natchez as tho source of .their infection. During\nthis time, there were also fresh supplies of goods brought\nout, and it free intercourse kept up with the city by ibose who\naffected not to fear the disease. On the loth of September\nthe first case of the Washington fever occurred, and five days\nafterwards the disease was considered epidemic; when ihe\ngreater part of tho proper inhabitants, as well as those frcm\nNatchez, deserted and fled to the country; but many of those\nfrom Natchez returned to the city, believing the epidemic\nthere bad subsided. In the first out-breaking ef the Washington fever, the inhabitants of Natchez wore much less liable in it than those of Washington. The disease prevailed\nwith great malignity among the citizens of Washington who\ncould not leave, as will as among those who contracted the\ndisease before they left the town, until ihe change of wealhcr\nand frosts about the 28th of October. After this change,\nthere were no now cases in Washington, until after the return\nof the inhabitants during the first week of November. Between the 1st nnd 10th of this month, about ten cases occurred, and only in those who returned to town after nn absence\nof five or six n eeks, Of these ten cases, five proved falal en\nthe fifth and eighth days.\nThe whole number of deaths by the Washington fever,\nfrom the 18th of September to the 12ih of November, was\nabout sixty ; and the whole number of cases were about one\nhundred and twenty-five. Out of the proper inhabitants of\nWashington, about forty died.\nTo many, the cause of epidemic yellow fever in such a\nclean, healthy village as Washington, is unaccountable.    Dr.","fullrs":{},"find":"510.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"509","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1759134","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
