<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/490</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>490</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/490/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"Ill\nS 0 n T IT -W E S T E R N   JOUR N AL.\nmilitary operations would be lost. Here, there is no time\nfor discussing the wisdom or expediency of tt command,\u2014no\ntime for wordy contests between the \" letter\" and \" spirit\" cf\nthe law, which regulates relative duties, lest ihe moment for\nexecuting be lost, in dispute about the manner. Orders must\nbe instantly obeyed, and during the leisure which may succeed, discuss their propriety: for each officer is amenable\nto a tribunal of his fellow-soldiers for every movement. That\na course of training is necessary to implicit obedience, everyone knows who has examined his own repugnance to being\nordered. Many of our Southern youth find it accord very\nill with their preconceived notions of liberty and courtesy,\nto do nothing as they choose, and be commanded, in an imperious manner, in the military academy. And we have often\nheard tin; Southern \"Pleib,\" (as the entering cadet is called,)\nlo say, on return from a drill in which he has figured most\nclumsily, that \"he would have performed ten times better, if\nhe had been asked or invited in a gentlemanly manner.\" Yet,\nby continued habit, cadets are so accustomed to orders on\nduty, that to substitute courteous invitation, would appear ns\ninsincere and ridiculous, as orders had originally seemed imperious and insulting.\u2014A second and equally important object, is, to instil habils of promptitude nnd punctuality,\u2014the\ndoing of every thing precisely at the lime and in the manner\nprescribed, without special command. And the regular recurrence of duties in military- schools, without the possibility\nof evasion, is strangely efficient in eliciting such habits. And\nso deeply arc; they incorporated into the character, that they\ninsensibly ramify into nil the business of civil, as well as of\nmilitary life. Again: warfare always exposes more or less\nto privation and hardship, which, without iniatory training,\ncould be borne but nt the expense of health and efficiency,\nund oftentimes of life'. To subsist upon the coarsest, least,\nand most indifferent provisions, and at the same time perforin\nthe most arduous duties; lo breast the severity of winter's\ncold and summer's heat, to be exposed to loss of sleep, drenci:\ning rain, or parching thirst, and yet to peisevere with assich\nilyand twin aridity, in the discharge of duty\u2014because his\ncountry, his own beloved country, demands it\u2014these are a\nfew of tho hardships to which the soldier's life is exposed\nThe illustrious Washington, (with becoming reverence be\nthai name pronounced,) experienced them nil in their most\nafflicting form; and saw many of the nobles! patriot hearts\nsink beneath the struggle, for lack of early training to exposure; and it was then that he formed those resolutions and\nprinciples, upon which was founded, at a later day, the Unit\nStates' Military Academy.\nYet every capability of physical endurance were attained\nto no purpose, if the principles of the possessor be radically-\nwrong. He must be enlisted, heart as well as hand, in the\nservice of bis country\u2014he must be actuated by loftier views\nand nobler patriotism than pecuniary gain can inspire; and\nhe must feel his bosom thrill with the pride and daring of\ngenuine soldier, at every call of his country for his service\nTo excite these emotions, and establish these principles, foim\nanother object of military education; and this is effected by\nmodels of greatness and devotion to country, taken from the\nhistory of all  nations, but chiefly of his own.    Who that\never knew a soldier's pride, can rend the biography of a PU|.\nnam, or a (hot n, a Washington, or a Bolivar, a Cincinnati!!\nor Leonidas, without one emotion, or wish to resemble them,\nBy observing and celebrating national festivals, to the meiI.0.\nry of glorious deeds; and with song, and jubilee, and inar-\nial pomp, commemorating the virtues of the immottal dead'\nby waving the banners under which patriots have fought for\nbleeding liberty, and marching lo airs that freshen ihe memory of triumph in battle,\u2014by these the flame of patriotism ij\nenkindled in the youthful soldier's bosom,\u2014a flame which\nburns til! the lamp of life flickers out.\nIn connection with the objects of military institutions, we\nshall insist upon the utility of these objects; a task which\nwere superfluous, but for the strange hostility, recently gotten\nup, in quarters whence more enlightened views might be n-\npected.\nAll who read the correspondence of Washington, (andib\nI not give offence by supposing there are any present who do\nnot 1) will remember bow often he repeats und laments the\ndifficulty of obtaining military engineers. He writes lo every quaiter, offering almost any compensation, and ordering\nthose who have the acquirements, wherever found in llie army, to be released from every oilier duty, to supply the imperative demands of the service. How often does he attribute\ndisaster to want of fortifications, the means of scientific attack, ignorant artillerists, and undisciplined, though brave\ncommanders? Ami it was at a time when our country was\nbeing blessed with the first fruits of dear-bought liberty, and\nenjoyed the fairest prospect of permanent peace, that he insblttl\nupon the establishment of a school for the education of officers. His ndvice was always prudent\u2014the result of reflection;\u2014in this case experience had made him wise.\nThe profession of military engineering is one which few\nwill learn for the chances of employment, when his country\nmay go to war; and civil engineers, if even these were pin.-\nty, are, in most cases, inefficient substitutes. For scientific\nartillerists there is no substitute: for few citizens are led by\nbare curiosity to analyze the parabolic curve described by a\nshell, or the exact mathematical force required to throw a\nball of known dimensions to a given distance. In the derailment of military surveying and drafting, wo should never,\nperhaps, find an expert hand that had not been trained on purpose. The ordinary drawer of pretty landscapes would\nserve bul to mislead and confuse. It is to one trained lo the\nobservation of thoso minute and evanescent irregularities,\nwhich are usually deemed plain, and to such only, thnt can\nbe entrusted the correct representation of grounds; and lo the\nperformance of such a task, a much more thorough know-\nledge of the principles of his art, are essential, than is voluntarily learned. Correct representation in drawing, is a means\nof improving the observation, and correct draftsmen, alone,\ncan be entrusted with the proper recollection of grounds for\naction.    It thus becomes important, that all military officftl\nshould bo well taught in the science of\nperspective.\nand ibe\ndrawing dependent upon it. \u00bb An action is often fought b)f\npositions,\u2014by means of manoeuvres based upon features ol\nground apparently the most trivial. And if he who has never\nimagined any other proceeding in battle, than that a few thou-","fullrs":{},"find":"491.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"490","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1874673","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
