<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/498</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>498</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/498/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:54">{"title":"Page 12","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"i*\u00ab.'\n[ti    ',.(*.\nHI\n122\nS 0 U T II -W E S T E R iN   I 0IJRNAL.\nchariot, the rolling thunder the noise of its wheels, and the\nflashing lightnings the breathings of its steeds. From long\nhabit and association, wo forget that this phrase, which wo\nthus personify, is mere metaphor, strictly speaking an empty\nname, adopted by figure of speech, simply to express tho fuel,\n\u2014not to account for it\u2014of the uniformity of what wc call\nthe operations of Nature. Wo forget that law implies an\nexecutor, supposes an agent, without which the law is destitute of all value, has no efficiency, can havo no existence.\nWere this not the case, we should feel, that what wecall \" laws\nof nature,\" are but expressions of a fact, and that the: divine\nagency must pervade the whole universe, causing and direct-\ning every change, producing all motion, harmonizing all\nevents. With this theory the language of scripture most\nfully accords; it is indeed one of its most prominent doctrines.\nThe beautiful and sublime scriptural representations of the\nDivine power and agency, though often dressed in the garb\nof poetry, wear not the less tho garb of truth, God rideth\non the wings of the wind;\u2014the clouds are his chariot, the\nlightnings are his arrows. Tho raging tempest is bul the\nbreath of his nostrils; tlio winds of heaven are bul his breath,\nand the roaring thunder but the sound of his voice. At his\napproach the earth trcnibleth, the foundation's of the hills arc\nmoved; he; toiiclieth them and they smoke. His pavilion\nrour 1 about him are dark waters and thick clouds ol the\nskies. At his presence, the mountains flow down. He cov-\nereth himself with light us with a garment. With Him is\nterrible majesty; tho whole earth is full of his glory.\nYes, Clod is an every where present Being\u2014an all-pervading, all-directing Spirit. Every operation of nature,\nevery thing which wo witness around us, speaks, in a loud\nvoice, of his existence, proclaims that He is here. \"His\npresence, his spirit is in the air we breathe; our life and our\nbeing are with Him.\" The doctrine of a divine Providence\nrests upon a firm and sure foundation. God is \"our Father\nin heaven\"\u2014but wheic is the meaning of this language\u2014\nv, by are wo directed to go to him in times of danger and\ndistress, to make known to him our wants anel our trials, if\nhe is indeed the far-off Being, which philosophical theories\nwould make him? If this world is one vast machine, kept\nin million, by an inherent or imparted power, and not by the\nimmediate agency of the Deily, what are the inward promptings, teaching the untoward barbarian, in seasons of peril to\nlilt up his eye to heaven, and pour out his heart's desires in\nthe ear of the Great Spirit, but delusion? What is tho language of Scripture, which points to God as \"the giver of\nevery good and perfect gift,\" and assures us, that without his\nnotice not a sparrow falleth to the ground,\" and that even \"the\nvery hairs of our heads are all numbered \"\u2014what is this language but bitter mockery?\nEstneDel scdes nisi terra, et ponttis, et aeVr,\nEt caelum, cl virtus 1\nJ. B.\nTranquility of Mind.\u2014A  pervading tranquility is\ngenerally the characteristic of tl.e first order of minds, as\nrestlessness is of the second. The planets twinkle?, the fixed\nstars shine with unbroken steadiness\nFEMALE INFLUENCE.\nA Lrc.leirc dell' erccl In the Mnsonlc Hull, Nalchez, MarollMth, tic-lore ll.c Uj.\u201e,,\nInstitute eiiiu Lyceum,   lly a. v. II. fossss, Esq.  [Published by request.]\nInfluence, like knowledge, is power, It gives to one ihe\nforce and the ability of many : and, as influence is often invisible to the superficial spectator, who looks only at the effects\nand the proximate agents, it becomes the duty of philosophy\nto trace all actions up through the; various agencies to the\nfirst cause. In doing this, the student of mind is often astonished to find, that some of the most illustrious deeds emblazoned on the pages of history, though achieved by the ruder\nand sterner sex, were yet the direct results of female influ.\nenco.\nIn accordance with the high example of tho Reverend\ngentleman* who delivered the first and foundation lecture before the Ladies' Institute and Lyceum, I shall strive lo make\nthe few remarks I havo the honor to present, on a topic so\nreplete with interest, and before an audience so intellectual\nanel accomplished, as practical as the nature of the subject\nwill permit;\u2014at least, so far as to blend the \"utile, cum dub\nc.c.\" I am aware: that the Lecture on the \" Importance of\nFemale Education,\" embraced the; subject I have chosen, as\none of its corollaries. Tho importance of Female Edtica-\ncation was argued in view of the Influence the sex must\nwield, whether for weal or wo. In selecting it, therefore, os\nmy theme, I only design to do homage to a master spirit, by\nbuilding on his foundation, and adding, if eve:r so little, something to the edifice'of moral beauty, which he contemplated\nas tho result of Female; Education,\nOf the Importance of Female Education there can be no\nquestion; of the power of Female Influence not a doubt.\nShould a philosopher unbosom the motives that actuate a favored youth just coming upon tlio stage of life; show ihat\nhis earliest aspirations contemplated the favor of a mother, a\nsister, or some loved one, whose happiness ho supposed either\nto be connected with, or promoted by his success; and should\nit be discovered that tho ardor of his spirit was kindled al the\nshrine of female virtue and beauty;\u2014that the vision, whether\nnear at hand or more remote, of female loveliness, beamed in\nupon the loneliness of his midnight study, and seemed lo\nsmile over his feverish and passion-tossed couch, summoning\nhim again, with the first gray streak of dawn, to climb the\nrugged steeps of science, promising him the reward for which\nonly he sighs, when he shall have entered into the proud\ntemple of fame which shines afar;\u2014should bis eagle eye he\ndetected, at the moment he was grasping the highest college\nhonors within his reach, resting fondly on some loved form\nin the audience assembled to do homage to his genius, borrowing inspiration from her glance of approbation and pride;\u2014\nshould he be followed in after life, and should it be discover-\nthat the same guiding star shone over his pathway, cheering him in the stormy debate, or lighting him in the arduous\npursuit of wealth, as the divinity of his fortune, before whom\nbo would willingly accumulate the gold of the Indies, if'1\nmight promote her happiness; nnd, at last, should he he\nfound, when about to leave this world of trial and struggle.\n&gt;&lt; 0. Winchester","fullrs":{},"find":"499.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"498","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1805183","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.72 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
