<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 25</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/581</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>581</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/581/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 25","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"The antiquarian discoveries made in Mexico during the\npresent century arc of equal interest nnd importance to the\nliterary world, ns are those made in Egypt, and of course\nshould be of greater to the present inhabitants of America.\nAnd it is somewhat singular that thoso discoveries in both\ncountries, lead to precisely the same results\u2014almost demonstrably proving that the same people originally built the ancient monuments of Egypt and Mexico. The style of building is alike; the portraiture of men is similar; the emblematical devices of primitive worship are very generally the\nsame; and the signs of language all but agree, both phoneti-\neal and symbolical. Thai there arc some differences, merely shows tho progress of events in ihe lapse of ages. And\nas Egypt is known to be indebted to the Phenieians for her\noldest architectural and lingual monuments, it may therefore\nbe fairly inferred that so also is Mexico : und consequently\nit may be concluded that ihe Phenieians were the original\ncolonists of America.\nTt has been fully proved by various modern wi iters, thai\nthe Cyclopean race, of which were, the Phenieians and some\ntribes of Canaan, carried with them in their wanderings, all\nthe favorite forms of the Pastoral or Cyclopean architecture:\n\"tho pyramids, gateways, triangular or graduated archways\nwithout the keystone, cellular cairnes, unsculptured initiatory caverns, irregular courses of colossal masonry, cylindric\ncolumns, and rock-built fortresses; which (wherever they are\nfound) attest their presence.\" These are found in various\nparts of Europe, Asia and Africa, where history records\ntheir settlement; and found in various parts of Mexico and\nCentral America, where tradition avows their colonization.\nAt the Bureau des Antiquites Mexieaines of Paris, various works have recently been published, describing and depicting several ancient monuments, ccc. lately discovered in\ndifferent parts of what was formerly called New Spain j nol\nonly a republished account of the three expeditions undertaken by captain A.  Dupaix in  1805, '6 and 7, by order of\nthe Spanish government, which is illustrated by Castaneda:\nbut tho works of Humboldt, Del Ris, Ncbcl, Gondra and\nothers.    Pyramids exist in   various places, similar to the\ngraduated ones of Egypt, although of larger base.    Vessels\nof noble architecture and sculpture arc visible at Cholula\nOlumba, Oaxac.a, Miltan and Tlascola.    The mountain  of\nTeseosa is  almost covered with ruins of ancient buildings\n'if a Phenician character.    The ancient town of Palenqiu\nexhibits excellent  workmanship in temples, palaces, mansions and baths; and in the sanctuaries of that town, are\nfound sculptured   representations of idols, resembling the\nancient gods of Syria and Egypt.    In the same ruins, planispheres and zodiacs exist, which indicate extraordinary attainments in astronomy and chronology.    And most of those\nmonuments or  memorials appear to  be coeval   with, and\nsimilar to, the Egyptian, Etrurian, Syrian and Indian antiquities of the oldest date.\nThese probabilities if not proofs arc so strong anel numerous, that wo may safely conclude as Mexican tradition\n(recorded by Cabrena) asserts the aborigines of America\ncame from tho maritime coasts and colonies of Phcnicia\u2014being probably composed chiefly of tho people who were ex-\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n217\npelled from Egypt by Scsostris, those from Canaan by Joshua, and those from Carthage by the Romans. Thai others\nmay have emigrated from the eastern parts of Asia by the\nnorthern straits of the Pacific ocean, at a subsequent period,\nis not improbable; yet it is simply conjectural.\nXT , H. Percy Leonard.\nNew Orleans, Jan.  1838.\nAntiquities of Eovpt.\u2014The Hon. Mr. Buckingham,\nlate member of the British Parliament and moro illustrious\nas an oriental traveller, has communicated to the United States\nMagazine a series of the most valuable papers in relation to\nthe antiquities of Egypt, under the head of \"Recollections of\nEastern Travel.\" From his last number we extract his description of the massive ruins in the vicinity of the Cataract\nof the Nile, and of the famous island of Syene or Assouan,\nwhich has given the name of Siennito to a certain description of granite.\n\"On crossing over to the island of Elephantina, or, as it is\ncalled by the natives, Gczirat Assouan, wo  landed at the\nsouthern extremity, and  climbed  over the  steep reeks by\nwhich it is here defended from the stream.    At this end are\nremnants of a solid quay-work building, founded on immense\ngranite  rocks, sculptured  with hieroglyphics, though  the\nbuilding itself is plain, and may be either of Egyptian, Greek\nor Roman workmanship, having been constructed wilh the\nmaterials of ancient edifices, tho broken and uiicemented ornaments of which, are visible in many detached spots     This\nembanked facing is continued towards the eastern edge ofthe\nisland, opposite the Arabic ruins of Assouan, founded also on\nrocks, and might have been intended to preserve the soil from\nbeing forcibly torn away  by the  stream, which  becomes\nrapid here from its depth and contracted channel.    Two portions of square windows, looking from a gallery toward the\nNile, are the only remains of the building which was about\ntliis massy wall, and the traces of steps communicating with\nthe water may also be seen, though now choked with rubbish,\nus well as iho door by which  they opened into lhc stream.\nFoundations of well built  private dwellings, scattered fragments of sacred edifices, and heaps of rubbish, formed by the\naccumulated destruction of Arabic settlements, cover all the\nsoil, and present a picture of ihe saddest desolation.    Among\nthe known Egyptian monuments, the  first on the south, is\nthe portion of a large gate, of red granite, ornamented with\nsculpture of a coarse style and execution, and beyond it, towards the cast, foundations recently dug up of an extensive\nbuilding which continues all the way to the water, and appears to have communicated with the flight of stairs leading\nfrom the freestone quay and gallery into the river.\nNorth of this, and nearly in the centre of the island, is a\ntemple of small dimensions, but in excellent preservation. It\nconsists of a sanctuary, entered by a portico of two columns,\nand enclosed on each side by a gallery of stpiarc pillars, the\nentrance facing towards the east. Every part of the building is ornamented wilh' considerable care, the subjects are\nvaried, the sculpture excellent, and the coloring beautifully\norcserved in several parts. On the facings of the pilasters,\nwhich form the surrounding gallery, are represented two\nVOL. I.\u2014XIV.\"\n4\nHi\n\u25a0\u2022\ni'u.\n.1\nr\nH_ '","fullrs":{},"find":"582.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"581","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1733653","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.65 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
