<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 2</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2227</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2227</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2227/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 2","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[*]\nBut in considering it, it should not be forgotten that this is an ^\nof advancement and improvement. It was but a few years ago onf\nthat it was said, and the world believed, that the power of steam\ncould not compete with the free winds of heaven in propelling Te8.\nsels to and fro across the ocean. And I am not prepared to say tW\nrailways may not compete with the Mississippi in the transporta.\ntion of merchandise, as well as of travelers.\nTimes have greatly changed -. you all can recollect, gentlemen,\nwhen the price of cotton depended upon which way the wind blew!\nIf easterly winds prevailed so as to prevent the arrival of the cotton\nfleet in Liverpool, up went the staple. Some swift-footed packet\nwas dispatched over with the intelligence, and he who could outride\nthe mail, and reach your markets first, made his fortune. But steam\nand the telegraph have done away with this. There is no mote\nroom for that sort of enterprise, as it used to be called. New-York\nand New-Orleans, with the forked tongue of the lightning, now talk\ndaily together about the price of cotton and every thing else; and\nthere is no more chance for the merchant to display his enterprise\nby getting control of private and peculiar sources of information.\nAll information now as to the state of markets, is common.\nSalem once had command of the tea-trade. Her merchants, ascertaining that the stocks on hand were small, and the sources of\nimmediate supply scanty, would club together and buy up, for a\nspeculation, all the tea in the country. But now, a cargo of tea arrives\u2014the fact is known. The telegraph passes the word fore and\naft through every state, and asks who wants *\nIf Salem merchants should demand one farthing more than those\nof New-York are willing to take, the telegraph would give the order\nto New-York. And so with every other article known to commerce.\nSouthern and Western merchants now, by reason of steam and\nlightning, can stay at home, send out orders, and get from France\nand England their supplies much sooner than a few years ago they\ncould get them from Baltimore, New-York or Philadelphia, ate\nhaving gone there to order them. The consequence is, that Southern\nand Western merchants do this; and there are now in that section or\nthe country, houses engaged in importing from abroad.\nThe fact is, the producer and consumer are much nearer together\nthan they used to be; consequently, the factor docs not keep *\nlarge stocks of former times on hand. He draws from the sources\nof supply just in proportion as the channels of demand arc glutted \u00ab\nfree.\nThe chances of speculation are small, and profits are brought doW\nto the smallest figure.\nAll these circumstances have impressed themselves upon the business of the country, imparted new features to it, and made necessa'I\nimportant changes in the mode and means of conducting it.        .\nThese changes, and the causes of them, have powerful bearn*\nupon the subjects which the Convention is called to take into cons\neration.","fullrs":{},"find":"2228.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2227","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"556728","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.53 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
