<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 02</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/541</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>541</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/541/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 02","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"I\nJS1   \u25a0 .\ni:;i  '' *\nI -   .\ni\nI, '\n! te\".' \u2022\nnil \u25a0\u25a0\n176\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\nii \/'.\n'\u25a0;l '\n.\n\u25a0\nabstractions. There is a guilty heedlessness on this subject\nundeserved by its importance. A modern poet, and wakeful\nsentinel in the camp of literature, relates an anecdote illuslra\ntiveof this incongruity in the use of words, \" When 1 first\nlooked upon the Falls of the Clyde,\" says he, \" I was una\nhie to find a word to express my feelings. At last, a man, t\nstranger to me, who arrived about the same time, said\u2014' How\nmajestic ! '\u2014(It was the precise term, and I turned round and\nwas saying\u2014' Thank you, sir I that is the exact word for\njt'_u.|icii he added, in the same breath)\u2014' Yes, how very\npretty !' \" An old writer deserves much confidence as well\nas much respect. Authorship was not always a trade, and\nthen more was thought of the quality than the quantity of\nmatter thrust into a book. An old book is like apiece of an\ncient architecture;\u2014it possesses a solidity nnd strength that\nyet admits lightness and beauty, and a simplicity which is the\nchief attribute of sublimity.\nFor the objection lo the multiplicity of law books, though\nthere are some palliatives, I acknowledge I have little desire\nto attempt an elaborate excuse. Il is remarkable that while\nin the mechanic arts the ingenuity and genius of modern\nman have been exerted to confine the sphere of his eneigies,\nwithout impairing them, to tho discovery of first principle!\nand active agents, in order to lessi'n toil or to transfer it to in\nanimate nature, and thus to emancipate himsell from the\nwithering curse of manual labor lo little purpose, the re\nverse has been the case in the world of literature. In thi\nwide range of the manufacturing aits, the motto has been\n\"Condensation,\" until the tribute to time and space seems al\nmust annihilated. But the knowledge that belongs lo ihe\nprovince of literature has become spread over a broad and\nbroader field, till like a brilliant light it has become dimmer\nand fainter as you recede from the parent source.\u2014In illustration, observe the characteristics of the literature ofthe day.\nIt may be divided into the utilitarian and imaginative. The\nutilitarian is limited to such works as the Family Libraries,\nPenny Magazines, and periodicals of that class,\u2014cheap literature, appropriately so called. The imaginative swarms upon\nus in the shape of novels and romances, purporting to illustrate society and manners, and works upon popular subjects\ntreated in the same alluring style\u2014light literature, also appropriately so called. Of the latter class there are, indeed,\nsome which recommend themselves to our notice by their\ncorrect sentiment, brilliant imagery, felicity of stylo and commanding and sublime morality. But this number, in comparison with those which are worse than worthless, is so\nsmall that the risk is too great not to include them all under the ban of proscription. .Such species of reading is the\nvery intoxicating draught of literature, anel although, for a\nwhile, it lends its victim, perhaps, an artificial and unsubstantial consequence in the eye of society, it is at the price of all\nwholesome and practical information, and at the sacrifice of\ngood taste and of a true sense of real excellence in art or\nnature. But tho evil is not content to rest here. Tho subtle\nspirit is fast encroaching upon every branch of composition,\nhowever solemn and important, and thus wc find works upon\nlaw, peditical economy, government, and even religion tinctured with this sickly distillation of speculative imagination.\nIt is the deadliest enemy to truth and sober reason, since I\nsides invariably conveying a suspicion of unsafencss a pa\nmirror of th,.\nlicalion of this character is seldom more than a\ncaprices of the writer's mind. The advice to \"reader\nthing,\" may make a ready, but is sure to make a weak mind\nSome run into the opposite error, and attach themselves e\nclusively to one author. Books are like men,\u2014if we stop\nconverse wilh all wc meet, we lose the best part of our tim,.-\nif wo admit the companionship of but one, we shall become'\nlike Johnson's Boswell, the mere literary parrot. Literature\ncan only serve an immediate purpose, when by improvinir\nthe public taste, it elevates the actual lone of society.\nIt would seem not to be much in favor of lawyers thnl\nin almost the only prominent instance where mention occurs\nof them in the scriptures, they appear to little advantage\nWo find one of them, as it is expressed, \"tempting\" thnSa-\nvionr, and endeavoring by artful questions, to confuse lumen\na theological point. But, by the term \" lawyers\" in the sacred writings, must be understood the interpreters of the religious law, many of whom, by the deceptions they practiced on a credulous people, justly brought upon themselves ihe\ndenunciations contained in St. Luke. Still, unhappily, there\nare many lawyers, in later times, who well deserve a similar\nsentence of condemnation. Men who examine and surrey\nthe laws,\n\"As rubbers shops and bouses do,\nTo see where best they may break through.\"\nWho read  the law, as Shylock did his bond, to gratify, in\nsafety, their malignant passions.\nA reproach has fallen upon the law by the very means\nwhich some of ils professors rely upon to secure llieir fame.\nThe eager pursuit of this study often persuades ils votaries\nto neglect others which equally aid and grace the iaiv.\nl'hey forsake polite literature and the arts, and an intercourse with polished society, and, in return, acquire a keenness and shrewdness, which, however useful, is but little ornamental. The law, alone, is like a grindstone, which shar\npens but narrows. Literary men, supposing them lo possess\na preponderance of intellect, should not only qualify themselves to be, but, in every material point, actually be, (ore-\nmost in society and the directors of public taste. A man of\nreal intelligence should be willing to exchange his contempt\nfor the world to compassion. It is this scornful indifference\nthat has abandoned society lo the control of those who are\nwithout legitimate authority, and who hold their commission\nto rule only on the fiat of foolish fashion. The true lawyer\nshould be most the man of tho world. Tho world is lns\nconstant study. He has to do with ils passions, its interests,\nits hopes, its fears, its agonies ! Crime, and folly, and misfortune, he analyzes as the physician scrutinizes a disease-\nhe penetrates and examines every shade, and coloring, and\ndegree, until human weakness, infirmity and vice, in then\nghastly deformity, are as familiar to him as a pictured map.\nThe magician of human life\u2014watch his ceaseless and unwearied efforts, as he searches out every influence thai can\nbe used upon the sympathies of man\u2014now sporting with\u2122\nimagination or arousing tho passions, now remonstrat\"1?\nwith the judgment or appealing to the heart I    Ho wields","fullrs":{},"find":"542.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"541","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1810628","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
