<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/478</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>478</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/478/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL.\nV. \u2022\u25a0; \u25a0\nI.\"'- ,'j\nacter and extent of their studies. Hence, those men who\nhave distinguished themselves in the literary world, were ei\niher trained up to one of the learned professions, or enjoyed\nliterary ease and leisure. We speak now of a general rule\nthere have been, we know, some exceptions. Thoso belonging to the learned professions, have distinguished themselves\nin the line of ihcir profession, by bending all the powers of\ntheir minds, nnd causing all their studies and researches to\npoint to a specific branch of literature, to the comparative\nneglect of all the others. The same remark, as far as it is\napplicable, is true of those distinguished literary men, who\nwere attached to no particular profession. Their talents and\nacquirements commonly shine in connexion with one only of\nthe many departments of learning, to the comparative neglect\nof the others. Now it is not proposed that females should\nprosecute the learned professions, or enjoy literary leisure, to\ntlie neglect of their household duties. There are numerous\naad weighty domestic duties, which devolve wholly upon\nthem, and which they must discharge in a suitable manner.\nAnd it would be as unfair to determine the duties of the one\nsex by those of the other, as to argue from the literary excellencies of the one, the deficiencies of the other. For, besides\nthe field of literature, which is common to both, females are\nrequired to cultivate a branch of knowledge peculiar to their\nsex, and which relates to their domestic duties. Now if we\nestablish a rule of comparison, which will operate to their\ndisparagement, let that rule work both ways, and by it, infer\nfrom their superior knowledge of household affairs, the intellectual and literary inferiority of the other sex. We shall\nthen be convinced of the injustice and absurdity of the rule\nitself.\nIt has been made a question whether or not females should\nstudy the dead languages.    But why not ?    Their exclusion\nfrom the practice ofthe learned professions, is surely no valid\nreason, else it would apply with equal force to literary men\nout of those professions.    If the meaning of (he term education be such as we have defined it, and if the cultivation of\nthe mind be an essential part of education, then a knowledge\nof the dead languages is not the end, but only the means of\neducation.    And if the end be lawful and proper, how do the\nnecessary means become less so ?    We four there is a disposition to regard the education of females, in the same light as\nthat of youth intended for a mechanical trade: and to argue\nthat the knowledge of the dead languages is no more necessary to a female in the discharge of her household duties,\nthan it is to mechanics in the performance of their no less\nimportant functions.    If, indeed, a female is to be regarded in\nno other light than as a house-keeper or a seamstress, the argu\nmentmay have some force : but are they not to be the companions and counsellors of the other sex?    Are they not to\nadorn and improve the society of which they are members,\nand to give life, and form, and polish to the circle in which\nthey move?    We might, indeed, turn the argument against\nthose who use it, and ask, will a knowledge of music, drawing, dancing, &amp;c., increase her ability to regulate her domestic affairs with skill and economy ?    You reply no;   but\nmusic is delightful to tho ear, and painting charms the eye,\nand a graceful movement in the ball-room is a conspicuous,\n103\nas well as a creditable accomplishment. We reply this is all\nselfishness You would educate a female only so far as was\nnecessary to enable her to serve and amuse you. Your own\nconvenience and gratification constitute the end and object of\nher education. This is only polishing nnd jeweling tho\nchains, by which you bind her to the task of serving and\npleasing you. Besides, even if you make the convenience\nand pleasure of the other sex, the standard of female education, it ought to be remembered that the taste and disposition of\nmen vary materially; and that what conduces to the pleasure\nof one, may be insipid, if not disgusting to another. Therefore,\nunless those who have no relish for the refinements of literature are disposed to exclude those who have, from all participation in the pleasures and profits of female society, they\nshould unite with us in endeavoring to elevate the standard\nof female education; which, if it were accomplished, would\ngreatly enhance the pleasure of female society to well educated and literary men, while, at the same time, it would detract nothing from the profitableness of such sociely to those\nof humbler pretensions to learning and intellectual cultivation.\nBut wo advocate the importance of female education, not\nwith the view to the convenience and selfish gratification of\nour own sex, but on the more exnlted ground of their own\ninherent rights and privileges. Wo are at no more liberty\nto shackle their minds, than to fetter their bodies. If their\nducation is to be limited in any case, let it be done by providential circumstances, as it is with the opposite sex : and not\nby a ruthless proscription, not by an ancient and long cherished prejudice, not by the force of a blind public sentiment.\nThese nre the chains by which they have been too long held\nin cruel subjection, and the age in which we live, the nation\nwhere we dwell, the advancing state of society, and our allegiance to the principles of liberty and free enquiry, all demand, with a loud voice, that they should be delivered from\ntheir bondage, and fully enjoy the gills of providence, and the\nprivileges of their being, as moral, rational, and accountable\ncreatures.\nWe say, then, let the study of the dead languages, and of\nevery other branch of literature, be regarded as a lawful constituent of female education\u2014let them especially study the\nLatin language, even it be merely to perfect a knowledge of\ntheir own.\nThe want of a proper and adequate education among\nfemales, often exposes them to contempt, and repels from their\nsociety, men of learning nnd science. It is related of Cas-\nsori's wife, that she destroyed his whole herbarium, by scraping off his dried specimens, for the sake of the paper. It is\nalso related of Peiresc's neice, that she used the epistles of his\nlearned correspondents, in lighting candles.\nA female, who, though ignorant, was anxious to be considered intelligent and literary, once asked of a gentleman,\nwho well understood her character, the loan of the History\nof England. He complied with her request, and sent her\nalso Walker's Dictionary, supposing that she would need the\none in order to understand the other. She, however, read\nthem both through ; and returned them with her thanks, and\nan expression of the pleasure she derived from the perusal of\nMjM-\n1.1 '.1?\nKii\nM\n\u2022 &gt;'-.\n:M'&amp;\n,i;m\n\u00bb1M\nIM\n\u25a0'\nm\n:r\n\u25a0j\nVOL. I. VII.\nI\n1     i!","fullrs":{},"find":"479.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"478","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1773195","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.69 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
