<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/567</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>567</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/567/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:01">{"title":"Page 11","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"ciplcs of either prudence or piety. His life was as full 01\nfollv as his writings are of wisdom, and he might be said to\nhave exemplified one of his own sarcastic, observations that\nthere are some persons who give away so much wisdom,\nthat they seem to have none left for their own use; or the yet\nmore important remark of John Foster, thnt the efficiency of\nof Truth itself depends entirely upon the communion ofthe\nsoul with the God of Truth.\nHis principal work \"The Lacon,\" ihat which is most in-\ndissolubly associated with his name, and is the fairest index\nof his character and nbilities, is one of tho most remarkable\nproductions of our age, ll is a Hook which only the wise\nrvill read, and only the profound can comprehend, Its title\ndeclares it \"addressed to those who think.\" It is an intellectual mine where' every thought is a diamond of the keen-\nest edge and of the purest ray, and where giants may work\nwith their pickaxes and still leave it unexplored ; and yet he\nwho created this mine had nothing in keeping with it\u2014no\nconsistency in morals or in money. lie was the most singular of men\u2014dining on a herring\ncoach in London\u2014wearing a hat soiled and rent wilh years,\nand clothes threadbare, greased and darned with no profes\nsional needle, nnd at the same time carrying in the top of hi;\nsnuff-box, a diamond which was in itsell an independent fortune\u2014preaching part of tho year to his English parishioner.-\nand gambling out the rest in the French metropolis. His inveterate attachment to ibis vice reduced him to beggary,\nwhile his excesses brought on diseases tho most painful and\nrevolting. Suicide closes this contradictory, melancholy history,\nWilh Ihe  mind thronged with  the reflections which will\ncrowd into it, after the retrospect of such a tragedy, can we\nbut ask, where is the consistency of human nature ?    Does\nlhc conduct of man  always  admit of explanation, from the\ntaoivn laws of mind and  motive?    From habit, and proba-\nblythat habit formed upon philosophical truth, we are accustomed to answer this question without hesitation, in the affirmative: although in every ago, instances occur, which throw\nthe whole machinery of accountable action, of motived action\ninlo strange disorder.   Anel in our confusion, we are temp-\nlea to resort to the hypothesis of ancient psychology, that man\nIS inspired of two souls, and that his conduct must be referred\nto that which happens to bo in the ascendant.    But modern\n\u2022iccumcn, and modern conclusions, founded on fact, have sent\ninto the realm  of shades, this shadow of an hypothesis, and\nwe are compelled to return, and re-examine the laws of mind,\ninvestigate new motives and now modes of thought, and attempt a rational Harmonising of the conduct of our fellows,\nWilli the axioms of philosophy.\nNever was there a more confounding instance of tho war\nof reason and of pnssion, and of the fearful triumph of the\n,a\"er, than in the person of the Author of Lacon. In him\nviolence is done, to every principle from which we are accustomed to dale conduct. The spirit of piety wept while she\nadmired, and the fiend of darkness shrank while he rejoiced.\nCalmly loom- eye, did he sit upon the judgment scat of charter, with the dice in one hand and a skull in the other, while\nWore him lay wl-it thoughts of wisdom, extended and pro-\nSOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\n203\nfound; but steeped in the gall of human hate, and gleaming\nWith the glare of a grave yard light.\n_  In word, a statesman, n philosopher, a divine; lo them all\nindeed, a living tic : in letter, almost inspired; inspirit-\nall I what was he ?    Hero minister of a mind diseased, bring\nthy pulse-glass, and tell me the workings of that soul; bring\nthy plummet, stern measurer of human thought, nnd tell me\nits depths: down deep, in the wells of the soul, where the\nstars of heaven  always   pour   their  hallowing light\u2014do\nstreams of-thought there flow, clear fresh and unfailing; or\ndo they send up the stench of tho Tartarian pools?   Oh, the\nheart of man! read not its character in tho varying shades of\nthe brow, the cheek, the eye!    Who would dream of themy-\nrinds of glorious suns that burn in the vault of heaven, when\nstorm, and whirlwinds are wrecking this netherworld, and\nthe vail ofthe sky itself is rent by the jagged lighlningl\nNo, rend not tho character then; but rise into the upper air\nand open thine eyes wide that visions of glory may break\nover thy soul.    Go \"a  winged traveller  from  mount  to\nand keeping a splendid mount through cloudland,\" into tho depth\/ess empyrean, and\nlet thy senses drink in the light nnd music which are there\nthe atmosphere of life!\u2014then read me the character of earth\nand sky.\nThe religious hypocrite is not alone in his hypocrisy; the\ngarb of piety is not the only cloak assumed or rejected at th*\ndictate of circumstances. The blinking heart often mantles\ntho cheek with a blush; bitter thoughts are often wreathed\nimid words of sweetness. So was it here. Cotton played\nhis most phantastical parts while his feelings were breaking\nover his heart \"like a sunless ocean surging over a dead\nworld.\" What were his thoughts then? Remorse and disgust for hinisi If, and contempt lor the' open-mouthed million\nwho gazed after him, some in wonder and awe, nnd some in\naffected superciliousness. Follow him aAer a midnight debauch, returning with n brain on fire, to the privacy of his\nown chamber and of his own mind; watch him till thoso\nthoughts of retrospection und of anticipation, which will\nthrust themselves upon us, even in our maddest moments,\ncluster around him like fiend spirits; see his soul struggling\nwith the fetters he has thrown around her, asserting and exercising for a short hour her acknowledged supremacy.\u2014\nWhat ages of thought and of anguish arc crowded inlo Ihat\nhour! how ho loathed himself, cursed his existence, anel desperate, looked open-eyed into the gulf of suicide, the gulf of\nhorror!\nAnd did ho wish for annihilation? oblivion in this world\nand the next? No! trembling as ho was on the verge of\nmudness nnd of hell, he would risk both, rather than bo forgotten, forgotten too by those whom he despised I Oh ! the\nhorrors of oblivion I of falling into tho \"dark backward and\nabysm of time! \" What thought can strike with a more palsying shock upon the soul, whose origin is heaven, whoso\nheritage is eternity, than that of\n ie dying like a dull worm to rot,\nThrust foully In the earth lobe forgot.\"\nThis has driven the chariot wheels of the conqueror; this\nhas caused blood to spout beneath his iron-hoofed war horse.\nAnd this has caused the student, when he might have floated\n:;:\n1","fullrs":{},"find":"568.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"567","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1783346","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
