<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
      <title>Louisiana Ecology and Conservation, The Percy Viosca Jr. Collection</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate"
        authority="naf"
        authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
        valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83230635"
        displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
     <namePart>Louisiana Sea Grant College Program</namePart>
     <role>
        <roleTerm type="text"
                  authority="marcrelator"
                  authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                  valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
     </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <note type="content" displayLabel="Collection Description">&lt;p&gt;While employed by the Louisiana Department of Wildlife and Fisheries, Percy Viosca, a pre-eminent herpetologist, documented the coastal Louisiana landscape between 1921 and 1932. He traveled the state for his work that included mosquito control, riparian and marshland studies, flood control, taxonomic work with native Louisiana irises, newts, and snakes, culture of crawfish and environmental impact of oil refinery practices. The images in this collection document locations on or near the Louisiana coast and a few sites inland. All images refer to water quality, water control, or environmental conditions affecting water quality. The age of these images provides a rare opportunity to compare identified areas within Louisiana across an 80 year span. The processing and digitization of this collection was supported through a regrant from the Louisiana Sea Grant College Program.&lt;/p&gt;</note>
  <abstract displayLabel="Collection Summary">&lt;p&gt;While employed by the Louisiana Department of Wildlife and Fisheries, Percy Viosca, a pre-eminent herpetologist, documented the coastal Louisiana landscape between 1921 and 1932.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Collection ID">lsu-sea-pvc</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Search)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/search/collection/LSU_PVC</identifier>
  <identifier type="local" displayLabel="Migrated From (Landing Page)">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/LSU_PVC</identifier>
</mods>
