<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2087</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2087</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2087/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:44">{"title":"Section 2, Page 23","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"23\nand its products arc estimated at one hundred millions of dollars. This change has taken place within my time, within\n1 all' a century ; and all this, fellow citizens, has been achieved\nhi American enterprise, by American industry, under this\ngreat and glorious Union. Who would not be proud to be\none of its citizens?\nIn conclusion, fellow citizens, I have only to say that, the\nonly thing that should be required to induce you to embark\nin this tri-eat work of internal improvement, will be the assurance that the necessary capital will be furnished, and that\nthe work will be carried out in good faith. It would be a\nproud day for me to see it finished. I may contribute towards the building, but my age precludes the hope that I can\nrealize much benefit from it.\nI thank you for your kind attention and marks of appro-\ndation to those desultory remarks.\nJudge Moore took his scat amid loud applause.\nGovernor Mouton, being loudly called for, was\ndetermined not to tire the patience of the Convention by a long speech.\nHe liked the way things had thus far been conducted. It augured well for the contemplated project. Speeches will not make railroads, and as to\nacts, we, of the country, are in earnest. Our people\nbelieve in the feasibility of the contemplated road,\nthey believe that the business which would spring\nup, would be amply sufficient to furnish it an ade-\nqnate support, and so believing, they are willing to\ncontribute their full quota of the funds required for\nits construction. Full of this faith and these assurances, they say, tax us ! Tax us, because we are\nsure that the result will be to our advantage. Tax\nus, because we are willing to hazard  something","fullrs":{},"find":"2088.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2087","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"512368","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.49 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
