<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/489</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>489</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/489/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:53">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOU T H -WES T E R N   J 0 U R N A \\,\n.and men, in long straight lines, march up towards each other,\nand fire in each other's faces, until a sufficient number on one\n\u00abide is killed, to give up the victory to the other,\u2014were told\nthat the best map-maker, ceteris paribus, would gain the battle he would probably suppose wo were sporting with his\ncredulity. Let him remember, (or read,) how Napoleon\nfought the actions of Moskwa and Leipsic.\"\nIf then it be granted that each nation should keep forces\nalways prepared for its protection; (and who dare deny this?)\nand if it be impossible, as we have shown, to obtain competent officers for the various duties and departments of warfare,\nthe necessity of military schools for their education will\nfollow.\n* # \u2666 \u00ab a \u00bb\n\u2022 2dly. We havo promised to show how far the objects of\nmilitary education are effected in several European countries,\nand compare them with our own. In this department, the\nextreme dearth of facts on record, will render my lecture still\nmore barren of interest. The subject of militaiy education\nseems never to have engaged the pen of an able writer; and\n\\ if we except a lew general views in Edgcworlh's \" Profession.\nal Education,\" and an eccentric and paradoxical article in the\nEdinburgh Review of 1820, we have been able to meet with\nnothing on the subject, and in these, wilh a very few facts.\nThe following statements are such as have casually fallen in\nj   my way, and I alone am answerable for their errors.\nBefore the melancholy fall of Warsaw, Poland boasted\nthe most efficient military academy, perhaps, with a single\nexception, in all Europe. The course of studies embraced\nthe classics, as well as mathematics, superadding the modern\nlanguages and line arts. It was accessible only to tho gentleman, who, in Poland, was any one who could trace his lineage 10 royal or distinguished ancestry. From this class, the\narmy was exclusively officered. For the efficiency of their\nacademy, we have but to refer to the actions of that gallant and\ndevoted little band, with iho countless numbers of tyrant\nRussia. In no battle of that Rovoltltion, which has ended\nin the ruin, and almost extermination of the Poles, were five\nhundred Russians equal to one hundred Poles, commanded\nj  by a commissioned officer.   It was in the military department\n' ol the university of Warsaw, that the first blow of resistance\nwas given to the aggressions of the monster, Nicholas. The\nobjects of military education were realized in an eminent degree in Poland, though the northern snows, ever prolific in\nsavage hordes, furnished numbers sufficient to crush her to\ni ihe dust.\nla Prussia, a military school was established by Frederic\nthe great, and nurtured with particular care. How thorough\nwas its course of studies, we have not been able to determine;\nbut il wc may judge from the taste and acquirements of its\nlearned founder, any course of his appointment was extensive\nraid profound. Such was its influence, says the Edinburgh\nEncyclopadia, that, at the death of Frederic, the Prussian\n\"nay was the finest in the world. Yet no sooner did his\nnephew, Frederic William, ascend the throne, than luxury\nand idleness entered the military academy, and it fell into\ndecay. From this time, we hear little more of Prussian mil-\ni'ary education.\nThe English army has long ranked high among the armies of nations for the bravery and patriotism of its soldiers,\nand the courtly manners of its officers. And perhaps in no\ncase has the influence of court, in an enlightened nation, been\nso great in establishing nn elevated rank for a class of so little mental acquirement. It is certainly a matter of some astonishment, that where deep learning is so abundant and cheap\na commodity,\u2014where the results of mental effort meet so\nprompt and liberal patronage, and where national pride is, in\nso high a degree, based upon Ihe intellectual attainments of\nthe belter circles of society,-\u2014that military schools should\nhave met with such parsimonious encouragement]\u2014ihat such\nscanty means have been furnished, for elevating this large\nportion of the very first circles, to an intellectual equality\nwith those among whom they mingle. \"And if there be any-\ndear friend\" of old England present, wo must beg his indulgence, whilst we describe, as il is, the attention paid to education in the Engligh army. For, as truth, as well as juntico,\nis our object, while wo admit their bravery and patriotism\nequal to that of any other nation, wc must not forget that education is our theme.\nEngland has an independent military college at Mnrlow,\nin which those who anticipate connection with the army, may\nstudy, at their own expense, whatever they may deem worthy\nof their attention.    Suffice it to say of Marlow college, that\nfew students make rare; proficiency here, since it affects very\nslightly the favoritism of appointments, nor gives them title to\nhigher rank or more rapid promotion, than him whose commission is purchased for a few hundred pounds, without the\nbenefit of any education.    At Portsmouth there is a naval\nacademy, where pupils are taught something of mechanical\nnavigation.     Their tuition  is paid  by government, and all\nother expenses by themselves.    Their rank while' here is that\nof an entered mid-shipman; and their time of service, antecedent to a commission, is abridged by as much time as they\nspend in the academy,  never exceeding two years.    Those\nwho know that midshipmen arc entered at the tender age of\nleven to twelve years, must be aware bow limited must be\nthe naval education of two years, and of how little: value is\nthe mechanical knowledge they get of the long and abstruse;\ncalculation necessary in practical navigation.   At Woolwich,\nhowever, there is a military academy supported by government patronage, to which cadets are appointed by warrant,\nand educated lo the number of one hundred and eighty, constantly.   Their instruction, (which embraces all the branches\nessential to a military education,) costs Ihe nation Is Gd each\nper day; and we leave it to the candor of any man to judge\nhow liberal is this expenditure, when we reflect ihat the standing forces of Great Britain amount to more than hnlf a million ; that the number of commissioned officers necessary to\ntheir command, is fully thirty-five thousand; that the vacancies occurring from death, resignation, nnd dismission, amount\nto full ten percent, yearly, which is three thousand five hundred.    If one  fourth of the cadets at Woolwich graduate\nyearly, the institution will fill one vacancy of every seventy-\nseven, a meagre, ridiculous proportion, indeed, of men of military science in that immense body, the Britiih army.    And\nthe results of this melancholy deficiency, are, that their few en-\n\u2022\u25a0 HM\nm\n\u2022 *&gt; it\n\u25a0t%\nm\n\u25a0  ':;\u2022 I'd\n;;\n'\u2022:   '\u2022","fullrs":{},"find":"490.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"489","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1896448","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.81 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
