<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 03</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/508</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>508</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/508/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 03","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T H -WES T E U N  J 0 U R N A I,.\n,it,0ry to sustain; our views are such as are the result of an\niinpicjttdiccd inquiry into the different circumstances of the\niiin'ti V epidemics which have occurred in various cities ofthe\nrjnjted States and of other countries. If the alleged causes\nurenot tho true source of the disease, wo shall at least prevent a false security being placed in such means as really afford no safety; while we urge the necessity of speedy flight\nupon tho first appearance of the pestilence. If it can thus bo\navoided, that fact alone will in some degree disarm it of ils\nterrors.\nWe contend that yellow fever, as an epidemic, is not dependent for its production upon animal or vegetable putrefaction, or upon the union of bolh ; and that when these mat-\ntors have been observed to precede an epidemic, it was only\na contingent, and not essential circumstance.    My views on\nthis subject are ably expressed by Dr. Cartwright, in his essays on the \" Malignant fevers of Natchez.\"    After alluding\nto \"some of the circumstances which are necessary for the\nproduction of yellow fever,\" he observes, \"although yellow\nlever may not occur any two years in succession, yet the effluvia to which it is erroneously attributed, may exist every\nyear in an equal degree.     Effluvia, as mere effluvia, are\ninnoxious, and should  not bo confounded with miasm, which\nis the real cause of yellow fever.    We all know, that when\nyellow fever has become epidemic in a cily,  it continues to\nprevail until it is checked by frost, in defiance of all precautions which can be taken to arrest its progress.    All the ma\ntorials which are in a state of putrefaction, may be removed;\nthe air, before moist, may become diy; the evaporating process may be suspended ; and the mercury may fall  30\u00b0 or\n40\u00b0 below the point at which  it stood when the disease first\nappeared; yet it will continue to prevail after every one of\nits supposed causes have been removed.     *    *    *    If effluvia produce it; if evaporation or moisture produce it; or if\nall these combined produce it; what should give rise to tho\ndisease when  each and every one of those supposed causes\nare removed ?\"    [ Med. Recorder, vol. x., p. 229, 230.    We\nanswer, nothing but a subtle,   invisible, and  imperceptible:\nmiasm, which is produced independently of all such circumstances.    Some have supposed that a peculiar miasm is gen\norated during the putrefactive process, but not necessarily\nfirtid.    In our opinion, neither foetor nor putrefaction are at\nnil concerned in its production : for we have shown that not\neven the putrefiablc materials arc necessary.    The advocates\nof uiiiinnl putrefaction admit thai the epidemic of 1825, \"on\nthe hill,\" was produced without putrid animal matters of any\nbind; and no one pretends to ascribe the epidemics of 1829\n\u00bbnd 1837 to such causes.    These two epidemics are ascribed\nlo city filth, to filthy and wet sewers and back yards; the\nsame causes which were said to have produced the fever of\n1825, on the hill ; causes which were not called into requisition at all in 1823, although the most extensive and fatal\nepidemic which has yet visited the city.    According to the\ntheories heretofore advanced, no two epidemics have ever\nMen produced by the same cause : and upon the same principle, every succeeding epidemic, if we should be so unfortunate as to have others, will depend upon a new cause.    The\ninference is, clearly, that the causes of yellow fever aro innu-\ne leave our readers to determine whether tho\npremises are tenable.\nBut we havo testimony incontrovertible that city filth is\nnot necessary to its production; nor is it at any time on auxiliary cause; us the disease prevails generally when there is\nleast of this existing; nnd often where it is most abundant,\nthere is no yellow fever produced. Dr. Rush1\" even declares'\nthat the city filth in the sewers, alleys, and streets of Phila-\ndolphin, appeared to absorb the pestilential miasm, and thus\nto produce a partial protection against it. He declares that\nluring the memorable epidemic of 1793, in that city, scavengers seemed especially exempt from its effects; as enly ono\nout of forty was attacked with yellow fever. This is confirmed by the experience of Dr. Tilton.f He states that it\nis injurious to remove city filth during an epidemic, ns the\nfilth seems to absorb the miasm, while the exposed pavements\nfrom which it is removed augment the reflection of the solar rays, and increase the miasm. On the same principle, it\nis believed by some, that fresh earth, strewed over the streets,\nmight be beneficial lo a certain extent. A mass of authority\nmight be adduced, to show that common city filth or offal\nis not a cause or source of pestilential diseases. Natchez\nis not more filthy than hundreds of other cities where no yellow fever exists. If city filth wero a cause, we know not\nhow it could ever occur in the cleanly and scattered village\nof Washington.\nWe cannot believe that the removal and exposure of fresh\nearth in digging down the streets and filling up low grounds,\nare essential or even auxiliary to the generation of yellow\nfever miasm.    More or less of this has been done in  Natchez every year; yet, for the last six years previous to 1837,\nthere has been no epidemic yellow fever in the city.   And,\nagain, we know that yellow fever prevails much more frequently, and  more extensively, in New Orleans and  other\ncities, where no such digging is done', or is even practicable,\nExtensive excavations and embankments have been carried\non in different parts of this State,  (luring the last year; yet\nin no case has yellow fever been generated  from it.    One\nrail-road enters Natchez by a deep cut of fifteen or twenty\nfeet; yet that was the most healthy part of the cily during\nthe last epidemic.    The same road passes through Washington, with a cut ten feet deep in the cenlre of the town; and\nwithin one hundred yards are extensive embankments, besides two hundred yards of the main street, which was filled\nup to the depth of about two feet, and two largo lots of one\nhundred and fifty feet square, which were dug down on one\nside and filled up on  the other, to the depth of six or eight\nfeet: yet the health of Washington never was better than\nduring the existence of iho epidemic of 1837 in Natchez,\nrhesame embankments and excavations extend twenty miles\nbeyond Washington, through some of the largest plantations,\nyet not a single case of yellow fever has been produced by\nthem.    Tho same is true of tho rail-roads from Grand Gulf,\nVicksburg, and other  points.    Again, within the last two\nyears, extensive embankments of alluvial earth and vegetable matters, have been made along ihe lower Mississippi, to\nt Med. Repos. v. ID.,11.184.\n' Med. liieruirlH, vol. If. p. 193, edition of IGI5-\nr.'j.\nmm\ni\n'....Vj\nkm\n.-\u25a0 h\n\u25a0m\n.\n\t\n&lt; in","fullrs":{},"find":"509.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"508","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1706845","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.63 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
