<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 11, Page 29</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2401</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2401</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2401/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:57">{"title":"Section 11, Page 29","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"APPENDIX.\nAN  AC T,\nProviding for the subscription, by the parishes and municipal corporations of this State, to the stock of corporations undertaking\nSection 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Louisiana, in General Assembly convened,\nThat it shall be lawful for the police juries and municipal corpora-\ntaking works of internal improvement, under the laws of this State,\non complying with the provisions of this act.\nSec. 2. Be it further enacted,  Sfc,  That all ordinances passed\n1st. A statement of the number and amount of the shares proposed to be subscribed; 2nd. The levy of a tax on the landed es-\nthe amount of said subscription, and specifying the rate of the taxation, and the period or periods when it shall be payable.\nSec. 3. Be il further enacted, eye, That no ordinance, passed\nunder the provisions of this act, shall be valid or take effect, until\nit shall have been approved and ratified by a majority of the voters\non whose property the tax is proposed to be levied, at an election\nto be held especially for that purpose, by order of the police jury,\nor municipal corporation passing the ordinance ; and said police\njury or municipal corporation shall prescribe the manner of holding\nsuch election, and shall cause to be furnished to the commissioners\nof the same, a properly certified list of the authorized voters, and\nsuch election shall be preceded by a notice of thirty days, published\nin one or more of the newspapers in the parish or municipal corporation where such election shall be held ; Provided, however, that if\nsuch ordinance shall be rejected by a majority of the voters, it shall\nbe lawful, at any subsequent  period, again to take the sense of the","fullrs":{},"find":"2402.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2401","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"524317","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
