<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 2, Page 10</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2074</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2074</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2074/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:43">{"title":"Section 2, Page 10","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"10\nIbll\nResolved, That a committee, to be called the Permanei\nCommittee of the Opelousas, Attakapas and New Oilcan\nRailroad, be appointed by the President of this convention\nwhose members shall consist of\t\nResolved, That said committee shall be apportioned\namong the several parishes represented in this convention\non lire basis adopted for voting.\nResolved, That they shall procure surveys of the rou\u00ab\nand estimates of the costs of constructing the road, and dt.\nvise the ways and means of defraying the expenses of sail\nsurveys, and estimates of all the preliminary expenditures I\nbe incurred in promoting the objects of the convention.\nResolved, That they shall take the necessary steps to pro]\ncure such legislation as may be required in the premises. I\nResolved, That they shall frame a provisional act of in.\ncorporation, rind apply to the police jury of each parish, am\nto the municipal corporations of New Orleans, for grand\nproportionate to their interest, for the purpose of paying tin\nexpenses contemplated by the fourth resolution, given above\nResolved, That when the company shall be incorporate!\nand organized, said committee shall resign their trust, aw\nplace the said surveys and estimates, with an account!\ntheir expenditures, in the hands of the stockholders or their\nproper representatives, who alone shall have authority \u00bb\nde.-idc the precise line of the road.\nMr. Cohen having read the resolutions addressed\nI he convention in explanation of them in an ckJ\nqueht   speech   of sound   judgment, full   of  stronf\ncommon sense and very useful practical suggestions\nas follows:\u2014\n\"I come here not to dictate, but, as an bumble fellovv-citizeij\nto interchange views, and take counsel together upon a queS\ntion of vast, nay, of vital importance to our beloved State.\nNor do I intend to inflict upon you a speech\u2014and that W\nfour reasons:","fullrs":{},"find":"2075.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2074","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"522953","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
