<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 5</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/366</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>366</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/366/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 5","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T II - W E S T E R N J O 0 1? N A L.\nhope and confidently expect, our meetings here will form a\nsource of gratification now, and a pleasing remembrance\nwhen we shall have been separated by the vicissitudes of life;\nand that our SUCCCSS may In- so brilliant, that we shall he\nproud to have our names enrolled among the founders of the\nJefferson ('oi.i.i-ci: and Washington Lyceum.\nTHE LIMITED NATURE OF HUMAN RESEARCH,\n\\s Ussav, r,-.,il boforo (in- JcnVrson College nnd Washington Lyceum,\n. V,-. M0M8TTH) .'I  U,\nMr, President, and Ladies ami Gentlemen,\u2014The\nPsalmist lets beautifully observed, \" When I consider ihe\nheacens th&lt; work of thy fingers, the moon, ami the stars\nwhich thou, hast ordained, what is man Hint thou nit mindful o\/him?\"\nI low vain lor man to suppose, that nil nature was made\ntor his use; to supply his wants: to minister lo his pleasure;\n&lt;ir to contribute to his exaltation: that all tho grand operations\nof earth and heaven, with all their diversified relations, are\ncarried mi solely for his good; tiny the sun holds his throne\nin tie- heavens, with all his system of planets revolving\naround him; thai (he seasons perform their annual rounds;\nthat tho ample storehouse of naturo's mysteries is provided,\nall for his use! Truly they must have an overweening estimate of man's importance, who can adopt such a conclusion.\nTho whole creation, this as wi II as oilier systems, none\ncan doubt, boars evidence of the wisdom anil goodness of]\n(!od, in adapting every thing, however great or small, to one\n: al .' i. ,\\-:i us:-, as well as to the particular use, nnd happi-\ni. .-   .; \u25a0'.'   individual creatures, constituting tho great chain\n'\u2022 .'\u25a0 ..'-. 'flu's adaptation of parts and uses,is traced,|\ni.t ;,-! :,i.-.i to each other, no', only in the grad :s of animal\na.i.l ,,i' vegetable life, bui also to the greater relations of oni\nplanet to another. Even in the structure of the earth, while\nthe superficial strata are performing an agency i-'.- sustaining\nand perpetuating animal and vegetable life, in tho various\norders which exist upon, or ni ar its surface, we have reason\nto believe, that tie- interior strata, to its c, ntrc, may he elaborating tint powerful, invisible, and mysti rious fluid, which\nholds the earth in its relative station, and regulates ail its\nmotions; while, at the same time, it retains smaller bodies in\ntheir duo relation lo the t arth.\nAil the orders of animals, from the largest down lo the\nsmallest; from tho Megatherium of an antediluvian world,\ndown to tho thousands ol animalculrn, which swarm in a\ndrop of water, or cluster in a fragment of rock ;\u2014seem formed fir their own happiness; to lill up the grades in creation;\nnnd lo sustain other orders of being. Each is governed by\nits own peculiar laws; each derives support from oilier orders\nof animals, alive or dead; while it, in turn, affords sustenance for others.\nin each component particle of mailer there arc certain\nlaws, or certain rules of adaptation by which each particle is\nconstituted an independent whole, nnd yet is a pari of another\nwhole; to which ii, bears its proper relation. Even in a matin matical point of view, take up Ihe most irregular piece of\nmatter, and it will be found to have, mysteriously interwoven\nin it, an almost unlimited series of squares, cubes, rhombs,\nspheres, and cones; and yet it extermally exhibits no evidence ol\neither of those figures. How many laws of matter may he-\nconcealed in like manner from our view, we know not; and in\nmost instances, even whore we think we know all, we know\ncomparatively nothing.\nIn relation to tile facts, the agencies, influences, or laws regulating the operations and existences of all the bodies in\nnature, man, who is but an atom in creation, with his limited\nnumber of senses, can expect to acquire a knowledge of only\na few fads, and a few principles. Even the towering geniuses of such men as Bacon, Locke, Kepler, Newton and Laplace, could obtain only faint glimpses, of a few, comparatively, of tho profound mysteries involved in the economy ol\nihe world. The great mass, the wide fields of knowledge,\nlay beyond their reach, locked up as in an impenetrable arcanum from the scrutiny of man.\nA knowledge of the laws, which regulate matter and spirit,\nso fiir as man can truce them, is called science; the attainment of which, however difficult and abstruse, constitutes one\nof the greatest intellectual pleasures which we can enjoy.\u2014\nTin- pleasure of discovery is in direct proportion lo the increased difficulty of investigation, if our minds could seize\nupon principles and hidden facts with that perspicuity, which\nangels may possess, constituted as we are, the interest, the desire of knowledge, the novelty of discovery, the pleasure of\ngratified curiosity would not he ours. The vigorous intellect would sink into satiety and inglorious indolence. For tho\ngreater tho mystery, the more a subject is hedged in with\nuncertainty and doubt; where hypothesis upon hypothesis is\nexhausted in the solution, the more attractive is it lo the restless genius of man. His mind is continually in search of\nsomething intricate for its operation, some difficulty to unra-\nvt 1: for strange as it is, his mind seems disgusted with simplicity in all its forms, and turns to investigate something\nmysterious, merely because it is mysterious.\nBut how humiliating lo human pride, to know that ihe\nmost splendid acquirements, made by the most towering groins, have only been able lo ascertain, in part, a few of the operations carried on in the universe I When we attempt to pry\ninto the causi s of the order and operations oi nature, we perceive, beyond what at first appeared causes, still other causes\u2014\nmystery upon mystery, extending in endless susscession, lar\nbeyond the reach of our limited faculties. In the search\nman's strongest intellect might advance, were it possible, with\nunabated ardour, through all lime, and slill not have entored\ntlie vestibule of Ihe great temple of absolute knowledge. Hovr\nhumiliating to our self pride, to know, that o( us, who probably boast of our knowledge of sciences, of arts, or of a few of\nihe languages of this babbling earth, not one in a thousand\nshall ever attain that exalted stand, which hut few have attained, to know how ignorant we are, and how unbounded is the\nheld of science beyond our reach.\nThe most perfect knowledge wo possess of any science, pertaining to thonatural world, is but superficial and imperfect at\nbest: we only perceive tho plainer ' its, and the coarser processes, while the more subtile, tho more intimate, escape our\nfew and imperfect senses, just as air eludes our vision. The\nessential properties of mailer and motion escape our perceptions unobserved, as in the external world we behold a kw","fullrs":{},"find":"367.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"366","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1739493","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.66 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
