<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 6, Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2208</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2208</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2208/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:49">{"title":"Section 6, Page 11","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[11]\nolved That a committee of three be appointed by the chair to addresB to\n7tfloneresB of the United States and to the Legislatures of the separate state b,\ntiie menials in support of the principles contained in these resolutions.\nCeo\"motion of Mr. J. T. Trezevant, of Tennessee, tbe resolutions presented by\nhirnvrere referred to the Committee on Routes.\nOn motion, the Convention adjourned until to-morrow.\nFriday, January 9,1852.\nMORNING SESSION.\nThe Convention met at half-past ten o'clock, a. m., Vice-President A. Fowler, of\nArkansas, in the chair.\nThe minutes of the 7th and 8th instant were read and approved.\nThe following, offered by Mr. R. J. Ranney, of Louisiana, was unanimously\nadopted:\u2014\nResolved, That a committee consisting of one member from each of the states\nrepresented in this Convention be appointed by the President for the purpose of\nrecommending (alter consultation with managers and engineers of the various\nrail-roads already made and in operation, or in progress towards completion,) the\nmost suitable and proper gauge or breadth between the rails, with a view to its\nadoption for all the rail-roads which \u2022 may be constructed in the Southern and\nWestern States.\nMr. W. N. Burwell, of Virginia, chairman of the Committee on Routes, presented the following:\u2014\nResolved, That the Committee on Routes regard the following Bystem of\ninternal improvements as not only indispensable to the development of the agricultural, commercial and mineral wealth of the Southwestern states and cities, but\nalso as essential to the equality and unity ofthe states of this Confederacy ; and\nthey earnestly recommend the same to the patriotic consideration ofthe legislature and citizens of the Southwestern states.\n1. A national road to the Pacific ocean ; with one terminus on the Mississippi\nBiver north, and one south of the mouth of the Ohio River, so as to divide the advantages of each road as equally as possible among the different states of the\nUnion.\n2. The Southwestern National Rail-road, from Washington City to New-Orleans,\npassing through the States of Virginia, Tennessee, Alabama, Mississippi and\nLouisiana; constituting the shortest practicable line of mail and travel transit,\nand consisting of the following continuous sections now under construction, to\nwn: the Richmond and Lynchburg Rail-road, the Virginia and Tennessee Road,\nme Georgia and Alabama Road, the Alabama and Tennessee River Road, the\noelniaand Jackson Road, the New-Orleans and Jackson Road.\n\u00ab  ,   .?\/\" Kentucky.\u2014The  Memphis and  Louisville Road, the   Louisville  and\nNashville Road.\n. For Tennessee.\u2014The Memphis and Louisville  Road, tbe Memphis and\n2!r8t0o Road'the Louisville and Nashville Road, the Nashville and South-\n\u2122&gt;tern Road, and the roads embraced in the \"National Route\" above referred to.\n.. m' .-     Alabama.\u2014The Mobile and Ohio Road, aud the roads embraced in the\nNational Route\" referred to.\nWest    rPeorSia and Florida.\u2014The Gulf Road, or a continuation of the South-\nj*\" Road of Georgia to Pensacola Bay ; the Florida and Peninsular Road.\nandN   [ Mississippi.\u2014The Mobile and Ohio Road; the New-Orleans, JackBon\nburt-l  i i     Roa&lt;:l; the New-Orleans, Holly Springs and Ohio Road ; the Vicks-\n8\u00b0 p Jackson Road, extended by Brandon eastward to Selma.\nor Van\u00b0R ^anSas-\u2014The Arkansas and Mississippi River Road, from Fort Smith\nMemnhi ? to Ltole Rock, and thence to White River, and there diverging to\nCentra\/fi!n lle,ena- A road h'om Fayetteville to Van Buren ; and one from the\nand lot) 'll'\",',ia&lt;l, leaving the same near the St. Francis Ridge, through Jackson\n10 the rep?1.&lt;ience counties to southwestern Missouri. A road from Little Rock\nA roadf)lSlana Line't0 iutersect with the New-Orleans and Opelousas Rail-road.\nPultoo. N\u00bbi*theastern Texas to Little Rock, crossing Red River at or near\n\u00ab\" Louisiana\u2014The New-Orleans, Algiers, Texas  and El Paso Road; the","fullrs":{},"find":"2209.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2208","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"537844","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
