<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2182</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2182</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2182/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 23","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"23\nconstructed into the interior, produce another consequence not contemplated by\n\u2022 nroiectors ; they pour into the fertile and illimitable West an immigrant popula-\nt|ia)   produces for the ports, and co-operates in the political prospects of the\n'  ,,,nl states.     Northern enterprise has wielded this element of power with most\nwrfal effect.    The immigrant is invited from Europe, provided with a guardian, an\ntopreter and a home ; be is transported from Dublin, Bremen and Liverpool into\nthe expanding interior of the Northwest at a cost merely involving the value of his\nlabor lost during the period of his transit.     He can come to America as cheap as he\ncan five at home.     The result of this system has been an acquisition of much the\nlarger portion of the original immigration, amounting, since 1790, to not much less\nthan one-fourth of our whole free white population.\nThese costly viaducts thus flow annually into the Northwest an immigrant population of nearly 500.000 ; their representation under the present ratio will be about equal\nto the whole representation of each of the several Southern States, whilst the value of\nthe money alone imported the last year with these immigrants, is estimated at\n$25,000,000, or one-sxth of the value of Southern staples exported. .\"The constant\noverflow of this vast human reservoir has created systems of Territories and States in\nevery condition from embryo to maturity, all requiring but time to organize a political\npower legitimate to their wealth and numbers. It is, therefore, palpable that the\ndirect representation of the numbers organized by the manufactures, commerce and\nimmigration of the North, is sufficient not only to control the legislation of the Union,\nbut to determine the Executive policy.\nIt is the province of wisdom to deduce from adversity the lessons which will obviate\nits evils. Why, then, may not the South prosecute the^same system of enterprise.\nOur statisticians demonstrate that the resources of the South are abundant\u2014we have\nclimate, staples, water power, and consumers. The able periodical published in this\ncity presents the proof that some manufactures are eheaper in the South than at the\nNorth, and that since the material and provisions have to be sent abroad to be\nre-imported into the South for consumption, our position is in itself equal to a protective duty\nWith such advantages, we may offer inducements to European immigration and to\n1 lzens o*\" the Northern States, to invest their capital and occupy their skill in Southern\nanulactures, as they have done so successfully in Southern commerce.     They may\n'\u2022ne into the interior of the Southern States and engage in the handicraft trades of\neh so little account is taken in the economy of nations, but which contribute so\nto the prosperity of the people and the power of the State.    They may use the\n- ve power of our mountains ; they may convert our staple into fabrics suitable for\n\u25a0onsirmption ; thus retaining much that we now expend abroad, and adding to our\nnca'   power.     It  will promote   also the   employment and   improvement   of\n0Ur own people.\n\u25a0   , .      startled at the proposition to invite population from abroad.    If we succeed\nngmg the Northern merchant or manufacturer to the South, he becomes at once\nhe h   i    Wl*k ^s in^erests ; he is no more hostage for the forbearance of those that\nthe    \u25a0 becomes a mediator between the prejudices of sections, and disabuses\nshould \u00b0f 6ac^ \u00b0*\" ^eir PreJudices. Better, in an economical point of view, that he\nem , al)or here, the competitor of his associates who remained at home. So,\ntheir * 1-CalIy' With the imrr\"&amp;ranfc population of Europe; all men are acclimated in\nor it \u00b0plmons' as in their physical system. The prejudices imbibed against a country\nadant ? u^ons are abandoned when the interests become implicated, and the habits\nS01],,e tothem. In Wisconsin, the European immigrant is the political foe of the\n&gt; ln Texas he will appreciate and sustain the interests which surround him.","fullrs":{},"find":"2183.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2182","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"565861","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.54 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
