<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 01</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/470</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>470</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/470/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 01","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL.\njjuMlslicti 5cmf\u00bbmo-ttIjl,g, nt Jfbc golI.-it-\u00ab iVur, b;t the Jefferson CEollinc ana BBasiifnnton Inccu\nINTER ivi.ui  a c a n k m Mi \u00ab o IE n k ii e veiHIM.\nVOL.\nNATCHEZ, MARCH  15, 1838.\nNO. 7.\nTHE EPIDEMIC YELLOW FEVERS OP NATCHEZ.\n\" IN  MCr.HI VERITAS.!'\nAn F.-fsay read before the Jefferson College ami Washington Lyceum, Dee. 1?,\n1837, by J. W. MoNsrru, SI. 1).\nCONVINCED.\n1.   The Miasm of Yellow Fevek.\u2014This we consider as a subtile, gaseous, invisible, and inodorous matter, generated by the action of the sun, or by solar heat, upon the atmosphere, independently of any effluvia or fcetor from the decomposition of animal matters, and independently of any exhalations from marshes, dry earth, or vegeto-animal compounds, or\nany thing of those kinds.  We believe it to be the result of some\nunknown combination of the solar rays, with the atmosphere,\nwhich takes place at all times and in till places, whilethctem\nperaturein the shade is steadily between 8S\u00b0and 0S\u00b0of Full\nreiilieit, or between 110\u00b0 and 130\" in the open sun : thatiti\nspecific gravity is much greater than that of common air, and\nthat it possesses the common properties of aerial lluids.     We\nthink it probable, that, in its simple stale of miasm, il is innocuous; bul becomes morbific by combination with impure air;\nthat commonly it becomes separated from pure air, and settles\nnear the ground; that it is partially neutralized by a temper-\nalureof 6,r)\u00b0 or 60\u00b0; and is entirely destroyed by a tempera-\nlure of 50\u00b0 or 45\u00b0 at the lowest.    The degree of its morbific\nqualitii s depends upon the nature and degree of combination.\nHence, in our opinion, it can accumulate in dangerous\nquantities only when the weather is steadily between 88\" and\n98s during the day, and above 00\u00b0 or 70? at night, and during a period when there is but little wind to disperse it, or\nonly sufficient lo wall it gently in the air, and cause it to settle\nin low confined places, in a manner similar to the collections\nof carbonic acid gas.    We think, unless the weather is unusually calm and sultry, or  remarkably warm, to cause its\nrapid formation, that it requires from ten to fifteen days for it\nto accumulate sufficiently to be in any wise prejudicial; that\nsliong winds sweep it away, or diffuse it in the general air;\nand heavy rains wash it partly ofT, or cause it lo settle in low,\ndamp places, and dei p buyoux;  where, in a long succeeding\ncalm, hot period of weather, it will accumulate until they\noverflow, and s  nnd it over the surrounding gtounds near\ntheir margins: that it assumes a level surface, like water, nnd\nhence is deeper in some points than al others, in proportion to\ntheir relative elevation: that it cannot accumulate on steep declivities without a barrier below, when it rises only to the levei\n\u00abl the barrier.  On perfectly level surfaces, it seldom raises its\nsurface more than three or four feet above the ground, and most\ncommonly not more than two or three  feet.    A cold night,\nwith a temperature below 50\u00b0, would destroy all that had\npreviously generated;   a   strong wind   or   tornado  would\nsweep it out from buyoux, ravines, or low confined places,\nHot weather favors its formation; calm weather favors ils\naccumulation, as well as the contamination of ihe air requisite to form a morbific union with the miasm.\nWe believe it requires for its formation an extreme temperature above 88\u00b0, because unless the temperature has been up to\nthat point during the hottest period of the day, for many\ndays, no yellow fever has occurred; whereas, although the\ntemperature of the nights may have been up to 80\u00b0 or above,\nso that the menu temperature is 80\u00b0 or 82\u00b0, yet if the great-\nest heat of the day has not been up lo 88\u00b0 at least, there is\nno yellow fever.    Again, a few days may give an extreme\ntemperaturo of 00\u00b0 or 95s; yet if one or two cool nights, at\na temperature of 50\u00b0 or 55\u00b0 succeed, there will be no yellow\nfever for ten days subsequently at least.    Again, there might\nbe thirty days in succession, with nn extreme temperature as\nhigh as 03? or 05\", and yet two cold nights, ten or fifteen days\napart, would neutralize nil the miasm previously formed; and\nalthough the mean heal, for a month or lunger, might average\nmore than 80\", there would be no yellow fever.    Hence the\nwean heat should not be taken into our estimates; but the\nactual temperature by day and  by night.    The wii.ds may\nbe fresh from the south, so ns not to reduce the temperature\nbelow 00? by day, nnd yet they may carry off all the miasm,\nor all the contaminated air: or a calm, hot day, may be succeeded by a gale at night, which will carry oil' the miasm.\nThis miasm is not injured or neutralized by damp air: on\nthe contrary if calm, damp, foggy, cloudy, or misty weather,\nsucceed ninnydays of intensely hot and sultry weather, the\nmiasm previously formed, remains, if it does nol accumulate;\ndamp, moist air is congenial to it, and seems to attract il: or it\nsettles over low, damp places, in preference to dry ones of the\nsame elevation.    Hence it accumulates in deep ravines or\nbayoux.     Upon these  principles, we perceive why yellow\nfever is most prevalent in low, damp sections of cities, near\nthe wharves and about the shipping.    These places attract\nand retain the miasm already formed: as well as favor its\ngeneration and preservation.    The temperature about such\nplaces, from their exposed situation, is often nt least two or\nthree degree's higher than in other parts ofthe city.    The\nreflection from the water adds to this eflect byelny.nnd moderates the cold by night.    ThrTtemperature of the country air\ns generally at least two or three degrees less than it is in any\nclosely built parts of cities, not only during the day, but at\nnight; country air is necessarily much cooler, because there\nis not such an accumulation of heat in radiating bodii's.\nAlthough it requires a temperature above SS* to generate\nmiasm, we find that it requires a reduction of nearly one-half\nto neutralize or destroy it. Hence yellow fever is often endemic nil the year in the West Indies; for there the temperature of the air is seldom below 55\u00b0 of Fahrenheit, and where\ninfection, exists, even that temperature will not destroy it.\nThese facts may be illustrated by similar ones in relation to\nanother fluid, Thus water, for example, under the common\natmospheric pressure, will not boil at 200\u00b0 or 205\" Fahrenheit; but it will boil at 212\u00b0.    At the hitter temperature it\n\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0}M\n:'1'.i\"'^; i\n- '\u25a0 'ifll\n,   .f'.I'li\n!.\u2022'$ fl\n: '    (\u25a0 :-5*U '\nm\nmm\nII\n:.- I a\nu\nI Kl\nVn","fullrs":{},"find":"471.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"470","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1835776","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.75 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
