<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 04</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/526</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>526</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/526/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 04","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"KM \u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\nI \u00bb1   ,*\n164\nS6UTH-WESTERN   JOURNAL\n\u2022'lift'::*, '.\nui.-t.\nIf\nd.S!?.\n\u25a0\u25a0\u2022 $\n..ti s\ni  ii\u00bb.-\nearth's composition during the early periods of ils existence,\nwe may first refer to the time when darkness enveloped the\ndeep, and the spirit of God moved upon the face of the waters,\nto arouse them from their deep slumber of inertia and to im-\npart to them the power of developing and reclaiming the component parts of this beautiful earth from their heterogeneous\nand useless confusion, At this primordial epoch in the history\nof our drop, we may date the commencement of that agency\nwhich has ever since been in active operation, and which in\nevery movement exhibits the strongest testimony of a wise and\nbeneficent design ; but we will pass over that eventful period\nof our earth that is chronicled with changes which sustain too\nclose a connection with sacred history to be profaned by the\ntouch of an unhallowed pen : a period that extends from the\ntime when the drop floated upon the bosom of Euphrates and\nirrigated the valley of the unpolluted Eden, ere ihe curse\nwhich drove man from his birthplace, and strewed weeds nnd\nthorns, where flowers and fruits were wont to dwell, until the\naccumulated iniquity of man had driven mercy from her sent\nand stern justice commanded all ihe fountains ofthe great deep\nto be broken up, and the windows of heaven to be opened, and\nwith an awful retribution, sweep all animated creation from\nthe face of the earth.\nThe rich diluvium that formed the upper crust of the earth\nafter the Noachian deluge, was deposited by our drop in com\nmon with its coadjutors, after the weighty and barren rocks\nhad subsided from llieir admixture with the turbulent floods of\nthe grand cataclysm.\nThe solvent property that enabled it to hold in suspension\nthe bases of future vegetation, provided against the possibility\nof a general and desolate sterility; and since that period the\nsame property has been in active operation, in the productioi\nof those newly formed soils, known under the denomination\nof alluvial; a process by which submerged lands and dan\ngerous sandbars are elevated, and covered over with ihe de\nbris of mouldering vegetation, richly impregnated with\nembryos that shall spring up to tapestry these late formations\nof the earth with new and living verdure. There is not a\ngeological change or a mincralogical fonnation, with which\nour little drop is not conversant. Here by delicate attrition\nagainst the rough surface of some shapeless rock it imbues\nitself with silicious particles, which it again transforms by\nmagic power into a brilliant and symmetrical crystal, or it\ndeposites them as stalactites to hang like icicles against the\nvaulted roof of some humid cavern. Now again we see it\nconcealed in the bosom of the caithand hid for ages from the\nscrutiny of intrusive man, it superintends the formation of\nthose little minerals, which, by their scarcity nnd beauty,\nseem more the elegant offspring of nature's pastime, than as\nconstituting any part of her more necessary products; or we\nmay regard them as the beautiful types of that creation which\nshall exist when these heavens and this earth shall have\npassed away. Having fulfilled its office in the supervision of\nthose refined and brilliant gems which adorn the earth, it becomes attached to some more humble mineral, washes modifies, and adapts it to purposes of art, or to the decorations of\nrefinement, and thus progressing onward it touches every in.\ndividual in the series of mineral produ cts, and impressesupon\nen to exhibi:\neach the marks of ils omnipotent agency.    Th.\nits powers upon a more inagnifinent scale, it m,lv n\u00ab\nthose mighty evolutions of nature, the tornado, eotthan l\"\nand volcano, which resemble ihe terrific bursting forth  i\nsome impetuous passion, and are the instruments that inn\nuses when she would shatter man's presumptuous confide\nin his control over her laws.\nBut the wisdom of God in the creation of this pccttlj\nagent is constantly exhibited in that relation which burdro\nsustains to the seasons, and lo those meteorological clianf\nwhich constitute the weather. It must be well known tli-t\nthe differences of climate under the same latitude and ihe\nvicissitudes of weather are not solely referable to (hesitus-\ntion that our earth maintains in the ecliptic; the relation thai\ntho earth bears to the sun will not account for the sudden\ntransitions from hot to cold, and from cold to hot, which so\nstrongly denote the character of our capricious climate\nThere must be some other cause in operation, some other\nagent at work, and the omniscient Creator has endowed our\ndrop with a properly that qualifies it lo uccomplish all Ihe\nchanges that we have indicated. This property consists in\nits capacity for caloric, in its different states of water, vapor,\nand ice, a capacity or property that enables it lo embody within itself, and conceal different amounts of caloric. The\namount of caloric or heat that a body contains, is nol necessarily cognizable to the senses; there is always a eeitaia\nquantity that is latent and essential lo the nature of the soli-\nstance, and this quantity seems to be in an inverse ratio to\nthe density of the body. Thus, water may b^ as cold esice\nand contain within itself a very much greater amount of caloric than the ice; an excess that constitutes part of thea*\nture of water, anel is called the caloric of fluidity; experiment has proved this difference equal to about M0\u00b0 of Fahr\neiiheil, and before water of 32\u00b0 can be converted into ice,it\nmust part with the 140\" of caloric that was necessary lo its\nfluid state. A portion of vapor of water contains a vast\namount more of caloric than when condensed into a fluid\nform. The liberation of caloric is so great during the change\nof water from the state of vapor lo its more condensed fount,\nthat an ingenious philosopher of this country, has expressed\nthe opinion that twice as much heat is made free during a\nfill of snow as would be given out by the same depth of red'\nhot sand. Most persons are familiar with the changes of\ntemperature produced by the transition of water into vapor or\ninto a more condensed state. As familiar examples, we may\nmention the refreshing coolness that is imparted to a vicinity.\nwhen water has been thrown over an extended surface in\nwarm weather, or the opposite, a liberation of great he111\nwhen.Water is poured upon quick lime. In the first instance,\nihe conversion of water into the state of vapor, causes an absorption of a great amount of caloric, and consequently pr\u00b0-\nIn\nduces coolness in the neighborhood of the evaporation,\nthe second case, the incorporation of water with the lime.\nsets free that excess of caloric that was necessary to it in*1\nfluid state, which, by its manifestation, induces a great elevation of temperature.\nWe have dwelt upon this point, that you might comprehend in what manner water is rendered subservient lo i\u00ab","fullrs":{},"find":"527.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"526","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1809603","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.73 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
