<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2173</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2173</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2173/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 13","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"1\nParish of Lafayette\u2014Alrt8re Martin, John A. Rigues, Joachim Revillon.\nb Mouton, Robert Cade, Paul L. St. Julien, Benjamin P. Paxton, C.H.\n7 ton Honore Beraud, A. Mouton, Dr. William G. Mills, John D. Patin,\nfl 01W W. Scranton, Alexander Moss, Donat Braux.\nSt Mary-\u2014R- B Brashicr, Bayou Ramos Postoffice; Octave Cornay,\npittersonvillc Postoffice ; William Pumphrey, Joshua Baker, Centreville\nPostoffice; Pinkney C. Bethel, Nathan Berwick, Pattersonville Postoffice,\nA L Field, Dr. John Lavlcton, Henry C. Wilson, Franklin Postoffice ; G. L.\nFusilier, Charenton Postoffice ; C. Grevcmberg, F. D. Richardson, Thomas\ntl, Thompson, Henry Penn, Henry Peebles, Jenerett's Postoffice.\nSt. Martin\u2014Drauzin Broussard, Ulgor Deeuir, Louis Miguez, Alexandre\nPeCkruet, V- A. Fournet, Joseph Caille, Alcibiadc DcBlanc, Cornelius\nVoorhies, Dr. James S. Peebles, Dr. Walker, Balthazar Martin, Collin\nCormier, William Robertson, Frederick L. Yates, Alfred Lastrapes.\nSt. Landry\u2014John II. Overton, E. H. Martin, Lastcr Dupre, William B.\nLewis, Thomas C. Anderson, Dr. R. E. Smith, Evaraste DeCuillon, Caleb L.\nSway, Marsden Campbell, James Buaud, John Cook, JohnE. King, Lucius\nDupre, Baptiste David, Philip Stagg.\nAssumption\u2014J. C. Delavigue, R. C. Martin, Dr. Tl. G. Roberts, D.\nMorrison, W. W. Pugh, Dr. E. E. Kittridgc, A. J. Foley, Vileon LeBlanc,\nW. A. Simms, G. C. Raby, F. Hickman, Drauzin Hiinel, James Vinson,\nDosinew Renthrop, D. LeBlanc.\nDeSotc\u2014D. Creswell, II. Marshall, A. 0. Baldwin, John Jordan, R. T.\nJohnson, J. McCraw, L. Phillips, William Franks, Jr., Robert Bums, Maj.\nCole, T. T. Williamson, II. Phillips, C. C. Campbell, Dr. R. S. Gibbs,\nErastus Crosby.\nSaSme\u2014Chichestcr Chaplin, Maj. Morehead, R. W. Stillie, Dr. T. II\nPatterson, Dr. Armstrong, \u2014 Montgomery, Dr. Ragan, Marcellus Branch, \u2014\nDavidson, Rev. Stephens, Maj. Bitchie, \u2014 Gandy, William Stillie,\n\u2014 Stoker, John Smart.\nNatchitoches\u2014Judge J. G. Campbell, Ambrose Lecompt, Judge Grenaux,\n\u00bb\u2022 Bartlett, G. W. Morse, Hector Somperac, Dr. J. W. Butler, P. Prudhome,\n5- p- Welsh, Michael Boyce, Dr. S. 0. Scruggs, Adam Carnehan, T. C. Hunt,\n~ Lascal, L. Prudhome.\n\u00b0n motion of Mr. F. J). Richardson, of St. Mary, it was\n* wved, That the respective Parish Committees bo empowered to fill all\nnes \u2122at may occur, by resignation or otherwise, in their number.","fullrs":{},"find":"2174.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2173","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"526900","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.50 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
