<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 08</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/547</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>547</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/547/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:51">{"title":"Page 08","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"131\nS 0 U T 11 -W E S T E R N   J O U II N A L .\n\u25a0 . \u25a0   ' -:\n-     '\nIf   ' '\neluded, and readily replied, \"that he would have given the\npledge required beforo she commenced her hist speech, had\nshe found it within the clemency of her disposition to have\nmade the exaction at that time.\" He had scarcely finished\nwhen Clara left her seat, took from her in ok a small pink\nriband, looped a bachelor's pin-cushion on the little streamer\nand with mock solemnity placed it about Herbert's neck, enjoining him to wear tho badge of his blushing honors a fortnight. Amidst the simpering of the group and ihe incontinent pecavi of poor George, she quietly seated herself nt the\npiano, and in a serio-comic manner executed the old fashioned air of \" 0 dear ! what can the matter be ? \"\u2014accompanying the instrument with her voice in the most ludicrous style.\nHere, Clara was all life, all gaity, and those around her\nseemed to catch the spirit of her humor, whilst I stood aloof\nwatching the rapid change of her beautiful features, the\nsparkling witchery of her laughing eyes, and admiring the\ngrace of her every motion as she ran her snowy white fingers\nover the keys of the instrument without seeming to touch\nthem.\nHow changed was the scene when professionally called to\nsee her! Before me lay the writhing form of this fair girl,\nand her whole system in such violent agitations, that the constant efforts of the mother were required to keep her in bed.\nHer eyes rolled about wildly, were completely unsettled,\nand so devoid of recognition, that a single glance told me,\nwith the paroxism she was laboiing under an aberration of\nintellect. 1 was satisfied of this fact when I took my station\nat the bedside, as an incoherence of speech which escaped her\npallid lips in broken sentences, and the startling effect of the\nsoul-damning cause which grated upon my ear, as in her\nwildness of speech it revealed itself, convinced me but too\npainfully that her affections had been abused, her hopes of\nhappiness disappointed, anel that the apparently amiable\nGeorge Herbert, with all his blandishment of manners and\nversatility of talent, possessed a heart so inhuman that he\ncould trifle with the noblest feelings that adorn the female\ncharacter.\n\" Hah\" I exclaimed tho unfortunate girl, as I took her Indie wrist to examine her pulse, \" where is George?\u2014do you\ncome  here to feast upon  my disap ? the letter I\u2014lie\nloves me not I\u2014be still my heart !\u20140 villain I\u2014villain I\t\nmother!\u2014mother I\u2014why do you not burn the le\u2014 ah-h-h,\nyou here Doctor\" ! !! Willi the last exclamation she throw\nherself violently to the back part of the bed, gnashed her\nteeth, deracinated her hair by handfiills, and then with an appalling shriek that went like a knife to my heart, leapt from\nthe bed, anel in despite of all our efforts fell prostrate on the\nfloor. We raise:! her up and replaced her in bed after much\nexertion, for her strength during the paroxysm almost bid defiance to restraint, and tlio irritation produced by a bruise received upon her temple when she fell, increased her frenzy.\nHer father and two sisters held her whilst I compelled her to\nswallow the fourth of a grain of morphia, and it v.asnot Jong\nbefore her muscular contortions abated. 1 ordered a foot\nbath or warm water before 1 left, anel was gratified to witness\nthis simple remedy relieve the brain of too great a determination of Wood to that organ.    Her exanguious features soon\nbecame mantled in scarlet j her extremities grew Warm \u2022 h\nskin became suffused in a gentle perspiration, and when I\nleft tho room she slept calmly. It was immediatelysil\nbreakfast that I mounted my horse, and was about to ride oil'\nwhen Madam Perryan hailed mc from the hall door ami'\nwished to know \"when I would repeat my visit?\" I replied\nihat I would return at 3 o'clock, P. M. of tho same day, ?M\\\nperceiving that she had something to communicate, I asked\nher if she \"had any message for tho village?\" she answered\nin the negative, but added a request that I would remain\nsilent upon ihe unpleasant cause of Chun's illness, dividend\nunconsciously whilst she raved upon the subject of her un.\nhappiness.\" I assured her kindly she need not be under any\napprehensions, that I should be so imprudent, and having requested her lo renew the warm fool-balh for Clara, (if upon\nwaking Symplons of mental alienation were manifest) 1 bid\nher good morning and bent my way to tho village.\nFor the first lime since I left Clara's apparlmciit, I had, nsl\nrode homeward, an opportunity to reflect upon the scene 1\nhad so lately witnessed) and aware that rumor gave it out\nthat Herbert and Miss Clara were soon lo be married, tho\nidea that he was now revenging himself upon her, for llic little ruse de. guerre she indulged in at his expense on the evening of the party at Professor A's, three months previous,\nHashed upon my mind as quick as thought. 1 remembered\ntoo, of having heard Herbert exclaim, aside, on that evening\nthat \"she should have u Roland forhei Oliver yet;\" but did\nnot deem him callable, at that time, of hurling at the very\nfount of her happiness, his envenomed shafts of vindictive\nness. Handsome, well-formed, and graceful in the extreme,\nGeorge Herbert was the possessor of a brilliant mind, well\nitored with polite literature, and it was not unnatural that Clara should become.pleased with his attentions, and eventually\nlo contract an attachment for him, which, with her, would\nprove no child's play passion, as her attachments, even in\nfriendship, were of the most lasting kind, whilst her enmity,\nwhen unjustly provoked, slept not.\nI reached my office, and during the day could not drive from\nmy thoughts tho circumstances connected with the case on\nhand; and an intimate acquaintance with Clara's constitutional temperament, induced me to fear a return of paroxysms\nso soon as the soporific effects of the morphia she had taken\nhould go oil'. I therefore paid a litllo more attention to my\ntoilet, having figured so ridiculously in the morning, ami\ngalloped off to the bdgo, where 1 arrived at half past two\no'clock. Upon entering the sitting room, I found all of the\nfamily around the lire but the mother, and, after an exchange\nof salutations, ventured to inquire after my patient.\n\"She did nol awake till one o'clock,\" replied Mary, \"a'\"1\nwin u she did, her unnatural exuberance of spirit and laughter at her own folly, for half an hour without intermission,\nfollowed by a low brooding melancholy, which still \u00ab\"\"''\nueies, keep us in constant fear of a return of convulsions.'\n\" Did her laughter sound natural, Miss Ma\n\u2022y'l\n\" 0 no, sir!\u2014it appeared so at first; but before she relapsed\ninto this gloomy thoughtfulncss, from which she soinetiiues\nwildly starts, her laughter was so hideous, that my father,\nunable any longer to listen to it, left her apartment.   w'nc\"","fullrs":{},"find":"548.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"547","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1784531","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.70 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
