<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 3, Page 7</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2116</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2116</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2116/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:45">{"title":"Section 3, Page 7","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"The first step in progress is barter; for without it, production will be\nnfinod to the mere abject necessities of life. Trade stimulates new\npnemies and life, and ultimately civilization. Industry is its hand-\naiden ' Manufactures go hand in hand with it, for every article ot\nmanufacture, except the very rudest, presupposes exchange^ since the\n*-:il of the field laborer must be supplied by that of the artisan. Ine\nfrequency of exchanges, and the capacities for them, thus operate upon\nF-^'W.n and fabrication. The Indian hunter will transport on his\nback, or itt &lt;*\u00bb\u2014- , . , hundreds 0f miies to the trader. This\nis exchange under the #*JL\\ -enable disadvantages. The Mexican trader will supply the interior cw ..\u201e., iiDon \u00b0ck horses across\ngreat deserts. This is commerce at one remove; uif\u201e ~**ij, \u201en^er such\ndiscouragements, it cannot thrive, and thus Mexico remains, from age\nto age, without improvement or progress. The wagon, the flat-boat,\nthe ship, the steamer and the rail-road, are successive steps in advancement. New wants spring up with the facilities of their enjoyment,\nand new energies are diffused. The poorer classes become consumers\nof what formerly was confined to the wealthy. The wealthy look\naround for new marks to distinguish them from the commonalty;\nthus industry is everywhere taxed and encouraged, manufacturing\ntowns spring up, and villages grow into immense cities. The forests\ngive way to the axe, and the age of highest civilization is ushved in.\n3, Upon Wealth.\u2014We shall confine ourselves here to a few facts,\nwhich go to show the immense results which have grown out of the\nconstruction of rail-roads. They are the creators of wealth in more\nthan one way. As a source of profitable investment, rail-roads have\nnot been surpassed by any other. We have stated, the actual earnings\non the roads of England are over four per cent.* on the present value of\nshares, whilst the interest on money is much less. If there has been\na depreciation in the stocks of the roads, it is easily accounted for by the\nmonomania which induced the construction of roads that were unnecessary, and by the reckless and extravagant system of construction,\nincident to the infancy of all novel enterprizes. The same remark\napplies to the United States, where the dividends of roads average over\nfive per cent., though in Massachusetts this average reaches eight per\ncent.; whilst upon many roads in the country ten, and even a much\ngreater per cent., has been realized by an economical management.\nNo other investments of capital have paid more, and if we take a long\nseries of years, no others have paid so much. Losses, to be sure, have\nbeen incurred, and immense amounts sunk, as our own State of\nLouisiana may exemplify, but in what department of business has\nexperience been otherwise 1 Certainly not in commerce, certainly\nnot in banking, nor even in agriculture and manufactures. Visionary\nand impracticable schemes, and ruinous extravagance, will find their\nplace in every branch of human affairs. In the United States they\nhave been, perhaps, less felt in the matter of rail-roads than in any\nother matter. Nor is it in actual dividends alone that rail-road profits are achieved.    Far from it.    These are among their least advan-\n*De Bow's Review, March, 1850, Vol. VIII.   New-Orleans.","fullrs":{},"find":"2117.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2116","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"508167","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.48 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
