<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 7</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/368</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>368</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/368/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:03">{"title":"Page 7","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH-WESTERN JOURNAL\ntheir distances; he has predicted their phases and changes, and\nmade them subservient to bis purposes. But does he comprehend all the principles, all the laws regulating the heavenly\nbodies? does he comprehend the nature of that great power that\nmoves and sustains them in their relative positions? can he\ntell the origin and nature of that universal principle, gravitation ? can ho tell us why the fixed stars twinkle with a more\nbrilliant light than the planets?\nWith all the advances made in modern astronomy, there\nstill remains as much ignorance of the cause of many important facts, as there was four thousand years ago: but there\nis increased reason for admiration and overwhelming astonishment, at the wisdom and power that has created and sustain\ned those orbs in boundless space.\nWhat becomes of a star when il suddenly and forever dis\nappears? Tycho Brahe informs us of one, which appeared\nvery brilliant for months together, and suddenly disappeared\nand has not been seen now for two hundred years: and Sir Isaac\nNewton informs us of others. Werethey annihilated; or are\nastronomers deceived in supposing the stars inhabited worlds?\nWith all the advances mid discoveries of modern times,\nmade in chemist ru, we know, comparatively, only a few facts,\nwhich might be extended to an unlimited amount, had we\nonly six dozen senses, like the inhabitants of Saturn, instead\nof our scanty five. With that number of senses, everybody\nin nature, simple matter, air, lire, water, would multiply its\nqualities and properties lo our observation in a geometrical\nratio. Chemical aflinities are mysteries lo the most profound\nchemists; they know thai certain bodies have an attraction or\nIndeed we know but little of that wonderful power which\npervades all nature, under its modified forms of Electricity,\nGalvanism, and Magnetism;\nThat mighty power,\n\"That over-busy wheels the silcnl spheres ;\nWorks in the deep: shoots streaming thence,\nThe lair profusion thai o'ersprcads the spring:\nFlings from the sun direct the naming day;\nFeeds every creature; hurls the tempest forth;\nAnd as on earth this grateful change revolves,\nWith transport touches nil ihe springs of life.\"\nThe discoveries in this branch of the sciences are among\nthe most wonderful that have yet been made by man; of a\npower that admits of an endless variety of operation; whose\ninfluence pervades every particle of matter; affecting all the\nanimt.1 and physical operations upon our globe; producing either directly, or indirectly, all the inexplicable phenomena of\nnature. Recent discoveries have shown that the galvanic\nfluid possesses powers, which, a few years since, were unknown; it bus been found capable of moving machinery equal\nloa powerfulstcam engine; of lifting almost incredible weights;\nand these properties have been discovered by only a change\nin the arrangement of the plates in the battery. How many\nother changes it is susceptible of, we know-not: could we know\nall its relations, we might find it was the cause or active agent\nof gravitation in all the planetary systems.\u2014 It may be under\nthe controlling power of God, the great Animus Mundi; that\noperates as variedly as the matter through which it operates;\nAtone time magnetism ; at another galvanism ; nnd at another electricity: at one  time attraction;   at another  reptil-\nr. pulsion fir each other; but they cannot tell why one at- sion : at one time il rends the clouds with its thunder; and at\ntracts, or another repels ; why tho union of two opposite substances should destroy each other and produce a third of a\ndifferent nature. Tiny cannot tell why lire will burn and\nconsume one gas, mid he extinguished in another; why it\nshould have no power on one body, and in another produce\nthe most tremi ndous explosion. When we leave the contracted laboratory of man, and descend into the great Offlci-\nnum of nature, mysteries thicken around, until, bewildered, we\nare lost in amazement. Examine the spars, and stalactites in\ncaves, near the surface of the earth; who can tell how they\nare formed; how the particles of which they nre composed,\nare held in solution in a transparent fluid, nnd deposited in\nthe form of the hardest rock: how nature generates all her\nstore of minerals, gases, and mineral compounds; how she\nprovides her combustible slons, and kindles up all her fires;\nhow siie prepares tier volcanoes, ami generates her floods of\nlava, which bury cities and countries in ruin; or how she\nagitates the confined gases, which make tho tottering earth\nreel to an 1 fro like a drunken man?\nCan wo t.-ll the s icret causa of gravitation, as connected\nwith our pi,nut? I low does il operate at the immense distance\nof the earth from the sun? And what is the vast projectile\nforce which puts ,!i \u2022 earth in motion? Should future experiments and discoveries satisfy us that it is a modified slate of\n(lie galvanic fluid, wc shall still be as far from its solution as\never: we cannot tell how this power is generated, why and\nanother rends the earth with its bolts; at one time it regulates\nthe small operations of man's little battery, and at another it\nholds Ihe planets in their orbits, and wheels them silently\naround their centres.\nWhen we look into the component parts of the earth, what\nis llieamount of our knowledge there?    We can trace a k'vr\nstrata near the surface; we can name them, and record the order in which they appear; we can turn many of them to our\nuse; but what do we know of the interior  of the   earth;\nwhat do we   know   of  nature's  uses    for   all the   strata\nknown to us, as well as those that are beyond our research?\nCan we suppose they are solely for man's use, when the great\nportion of it has been hidden from his research for thousands\nof years before man's creation, as well as since?    Have the\ntgnectic effluvia been coursing tho earth for thousands of\nyears only lo hold here anil (here a mariner's or surveyor's\nneedle; and still not he discovered  by man until  the human\nfamily had almost approached their dotage?    Do the numerous strata of earths and rocks, and the alternate -reins of metals; silver, gold, iron, copper, &amp;c. perform no agency in the\nplan of creation, except now and then to reward the toil of the\nminer?    Is all the vast interior of the earth, with its numerous strata, to a depth of four thousand miles in every direction, created only to sustain the slender shell for man to\ntread upon?    No, nothing is made in vain:\u2014and may we not\nreasonably infer that they perform some important office in\nhow it operates;  we can only know that such  are its opera- the great economy of the world?    May not they, as a whole,\nlions\u2014and no more. I constitute a vast generator of that fluid, power, or influence","fullrs":{},"find":"369.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"368","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1699901","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.62 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
