<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/482</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>482</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/482/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:52">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"SOUTH.WESTERN JOURNAL.\n109\nEDUCATION CONVENTION\".\nAt a meeting of the teachers of Adams county, and the\nfriends of education in general, convened, pursuant to notice,\non Saturday, tho 17th of March, nt the City Hall, in the city\nof Natchez, Professor C. G. FoRSHEV was called to the\nchair, and S. H. B. Black was appointed secretary.\nThe chairman stated the object of the meeting to be the\nformation of an Association for the county of Adams, auxiliary to the Education Association of the State of Mississippi.\nThe benefits to be derived from such an organization were\nably discussed and commented upon. Professor Van Hoesen\noffered the following resolution, which, after being amended,\nwas adopted.\nResolved, That we, the teachers and friends of education\nin Adams county, unite our efforts for the advancement of education, and for elevating the character of the professional\nleacher,and for the frequent discussion of all the principles\nand practices embraced in the profession of instruction.\nOn motion of Mr. 1. C. Patridge, it was resolved, that the\nchair appoint a committee of two poisons to report a constitu\ntion for the Association. Whereupon the chair appointed\nMr. Patridge and Professor Van Hoesen. On motion, the\nchair was added to the committee.\nThe committee, haying withdrawn for the purpose, returned and reported the following preamble and constitution,\nwhich, after being read, and the several provisions separately\nand closely examined, were unanimously adopted.\nCONSTITUTION.\nWe, the teachers of Adams county, and the friends of education in convention assembled, deeply impressed with the\nimportance of organizing their profession in the valley of\nthe Mississippi, by a permanent association, in order to promote the sacred interests of education, by collecting its members, advancing their mutual improvement, nnd elevating the\nprofession lo its great intellectual and moral influence in com.\nmunity, do hereby resolve ourselves into an association, to be\ngoverned by the following constitution.\nARTICLE   I.\nSection 1. This Association shall he known by the name\nof the \"Adams County Education Association,\" auxiliary to\nthe State Association of professional instructors.\nSec. 2. Its object shall be, by every laudable means, to\npromote the diffusion of knowledge in regard to education,\nand especially by aiming- at the elevation of the standard of\ninstruction, and the literary character of thoso who have\nchosen instruction for their profession.\nARTICLE II.\nIt shall be composed of such teachers and citizens, of good\nliterary and moral character, as shall sign this constitution,\nand pay the treasurer an initiation fee of two dollars.\nARTICLE   III.\nSec. 1. Its officers shall be a President, Vice President,\nSecretary and Treasurer, all of whom shall form a Board of\nDirectory, to be elected annually by ballot.\nSee. -i.    These officers shall severally perform the duties\nof the society\u2014appoint competent persons to address its meetings\u2014to divide its members into committees, and assign their\nduties not inconsistent with this constitution\u2014nnd to select for\npublication such addresses and reports of standing committees\nas they may deem worthy.\nARTICLE   IV.\nSec. 1. The stated meetings of this society, shall be held\nquarterly, on the third Saturday of March, June, September,\nand December.\nSec, 2. Tho exercises of its meetings shall be, first, an\naddress by some person chosen by the board; second, the free\ndiscussion of some question in regard to education, which\nshall have been proposed tit the previous meeting; third, a report from at least one of the standing committees, and discussion thereupon.\nARTICLE   V.\nThis constitution may be altered or amended at any regu-\nar meeting, by vote of two-thirds of the members present.\nThe constitution was then signed by those present, and the\nconcluding requisition of tho 2d article was complied with.\nOn motion, the Association proceeded to the election of\nofficers for the year, in accordance with the provisions of the\n1st section of article 1st.\nThe result was as follows:\nPresident, C. L Dubuisson.\nVice President, C. G. Forsiiev.\nSecretary, S. H. B. Black.\nTreasurer, W. H. Bruner.\nOn motion, it was\nResolved, That the editors of this city and of the State ba\nrespectfully requested to insert the proceedings of this meeting in their respective papers.\nOn motion, adjourned.\nC. G. FORSHEY, Chairman.\nS. H. B. Black, Secretary.\nusually incident to such officers; and as a Board of Directo\nty, they shall have the general management and supervision\nTHE AMERICAN MECHANIC.\nOne of the richest and purest specimens of thought and\nfeeling we have recently seen, is the address of Bin Excel-\nency, Edward Everett, Governor of Massachusetts, de-\nivercd before the Charitable Mechanic Association, last\nSeptember. There are noble sentiments in this address, that\nshould sink eleep into the heart of every American Mechanic,\nand shape his life to the sublime destinations of his calling.\nWe give two brief extracts:\u2014\"Let us but advert for a moment to the mariner's compass, the telescope, the quadrant.\nFor myself, I never reflect upon their influence on the affairs of man, and remember that they are, after all, merely\nmechanical contrivances, without emotions of admiration\nbordering upon awe. This sentiment, I know, is so worn\naway by habit, that it seems almost to run into sentimentality.\nBut let us not be ashamed to reproduce tho emotions that\nspring from the freshness of truth and nature. What must\nnot have been Galileo's feelings, when he pointed the first\ntelescope to the heavens, and discovered the phases of Venus\nand the moons of Jupiter! When I behold the touched\nneedle trembling to the pole,\u2014when I know, that, beneath\n\u2022II\nqli\n\u25a0' \u2022 M\n\u2022'\u2022\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0%*.\n;\u25a0' -ir-il\nS\/'Vl\u2122\n! $\nm\nm\n&gt;\u00abva\nMil","fullrs":{},"find":"483.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"482","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1761761","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.68 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
