<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 13</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/427</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>427</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/427/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:31:04">{"title":"Page 13","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S O i; T 11 - W E S T E I? N J 0 U It N A L.\n,,i ihe public, as a learned and valuable writer, by several\nsmaller publications, which have attracted, as they deserved\nmuch praise. But on this great work his reputation, as a\nChristian Moralist and Philosopher, will rest in fiitur,-\nliinc.\nAn elementary treatise of practical morals, such as Christians of every denomination, and all good men, would unite to\napprove, must be the work of one who is not the slave of party\nin religion or politics, but ihe disciple of truth. As a moral\nteacher, this writer professes to draw his authorities from the\nsacred scriptures, from the law of the land, and from the illtis\ntrations, amplifications, and deductions ofthe great masters ol\nreason and argument, who have adorned the annals of man\nkind, both in ancient and modem times. The work is intend\nt .1 particularly for the young; but it may, I think, be read with\nprofit by persons of all ages. Whatever else we cease lo study\nof ornament or pleasure, the science of good morals is appropriate ,o every age and condition of life.\nThis volume will allract the attention ofthe editors and conductors of the principal Literary and Religious Journals ol\niho United States. They are able to scan its merits, and to doted its faults in the spirit of liberal and candid criticism, 1, is\ntheir vocation. A book designed to convey the principles of\naction to the citizens of this great and increasing Republic of\nStates, cannot be neglected by tho learned without a manifest\nfiiilure in duty. I wish merely to ask the attention ofthe reading community to the work for its own merits, and to commend it lo their patronage for the benefit mid encouragement\nof its learned and modest author. Letters are to be fostered,\nand can flourish only in a rich soil. Wealth owes to them a\ndeserved tribute ; and I add with pleasure, for the honor of my\ncountry, thnt while Rome boasted of but one Mascenas, we can\npoint thrin out in every city,\nIl is known lo scholars, that the greatest and best men of\nall ages, have delighted to form theories of morals, and to\nfound on thorn schools of instruction with which to perpetuate\nllieir own names. Generally, they agreed to recommend virtue as the only true source of felicity. Whatever were their\nerrors in speculation, their practice was conformable to the\nprecepts oftruth, however they differed in the grounds of mor\nal obligation. Socrates, the chit f ofthe ancient philosophers,\nmaintained, that an action lobe gootl must be both useful and\nhonorable; while Plato, his favorite pupil, made virtue to consist in self government and a well balanced mind. (hie philosopher contended, that virtue consisted in practical habits; and\nanother, in just sentiments and reasonable judgments. Accordingly thoStoics, perfect rectitude was comprised in living ac\ncording to nature, and in bestowing upon every object ihe precise degreo ofattention it deserved, according to the standard ol\nits worth in the natural scale of things. The primary objects\nof natural desire consisted, according to Epicurus, in bodily\npleasure and pain, and in nothing else. '' Oprcre'laram beate\nVivendi, et apertam, et simplicem, el directum viam ! cum enini\ncerte nihil bouiini possit melius esse, quam vacarc onini dolore\nel molcstia, porfruique maximis et animi et corporis volupteti-\nbus.\" Cic. De Finibus. I. 18. Virtue was not to be pursued\nlor its own sake, but only as it tended to prevent pain, and to\nprocure ease and pleasure.    And yet Epicurus believed, that\ntho best and most perfect pleasure was to be derived from the\npractice of truth and virtuei\nThe following extrael from tho chapter of \"Preliminary\nPrinciples and Discussions,'' will servo as a specimen ofthe\nstyle ofthis work, and will show the respect anil diligence\nwilh which the author has consulted the writings of eminent\nmoralists of modern limes.\n\"Nor has this diversity of sentiment on the theory of morals\nbeen confined  lo the ancient philosophers.    Modern writers\nhave not concurred in their views en the theoretical pari of\nthe subject.    Tho opinion of Dr. Samuel Clarke is, ihat moral\nobligation is lobe referred to the eternal and necessary differences of things ; and Ik- makes virtue lo consist in acting suitably to the different relations in which we stand.    Wollaston's\ntheory is, that moral good and evil consist in a conformity or\ndisagreement wilh truth, in trealingevery thing as being what\nit is.    Lord Shaftsbury makes virtue to consist in maintaining\na proper balance ofthe alii ctions, and in allowing no passion\nlogo boyond its proper sphere.   Dr. Palcy teaches 1 bat it is the\nutility of any action alone, which constitutes the obligation  of\nit.     I Ir. Adam Smith resolves moral obligation into propriety, arising from feelings of sympathy.     I )r. Bush considers Ihe\ncommunicated will of God the grand exposition of human duty; while Dymondsays, that ibis will not merely declares the\ndistinction between right antl wrong in regard lo moral conduct,\nbut also is itself tin' constituting cause of moral good and evil.\nThe immutable principles ol morality necessarily result, says\nDr. Appleton, from the natureof things, and from the relations\nwhich they have to one another.    As God is the author of all\nthings, the relations subsisting between llicm may be considered as depend ing on him.    But while objects continue in all re-\nspects as they are, no change can he produced in llieir relations.\nIt is absurd, continues he, to ascribe to  Deity the power of\nchanging vice into virtue, or virtue info vice.  ]{ig bt and w rong,\nsays Dr. Price, denote what actions are.    Now, whatever any\nthing is. that it is, not by will, or decree, or power, bin by nature\nand necessity.   Again, the natun s of things being immutable,\nwhatever wo suppose the natures of actions (o be, that they\nmust be immutably,    If they are indifferent, their indifference\nis itsell'ininiutable.    The same is lo be said of right and wrong-,\nmoral geiod and evil, as far as they express real characters of\nactions.    They must immutably and necessarily belong to\nthose actions of which they are truly affirmed.    \"God hath\ngiven us,\" says Bishop Butler, \" a moral faculty, by which\nwe distinguish between actions, and approve of some as virtuous and of good desert, and disapprove others as vicious, and\nof ill desert.  This moral discernment,\" continues he, \" implies\na rule of action, and a rule of a very peculiar kind; for it Carrie's in ii authority, and a right of decision : authority, in such\na sense, that we cannot depart from it without being self-condemned  and the dictates ofthis moral faculty, which are by\nnature a rule to us, are moreover (he laws of God\u2014laws, in a\nsense including sanctions.\"\nThe great question in morals relates to the rules of duty.\nEvery system on this subject, must be founded on some basis\nwhich shall constitute the supreme and ultimate guide. Dr.\nAdams has considered this subject with great ability in his\npreliminary discourse.    In various -passages  he is highly\ntil\n\u25a0ri\n\u2022I i,'\nm;\n-  I \u25a0 L\n'   I. 1\n1       'H\n'        ''I\nI 1\n.","fullrs":{},"find":"428.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"427","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1876227","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.79 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
