<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 11, Page 17</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2389</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2389</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2389/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:56">{"title":"Section 11, Page 17","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"distance from New Orleans to the Pacific Ocean 1610 miles,\ns latter portion of the route, from reliable sources of informa-\nlay be regarded  as  presenting no  great physical difficulties\nofthe Railroads already constructed in the United States.\nCol. Graham of the Topographical  Engineers, in  his report to\nthat Bureau, says :\nIn crossing the Sierra Madra, no difficulties are presented.    It\nDne by a rise so gradual, that were we not admonished by the\nfall of the Mercury in the Barometer, we would be unconscious of\nelevation, from five to six thousand feet above the level of the\nt    The climate along the whole belt of country traversed, is par-\n1. Ii    ni   prises.   It is open all the year round.\nThere are no frosts to upheave the foundations of such a road and dis-\nits superstructure.    No deep snows remaining for months, to\nct a passage.\"\n;re can be no question, we think, that no other route can com-\ndth this in any of the main facilities, for such a work, either in\ngeneral grade, distance from ocean to ocean, climate, or cost of\nuction. We regret our inability, on this occasion, to lay here Stockholders a more comprehensive description of the\ncountry to be traversed by the proposed line of road, beyond the\nof our own State. It is comparatively new and imperfectly\nknown, except in its general features and character. We may,\nshould a more satisfactory knowledge of it be obtained, make it the\n. upplemental report.\nBy the 15th section of the Charter, the project of a branch from\nie trunk of this Road through the North Western Parishes of the\nlate to the Northern Boundary ofthe State of Arkansas is contemplated.\n_ 3 capital and enterprise of the North and East, have by means\nof Railroads and Canals borne off much of the commerce of the\nlississippi Valley, which by natural position was ours, and an ex-\naordinary effort is required on our part to arrest the ebbing tide,\nr to obtain compensation for its loss by the fruits of new enter-\nrises in the West.\nSt. Louis, in a spirit worthy of the intelligence and public spirit\ncl","fullrs":{},"find":"2390.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2389","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"529646","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.51 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
