<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 11</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2171</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2171</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2171/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 11","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"11\nla\u00bbbeen butchered the same morning at a distance of four hundred miles!\nasportation was cheapened, and country and city mutually benefitted.\nCol Payne's idea that the road to Opelousas should be considered as the\nnoncement 0f a ]inc to he carried through Texas, and ultimately to the\nPacific is a noble, magnificent idea\u2014an American idea. It is the idea of a\ntrue-hearted Louisianian, who consults the prosperity and greatness of these\nSouthern States. Let this extension be contemplated. Is London to be the\ngnat mart of the world ? A half century will not elapse before the glories of\n[Jew Orleans will shine bright, and those of London will pale before them. If\nwe do our duty to ourselves, the great State of Tex^s will be open to us. If\ntrue to ourselves, to our manifest destiny, tliis commerce must be ours.\nIt behooves New Orleans to throw off its lethargy. It will be a shame, a\ndisgrace, if the country is not met half way. We are in a wretched crisis.\nOur credit abroad is lost. Wc are lying down supinely, while others arc\nawake and active ; and if we do not arise, half the evil is yet untold.\nThe intellectual and physical power of a great nation, which can send its\nproducts from end to end of the land, literally with moro speed than that of\nthe winds, is immeasurable. It is by subsidizing nature that a people emancipate themselves from barbarism, and become civilized and great. Wc have\nsuhsidized wind, water, magnetism, and even the stars in the heavens. A\nman does not now write a book to read to a few Athenians, but has an audience\nof millions.\nI hope never to see, said Mr. Hunt, the peaceful relations of this country\ndisturbed; but should a foreign power invade this soil, with railroads from the\n1 acific to the Atlantic, from north to south, if necessary to concentrate the\nforces of this Republic, a multitude of citizen soldiers could be assembled at\nany point that would be able to meet the world in arms.\nsir. Hunt apologised for his unpreparedness to address the Convention more\n\u00ab&gt; \"is own satisfaction. His welfare was bound up in Louisiana forever. He\nttuul uot see her despairing and declining, without raising his humble voice to\nJ r ker UP- He counselled his audience not to be timid or dispirited, but to\nw manly and bold, and he was satisfied they would do their duty to Louisiana\n3 taithful sons. Let them carry out the projects to be considered on Monday,\nconsolidate this Union, the only country in which he could, with a whole\n' M ^ and without hesitation, fall down and worship Liberty.\nAs Mr. Hunt left the rostrum, he was enthusiastically\napplauded, as he was frequently during- the delivery of his\nspeech, of which the above is but a sketch.\nThe President announced the appointment of Messrs\n' M. Cohen, Randall -Hunt, Miles Taylor, Alex.","fullrs":{},"find":"2172.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2171","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"575997","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
