<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 26</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/615</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>615</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/615/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:57">{"title":"Page 26","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"f w,\n\u00ab*!\nm\nit&lt;-'\n\u25a0\u25a0:.\nli;-;\nS 11II '1' H - VV E 8 T E 1-. N   J t &gt; V R N A L,\n. i &gt; \u25a0\u25a0\nm'\n1\nj!\nHi\nI\nT J\nII\nI\nI\nI\nI\n1 *.\u00bb'\nrfe\nI? lie-\nkingdoms of Europe- rank their periods of greatest national\nprosperity under th&lt; rights of female sovereigns\u2014among\nthose are Catharine, of Russia; Christiana, of Sweden; and\nElizabeth, of England. And even nt this time, three powerful kingdoms of enlightened Europe acknowledge females as\ntheir political heads. Bul in too many instances such power\nhas been obtained by energy of mind, united with those masculine qualities which have been cultivated to ihe exclusion of\nthese virmes which adorn and beautify the female character.\n\" In life annals of literature, woman holds an exalted station. By the mighty power of intellect, she has enchained\nthe hearts of enraptured and admiring nations ; by the simple\nbut magic strains of poetry, she has touched the spring which\nunlocks the human heart\u2014she has 'spread beauty all around\nour paths,' and has scattered many a flowrct to beguile the\nsorrows of the way-worn pilgrim through life. The character of the sex has been well sustained by the labors of a\nGenlis, an Edgeworth. a Hemans, a Somerville, a Sigoumey,\nand many others of our own day and country, who have won\nlor themselves an imperishable name. There exists a great\ndiversity of sentiment with regard lo the relation which woman ought to sustain in society. Some argue that she is possessed of intellect and capacity equal to that of the other sex,\nand should enjoy the same rank and privileges : while there\nhave been others who seemed unwilling to allow that woman\nwas possessed of a living soul\u2014they would leavens to suppose, that although the Almighty had formed a shrine so\nbeautiful in its symmetry, so exquisite in all its arrangements,\nHe had neglected to place therein the Divinity worthy of\nhomage. Some, of both sexes, have contended for what they\nare pleased to call the rights of woman, whose systems, were\n\u2022hey reduced to practice, would sacrifice those lovely and amiable qualities, the exercise of which constitute the true influence of woman.\n\" Woman is out of her clement when she contends for empire mid the din of battle, or seeks to give laws to nations:\nsuch scenes are incompatible with the duties of daughter.\nwife, and mother, stations of dignity and importance which\nwoman is called lo fill. Her empire is the heart\u2014and, were\nthe relation changed, how much of the beauty and perfection\nol her character would be. sacrificed. The change might\npossibly be effected, though Nature seems to have placed an\ninsuperable barrier to such an innovation. But custom is\nsecond nature ;\u2014woman, by training, might become an Amazon ; and man, by effeminacy, the most delicate, sensitive, and\nhelpless being in creation\u2014but such a state of things would\nfearfully distort the most beautiful feature of society. Wo\nman's influence is mighty, and no less powerful because\nsecret and silent. Its legitimate place is the fireside and do\nmestic circle; and there an impetus to action may be given,\nwhich, like a wave of the ocean, shall be unlimited in its circumference. Such influence animated the Spartan soldier in\nthe battle, to which he bore his mother's command, ' return\nwith your shield, or upon it.' The same influence was exert\ned in the struggle of our own country for liberty; ono of the\nnoblest principles which can animate lhc heart of man. Had\nnot that high and holy principle of independence, implanted\nin the bosoms of our forefathers, who, breaking asunder, the\nlies which bound them to their native hind, soughtasanctini\nn  the forests of the New World, where they might Ivor.\nship God according lo the dictates of their own conscience\nbeen watered, nourished, and consecrated\n' By the tears, the anguish and ihe blood,\n01 those stern martyrs tu the cause of God '\nend bequeathed, as a most precious boon to their children\nfound so firm a strong bold in the hearts of patriotic mothers\nwhose motto was ' Liberty or death ;' had they not by their\nheroic examples of self-denial, contempt of danger and of\ndeath, so strengthened the hanels and encouraged the heartsof\nthe brave few resisting the power of the oppressor, our country\nnight still have been groaning beneath the yoke of tyranny.\n\\nd it was the exercise of womanly virtues which has reflected such a lustre upon the names of mother of the\nGracchi, and mother of Washington.\n\" In the dark ages of the world, when science and literature were confined to the cloister\u2014when the blessed light of\nthe gospel but dimly illuminated a portion of the earth shadowed by the power of superstition\u2014when ' might was\nright,' und confusion and anarchy prevailed, our sex shared\ndeeply in the common degradation. But, when a brighter\ndawn gleamed upon the earth, and the mind of man arose,\nbursting the chains which enthralled it\u2014when the truth of\nGod in its onward course dispelled the shades of ignorance\nand superstition\u2014woman was then elevated to her proper\nrank, which she has ever since in all Christendom retained,\nIf, then, the influence of woman is so extensive and powerful,\nand who will deny it, is it not all-important ihat the principles\nwhich actuated her should be high and holy ? That she should\nbe divested of passions nnd weakness which are but a degradation to her nature ? That she should live for others rather\nthan herself? We should place high the standard of woman's\nexcellence, and constantly endeavor lo elevate ourselves lo\nthat mark, and emulate the virtues which have added so much\nlustre to the character of many of our sex. It has been said\nwith truth : fix your eye on any object which you wish to attain and steadily persevere, surmounting every obstacle, un-\ndiscouraged by difficulties, undismayed by dangers, and you\nwill eventually reach tho eminence you desire.\n\" The character is formed in youth, and the first years of\nour existence may be considered as nn index of our future\ncourse. Woman, then should be early impressed with a just\nsense of her true importance in society ; and all training, ami\nefforts for self-improvement, should be conducted with regard\nto this object, The hand of God is visible in all the works\nof his creation, and nowhere are such combinations of his\npower manifest as in the human form, uniting strength, beaut),\nand utility: but woman should not value herself for her external charms, even though these may be transcendant, and imagine because homage is so often paid to beauty, those lacu \u25a0\nties and powers of mind which arc ctpially the gift of the-\nCreator, are of less value. Though tho beholder may be\nenamored with lhc beautiful casket, yet if it contain no jewe s\nof corresponding value, he will soon become weary of it Wl\npass it by as a useless bauble. But beauty is evanescent. Influence must be based on a firmer support. Neither stiou\nshe trust alone to those accomplishments and graces of mannei","fullrs":{},"find":"616.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"615","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1945194","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.86 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
