<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 21</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2246</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2246</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2246/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 21","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[\u00bb]\n\u25a0 \u25a0 (T witnesses to the fact that they advanpe to greatness with giant\ntHdes- and with equal step.\nif therefore, we prove worthy of our destiny, why, let me ask, may\nNew-York and Philadelphia be repeated on the margin of the\nGulf of Mexico 1\nThe great design which took its origin with your citizens, and\nwhich in my humble judgment challenges in the highest degree their\nttention the connection with the Pacific by the Isthmus of Tehuante-\noec will, if successfully pursued, reflect immortal honor upon its projectors and confer incalculable advantages not only upon your own city,\nbut upon the whole region of country with which she is connected.\nA work so full of promise, and commenced under such auspices,\nshould not be permitted to stop. Neither cold indifference, nor\nsecret hostility, proceeding from quarters however powerful, should\nbe allowed to obtrude themselves between your rights and the protection of the government, which is bound to guaranty them.\nBelieving, therefore, you will receive that goverymental support to\nwhich you are justly entitled, I cannot doubt that the day is near\nat hand when the Gulf and the Pacific will be thus united, and Tehuantepec become a great highway for the nations.\nThere is another subject, kindred to this, and to which I would\nbriefly, through you, call the attention of the Convention : it is the\nconstruction of a ship canal across the state of Florida, from Cedar\nKeys to the St. Johns, or at any point more suitable.\nThe practicability of this work, I assert, upon the authority of some\nofthe most eminent engineers in this country\u2014and its utility, is so\nself-evident, and rests upon so broad a basis, that I would not be justified in consuming time for the purpose of sustaining it.\nWe all know that the chief inducement now held out, to deprive\nthe gulf market of its commerce, is the delay, expense, and danger,\nof navigating the Cape of Florida\u2014the truth of all which is beyond\ndoubt or contradiction. The loss which is incurred by the dangers of\nthis navigation would, in a few years, compensate the cost of such a\nwork.\nEvery motive, therefore, which could address itself to those who\nare interested in the navigation of the gulf, comes in the most imposing form to urge this subject upon the public mind.\nIt is wonderful that, suffering under the burthens so long imposed\nupon our commerce by these difficulties, so interesting a question\nis this should have slumbered until this day, without that scientific\ninvestigation which its vast importance merits.\n-fhis route would not only save the immense contribution now\ned upon our commerce, but would  also  greatly modify the\n\"Heal aspect ofthe Cuba question, giving a transit for much of our\nn commerce over our own territory, and greatly strengthening\n| confederacy in its military defences.\nbpj mP^ssed by the great importance of this work, I took occasion to\nthia^*     -SU^'ect before an internal improvement convention, held in\nthe     * -U \"^a^* 'ast' ant* wh'ch adopted a resolution, expressive of\n\u00b0pmion favorable to its practicability and great value.    Acting\n3","fullrs":{},"find":"2247.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2246","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"550781","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.53 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
