<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 5, Page 8</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2168</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2168</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2168/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:47">{"title":"Section 5, Page 8","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"The resolution having been read, there was a genera]\ncall for Mr. Robb, who came forward, and addressed the!\nConvention in support of the resolution :\nHe expressed his deep gratification that the subject of railroads had enga\u00abj [\nso much of the attention of the people during the past year, in a State whij I\nhad hitherto neglected so greatly the unequalled advantages Nature Had I\nbestowed upon her. It was necessary that every man, who felt an interest a I\nLouisiana, should rally in support of the cause, and give material aid. It m I\nuseless for them to assemble in Convention, or otherwise, unless they were til\ndo every thing in their power; and not only give their individual exertions mi I\nassistance, but exert their influence to obtain from the Legislature a repeal c I\nthe laws which held in abeyance the enterprise and public spirit of the State, |\nIf wc, at this moment, possessed millions, under the existing laws, we could nil\nbuild railroads. \"What instance is there in the history of the Anglo-Sara I\nrace of an inhibition to embark in an enterprise, requiring over five hundred I\nthousand dollars capital ? And, yet, such is the anomolous situation i I\nLouisiana.\nTalk of republicanism and freedom; what is there in the history of tie I\nOld World equal to this ? These are matters that should engage the attcnta I\nof assemblages here. Time should not be wasted in uttering idle scntiniento; I\nbut a determination should be shown to remove the impediments to progre* I\nand improvement. It is not New Orleans alone that is fettered, the whet I\nState is suffering from the same causes ; and it is gratifying to see the pc;\nfrom the country, the repository of political power, coming in and puttae I\ntheir shoulders to the wheel.\nWe should look to something more than sugar and cotton planting- \u2122\nshould invite and foster every species of industry that tends to make a (\u2022\nnionwealth permanently great and prosperous.\nHe warmly supported the resolution under consideration.     Pass % w\nurged, and the Legislature would enter with increased confidence upon &lt;*\nneeded reforms.     Legislators would not seek to know whether they *ot*\nmake votes by passing this measure or that; but would ask what was for\ngood of the State 1     Nothing could compare with the advantages we ff\u00b0\ngain by embarking in a magnificent railroad system, such as our sister Sw\nare building up ; and in the consideration of this grand subject, private!\nindividual benefit should be lost sight of, in the ambition for the general 0\nRepresentatives should be made to feel that their allegiance is not du&lt;\nparties, nor their support to sectional measures alone.     Enlightened 1\u00bb\nliberal and enlarged policy are wanted, and they would make New Orle\"\nfirst city in the world.     She possesses every advantage, except the advaB\nof good laws.","fullrs":{},"find":"2169.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2168","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"620906","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.59 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
