<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Section 7, Page 1</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p15140coll10:collection</url>
      </location>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p15140coll10/id/2226</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2012-01-18</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p15140coll10</alias>
         <pointer>2226</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p15140coll10/2226/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-03 08:24:50">{"title":"Section 7, Page 1","subjec":{},"descri":{},"creato":{},"publis":{},"date":{},"year":{},"format":{},"reposi":{},"collec":{},"reposa":{},"rights":{},"digitb":{},"langua":{},"topics":{},"cite":{},"notes":{},"notesa":{},"source":{},"box":{},"folder":{},"identi":{},"relati":{},"findin":{},"catalo":{},"type":{},"full":"[1]\nOX EXTENDING THE COMMERCE OF THE SOUTH AND WEST BY SEA.\nNational Observatory, )\nWashington, Dec. 16, 1851. J\nTo Gi.esdy Burke, A. D. Grossman, J. D. B. De Bow, Esqs., &amp;c. &amp;c,\nCommittee Southwestern Rail-Road Convention:\nGentlemen,\u2014I am in receipt of your esteemed favor, informing me\nofthe Rail-Road Convention to be held in New-Orleans on the first\nMonday in January next, and inviting me to be present, and \" address the Convention upon the extension of Southern and Western\ncommerce; the home and foreign trade as they are influenced by facilities of intercourse and communication by rail-roads or otherwise;\nor to prepare a report upon these subjects, to be read before the\nConvention, and placed among its documents.\"\nMy official engagements put it out of my power to attend ; and I\nregret exceedingly that present calls upon my attention will\nnot, at this late day, allow me to give as much time to the consideration of the vast subjects which are about to occupy the attention\nofthe Convention as their importance deserves.\nHad I the time requisite for the necessary reflection, arrangement\nand consideration, the very few thoughts that I have to offer might\nbe presented in paragraphs as few.\nHappy at all times to aid in a good work, and truly grateful to\nyou for the privilege of doing good, if I be able, I make the following reply, in homage of my respect, and as a good-will offering for\nthe success of those great enterprises which you have in hand.\nMost of the rail-roads run across the ridges, and go from valley to\nvalley. In one sense, our navigable water courses may be considered\nas inclined planes, and the river craft as gravity-cars, which, taking\nadvantage of a physical principle, convey the produce to market at\na cheap rate along the natural descents of the country. Hence the\nvery striking feature in our internal improvement system : the\nJjaii-roads and navigable rivers cross at right angles. This is the rule.\n. e Hudson River Rail-Road, and some of those which are either\nn contemplation or in process of actual construction in the South,\nare the exceptions which make that rule general.\nU&amp;n the steam-ear on the land successfully compete in the trans-\nmL.ti0.n \u00b0f merchaudise with the gravity-car on the water?\nlih      .'s one \u00b0f the questions which will no doubt command the delations \u00b0f the Convention.    Rs members will be far better able\ntrv K      than * am' whether the condition of your part of the coun-\nj be such that railways may run along parallel with your magnifi-\nnt Water courses, and live.\n1","fullrs":{},"find":"2227.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2012-01-18","dmmodified":"2012-01-18","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"2226","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"579797","cdmfilesizeformatted":"0.55 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
