<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Page 09</title>
  </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate"
         authority="naf"
         authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names"
         valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015036095"
         displayLabel="Contributing Repository">
      <namePart>LSU Libraries. Special Collections</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text"
                   authority="marcrelator"
                   authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
                   valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/rps">Repository</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <location>
         <url displayLabel="Relation">http://louisianadigitallibrary.org/islandora/object/lsu-sc-p120701coll12:collection</url>
      </location>
      <titleInfo displayLabel="Digital Collection">
         <title>LSU Libraries Louisiana and Lower Mississippi Valley Collections</title>
      </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation authority="oclcorg" displayLabel="OCLC Member Symbol">LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation displayLabel="Physical Location" xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu">LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      
   </location>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Rights">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" displayLabel="Contact Information">Please submit an LSU Special Collections reference ticket at https://askus.lib.lsu.edu/special for any questions or comments about this digital object.</accessCondition>
   <identifier displayLabel="Migrated From" invalid="yes" type="uri">http://cdm16313.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p120701coll12/id/406</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordOrigin>Transformed into MODS from extended Dublin Core by the LDL Development Team at Louisiana State University.</recordOrigin>
      <recordCreationDate>2010-10-08</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate>2018-12-05-06:00</recordChangeDate>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <extension>
      <CONTENTdmData>
         <alias>p120701coll12</alias>
         <pointer>406</pointer>
         <dmGetItemInfo mimetype="application/json"
                        source="https://server16313.contentdm.oclc.org/dmwebservices/index.php?q=dmGetItemInfo/p120701coll12/406/json"
                        timestamp="2017-02-09 16:30:59">{"title":"Page 09","creato":{},"date":{},"biogra":{},"summar":{},"descri":{},"langua":{},"publis":{},"type":{},"covera":{},"subjec":{},"notes":{},"contri":"Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections (http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special).","reposi":{},"reposa":{},"source":{},"cite":{},"rights":"Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. In accordance with U. S. copyright laws, this work is in the public domain.","contac":"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See instructions for ordering reprints of this item here: http:\/\/www.lib.lsu.edu\/special\/services\/duplication.html Mention the \"Item number\" or \"Item URL\" in your request. ","object":{},"identi":"See 'reference url' on the navigation bars.","collec":{},"format":{},"relati":{},"coverb":{},"catlog":{},"catalo":{},"image":{},"hardwa":{},"digiti":{},"digita":{},"transc":"S 0 U T H - W E S T E i!N J 0 H R N A L.\n41\nroots around their trunks, creep to the summit of their branch-\nis, and, passing from tho maple lo the tulip tree', and nleea,\nform a thousand bowers and verdant arcades; stretching from\ntree to tree, often do they throw their fibrous arms across rivers, and erect on them arches of foliage and flowers: amidst\nthese fragrant clusters, tho proud magnolia raise's its immovable cone, adorned with snowy roses, and commanding over the\nwhole forest, meets with no other rival than the palm tree\nwhose green leaves are softly limned by the refreshing gales.\"\n\" But Gallia's gallant suns, sunn understood\n, By the fair moons, 'IV. \"\nThe French cavaliers and adventurers never omitted, we\nbelieve, an opportunity, wherever they were, of showing their\ndevotion to the female sex. There arc many fragments of\ntraditions still extant, respecting the loves of the Indian\nmoons, with these gay colony-founders.\n\" And heard an Indian widow's lone lament.\"\nThe fact here narrated is authentic; but it was not a widow\n\u2022 if ihe Natchez tribe, who thus dug down  to the remains of\nher chief, and died upon them, to secure a burial with him.\n\" Where yonder mounds stilt liruve the waste of years. \"\nReference is here made to tho interesting and well-preserved mounds near Sclscrtown, in  this county, about sixteen\nmiles from Natchez.\n\" For there a city spread its ample, domes. \"\nIt is but reasonable to conclude that a number of mounds\nindicate the site of a city, as these mounds were, undoubtedly,\nboth places of burial for the dead, and mural altars, where sacrifices by fire were offered, either lo tho deities, or to the manes\nof the dead. The mounds appear lo be raised by the successive layers of the dead, covered deeply over, making a plateau\nfor another layer, nnd thus for another. They wero truly the\nsacretl places, or urns, of ihe Indians, who had a high reverence for ihe bones and dust of their fathers.\n\"('nine to tic conquered by a. siniilc glance.\"\nThere is a tradition, received by the venerable John Hutch-\nins,  Esq., of this vicinity, from his father,  Col. Anthony\nHutching, who received it from some of the Natchez Indians\nthemselves, that a young Indian maiden, in love with a gay\nyuan.;' Frenchman in the fort, sought means to cause a failure in the grand expedition concerted for iho destruction of\ntho French garrison by the Natchez and Choctaw Indians.\nHer plan to ruin the concert between the two tribes did not\nanswer tho end which she intended; for when the Natchez\nhad drawn tho last slick, or arrow, from tho bundle, which\nindicated the concerted time of attack by both tribes, they advanced to the attack alone, and effected the slaughter.  When\nthe Choctnwscamo to the foray, they were surprised that the\nNatchez were beforehand with them, and both accused the\n. other, alternately, with treachery or cowardice.    A quarrel\narose respecting the division of plunder, and ihe two tribes\nfought with each other until almost the entire tribe of the\nNatchez was exterminated.    The unhappy moon, who had\nthus been the indirect cause of Ihe slaughter of her father\nand In-other, as well as most of her tribo who had first murdered her lover, was seized with melancholy, and went and\ndrowned herself in a lake.\n\"tn yonder fountain gushing from the bonk.\"\nReference is here made to a beautiful perennial fountain,\nin a deep dill, in the grounds attached to Jefferson College:\nThis would have been a convenient place of gratuitous refreshment, when restaurants were scarce, to a panting Indian\ngirl,\n\"Lost Rosalicl\" tf.e.\nThe destruction of the French fort and garrison occurred\nsometime in the period included between the years 1717 and\n1727\u2014antiquarians have not as yet fixed upon the precise\nlale, although it might be ascertained, doubtless, by a starch\nin the colonial archives of France.\n\/-\" \" To summon Holbrook from his soldier's bed.\"\nThe remains of tho intellectual and high-minded Maj.\nHolbrook. the Principal of Jefferson College, while it was\nunder a military organization, as a Polytechnic Academy,\nare interred in a lonely field, in the rear of Jefferson College.\nThe paling, which incloses his resting place, can be seen from\ntho College windows.\nErratum,\u2014The Latin line on the -10,h page should rend \"Scd cc-\nduiil arma, t$*c.\nDISCOVERY OF Mississippi.\nBY   MANN ni'Tl.cn,  ESQ.\n(in tho 27lh March, 1512, fourteen years after the discovery by Columbus of tin\" main land of America, Ponce do Leon\ndiscovered Florida, in his romantic search for iho fountain of\nyouth.    This was a spring, which was extensively believed\nai ihat day, lo possess tho virtue \"I renewing the wasted powers of lilo.     Notwithstanding this charmed power in the\nwaters of Florida, the discoverer died mortally wounded in a\ncontest with the warlike natives.    lie was soon followed by\nvarious adventurers, British ami Spanish.    Bui Pnmplu'lo do\nNarvaez and Hernando de Soto, were ihe most distinguished,\nThe former is supposed lo have landed, mi the 12th ol April,\n15211, near tho bay, now called ApolacllCC,     After passing\nsix months in exploring Florida, ho coasted tho southern\nmargin of ibis State, and tho whole | arty, t xei pi four, wore\nshipwrecked, near tin: mouth of tho Mississippi.    Tin-survivors, after years of captivity and hardship among tho Indians,\nreached the city of Mexico.    He Soto, whoso famo you so\nwell commemorate, in ono ofthe northern counties of the\nState, possibly in the path of his ancient  exploration, next\nfollowed.    This most remarkable adventurer, even a, a lime\nand in a nation of unsurpassed enterprise, as if destined to\nrealize the wildest visions of roiumico\/hud participated with\nI'izarro in the conquest of Peru.    He had realized, in that\nfairy work, every thing, it might well be supposed, Ihat love\nof fiiine and wealth could desire. Still this favorite of fortune,\nthe pride of the knights of (lid Castile, panted to intertwine\nhis heroicand wayward fato with the stately forests of Mississippi.    His keen passion for advt itiiiii- kindled a' tho news\nlirouglit to Spain, by the surviving associates of Nu vaez; ami\nhe easily obtained from the partiality and confidence of Charles\nthe Fifth, then Emperor of Germany, and King of Spain\nanil the Indies, tho government of Cuba and of Florida,\nIn May, 1539, all but 300 years ago, the Adelantndo of\nFlorida landed al the bay ol Espirilu Santo, the Tampa Bay\nLibrary vi\"- \u00bb\u2014\u00bbi\nLouisiana State University","fullrs":{},"find":"407.jp2","dmaccess":{},"dmimage":{},"dmcreated":"2010-10-08","dmmodified":"2010-10-08","dmoclcno":{},"dmrecord":"406","restrictionCode":"1","cdmfilesize":"1749138","cdmfilesizeformatted":"1.67 MB","cdmprintpdf":"0","cdmhasocr":"1","cdmisnewspaper":"0"}</dmGetItemInfo>
      </CONTENTdmData>
  </extension>
</mods>
